Ninety-one,Ninety-two...
It's down there.  Where? If they catch us...
There's a million bottles of booze in there.
You think they're gonna miss one?
Weather is with us,sir.
We arrive in port in a couple of hours.
Very good.
You're welcome,sir.
Man,I never smelt anything like this. Not even when you're in the crapper.
Oh,what,your shit smells like roses?
Hey,look.
I'll give you a hand.
Thought you said it was booze.  That's what the papers said.
Captain,we have a breach in lower level. Look.
Which section?  101.
Fuck. Take the wheel.
Yes,sir.  Fuck.
Close the door! Get the masks.
Holy shit.
Take care of them.
Morning.  Passport,please.
Rough seas?
The sea was smooth. The party was a bit rough,if you know what I mean.
Ibiza.  Yeah.
Thanks.
When I was a kid,my father used to take me fishing.
Never could figure out how he knew where the fish were.
They were always exactly where he said they would be.
Security check.
Do I look like a security risk?
Please step out of the car and bring your documents to the office.
My documents are right here,sir.
The computer is in the office.
Her too.
She's sleeping.
With her documents.  Okay,sure.
Come on. You're gonna lose it.
Close,inspector,you're close.
That's a big one. Go left,go left.
Don't let him get away.
You're close.
Go left,go left! Go right!
Must be Moby Dick you hooked. Need some help?
No,thank you,Frank.
I have been fishing these waters since before you were born.
You were close,inspector. You were close.
Good thing that we French have such a highly developed sense of humor.
With all due respect,the French think Jerry Lewis is a genius.
Jerry Lewis is a genius.  Dean was the genius.
No,Dean just stood there with a drink and a cigarette.
My point exactly. Anyone can fall down and get a laugh.
How many people can do it standing still with a drink and a cigarette?
I am afraid our day of leisure is cut short.
There is a big mess in Marseilles.
Some madman driving an Audi at impossible speeds.
Don't look at me.
That is the first place the chief told me to look.
But I will tell him you have the perfect alibi.
As usual.
Tarconi!
Please!  I am sorry,Frank.
It's our first bite!  Yeah,yeah.
Please.  Yeah.
Stop the boat. Come on.
No. No,Frank.  Come on,please.
Purpose of your visit,Mr. Johnson?
Business.
What kind of business?
Environmental protection.
Thank you.
Mr. Minister,you're giving the opening address at an EU conference...
on environmental impact of industry in Odessa tomorrow.
What is top on your list of priorities?  It's a short list.
There's only one item: The environment and how to protect it.
In the face of increasing pressure...
for industries to compete successfully in a global economy...
that goal can sometimes come up against some very harsh realities.
Well,not as harsh as a polluted and uninhabitable planet.
Gentlemen,if you'll excuse me now...
I have trees to save and industrialists to disappoint.
Your speech for tomorrow.  Any good?
It's going to piss off a lot of people.  Excellent.
Hello?
Mr. Minister?
Who is this?
My name is not important.
I've been put in charge of the negotiations...
you are engaged in with Ecocorp...
for issuance of their license to do business in the Ukraine.
You must be misinformed,Mr. Whatever-Your-Name-Is.
I've terminated negotiations permanently.
I think you will reconsider that position...
once you have a chance to study the documents in the envelope.
I'll be in touch.
Yeah,there's been an accident.
Send an ambulance,8 Route de la Falaise.
Malcolm.
Malcolm. Malcolm.
I asked you for your price. What is this?
A man who might be interested in taking the job. This man will.
My boss said you're the man for the job.
Your boss got his facts wrong.
Two things you should know about my boss:
He never gets his facts wrong,he never takes no for an answer.
Well,there's a first time for everything.
Well,not this time.
You don't wanna do this.
I don't think you're in a position to tell me what I do and don't wanna do.
You have 10 seconds to change your mind.
I'll give you five seconds to remove your hand.
Malcolm. Malcolm.
You hear me?
Mal,I said drop in anytime,but I didn't mean...
Nowhere else to go.  Just take it easy,okay?
Don't move me from the car.
It's just get you comfortable till the ambulance arrives.  No ambulance.
You need a doctor,you've been shot. I can't take care of this.
Not far from car.
Relax.
Just try to stay calm. We'll have you fixed up in no time.
He's inside. Quick,it's serious.
Sir?
You wanna be careful moving him.  We know our job,okay?
Sir,can you hear me?
This car No...
If you hear me,press my hand.
The car...
Am I in heaven?
Actually,you're in a bit of the shit.
You'll help me out of it?
That depends on how deep you're in.
Don't trust anyone.  Couldn't agree with you more.
Come on.  No! Don't leave the car!
What's so special about the car?  Not the car.
Wait!
I told you.
Don't trust anyone.
I took the liberty of bringing your suit.
It's what you wear when you're working,correct?
Correct. But I'm not working.
You see,boss? I told you.  Please,Joseph.
Your approach was not very effective in presenting our proposal the first time.
Thank you.
As I was saying...
we came to you in good faith. You said you were unavailable.
We contracted with the man whose number you gave us.
He proved to be ineffective.
And now I am left with unfinished business.
The way I see it,you're responsible.
I understand your point of view.
But I'm still unavailable.
Boss,can I say something?
Anyone else wanna say something?
Good.
Find me a smarter one.
You have three seconds to change your mind...
or you're gonna be permanently unavailable.
One.
Two.
One condition.
I'm listening.
I drive my own car.
Deal.
In anticipation of your answer,we took the liberty of bringing your car.
Changed the oil,gave it a tune-up,took out all the non-essential material.
Left the switch-over license plates. Love that.
Replaced the GPS with one of our own.
Preprogrammed. More efficient that way.
Why I was so insistent on using only the best man for this assignment?
We're playing in a much larger game here.
Don't think of this as just another job. Think of it as a mission.
I'm so pleased to find we share the same approach to our work.
I make a deal,that's the deal. Just like you.
You don't like names. Neither do I. We're both precise.
Neither one of us has any interest in what we're paid to do...
beyond what we are paid to do. Those are your rules,right?
You forgot one.
I work alone.  I thought you might like the company.
Thought you wanted me to complete a mission.
You're right. I do.
Wait.
What,you wanna change the rules?
Every rule has an exception. Let's make one for today.
You're the boss.
Anything else?
The jewelry. Anything I should know?
You remember those jokers trying to blow up airliners...
by sneaking liquids through and combining them onboard?
Same principle,just refined.
Twenty-five feet from the car...
yellow light comes on,signaling the first liquid is ready.
Fifty feet,orange.
Second liquid flows into the chamber.
Seventy-five feet,you're gonna see red.
Time to go.
This phone is programmed to call only one number,mine.
When you pass the first toll on the road going north,call me,all right?
Money for gas and food.
Any other questions?
Would you mind buckling your seat belt?
Don't suppose you wanna tell me what this is all about?
Great.
Ocean Pearl requesting cargo clearance.
The papers are with the environmental agency.
Drop anchor and wait to dock.
We'll inform you when they're signed.  Okay.
I know what happened to you.
But what happened to Frank?
Colonel Medved over at Intelligence has been given all the information.
He knows it's top priority.
He wants you to know he has his best men on it.
He'll keep it out of official channels.
He suggests you buy as much time as you can.
Look,I don't know what your part in all this is or isn't. And I don't really care.
You were here first,you know more than I do...
download me on what you know.
I know nothing.
How did you know Malcolm?
I didn't.
You just happened to end up in a car with a man you don't know?
I'm now in a car with man I don't know.
Aren't you supposed to make a call?
Nice to hear from you.
You can skip the pleasantries. Just give me the code.
1-1-2-6.
Call me when you arrive.
What's in Budapest?
Goulash. Beer.
All right.
Let's rewind here,start with the proper introductions.
What happened to the rule of no names?
I'm suspending that rule for the moment.
I'm Frank Martin.
And your name is?
What matters,my name?
Well,we're in this situation together.
No.
We're sitting here with two exploding bracelets on,going to the same place.
I'd call that being in the same situation.
It's not. They are going to kill you.
I'm aware of that.
In all probability,after they kill me,you're next on the list.
Now,if I'm gonna keep that from happening,I'm gonna need a little help.
From the top. We have this problem.
You think I don't know it's a problem?
I look stupid to you?
I didn't say you were stupid.
But we have a problem
and you're not being very helpful in participating in the solution of it.
I don't want to talk anymore.
Fine.
What did you say your name was?
Frank. Frank Martin.
Frank Martin.
Valentina.
Pleased to meet you.
The gentlemen from Ecocorp are here.
Show them in.
Gentlemen.
Mr. Minister.
We'd like to thank you for reconsidering our proposal
on such short notice.  You make it very hard not to.
Well,yes. We do have a reputation of not taking no for an answer.
Here are the contracts.
All in order.
We were told the ships couldn't be cleared
unless you personally signed off on them.
Ships?
I thought there was only one.
Oh,well,here's the thing.
In order to make the venture more profitable
we need to process the material in a volume that makes sense.
How many ships are we talking about?
Plus the one in the port waiting on clearance,eight.
Eight.
This year.
Protecting the environment is a long-term commitment.
You've said so yourself,haven't you?
And I will do again tomorrow in Odessa
where I will sign these.
We were really hoping to settle this today.
I want to review them,now that there are some addendums.
Twenty-four hours doesn't make a difference
on such a long-term commitment,will it?
No,of course not.
Then I will see you tomorrow in Odessa. Let's say 9 a.m.
Yes.
Okay,I'll stay.
But the material is leaking everywhere.  And?
We won't be able to hide it.  I'll take care of it,just give me some time.
If ever they check...
Easy. The deal will be closed very soon.
Twenty-four hours. No more.
Yes?  I've bought you another 24 hours.
You have until tomorrow,9 a.m.
That should be more than enough time.
Do you have a lead?
Better than a lead.
A location.
I'm hungry.
We're 100 kilometers from beer and sausage.
I don't like sausage.
What would you like?
Veal.
Roast,with carrots...
and beets.
In gravy,with Madeira in stock.
Nothing to start?
A salad.
Greens tossed with balsamic.
From Modena.
Aged?
Of course,aged.
And for dessert?
Sachertorte.
With whipped cream or without?
With.
To drink?
Wine.
Tokaj,perhaps?
Ice wine.
Of course.
What are you doing?   Seeing a man about some jewelry.
He's gone off the reservation.
Send someone to get him back on.
Don't kill him.
Frank. It's so good to see you,mein Freund.
Good to see you too,Otto.
You didn't mention you bring company.
It's not really company.
It's...
complicated.
With you,it's always complicated. But you can tell me about it...
over a nice schnitzel with Kartoffelsalat I have prepared.
Hey,Otto,you know I love your schnitzel
but we need to get rid of this first.
Binary free-form magnetic-resolution technology.
English,please,Otto.
There's a program the Pentagon has funded
through one of their subsidiary front companies
that's been experimenting with this new kind of weaponry
based on the theory of magnetic attraction.
Very hush-hush stuff.
I didn't realize you were in the loop on the Pentagon hush-hush.
You wouldn't believe what you can discover
when you left your fingers walking through the Internet.
You wanna see the invasion plans for Iran?
Maybe some other time.
Right now we need to get this thing off without blowing myself to Iran.
I don't wanna bother you with the details
but usually there's a transmitter plate close by.
You should not be doing this.
First you don't talk,now you offer advice.
Not advice. A warning.
Well,a little late for warnings,don't you think?
I agree with you.
You're off course.
Should I?   Yeah,you should.
Look,fellas
some things in the car were a bit off,needed checking.
In my profession,a man is only as good as the car he drives.
You take care of the car,the car will take care of you.
The boss says," Back on the road."
Frank?
Keep at it.
Back in the car,Frank.
No.
Find it?   Not yet.
You're the smart one?
No. I'm the big one.
Not so big anymore,are you?
Found it.
The transmitter.  Can you remove it?
It's wired.
If I do: it comes boom.
You fight good.
But your tie bad.
Where are you going?
Tired.
That's why I prefer to deal with cars.
That makes two of us.
What do you want me to do when they? When they wake up?
Probably best to take the rest of the day off.
I'm not amused.
You'd be less amused if you ended up dead.
If you wanted me dead,I'd be dead. You need me alive.
You want me to complete the job,I need some clarification.
I'm listening.
In person.
We've already done in person.
Well,not to my satisfaction,apparently.
Right now,my satisfaction should be your main concern.
Same place. One hour. Wait for my call.
Hello?
You've disappointed me.
You won't be the first and you won't be the last.
I told you I wanted to do this in person.  That won't be necessary. You see...
since our little chat at the beginning
I've been thinking I don't need the best for this mundane assignment.
Any idiot with a driver's license will do.
So in the words of the great American,Donald Trump:
I'm sorry,but you're fired.
Who are you?
Your new chauffeur.   I want the old one back.
He's about to go to pieces.
You're fired.
How was your nap?
Restful. How was your phone call?
Brief. Fasten your seat belt.
Tarconi.
It's me.
I was wondering when you would call.
I've been busy.
Let me guess. In Budapest?
You've been busy too.
Never a problem keeping that way with a friend like you,Frank.
So I don't have to be redundant,tell me what you know.
There is a black Mercedes also in Budapest.
Probably not occupied by friends of yours.
That is what I know. Now tell me what you know.
I have two bags in the back and a girl in the front.
Russian,I think.
I don't know what she has to do with anything.
Have you tried asking her?
Now,why didn't I think of that?  Sorry.
Of course you've asked. And she says?
I'm going to die.
Typical. Russians.
They are so dark.
I remember,in school,reading Dostoyevsky and thinking
when do these people laugh?
One page after the other
misery and suffering like you wouldn't believe,Frank.
Inspector,can we save the literature lesson? I'm blinking here.
Is that code?
No,it's some bracelet they accessorized us with.
Wired to explode if we get too far from the car.
They?
Some American.
Can you be more specific? A name? A number?
Nothing.
Why do you always make it so easy,Frank?
It's my nature.
Where are you? I will come there.
That's not a good idea. They have me on a short leash.
I can't be of much help if you do not give me something.
How close are you to a computer?
Yes,Frank?
That wasn't very nice,back there in the market.
You were the one who broke the rules,not me.
Point well taken.
That makes us even. What say we start with a clean slate?
So this call is about kiss-and-make-up,then?
More or less.
You have what I need to get the bracelet off...
I have the packages you need delivered.
Here are the new coordinates,then: 2-6-12.
That'll take you to the place...
where we can have a conclusion to this business.
I look forward to it.
Frank.
Did you get it?
Got the signal. Give us a little time...
and we should have his number and location.
Your new phone,sir.
Anything else?  No.
Frank,do you know where the signal is taking you?
I know restaurant there. Fish like you never had.
Roasted with small carrots and black pepper.
Romanian wine,not so good.
But for the last meal,could be worse.
You really should begin to think more positive.
I'm realist.
My friend was right when he said you were doom and gloom.
What means "doom and gloom"?
You know,you only see the horrible and the terrible.
Your friend,where does he get this? He doesn't know me.
He was talking about you in general. Russians,as a people.
I'm not Russian. I'm Ukrainian.
Excuse me.
Not excused. We're different people. We're different here...
and here.
Me,personally,I think there's a little bit of an optimist in you.
How you can make such a statement? You don't know me.
Well,I see you're putting makeup on.
If you were so convinced we was gonna die,why bother?
What does looking good have to do with dying?
Hello.
What's that?
Souvenirs from Ibiza. Do you want one?
No,thank you. And neither do you. We need to stay sharp.
Okay.
You stay sharp.
I stay,how you say? Optimist?
Give me that. Give me that thing. Give me the pill!
Give me that...
Jesus.
Great.
Just great.  Come on,Frank Martin,lighten up.
I should? How about when those pills hit?
You're gonna be lighting up like a goddamn Christmas tree.
That would be nice.
Boring. Boring. Boring?
Oh,yeah.
You should stay in the car.
You want me to pee in car?
Okay. Go on.
You remember.
Don't.
Oh,no.
Stop,all right?  Why? I don't drive.
I want to have fun.
I want to be happy. You should try happy instead of so serious.
It's important to stay positive,like you say,yeah?
Drink with me,Frankie.  I don't want a drink.
Now who is all gloomy and doomy?
I say it right? Gloomy doomy?
Come on,get in the car.
I am free,like a bird.
The girl! Come on! Faster!
I have lost my friend!  I'll buy you a new one.
Have any idea why we have a car on our ass?
I don't know. I don't care.
You mind?  First you say I'm doom and gloom...
and now you tell me do not be happy? Make up your mind.
Yes,Frank?  I thought we had an agreement.
We do.
It had nothing to do with a car on my ass.
I don't have anything to do with that. Someone else has issues with you?
Likely.
What I think is that there are other forces at work here.
Let me check into it,see what I can find out.
What do I do in the meantime?
Drive faster.
What the hell is he doing?
There!
He's down there!
I'm hungry.
Should have thought about a sandwich,not vodka.
Look!
I wasn't hungry then,I was thirsty.
Why you are so mean to me?
I'm not being mean. I'm preoccupied.  What means "preoccupied"?
That means preoccupied.
Shoot the tires! Come on! Get him!
Get down!  Shoot him!
Bloody hell!
Faster!
Stop the car!
Oh,shit!
What are you doing?
You're so tense.
You don't say.
I make you relax,okay?
Yeah.  I'm good at this.
Making tense go away.
What are you doing?
I want to feel sex one more time before I die.
Don't you?
What is it with you and dying?
There is something wrong with me?
Am I not sexy?
Yeah,you're sexy.
You're the gay.
Nope,I am not the gay.
I don't mind.
I'm not,okay?
Then what's the problem?
Did it ever occur to you that maybe I'm not in the mood?
I thought rule is don't open package.  It is.
Why you have rules if you break them?
I keep asking myself the same thing.
Phone books.
You're the package.  Yes.
Could have said something.
Would it make a difference?  Yes.
Now what are you doing?
You know,back in garage...
it was very turn-on to me when you take off your clothes.
I was trying to keep five cretins from caving my head in.
I don't see the turn-on in that.
You think it's only man gets turned on by striptease?
I don't like where this is going,Valentina.
Would you striptease for me again?
Give me the keys. This is not funny.
You want keys?
I want you to stop playing around,is what I want.
Maybe it's last chance to play around for you and for me.
This is not the time or the place for playing.
Why do I get feeling with you it's never time or place?
If I wanna get analyzed,I'll see a psychiatrist.
Now,give me the keys.
Come on,Frank Martin.
Make playtime for me.
All right? That enough?
Not enough. That is not a striptease,Frank.
Striptease is sexy. You know,move your ass a little.
Come on,Frank Martin.
You want keys?
I want strip.
You know what I'm gonna do to you for making me do this?
Spank me?
For starters.
Tie me up?  You'd like that,wouldn't you?
I like the rough stuff.
Really?
Oh,but not too rough.
Deal was a striptease for the keys.
New deal. Kiss me for the keys.
Like you mean it.
Do you ever kiss like you mean it,Frank?
I'm thinking maybe not.
I'm thinking you live alone.
Inside and outside.
Thinking it is not dying you're afraid of.
It's living.
Live with me.
Just this once.
Just this moment. Live with me.
What's his position?  We lost him.
He headed into the mountains. We can't get reception up there.
Hack into one of the military satellites.
Yes.
You think we're playing games here,Mr Minister?
I don't know what you're talking about.
I'm talking about a black car full of your incompetent operatives.
One more move like that and you will never see your daughter again.
I want to hear her voice.
When the contract is signed and delivered.
I will not sign until I hear her voice.
You are in no position to play hardball,Mr Minister.
Well,neither are you,Mr Johnson.
Yes,I know who you are.
And I can assure you,if anything happens to my daughter...
I will use all the power I have.
I will hunt you down and make you pay in a most hideous way for this.
We have to move now.
Pick up,Frank. Pick up.
I'm in Ibiza. Making holiday.
Someone hands me glass of champagne.
I drink.
Then I don't feel so good.
I go to bathroom,and next thing,I'm awake in the car.
I ask him,"Where is this?" He tells me he's just a transporter.
He's pretty good driver.
Not like you good.
I tell him,"Please. My father a really powerful man.
Big influence. Knows a lot of people. Let me call him."
He's afraid. He's never done this before.
It's supposed to be simple. Pick up,drop off. Easy money.
He's been told no calls,never leave car.
But I convince him.
I call.
But before I say to my father where we are...
Inside the car. Come on!
We get away,but...
There's people shooting at us. Why?
Why they shooting at us?
He says they shoot because we didn't go according to plan.
I said,"Okay,that's the old plan. What's new plan?"
He says he has a friend.
And then I met you.
And then I feel it's gonna be okay.
You didn't even know me.
Of course I don't know you.
I talk about feelings,not knowing.
Well,if you was feeling that way,you sure had a funny way of showing it.
Better for a woman to have a little mystery to her.
No?
No.
Yes. Just a little.
He's back on the radar,sir.
Yeah.  Where the hell are you?
On the way to Bucharest.
Not any longer.
New coordinates: 3-7-13.
Excuse me,Mr. Minister.
Sorry,just a minute.
Inspector Tarconi,from Marseilles.
Well,not exactly Marseilles...
but a small town to the east What do you want,inspector?
A word with you.  I have no time.
It's about your daughter.
Odessa,Frank. My country.
You take me home. Thank you.
What happened to Bucharest?
Change of plans.  It's a good change. I prefer Odessa.
Yeah.
I was looking forward to that fish with the carrots myself.
Oh,it's much better here.
You know chicken Kiev?  I do.
I know restaurant here.
Best in the world.
The chicken's so fresh. And the butter,when it's coming out...
Like you cannot believe,it's so nice.
You know what I feel like now?
Hungry.
Safe.
It's going to end up like the movies,this happily ever after?
By tonight,this is all gonna be a fading memory.
It's gonna be you and me,laughing over chicken Kiev.
Liar.
Mr. Minister,an update,please.
I am ready to sign the contract once I speak to my daughter.
Hello? Hello?
Have that pen ready. I'll call you back.
Yeah.  We are closing the noose,Frank.
Well,when it closes,make sure no one tries to drag me out of the car.
You know what this is about yet?
The girl. Her father.
Large amounts of toxic waste.
It is a trade. His signature for her life.
I have a reputation to uphold here,inspector.
One hundred percent successful delivery rate.
Am I detecting a little attachment?
That is not the Frank I know. With his rules,no names,no attachment.
Why is everyone so concerned about my rules?
Frank,I always suspected you are a romantic at heart.
Anything else?
Where is the rendezvous?
I'll call you back.
Yeah.  We're almost at the end,Frank.
Just give me the coordinates.  No more coordinates.
The road you're on.
Make your first left.
I'd like to know where I'm going.
You'll know when you get there.
Don't worry. We got them right where we want them.
My compliments,Frank.
Our trust in your abilities was well deserved.
Now if you could please send the girl out.
She's coming.
I'm not coming.
They need you. They won't kill you.
But they will kill you.
Do I look like a man who came halfway across Europe to die on a bridge?
Do I?
We don't have all day,Frank.
Look how many of them.
They have all the guns.
How it's gonna be okay?
Tell you over dinner.
Now,go.
Go.
Kiss me.
You're gonna get me killed. Now,go.
Get to her,you bastard.
Better now,darling?
Finish him.
No! Frank!
His beloved car will be his grave.
Leaves it,he blows. Stays,he drowns. Let's get out of here.
Tarconi.  They have the girl.
Frank,we are trying to track him through the phone signal.
Where are you?  In a lake.
A lake?
Can you be more specific?
There's a dam.
A dam?  I know the place,sir.
How far?  Ten minutes at least.
Frank,we'll be there in 10 minutes.
Can you make it any faster?
We'll do our best.  Thank you.
Buy tickets for all of us.
Where to?
Anywhere this train is going. We need to keep moving for half an hour.
Why don't we just keep driving around?
Another day.
Sir! There!
Out. Out!  Everybody out!
Come on.  Move!
Move,quick!
Mr. Minister?  Yes.
Someone wants to talk to you.
Papa.  Are you all right?
Don't sign.
What you have is 15 minutes.
You ever find out what this is about?  Garbage.
How much garbage are we talking?
Enough to pollute half the country for a hundred years.
Try it again.
For a modern woman,you are very uninformed.
This is the new world.
There are no more countries. That's old think.
There are just economic realities. Profit and loss.
Efficiency and waste.
Think global,not local.
Think this.
Yes?  Where are we?
We're almost there.
Where?
Here. He is on a train.
And where are we?  Here.
We can get units there.
That's a good idea. Do that.
Oh,Frank,come on.
Mr. Minister,I assure you,everything is in order.
I'm sure it is.
If there are any problems I know you will solve them.
Now,if you don't mind...
You might not believe this,but I am,at heart,a pacifist.
I hate violence.
It creates more problems than it solves.
You know,I never wanted to do any of this.
A client asked me to obtain a result...
so I went about creating an environment...
with the least amount of bloodshed.
No one wanted to cooperate. Not you,not the first driver...
not your father,not the recently deceased Frank Martin.
Everyone wanted to fight.
What's so funny?
Hearing a dead man talking.
One more step,Frank.
Come on. One more.
Look.
It's over.
Two minutes to 9. He signed.
Oh,my God.
No,Frank. No,no.
It's over,Frank. It's over.
Mission accomplished. You and the girl are free to go.
Matter of fact,I'm so impressed by your talent...
I'd like to offer you a position.
I'd like to offer you one. Permanently disabled.
I hate to waste talent.
But I really don't think we'd make a very good fit.
That's right.
No!
We wouldn't fit,but you and the bracelet were made for each other.
No,no.
No!
You're doing the right thing.
Valentina.
Am I in heaven?
Looks more like we're in hell.
I don't care.
As long as we're there together.
Yes?
Mr. Minister,your daughter is in good hands.
Thank you.
What are you doing?  What you said,the right thing.
And now,gentlemen. if you'll excuse me,I have a conference to address...
on the dangers of doing business with people like you.
Thank you very much.
Is the launch ready?
It's on the water,sir,waiting.  Time to leave.
Grab the log.  Okay.
I just don't understand it.
When I was a boy,my father and I...
used to pull fish out of this very spot all day long.
Times change,inspector.
As do people.
You referring to me?
I don't think that's a very accurate statement.
I drive the same car,live in the same house.
Oh,I was not referring to your car or your house.
The sea is so restful.
Is lunch ready yet?
Mademoiselle,there is a certain progression to things.
In order to eat the lunch,you first have to catch the lunch.
And if we keep talking instead of concentrating...
we're gonna catch nothing.
I have better idea. Why we don't skip catching of lunch...
and go right to eating of lunch?
I know wonderful place just up coast from here...
where they make fish stew. Incredible.
They use tomatoes and onions,and little amount of wild lavender.
What kind of wine?
Pink. From south.
A Chateauneuf,perhaps.
Chilled.  Of course,chilled.
And for dessert?