(FANFARE)
(FLAMES CRACKLING)
JOHN: In the beginning...
was the Word...
and the Word was with God...
and the Word was God.
He was with God...
in the beginning.
He was there, in Paradise...
with Adam and Eve.
He was there with Noah...
in the great flood.
He was there with Abraham
when he was chosen.
GOD: Abraham, I will make you
a father of many nations.
JOHN: He was there when Moses
led our people out of Egypt.
GOD: I will be with you.
Moses! Moses!
(SHOUTS)
Lord!
God is with us!
JOHN: In the struggle for
the Promised Land...
(GRUNTS, ROARS)
He was always by our side.
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS)
(MEN SHOUTING)
(HORSE NEIGHS)
Jerusalem.
Our new home.
JOHN: He was the light
shining in the darkness.
Then He came into the world.
(THUNDER CRASHES)
A star shall come out of Jacob
and a scepter shall
rise out of Israel.
(BABY CRYING)
JOHN: The Word became flesh...
Look. ...And made His
dwelling among us.
(THUNDER CRACKS)
(JESUS CRIES, MARY WHIMPERS)
Our son.
♪ ♪
Lady, I believe your son
is the promised
King of His people.
What is His name?
Jesus.
His name is Jesus.
(KISSES, SNIFFLES)
♪ ♪
I am John...
and I was one of His followers.
After what I saw...
how could I not be?
Jewish land.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(ANIMAL BLEATING)
Jewish people.
Our Jewish nation...
under Roman rule.
MAN: In the name of Rome,
taxes are owed.
So just pay up.
(CLAMORING) Get in line.
That'll do.
Times are tough! Put it there...
all of it.
Get out of the way. Get back.
JOHN: Occupied... and oppressed.
(SHOUTING)
Those who spoke out...
were crushed.
(SHOUTING)
We craved a savior.
A messiah.
(SHOUTING)
(SCREAMING)
But instead we got a
new Roman governor.
(HORSE NEIGHS)
Pontius Pilate.
MAN: Halt!
What's going on?
I can't lift it. It's too heavy.
You're in the way!
Let me help.
You need to be quick. I know.
(SIGHS)
ANTONIUS: Prefect.
What's the delay this time?
It's a broken cart, sir.
Well, what are you waiting for?
Get it off the road.
Let's get it moved.
Will it be much longer?
(HORSE NEIGHS)
Very soon, my love.
(MAN GRUNTS)
Come on, move.
Move!
(SIGHS)
The governor needs to pass.
I'm doing all I can.
SOLDIER: Pilate won't wait.
Wait, I can fix it. Move it!
(SOLDIER GRUNTS, BOY GASPS)
No, my son.
Move! No, my son.
(GASPS)
Father.
(BOY SCREAMS)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
MAN: Son. My son!
(SOLDIER SHOUTS)
(MOTHER SCREAMS)
Come on.
(SCREAMING)
♪ ♪
(BREATHES HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: Nothing here.
Do you need help?
I'm not looking for any
help, and besides,
there's nothing to help with.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Hey, you can't just
climb into my boat.
Yeah, you're right.
Give me a helping hand.
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
What do you think you're doing?
We're going fishing.
There are no fish out
there this time of day.
In fact, there are
no fish out here
any time of day. Peter...
just give me an hour,
and I will give you
a whole new life.
Who says I want one?
I'm telling you...
there's no fish out there.
♪ ♪
(WATER RIPPLING)
(SPLASHING)
(GRUNTING)
There's fish.
(PANTING)
How did this happen?
What did you do?
I'm giving you the chance
to change your life.
Peter...
come with me.
Give up catching fish,
and I will make you
a fisher of men.
What are we going to do?
Change the world.
PETER: When Jesus spoke to me...
I followed.
Others joined us.
Soon our numbers grew.
And all who heard Him
felt His power.
♪ ♪
BOY: No, it's my turn.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
SIMON: Put the Lord
your God to the test.
You shall untiringly
keep the Commandments
of the Lord your God
and His statutes which He
has commanded you.
You shall do what is right
and what is good in
sight of the Law.
BOY: Look, can you see?
Over there.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(GROUP CHANTING)
So the Lord commanded us
to observe all these statutes.
It's Jesus!
(CLAMORING)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
This way, John.
Keep everyone moving.
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
Welcome, Jesus.
(HUSHED CHATTER)
(CHATTER CONTINUES)
(CHATTER SUBSIDES)
How shall we picture
the Kingdom of God?
It is like a mustard seed
which a man took and
sowed in his field.
(CLAMORING)
The smallest seed
in the world...
yet, when planted...
(WOOD CREAKING)
(GRUNTS)
it grows up.
PETER: Rabbi.
BOY: He's paralyzed.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CHATTER SUBSIDES)
(WIND BLOWING)
Your sins are forgiven, my son.
Did you hear that?
He has forgiven his sins.
I thought only God
could do that.
Isn't that blasphemy?
He knows.
It is blasphemy.
Is that your wish, my friend?
Well, answer me.
Tell me which is easier.
To say his sins are forgiven...
or say...
get up and walk.
(CROWD ULULATING)
(CHEERING)
Wait.
JESUS: The Son of Man
has authority to forgive sin.
Friends.
What is this about?
Not even Moses himself
would have thought
he could forgive sin.
You heard what our teacher said.
On what authority
does he think he can do this?
On His authority.
That is blasphemy.
Only God can forgive sin,
and your friend...
could be stoned for a
false claim like this.
This is just the beginning.
Let's go.
♪ ♪
Greetings, Prefect.
Welcome to Judaea.
I hope your time here
will be prosperous
and peaceful.
I intend to make sure it is.
From Caesar.
Disorder will not be tolerated.
Next.
Is that all?
All taxes must be paid in full!
It's all I have. Get out of here.
Take it away.
No.
(SCREAMS)
THOMAS: We're all Jews.
Our own people working for Rome.
Makes me sick.
Collaborators.
Let's move on.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
They're stinking vermin.
You should keep your
distance from them.
Two men...
went to the Temple to pray.
One a Pharisee
and the other one...
a tax collector.
The Pharisee prayed,
"God, I thank you that
I'm not like other men."
"Thieves... adulterers...
or this tax collector."
But the tax collector
didn't even look up to Heaven.
He said,
"God...
"have mercy on me.
Have mercy on me.
"I'm a sinner." I'm a sinner.
(SOBS)
God blessed the tax collector,
not the Pharisee.
Anyone who praises himself
will be humbled...
and anyone who humbles himself
will be praised.
Matthew...
come.
♪ ♪
SIMON: See...
(JOHN CHUCKLES)
now he even calls the
sinners to follow him.
One has to wonder of
the sins committed
by his other followers.
BEGGAR: Alms.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Tax collectors.
There's not a thread of
good in any of them.
JOHN: Thomas, Jesus has
not come for the good
but for the sinners.
MARY MAGDALENE: He gives
people a second chance.
We should, too.
JESUS: Blessed are the poor,
for theirs is the
Kingdom of Heaven.
Blessed are the meek,
for they shall
inherit the earth.
Blessed are the pure in heart,
for they shall see God.
Pray to Him and He will listen.
And how should we pray?
Like this.
Our Father who is in Heaven,
hallowed be Your name...
Your Kingdom come,
Your will be done
on Earth as it is in Heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those who
trespass against us.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
(SCREAMS)
MAN: Stone her!
MAN 2: She's a whore!
GIRL: No! Mother!
GIRL: Mother!
- GIRL: Please!
- MAN: Adulteress!
- SIMON: Here.
- MARY MAGDALENE: Come away.
PETER: Mary, over here.
SIMON: The Law commands us
to stone such a woman.
What do you say?
(HUSHED CHATTER)
♪ ♪
(SOBBING)
I'll give my stone...
to the first man who tells me...
that he has never sinned.
♪ ♪
(SOBBING)
Go...
and sin no more.
Thank you. Thank you.
♪ ♪
SIMON: This cannot continue.
He ridicules our laws...
insults the traditions
of our fathers.
Everything we have
fought so hard for.
Our faith, our communities.
Everything God has given.
You have heard it said,
"Do not commit adultery."
Why don't you join us?
JESUS: But I tell
you that any man
who even looks at a
woman with lust...
You're welcome, brother.
Has already committed adultery.
Why do you follow him?
He is leading us to
something greater.
Open your eyes.
This is a dangerous man.
♪ ♪
GUARD: High Priest, Nicodemus
is here to see you.
(DOOR OPENS)
Caiaphas.
Nicodemus.
NICODEMUS: I've had reports
of a young prophet,
a Jesus of Nazareth.
He has a big following
in Galilee.
It's rumored he'll
come to Jerusalem.
Galilee?
He works miracles.
They all do.
(LAUGHTER)
Nicodemus, don't worry.
Nothing important ever
came from Galilee.
(LAUGHTER)
A miracle worker from Galilee.
♪ ♪
(CHILDREN SHOUTING)
Jesus! Jesus!
Looks like a quiet place.
PETER: Pull. That's it.
THOMAS: Take a rope.
Lock it off.
Rabbi, let me help you.
(LAUGHTER)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Look, it's him.
Look, it's Jesus!
There he is.
(CHEERING)
(GASPS)
MARY MAGDALENE: They've
come a long way.
They're hungry.
Give them food.
But how?
We have nothing.
Just a few fish and some bread.
Bring them to me.
♪ ♪
Thank you, Father,
for what You bring us.
Our Father in Heaven feeds
the birds of the air.
How much more will
He give to you?
(CROWD GASPING)
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Don't worry about daily needs.
God will provide.
Put God first and everything
else will follow.
(CROWD SHOUTS AFFIRMATIONS)
If you hunger for righteousness,
you will be filled through me.
JOHN: He said ask...
(LAUGHS)
and it will be given.
JESUS: John, we can
feed them all.
MARY MAGDALENE: From God.
It's from God.
CHANTING: Messiah! Messiah!
Messiah! Messiah! Messiah!
(SHOUTING)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
PETER: They want you to be
their King.
King of the Jews.
You can lead us like an army.
We're strong enough
to beat the Romans!
No.
No, this is not the way.
Not by force.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Peter!
Where is he going? What's wrong?
5,000 came to see him.
5,000.
Now they shout "Messiah."
♪ ♪
JOHN: The people today,
they called you "King."
They think you are a messiah.
But you seemed to ignore them.
Aren't you going to be our king?
Who do you think I am?
You are the Son of God.
You can't have known this
by what you know of me, Peter.
It has been revealed
to you by God.
You are Peter,
and on this rock...
I will build my church.
Tomorrow...
I will meet you on
the other shore.
♪ ♪
Why did he walk away just
when we're getting strong?
Surely a messiah wouldn't
leave us like this.
A messiah should be a...
a warrior, a conqueror
like David.
PETER: Judas,
force is not the way.
So tell me what the way
of the Messiah is.
He's different.
THOMAS: But, Mary, what
if he's not the one?
We're risking our
lives, for what?
Thomas!
He has shown us his power.
We must have faith in him.
PETER: He said he'd meet
us on the other side.
Let's go!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
PETER: Bring the sail down!
Tie everything down!
(THUNDER CRASHING)
THOMAS: This is too dangerous!
We should turn back
while we still can.
PETER: You heard what he said.
He wants us to cross.
THOMAS: What is that?
What's that?
It's a ghost!
(GASPS)
JOHN: No, Thomas,
it's Jesus!
He is the Messiah.
Peter.
DISCIPLE: Peter,
what are you doing?
Don't be afraid.
Come.
♪ ♪
THOMAS: Peter!
(SCREAMS)
Peter!
JESUS: Peter.
You of little faith.
Why did you doubt?
Who do you think I am?
PETER: The Son of God.
(SIGHS)
(CROWD CHATTERING)
MALCHUS: Make way for
the High Priest.
Make way for the High Priest!
(SCREAMING)
GIRL: Mama, they're coming!
Mommy!
Malchus? Malchus?
Malchus! What's happening?
It's another protest,
High Priest.
We need to get you out of here.
It's turning into a riot.
Get the master back
to his residence
quick as you can!
What is all this about?
The aqueduct.
People are furious
that the Romans
used the Temple
funds to build it.
Hundreds are heading
to complain to Pilate.
What?
He'll have them cut down before
they can get anywhere near him.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Thieves!
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
PILATE: Jerusalem needs water.
You think your God brings it?
No, He does not.
Rome does.
It's time you understood
what your masters do for you!
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING CONTINUES)
♪ ♪
There's nothing Pilate
won't do to keep control.
(WAILING)
♪ ♪
(WOMAN CRYING)
MARY MAGDALENE: Martha,
what's wrong?
My brother is dead.
Show me the tomb.
♪ ♪
MARTHA: He's been
there four days.
♪ ♪
Lazarus.
(CRYING)
I am...
the resurrection...
and the life.
Anyone who believes in me...
even if he dies...
he will still have life.
(GASPS)
(CRYING)
Lazarus!
(CROWD GASPS)
(CROWD MUTTERING)
My brother!
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Whoever believes in me...
shall never die.
Believe in me,
and you will see
the glory of God.
JOHN: I knew that word
of such a miracle
would spread fast.
No one could ignore it.
Least of all, the authorities.
Caiaphas.
They say this Jesus has
raised a man from the dead.
What?
He-he could come here
to Jerusalem for Passover.
No.
But if he comes
with thousands of supporters,
the city will
already be breaking
at the seams with those arriving
for the festival.
Nicodemus, you are right.
The Romans will step in.
We...
must not allow this miracle man,
this fraud,
to disrupt Passover.
Does Pilate know?
Hmm.
(SIGHS)
Where's my wife?
It's late.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
Claudia, what?
I...
I saw a man...
in a dream.
A man being beaten
and killed.
An innocent man.
A holy man.
A good man.
Help your lady back to bed.
No!
It was a warning.
It was you who killed him.
(SOBBING CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(WOMAN HUMMING)
Mary, he's here!
Who?
Jesus! He's back at last!
BALTHAZAR: Lady,
I believe your son
is the promised
King of His people.
What is His name?
MOTHER MARY: His name is Jesus.
♪ ♪
(RABBI CHANTING IN HEBREW)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
RABBI CHANTS: Amen.
CONGREGATION: Amen.
RABBI: Jesus will now
read from Isaiah.
The spirit of the Lord...
is upon me
because He...
has anointed me
to preach good news to the poor.
He has sent me...
to declare freedom
for the captives
and recovery of sight
for the blind.
To set free...
those who are oppressed.
Today...
this Scripture...
is fulfilled.
(CONGREGATION GASPING)
(CONGREGATION MURMURING)
What are you saying?!
What are you saying?
That you have achieved all this?
That you are the Messiah?
The Chosen One sent by God? No!
I'm saying you must
accept God's Word.
How dare you.
That is sacrilege.
He has never studied the Law.
This man knows nothing!
His healing is the
work of demons.
It has begun.
He undermines our faith!
He recruits adulterers!
JESUS: Peter!
Turn the other cheek.
You'll pay the price for this!
Like your friend,
John the Baptist!
You haven't heard, have you?
He was executed! Beheaded!
(CROWD SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
He was a good man.
JESUS: Baptize me.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
John was the greatest
teacher I ever knew.
He was more than a prophet.
Our work goes on.
Soon we go to Jerusalem.
Jerusalem?
It's too soon.
It's too dangerous.
We're not ready.
Judas,
why are we all here?
To take the easy path?
We must take the
message to Jerusalem.
Right to the heart
of power.
JOHN: We set out for Jerusalem.
Thousands were heading there
for the festival of Passover.
(LAUGHTER)
CHILD: The Messiah!
Bring your palm!
Messiah! Messiah!
Bring your palm leaves!
(CROWD CHEERING)
This way! This way!
Look at this!
MAN: Messiah! Messiah!
Messiah.
♪ ♪
Where is he now?
He's just entered the city
on a donkey.
"See, your King comes to you
"righteous and victorious,
"humble
and riding on a donkey."
Where's he headed?
Towards the Temple.
He must not interfere
with Passover.
God...
will bring His wrath
down upon all of us,
and...
who knows what Pilate will do
if the crowds run
out of control?
Nicodemus, go with Malchus.
If he enters the Temple,
watch him.
Do not blink.
Go.
(CLAMORING, LAUGHING)
(WHOOSHING)
(MUTED CLAMORING)
(CLAMORING NO LONGER MUTED)
(WHOOSHING)
(MUTED CLAMORING)
(CLAMORING NO LONGER MUTED)
BARABBAS: The Kingdom is coming!
MAN: Jesus!
The Kingdom is coming!
Messiah!
It's Barabbas.
- Messiah!
- OTHERS: Messiah!
King of Israel!
Why don't you make us free?
Save us from the Romans, Lord!
(WHOOSHING)
(CROWD QUIETS ABRUPTLY)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
We come in peace, Barabbas.
(PEOPLE WHISPERING)
(CLAMORING RESUMES)
Get out of the way! Get back!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
♪ ♪
WOMAN: It's Jesus.
MAN: He's going into the Temple!
♪ ♪
(BIRD CALLING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, GOATS BLEATING)
Do you exchange money here? Yes!
MAN: Change your money here!
Two and a five. I give you one.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
MAN: Very best rates...
- Don't like the look of this.
- MAN: Exchange here!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER, GOATS BLEATING)
♪ ♪
Jesus...
- (ANGRY SHOUTS)
- MAN: What are you doing?
- (WOMAN SCREAMS)
- JUDAS: Jesus,
please...
please.
Is it not written?
Wait.
My house!
My house shall be called
a house of prayer?
But you... you have made it
a den of thieves!
NICODEMUS: Who are
you to tell us this?
♪ ♪
NICODEMUS: We teach the Law,
not you.
You pray lofty prayers...
and love
your shows of piety
in the Temple.
Hypocrites.
♪ ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER RESUMES)
This is outrageous.
And you were little help.
He's clever.
The crowd worship him.
There is something...
unusual about him.
There is nothing
unusual about him
apart from his ability
to 'cause havoc.
If he returns,
challenge him.
Make his supporters
see their "Messiah"
for the simple-minded
peasant that he is.
Sir.
We're eating.
Sir, a Jew has been causing
trouble in the Temple.
So?
He has a large number
of supporters.
What's his name?
They call him Jesus of Nazareth.
My servants talk about him.
He's Caiaphas' business.
But you keep an eye
on the crowds.
If they start to
get out of hand,
I'll shut the Temple... festival
or no festival.
LAZARUS: Thank you very much.
You're very kind.
PETER: Where's Judas?
Have you seen him?
No.
♪ ♪
(PANTING)
(WIND ECHOES)
(WHOOSHING)
(DISTORTED PANTING)
(DISTORTED FOOTSTEPS ECHOING)
JUDAS: I'm worried.
Things are getting
out of control.
Come to me when you need...
assistance.
(EXHALES)
(BIRDS CHIRPING, SCREECHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(LIVELY CHATTER)
Alms for the poor.
God bless you.
♪ ♪
MAN: Be quiet, be quiet.
(CROWD QUIETS)
It is much harder...
for a rich person
to enter the Kingdom of God
than it is...
for a camel to go through
the eye of a needle.
The most important thing
is that you should
love your neighbor
as you love yourself.
NICODEMUS: Teacher!
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
They say you are learned.
So tell us,
should we pay taxes
to the Romans?
CROWD: No! No!
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
Well, teacher...
should we...
pay the Romans taxes?
- Or...
- BARABBAS: Not pay!
Not pay! Not pay!
(CROWD SHOUTING)
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)
Israel! Israel!
(CROWD CHANTING)
Tell him.
Whose face is on the coin?
Caesar's.
(SPITS)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Then give to Caesar...
what is Caesar's.
And give to God...
what is God's.
(CROWD SHOUTING)
♪ ♪
(CROWD CONTINUES SHOUTING)
High Priest...
that man, there,
with Jesus...
he wants to help us.
CAIAPHAS: Really?
That could be useful.
(CROWD CONTINUES SHOUTING)
You let him get the
better of you.
CAIAPHAS: Yet I may have found
a way to deal with him.
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CROWD QUIETS)
Do you see all these...
great buildings?
Not one stone of this place...
(LAUGHS) Not one stone...
(GIGGLES)
will be left standing.
♪ ♪
CAIAPHAS: He said what?
Not one stone will
be left standing.
He threatens to
destroy the Temple.
We must move swiftly but softly.
We cannot arrest him openly,
or his supports will run riot.
No, not at Passover, no!
No.
We must bring him in...
quietly, at night,
before Passover.
Malchus, what was
the name of that...
follower of his that
you pointed out to me?
Judas, High Priest.
Judas. Yes.
Bring him to me.
Here.
(SWORDS CLASH)
(GRUNTING)
(GRUNTING CONTINUES)
(GRUNTS, YELLS)
(LOW PANTING)
(YELLS)
(MAN GROANING)
Prefect,
you're needed.
There's trouble.
Roman scum! Roman thieves!
Let's show them!
CROWD: Roman thieves!
MAN: Scum!
(CROWD CLAMORING)
Roman thieves! Roman scum!
PILATE: Since I've
been prefect...
you Jews
have tested my patience
to breaking point.
Now I'm beyond it.
Yes, but, Prefect...
I'm speaking!
If the disturbances
that took place today
are repeated tomorrow, I will
shut the Temple immediately.
There will be no Passover.
I will put this
city under curfew.
I will crush any rebellion.
Do I make myself
absolutely clear?
♪ ♪
(ANIMALS BLEATING, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MAN: What are you
preparing, Mary?
(LOW, INDISTINCT TALKING)
♪ ♪
Rabbi.
Welcome.
I come here of my own accord.
The High Priest knows
nothing of this.
What's he doing here?
♪ ♪
Judas.
Your friend from Galilee
has caused quite a stir.
One cannot deny
that he has followers,
especially amongst
the less well-educated element.
But you, Judas...
I'm intrigued.
He...
he has a power.
(STAMMERS)
It's hard for me
to put into words.
A power
to 'cause trouble,
to stir things up.
Attacking money changers...
threatening
to destroy the Temple...
the holy of holies.
If he were
the Son of God...
if...
would he abuse the House of God?
The true Messiah
will unite Israel,
not divide it.
What do you want with him?
Just to talk.
If the Romans step in,
can you imagine the slaughter?
It will mean the end
of the Temple...
the end of our faith...
the end of our nation.
Is that what you want, Judas?
Judas...
you are his friend.
Bring him here, discreetly.
Let us try to stop this
while we still can.
And what's in it for me?
(COINS JANGLE SOFTLY)
Good.
We shall expect to hear
from you presently.
They say you can
perform miracles.
That you have seen
the Kingdom of God.
You can see the Kingdom of God.
But you must be born again.
Born again? How can you be...
born again?
You must be reborn...
not in the flesh...
but in a spirit.
♪ ♪
(WIND RUSHING)
The wind blows where it wishes.
You don't know where
it comes from...
or where it goes.
And so it is when the
spirit enters you.
God...
so loved the world...
that He gave His
one and only Son.
Believe in Him...
and you will have eternal life.
♪ ♪
CAIAPHAS: Malchus,
any word from Judas?
MALCHUS: Nothing, High Priest.
I won't wait any longer.
We arrest this false
prophet tonight.
NICODEMUS: How do we know
he is a false prophet?
Has he fulfilled...
any of the signs of a
true messiah as written
in our Scriptures?
He will be tried
according to our Law.
We remove this man,
or the Romans
destroy everything.
Remove?
Yes, Nicodemus.
The life of one peasant
for the future of God's nation.
♪ ♪
What does he want us for?
To take supper.
JUDAS: Just supper?
(LOW, DISTORTED CHATTER)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
Whose is it?
♪ ♪
(SCREAMS)
(WHOOSHING)
(CHATTER STOPS)
We thank You, Lord,
by whose Word
everything comes to be.
ALL: Amen.
♪ ♪
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER, MAN CHUCKLES)
John.
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUES)
This is our last meal together.
Before I die.
What do you mean?
I'm going to be betrayed
to my enemies...
arrested...
and condemned to death.
♪ ♪
Don't be afraid.
Trust in God.
Trust in me, also.
You know the way to
where I'm going.
THOMAS: We don't know
where you're going.
How can we know the way?
I am the way...
the truth...
and the life.
♪ ♪
Take it.
(MUFFLED SOB)
Eat.
(CRYING QUIETLY)
This...
this is my body.
♪ ♪
This is my blood.
JESUS: Remember me...
by doing this.
I'm going to the Father...
but I will always be with you.
Now I must tell you
that one of you here...
will betray me.
Who?
♪ ♪
Whoever eats this.
I will not.
I will not betray you.
♪ ♪
(WHISPERS)
Do it quickly.
(SNIFFLES)
(JUDAS PANTS)
JESUS: Let him go.
♪ ♪
(FLAMES WHOOSHING)
(JUDAS GRUNTS)
(PANTS, GRUNTS)
(COUGHS)
♪ ♪
(FLAMES WHOOSH)
You will all fall away.
♪ ♪
Rabbi.
I will not fall away.
I will lay down my life for you.
Will you?
I will.
♪ ♪
Peter...
I tell you...
before dawn...
you will deny me three times.
♪ ♪
Judas.
Where is he?
I-I... Do you know
where he is now?
I know where he's going.
Lead my servant to him.
♪ ♪
(WIND BLOWING GENTLY)
(PANTING)
JESUS: Wake up, and keep awake.
The time has come.
The spirit is willing,
but the flesh...
is weak.
I must pray.
♪ ♪
JESUS: Father...
I know...
it must be...
as You will it.
Father...
take this from me.
Spare me.
CAIAPHAS: Lord, I know
You are pleased with me,
for You sustain me in sincerity.
We thank you, our ancestors,
for watching over us.
(WHISPERS)
Father...
CAIAPHAS: Praise the Lord...
God of Israel,
everlasting and everlasting.
ALL: Amen and amen.
♪ ♪
If You will it, Father...
if You will it...
Your will...
is mine.
(DISTORTED WHOOSHING OF FLAMES)
♪ ♪
Do what you came for.
PETER: Traitor!
(GRUNTING)
MALCHUS: Take him!
(MEN SHOUTING, GRUNTING)
(BLOWS STRIKING)
PETER: Run, Jesus, run!
(MEN SHOUTING, GRUNTING)
PETER: Run, Jesus!
(YELLS)
PETER: Run, Jesus, run!
- Run, Jesus! Run!
- JESUS: Peter.
Peter.
He who lives by the sword...
dies by the sword.
♪ ♪
(DISTORTED, ECHOING SCRAPE)
(AMPLIFIED THUMP)
♪ ♪
(LOW WHOOSH)
(WIND WHISTLING)
(LOW GASPING)
(WHOOSHING)
(FLAME WHOOSHES)
♪ ♪
THOMAS: Run.
GUARD: Come on, you, move!
Move it!
MALCHUS: Take him back.
GUARD: What about this one?
Get out of here!
(GRUNTS)
(FLAMES WHOOSHING)
♪ ♪
JOHN: Come on.
- I won't leave him. Come on!
- MARY MAGDALENE: Peter!
QUIETLY: Come on, Mary.
♪ ♪
MALCHUS: Quickly!
(JESUS GRUNTING)
Keep him moving.
(INDISTINCT SHOUTS NEARBY)
♪ ♪
MALCHUS: Quickly!
(JESUS GRUNTS)
♪ ♪
Tell Caiaphas we have Jesus.
Yes, sir.
Not you.
(JESUS GRUNTS, PANTS)
(PANTS SOFTLY)
(FLAMES WHOOSHING QUIETLY)
(PANTING QUIETLY)
(CONTINUES PANTING)
(EXHALES)
♪ ♪
(GRUNTS)
(GASPING BREATHS)
♪ ♪
You cannot go through with this.
It is not legal.
Our scholars say it
must be in court,
in daylight, in public.
It is necessary.
Why the rush?
You know why.
Pilate will close the Temple.
We must be rid of this Jesus.
But what if he really
is who they say he is?
We are to decide precisely that,
now, with God's guidance.
God demands we obey the Law!
Let me remind you
what the Law says!
"Anyone... who shows contempt
for the judge or for the priest
shall be put to death."
Anyone.
(LOW, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
CAIAPHAS: Brothers...
thank you for coming
at this hour.
You know I would
not have asked you
if it were not so serious.
(CHAINS CLINKING)
Ah.
(FLAMES WHOOSH)
(PANTING)
♪ ♪
Get him up.
CAIAPHAS: Jesus of Nazareth...
you are charged
with blasphemy.
(PEOPLE SINGING, INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(FLAMES WHOOSHING)
(SINGING, INDISTINCT CHATTER CONTINUE)
Mary?
SIGHS: Mary.
Oh! Oh!
(CRYING)
What has happened?
Where is my son?
Jesus has been arrested.
Arrested?
But we don't know where
they have taken him.
Arrested?
At night?
They want to keep it secret.
They don't want any protests.
CAIAPHAS: He...
has employed
demons to heal.
He...
has threatened
to destroy the Temple
of our Lord!
But, brothers, we must listen
before we judge.
And so I invite...
the prophet
to speak.
Tell us the message
you bring from God.
CAIAPHAS: Nothing?
Nothing to say? Surely...
Tell us this:
Are you
the Chosen One?
Are you the Son of God?
I am.
(MEN GASPING)
♪ ♪
And you will see me coming
with the clouds of Heaven,
sitting at the
right hand of God.
This is repulsive!
With God?!
Imposter!
Fool! Blasphemer!
(CAIAPHAS PANTING)
We have heard enough.
There is only one verdict.
Guilty.
♪ ♪
JOSEPH: This is wrong!
This brings shame
on our council.
Does it not?
♪ ♪
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
MALCHUS: Let it be known,
Jesus of Nazareth has been tried
by the Supreme Court of Elders,
and he has been found guilty
of blasphemy
and of threatening to
destroy the Temple.
MALCHUS: The sentence...
is death!
(GASPS, EXCITED CHATTER)
JUDAS: You!
Take back your money!
♪ ♪
You.
I've seen you before.
You know him.
♪ ♪
No.
I don't know him.
You called him Rabbi.
He has nothing to do with me.
WOMAN: You know him.
I've seen you with him.
I don't know him.
JESUS ECHOING: Peter...
you will deny me three times.
(CRYING)
ECHOING: Don't be afraid.
MALCHUS: Take him to Pilate.
♪ (ROOSTER CROWING) ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Sir, the High Priest Caiaphas
and his elders are
here to see you.
(HEAVY SIGH)
CAIAPHAS: Prefect, good morning.
(EXHALES)
Prefect, we need your help.
We have convicted a
dangerous criminal.
So? Execute him.
We cannot.
This is a tense time,
when my people
celebrate their deliverance
from past oppressors.
He claims to be our king...
and is whipping up the
crowds into a rebellion,
a rebellion that could
tear Jerusalem apart.
Caesar would not be pleased.
♪ ♪
His name?
Jesus of Nazareth.
You better not be
wasting my time.
I'll see the prisoner.
♪ (FLAMES WHOOSH) ♪
PILATE: So...
tell me who you are.
Are you the King of the Jews?
Are you asking...
or is it a question
coming from others?
Are you a king?
That's what your own people
and Chief Priest tell
me you claim to be.
My Kingdom...
is not of this world.
If it were,
my servants would
fight my arrest.
My Kingdom is from
another place.
♪ ♪
(DROPS LADLE INTO BUCKET)
You are a king, then?
You say that I am a king.
I have been born and
come into the world
to testify to the truth.
Everyone on the side of truth...
listens to me.
Truth?
What is truth?
♪ ♪
(FLAME WHOOSHES)
- (DOOR SLAMS SHUT)
- CLAUDIA: That's him.
The man I saw in the
dream, that's him.
(LONG SIGH)
They want him executed.
WHISPERS: You can't.
They say he could
start a revolution.
You mustn't!
If I don't,
Caiaphas will blame
any rebellion on me.
And Caesar will see
it as my failure.
He's warned me once; He's
not going to warn me again.
I'll be finished.
We'll be finished.
♪ ♪
He's guilty of nothing
more than being deluded.
He has... broken the Law.
Your law...
not Caesar's.
Prefect...
we cannot be held responsible
for what the people may do
today, with their eyes on God,
if you release a man
who has broken our sacred laws.
The people?
Caesar decrees...
I can release a
prisoner at Passover.
Let the people decide
which of the prisoners I
hold will be executed.
♪ ♪
(SIGHS)
Get him out
and teach him some respect.
40 lashes.
(SIGHS)
JOHN: Peter! Peter!
What's happened? Where's Jesus?
Peter... Peter, where's my son?
(PANTING)
They've condemned him.
JOHN: Peter, stop.
Where are you going?
(CRYING QUIETLY)
I denied him.
Three times.
(MOTHER MARY SOBS)
(GUARD SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY)
(GRUNTING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
GUARD: Come on!
(GASPING)
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
(GROANING)
What have they done to him?
(PANTING)
They're going to kill him.
♪ ♪
PILATE: It's as if he knows
this must happen.
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(GROANS)
(GASPING)
(GROANING)
♪ ♪
JESUS: One of you here...
(GROANING)
will betray me.
(CRYING)
♪ ♪
(SOBBING)
(GROANING)
(WHIP CRACKING, JESUS GROANING)
Get up!
(GRUNTS)
(SOBBING)
♪ ♪
(METAL DOOR CLANKING)
(MAN CACKLING)
GUARD: So you're a king?
(CHUCKLES)
Every king needs a crown.
(GROANING)
Get up.
(GROANING CONTINUES)
Come on!
(LAUGHTER)
You...
Yes, you, yes. You and you. You.
Go on.
Yes. You.
No followers of Jesus!
Stop. No, not you.
Back, back.
No. Back!
Step back. Not you.
Back!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Let me through!
Back! Oh!
GUARD: Close the gates!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
JOHN: Hey, Mary!
Mary, move.
Move. Let's go.
Today Passover begins,
and your emperor, Tiberius
Caesar, makes you
a gesture of goodwill.
The release of a prisoner...
(GASPS)
chosen by you.
I give you a choice.
Barabbas, a dangerous agitator.
Or this preacher...
who claims to be your king.
(GASPING, CRYING)
He is not our king!
We have no king but Caesar.
You must decide.
- (MUTTERING)
- MAN: Barabbas.
Barabbas.
- Barabbas!
- WOMAN: Free Barabbas!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Give us Barabbas!
Release Barabbas!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Jesus! Jesus!
You choose a murderer?
Do it.
(CROWD CHEERING)
MAN: Free Barabbas!
Do it.
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
And the prophet?
How could this
blasphemer be our king?
MAN: He's a false prophet!
Crucify him! Crucify him!
(CHEERING)
Spare him!
Save him!
Kill him!
MAN: Crucify him.
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
♪ ♪
Crucify him! Crucify him!
Very well.
Crucify him.
(CRYING)
No!
♪ ♪
GUARD: You, go back!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Back!
(GROANS)
(GROANS, PANTING)
♪ ♪
(HORSE WHINNYING)
Move!
(GROANING)
(CRYING)
John, I need to see him.
- I need to see my son.
- GUARD: Get back!
Get back! Get back!
(JESUS GROANING)
(CROWD CHEERING DISTANTLY)
(WHIP CRACKING, JESUS GROANING)
♪ ♪
MAN: Somebody help him!
Show him mercy!
(GRUNTING)
No!
GUARD: Get back!
Stay back!
(PANTING)
My son.
Don't be afraid.
Everything is possible
with God.
GUARD: That's it, pull her back!
(CRYING)
Move forward!
Oh, Jesus.
Jesus.
Please, she's his mother!
♪ ♪
Get back!
Please!
You!
Help him carry the cross.
Move!
My Lord.
(GASPING, GROANING)
♪ ♪
CAIAPHAS: What will the sign
on his cross say, Prefect?
Put in Aramaic, Latin and Greek,
"Jesus of Nazareth,
the King of the Jews."
He was never our king.
It must read,
"This man said,
I'll am the King of the Jews..."
It stays as I've commanded:
"The King of the Jews."
(CROWD SHOUTING)
MAN: This is unjust!
Help him!
♪ ♪
MAN: Release him!
GUARD: Get away!
Get away from him!
(GROANING)
♪ ♪
(BLOWING)
(HORNS CONTINUE)
Bless you.
Thank you.
(LAMBS BLEATING)
(LAUGHTER)
Come on!
Come on, move! Come on.
Move!
Come on, hey!
Come on!
(PANTING)
GUARD: You!
Leave! Leave!
Move!
Come on, King!
Come on!
(LAUGHTER)
(LAUGHTER CONTINUES)
Look at him!
Pin him up on the cross!
(GROANING)
GUARD: Come on!
No further.
(GASPING)
(GROANS)
(SOBBING)
♪ ♪
ANTONIUS: Secure the ropes!
(GASPING)
♪ ♪
(SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
(GUARD GRUNTS)
(JESUS SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING)
(SOBBING)
(SIGHS)
You'll live to regret this.
Hardly the first
Jew we've killed.
He was different.
He was chosen by the gods.
He thought he was.
He'll be forgotten in a week.
ANTONIUS: Lift!
Get him up there!
GUARD: Steady.
(GUARDS SHOUTING)
Steady!
♪ ♪
(SOBBING)
(GASPING)
My son...
PHARISEE: King of the Jews!
Can you see the
Temple from there?
Leave him!
(LAUGHTER)
JESUS: Father...
Father...
forgive them.
For they know not what they do.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(SOBBING LIGHTLY)
(GASPING)
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
Aren't you the Messiah?
Why don't you save
yourself and us?
MAN: Our punishment is just,
but this man
has done nothing wrong.
Remember me when you come
into your Kingdom.
JESUS: Truly, I say to you,
today...
(GASPING)
You will be
with me in Paradise.
♪ ♪
Mother...
this is your son.
John...
this is your mother.
My God.
Why have You forsaken me?
(GASPING)
I thirst.
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(CHANTING IN HEBREW)
(CRYING)
(GASPING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
♪ ♪
It's finished.
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(THUNDER CONTINUES)
♪ ♪
(RUMBLING)
(WIND HOWLING)
Father...
into Your hands...
(GASPING)
I commend my spirit.
♪ ♪
(RUMBLING)
PILATE: Claudia!
This is an omen!
(PEOPLE SHOUTING IN THE DISTANCE)
(RUMBLING)
(SCREAMING)
(RUMBLING CONTINUES)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(GASPS)
(WIND HOWLING)
(BLADE PIERCES FLESH)
♪ ♪
(NICODEMUS CHANTING KADDISH PRAYER)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
(ROCK SCRAPING)
(SCRAPING STOPS)
♪ ♪
(EXHALES)
Where were you?
You were supposed
to be his rock.
I failed him.
Now I can't ask him
to forgive me.
♪ ♪
(GASPS)
(PANTS)
(WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY)
JESUS: Who are you looking for?
(SOFT GASP)
If you've taken him,
tell me where he is.
Mary.
Teacher?
Go and tell our brothers...
I am here.
MARY MAGDALENE: Peter! Peter!
Everyone!
The tomb is open.
He's alive. What?
That's not possible.
I saw him. Mary, maybe
it was someone else.
You think I'm mad.
Peter...
see the tomb for yourself.
(PANTS)
Now do you believe me?
(WIND RUSHING)
(WHOOSHING)
But he's gone.
Gone?
No.
(WIND WHISTLING)
He's back.
♪ ♪
Thank you.
PETER: A cup. I need
a cup and some wine.
What happened?
His body.
His blood.
♪ ♪
"I am the way..."
"...the truth...
and the life."
♪ ♪
No.
No, this isn't real.
♪ ♪
Thomas.
Stop doubting.
♪ ♪
And believe.
It is you.
Because you see me,
you believe.
Blessed are those
who have not seen me...
and yet...
have believed.
♪ ♪
When the Holy Spirit
comes to you,
you'll receive power.
The power of the Holy Spirit
can be with you all
wherever you are.
Go into the world
and preach the Gospel
to all creation.
Peace be with you.
♪ ♪
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
♪ ♪
PETER: My brothers,
my sisters...
we have work to do.
♪ ♪
JOHN: With Peter as our leader,
we spread the Word of Jesus
throughout the world,
shining the light
on all creation.
♪ ♪
But in the light,
there was darkness.
Persecuted for our preaching,
all of the disciples
died for our 'cause...
except one.
I must live out my
days in exile...
alone.
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
One day...
I hope to see my
friends again...
for they are with Our Lord.
The people today...
they called you "King."
They think you are the Messiah.
Who do you think I am?
You are the Son of God.
THOMAS: What if
he's not the one?
We're risking our
lives, for what?
He has shown us his power;
We must have faith in him.
JESUS: Don't be afraid.
Trust in God.
Trust in me, also.
You know the way to
where I'm going.
We don't know where you're going...
how can we know the way?
I am the way...
the truth...
and the life.
I am the Alpha...
and the Omega,
the first...
and the last...
♪ ♪
(TREMBLING BREATHS)
the beginning...
and the end.
(GASPING LAUGH)
I knew it!
I've been expecting
death to come.
There will be no more death...
or mourning...
or crying...
or pain.
I am making everything new.
(LAUGHS)
Yes.
I am coming soon.
(CRYING SIGH)
May the grace of the Lord
be with all God's people.
Amen.
♪ ♪
♪ Mary, did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Would one day ♪ ♪
walk on water? ♪
♪ Mary, did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Would save our sons
♪ ♪ and daughters? ♪
♪ Did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
Baptize me.
♪ Has come to make you new? ♪
Mary!
♪ And this child that you ♪ ♪ Jesus!
He's back at last! ♪
♪ Delivered ♪
♪ Will soon deliver you ♪
- ♪ Mary, did you know CROWD ♪
- ♪ (CHANTING) Messiah! Messiah! ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Would give sight ♪ ♪
to the blind men? ♪
♪ Mary, did you know ♪ ♪
Peter, where is my son? ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Would calm the storm
♪ ♪ with His hand? ♪
♪ Did you know ♪
(INDISTINCT SHOUTS)
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Has walked ♪ ♪
where angels trod? ♪
♪ And when you kiss ♪
♪ your little baby ♪
♪ You kissed the face of God? ♪
♪ O Mary, did you know? ♪
♪ Mm, mm ♪
My son...
♪ Mary, did you know? ♪
♪ Whoo, ooh-ooh, ah-ah ♪
♪ The blind will see ♪
♪ The deaf will hear
♪ ♪ It is you. ♪
♪ And death will live again ♪
Get out of him.
♪ The lame will leap, ♪
♪ the dumb will speak ♪
♪ The praises of the lamb ♪
(NEIGHS)
♪ Mary, did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ (CROWD GASPS) ♪
♪ Is Lord of all creation? ♪
♪ Mary, did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Would one day rule
♪ ♪ the nations? ♪
♪ Did you know ♪
♪ That your baby boy ♪
♪ Is heaven's perfect lamb? ♪
♪ And the sleeping child
♪ ♪ you're holding ♪
♪ Is the great ♪
♪ "I... ♪
♪ Am..." ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh. ♪
(MUSIC FADES)
(SDH-ENGLISH - BY BOZXPHD)
http://subscene.com/u/659433
IMPROVED BY: @Ivandrofly