本片与原诗出入较大
请加以鉴别
片名：《贝奥武甫》
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\N洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
把蜜酒拿来！\NI want mead!
王后，为我倒上蜜酒！\NGive me some mead, my Queen!
丹麦\N公元507年
谢谢，我美貌的王后\NThank you, my beautiful Queen.
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
事情乃是这样，亚瑟\NThis is how it works, Aesher.
你在身后未必会化为尘埃\NAfter you die, you wouldn't really be dead
只要你信他，尊他是唯一的神（指基督）\Nproviding you have accepted him as the one and only God.
好了，大伙回来\NAll right, back! Back!
我的美人，吻我一个\NHere, my beauty, give me a kiss.
我要你吻我一个，吻一个\NI want a kiss! Give me a kiss! I want a kiss!
不要这样！\NPlease, stop it!
再来！\NMore!
诸位王民，我俊骁的王民！\NMy thanes, my beautiful thanes!
一年前，我，洛斯戈，你们的王\NOne year ago, I, Hrothgar, your King
许下诺言，将把我们的功绩庆祝\Nswore that we would celebrate our victories
在一个至高、壮美的宫殿\Nin a new hall, mighty and beautiful!
- 我可曾遵循誓言？\N- 是的！\NHave I not kept my oath? Yeah.
在这大殿，我们把掠获的战利品分发\NIn this hall, we shall divide the spoils of our conquests,
有黄金，有财宝\Nthe gold and the treasure.
让这座大殿充满欢乐，喜悦\N肉体的欢愉！\NAnd this shall be a place of merriment, joy, and fornication!
从此，我命此殿为西奥鹿特\N直至时间尽头！\NFrom now until the end of time, I name this hall Herot!
财宝！我们把财宝分发！\NTreasure! Let's hand out some treasure!
给我！\NGive me some of that!
攻城略地的奖赏！\NFrom my conquests!
安浮斯!\NUnferth!
赏与安浮斯，赏与安浮斯\N最智慧的策士\NFor Unferth, for Unferth, my wisest advisor,
处女的掠夺者\N最好，最勇猛的诡辩家！\Nviolator of virgins and best and bravest of brave brawlers.
安浮斯，你在哪？\N你这眼贼颊长的混账\NUnferth, where the hell are you, you weasel-faced bastard?
我在这，我的王\NI'm here, my King.
安浮斯，过来，你这忘恩负义的小丑\NUnferth, come here, you ungrateful lout!
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\N洛斯戈! 洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar! Hrothgar!
独面魔样巨龙，常人血冷脚痹\NHe faced a demon dragon When other men would freeze
吾王剑拔出鞘，巨龙膝折难立\NAnd then, my lords, he took his sword And brought it to its knees...
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar!
吾王世间无敌\NThe greatest of our kings
力斩妖龙双翼\NHe broke the dragon's wings
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar!
王地阴霾入遁，黑影夜深频来\NThe kingdom fell in darkness And shadows ruled the night
曙光指日无望，吾王力挽狂澜\NWith no sign of dawn, he soldiered on And brought us back to life
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar!
笃信吾王不移\NHe never shook your faith
满斟万杯同举！\NLet every cup be raised
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar!
吾王庇佑众生，哪怕魔怪横行\NHe offered us protection When monsters roamed the land
张牙舞爪而来，接二连三送命\NAnd one by one, he took them on They perished at his hand
蜜酒!\NMead!
你弄洒了蜜酒，蜜酒哪里去了？\N你弄洒了\NYou're spilling it. Where's my mead? You're spilling it.
被你弄洒了！\NYou're spilling it!
该隐，你这拙笨的蠢夫！\NCain, you clumsy idiot!
居然敢浪费吾王的蜜酒？\NHow dare you waste the King's mead?
吾王鼎立救世，即便希望渺茫\NHe rose up like a savior When every hope was gone
斩怪驱魔和平世\NThe beast was gored and peace restored
英名永不忘\NHis memory will live on
洛斯戈! 洛斯戈!\NHrothgar! Hrothgar!
满斟万杯同举！\NLet every cup be raised
功名千秋万世！\NNow and forever
剑！给我一把剑！\NA sword! Give me a sword!
快，拿起武器！\NCome! Arm yourselves!
王后，快蹲下！\NStay down, my Lady!
- 剑！给我一把剑！\N- 殿下！\N- Give me a sword! A sword! - My Lord!
不要！\NNo!
跟我打！\NFight me!
跟我打\NFight me.
你来战我，混账\NYou fight me, damn you.
不\NNay.
那是什么？\NWhat was that?
哥伦德\NGrendel.
哥伦德，你做了什么？\NGrendel, what have you done?
你做了什么，哥伦德？\NWhat hafast flu done, Grendel?
母亲
鱼，狼，熊\NFish and wolf and bear
或几只羊可以\Nand sheep or two,
别碰人类\Nac nan men.
人
人，哥伦德\NMen, Grendel.
猎杀了我众多族类\NThey have slain so many of our kind.
洛斯戈也在吗？\NWas Hrothgar there?
我
没伤他
我没伤他
没，没
好\NGood.
好孩子\NGood boy.
乖\NAnd tender.
来人，再堆起一座柴堆\NMen, build another pyre!
厩后还有枯木\NThere's dry wood behind the stables.
来把死者燃葬\NThen burn the dead.
把大殿封禁！闭上门和窗\NAnd seal the hall! Close the doors and the windows.
王颁下的命令\NAnd by the King's order,
从此不许有歌声与欢畅\Nthere should be no singing or merrymaking of any kind.
这里满是死尸的恶臭\NThis place reeks of death.
诗人正在传唱西奥鹿特的耻辱\NThe scops are singing the shame of Herot
南至中土的王国（今德国）\N北及冰封的土地（今挪威，瑞典）\Nas far south as the middle kingdom and as far north as the ice-lands.
我已承诺，将王国一半的黄金\NI've let it be known that I will give half the gold in my kingdom
赏给为我们杀死哥伦德的人\Nto any man who can rid us of Grendel.
吾王，为求解救\NMy King, for deliverance
族民给奥丁和海姆达尔\N祭上了公山羊，公绵羊（两位北欧神）\Nour people sacrifice goats and sheep to Odin and Heimdall.
您是否允许\NWith your permission,
向罗马的神，耶稣基督祭献？\Nshall we also pray to the new Roman god, Christ Jesus?
也许他，可以将我们的痛苦祛除\NPerhaps he can lift our affliction.
不， 安浮斯， 不要\NNo, Unferth, no.
如果我们自己不想办法\N神明也帮不上我们\NNo, the gods will do nothing for us that we will not do for ourselves.
我们需要，一位英雄\NWhat we need is a hero.
推起船桨！\NHold your oars up!
用力划！\NAnd heave!
能不能望到岸？\N有没有丹麦人引航的篝火？\NCan you see the coast? Can you see the Danes' guide-fire?
我只看到风和雨\NI see nothing but the wind and the rain!
没有火光，没有星斗作导航\NNo fire, no stars by which to navigate.
失去了方向！\N性命交给了大海！\NWe're lost! Given to the sea!
这海是我母亲\NThe sea's my mother!
她不会再将我收回她黑蒙蒙的子宫\NShe'll never take me back to her murky womb.
我母亲是亚兰的渔妇\NMy mother was a fishwife in Uppland.
我宁可战死在沙场上！\NI was rather hoping to die in battle as a warrior should!
划！\NHeave!
大伙担忧\N这永不停息的风暴，贝奥武甫\NThe men are worried the storm has no end, Beowulf.
可以确定，这并非人间的风暴\NIt's no earthly storm, that much is for sure.
但这恶魔卷起的暴风雨\N无法阻挡我们\NBut this demon's tempest will not hold us out
因为我们想要活！\Nif we really want in!
谁想要活？\NWho wants to live?
我们！\NWe do!
那就拉起桨来，给这天看看！\NThen pull your oars! Let's see you do it!
为贝奥武甫！\NFor Beowulf!
为黄金！\NFor gold!
为荣耀！\NFor glory!
划！划！\NHeave! Heave!
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf.
拽住！\NHold fast!
不\NNo.
你是谁？看装束，你是一名战士\NWho are you? From your dress, you are warriors.
说！为何现我现在不该一枪将你刺穿？\NSpeak! Why should I not run you through right now?
我们是基斯人\N（瑞典部族）\NWe are Geats.
我是埃戈西奥之子，贝奥武甫是我的名字\NI am Beowulf, son of Ecgtheow.
我们以朋友的身份来见你们的王洛斯戈\NWe come seeking your Prince Hrothgar in friendship.
有人说你们这里出现怪兽？\NThey say you have a monster here?
有人说你们的土地已经被诅咒\NThey say your lands are cursed.
他们是这样说的？\NIs that what they say?
诗人把洛斯戈的耻辱吟唱\NBards sing of Hrothgar's shame
从冰冻的北方到文兰的海岸（疑指芬兰）\Nfrom the frozen North to the shores of Vinland.
这里从未有被恶魔诅咒的耻辱\NThere's no shame to be accursed by demons!
我是贝奥武甫，我来这里杀死你们的怪兽\NI am Beowulf! And I am here to kill your monster.
我以为不会再有愚蠢的英雄\NI thought there were no more heroes foolish enough
到这里来，为我们的黄金而死\Nto come around here and die for our gold.
如果我们死了，那是为荣耀，而不是黄金\NIf we die, it'll be for glory, not for gold.
吾王？\NMy Lord?
吾王，外面来了许多战士，基斯的战士\NMy Lord? There are warriors outside. Geats.
并非为谋生讨赏\NBut they are no beggars,
其领袖贝奥武甫雄武……\Nand their leader Beowulf is an imposing...
贝奥武甫？埃戈西奥的小娃娃？\NBeowulf? Ecgtheow's little boy?
贝奥武甫？他在哪？哪里？\NBeowulf. Where is he? Where?
你在这，贝奥武甫，欢迎你，孩子\NThere you are. Beowulf, welcome, my boy.
欢迎你，你的父亲如何？\NWelcome. Yes. How's your father?
死了\NDead.
与海上来的袭击者战斗而死\N两个冬季之前\NDied in battle with sea-raiders two winters back.
是的，他勇敢非凡\NWell, he was a brave man.
我想问你，为何渡海而来？\NMay I ask why you have come to us from across the sea?
我来这里把你们的怪兽杀死\NI've come to kill your monster.
将你们美名传扬的蜜酒品尝\NAnd to taste that famous mead of yours.
曾有众多勇猛之士来品尝吾王的蜜酒\NThere have been many brave men who have come to taste my Lord's mead
许多人发誓驱散缠绕大殿梦魇\Nand many who have sworn to rid his hall of our nightmare.
但曙光微露之际，他们已不见踪影\NBut in the morning, there was nothing left of any of them
只有洒满地板的血迹，等待擦干\Nbut blood to be cleaned from the floor
桌椅，墙上的血迹\Nand the benches, and the walls.
我尚未喝到蜜酒\NI have drunk nothing, yet.
但我将杀死你们的怪兽\NBut I will kill your monster.
他将杀死怪兽，听见了吗？\N哥伦德时日不多了\NHe will kill the monster. Did you hear that? Grendel will die.
- 哥伦德？\N- 是的，怪兽叫做哥伦德\N- Grendel? - Yeah, the monster is called Grendel.
那我将杀死你们的哥伦德\NThen I will kill your Grendel.
我，贝奥武甫\N曾在奥克尼杀光一个巨人的部族\NI, Beowulf, killed a tribe of giants on the Orkneys,
曾在海中击碎海怪的脑骨\Ncrushed the skulls of sea-serpents,
这个怪兽将不再使你们困扰\Nand this troll of yours will trouble you no more.
英雄！英雄！\N我知道大海会给我们送来英雄\NA hero! A hero! I knew the sea would bring us a hero!
那么，你是否将深入沼泽\N走入洞穴中黑暗的污池\NSo will you go up to the moors, to the dark pool by the cave
在怪兽的巢穴将它杀死？\Nand kill the monster in its den?
我带来了十四位骁勇的战士\N在海上沉浮已久\NI have 14 brave thanes with me. We have been long at sea.
现在正是时候，强大的洛斯戈\N拿出你黄金般流淌的蜜酒\NIt is high time, mighty Hrothgar, to break open your golden mead
无人不知的佳酿\Nfamed across the world
在你传说中的蜜殿里畅饮\Nand to feast in your legendary mead hall.
蜜殿已经被吾王下令封禁\NThe mead hall has been sealed by his Lord's order.
大殿中的欢乐会带来魔鬼，那哥伦德\NMerrymaking in the hall brings the devil, Grendel.
那就这样\NWell, then.
打开蜜殿！我们喝！\NOpen the mead hall! Let's drink!
我们不要跟这里的人惹上麻烦\NWe don't want any trouble with the locals.
悍朔，我觉得你在假装听我讲话\NHondshew, make me feel you're pretending to listen to me.
你与的妻子挥别，不过仅仅五天\NIt's only been five days since you waved your wife goodbye.
已过了五天？奥丁我神\N难怪我腹下炙热难忍！\NFive days? In the name of Odin, no wonder my loins are burning!
贝奥武甫，你在这\NBeowulf, there you are.
我正想着你的父亲，一位强人\NI was thinking about your father. Great man.
当年他从武甫人那里逃出\NHe was fleeing the Wulfings
空手将他们的一个族人杀死\Nand he'd killed one of them with his bare hands.
- 西索拉夫\N- 就是他，没错\N- Heatholaf. - That's it, yeah. That's right.
我替你父亲偿还了血债（用财产）\N于是他宣誓效忠于我\NI paid the blood debt for your father, and he swore his oath to me.
我救了他一命，所以你把我们拯救\N是这样吧？\NSo I saved his skin, and you're here to save ours, that right?
荣耀属于伟大的贝奥武甫\NAll hail the great Beowulf,
来把我们丹麦人可怜的小命拯救，啊？\Ncome to save our pathetic Danish skins, eh?
我们至死感激不尽，强大的贝奥武甫\NAnd we are so damned grateful, mighty Beowulf.
但有一问题不知该不该问\N秉着对你狂热的仰慕\NBut can I ask a question, as a huge admirer of yours?
我听说有另一位贝奥武甫\NThere was another Beowulf I heard tell of
挑战无敌的布勒卡，在深海里赛泳\Nwho challenged Brecca the Mighty to a swimming race out on the open sea.
那人可是你？\NWas that you?
我是和布勒卡赛泳\NI swam against Brecca.
我以为那定是另一位贝奥武甫\NBecause I thought it had to be a different Beowulf,
另外一人，却有相同的名字\Nsomeone else of the same name.
因为，我听说的这位贝奥武甫\NBecause, you see, the Beowulf I heard of
与布勒卡赛泳，输了\Nswam against Brecca and lost.
此人用自己和布勒卡的生命做筹码\NHe risked his life and Brecca's
来满足自己的虚荣和傲慢\Nto serve his own vanity and pride.
一位自负的愚人\NA boastful fool.
最后却输了\NAnd he lost!
所以，我想那定是他人\NSo I thought it had to be someone else.
我是和布勒卡赛泳\NI swam against Brecca.
但胜利属于他，不属于你\NBut victory was his, not yours.
一位无敌的战士，却无法赢得赛泳\NA mighty warrior who cannot even win a swimming match!
且说我自己的想法\NSpeaking only for myself here,
我不仅质疑你能否有一个片刻\Nnot only do I doubt that you will be able to stand for a moment
抵挡住哥伦德\Nagainst Grendel,
我质疑你是否有勇气在这大殿度过一夜\NI doubt that you will even have the belly to stay in the hall all night.
与醉人争辩是最难不过\NI find it difficult to argue with a drunk.
但你说的乃是事实，我没有赢得比赛\NBut it's true, I did not win the race.
我们游过了五个昼夜，颈并着颈\NWe swam for five days, neck and neck.
我保藏着力量，为最后的冲刺\NI was conserving my strength for the final stretch
风暴突然地吹起\Nwhen this storm blew up
带来了海中的怪兽\Nand with it came sea monsters.
一次又一次，海怪接连袭来\NAgain and again, the monsters attacked!
黑暗的事物，来自大海的深处\NDark things from the sea's depths.
我拿起宝剑\N砍向这些污秽的怪兽，刺进他们的身体\NI hacked and I lashed at these foul beasts with my sword,
它们剖开的肚肠，洒进大海\Nspilling their guts into the sea.
贝奥武甫!\NBeowulf!
然后，其中一只把我咬住\NThen one of them seized me by its jaws
拖我到了海底\Nand dragged me to the bottom.
被我用我的剑杀死\NI killed the monster with my own blade
直插进心脏\Nand I plunged it into its heart.
是的，海上的怪兽\NYes, of course. The sea monsters.
那么你杀了，有多少只？\N二十只？\NAnd you killed, what was it? 20?
九只\NNine.
上次说的是三只\NLast time it were three.
那么，你能告知，你的姓名\NBut would you do me the honor of telling me your name?
我是俄戈拉夫之子，安浮斯\NI am Unferth, son of Ecglaf.
俄戈拉夫之子，安浮斯\NUnferth, son of Ecglaf.
我知道你\NI know who you are.
他们说你把你的两个兄弟杀死\NThey say you killed both your brothers
因为你撞见他们与你母亲私通\Nwhen you witnessed them having knowledge of your mother.
我还要告诉你另一个事实，弑亲的安浮斯\NI have another true thing to tell you, Unferth Kinslayer.
假如你的勇气和你的心\N如你的话语般强劲和锐利\NIf your strength and heart was as strong and fierce as your words,
哥伦德便不能肆无忌惮地杀死你的族民\N把他们吞食\NGrendel would not feel free to murder and gorge on your people
绝不担心报复的索求\Nwithout fear of retaliation.
这个夜晚将不一样\NTonight will be different!
这个夜晚，他将发现等待他的基斯人\N并非畏缩的羔羊\NTonight, he will find Geats waiting for him, not frightened sheep
如你一样\Nlike you.
很好！\NWell done!
正是这种精神，贝奥武甫\N我们正需要\NThat's the spirit, Beowulf. That's the spirit we need.
那么，你将为我把哥伦德杀死，是吗？\NSo you will kill my Grendel for me, will you?
好的，我们来畅饮，把将要来的击杀庆祝\NWell, let's all drink in celebration of the kill that is to come.
唇瓣，六月梅熟\NLips ripe as the berries in June
玫瑰，红，玫瑰，红\NRed the rose, red the rose
肤淡，云清月素\NSkin pale as the light of the moon
轻轻，她的脚步\NGently as she goes
蓝眸，海天之合\NEyes blue as the sea and the sky
贝奥武甫，来！\NBeowulf. Come.
溪水，流，溪水，流\NWater flows, water flows
过来，我要给你看一样东西\NCome with me. I want to show you something.
心儿，静静夜火\NHeart burning like fire in the night
轻轻，她的脚步\NGently as she goes
来\NCome.
看\NThere.
王者的龙角\NThe Royal Dragon Horn.
很美\NIt is beautiful.
美极了吧？\NIsn't it magnificent?
她是我瑰宝中的珍宝\NShe's the prize of my treasure.
在战胜了盘踞在北方沼泽的龙，法夫那之后\N我把她得到\NI claimed her after my battle with Fafnir, the dragon of the Northern moors.
几乎把性命赔上\NNearly cost me my life.
在颈下有一处弱点，这里\NAnd there's a soft spot under the throat, there.
看到吗？要用刀或匕首直插进去\NSee? You have to go in with a knife or a dagger.
龙只有这样才能被杀死\NIt's the only way you can kill a dragon.
不知道曾有多少勇士\N为获得这美人的心而逝去\NI wonder how many men have died for love of her beauty.
也怪不得他们\NCan you blame them?
如果你为我把哥伦德杀死\NIf you destroy my Grendel for me,
她将属于你，永远，永远\Nshe'll be yours forever and ever and ever.
您赐予了我极大的荣耀\NYou do me great honor.
是我们的荣耀\NIt is we who are honored.
这可是你们的恶魔？\NIs that your demon?
那不过是狼\N没有任何声音预示哥伦德的到来\NThat was a wolf. You don't hear Grendel when he comes.
没有？那可好，我“到”时会让你听到\NNo? Well, you'll hear me, I promise.
来吧，我强大的爱的枝干\N会将你送向天国\NCome on, my mighty lust limb can transport you to paradise,
到狂醉而止\Nto ecstasy and back.
再不会有人让你如此满足\NNo other man will ever be able to satisfy you again.
- 抱歉\N- 来嘛\N- Sorry. - Come on!
- 我说不，是认真的\N- 为什么？\N- I said no and I meant no. - Why not?
因为天色已晚，黑夜降临\N怪兽随时可能出现\NBecause it's late and it's dark and the monster could arrive at any moment!
好吧，那么快快来个鸡啄米如何？\NWell, then, how about a quick gobble?
时刻到了\NThe hour is upon us.
老人需要他的睡眠\NThis old man needs his sleep.
我美貌的寝伴在哪？\N来，我的爱\NWhere's my beautiful bedmate? Come, my love.
一会儿\NIn a moment.
我们来拿枕头戏耍\NCome, Wealthow, let us pound the pillows.
别碰我！\NDon't touch me!
要的正是这种精神，我的女孩\NThat's the spirit, my girl.
吾王！\NMy Lord!
王后可以为我们的耳朵赐福\NPerhaps Her Majesty could grace our ears
在我们就寝之前，用一段美妙的乐曲\Nwith one more melody before we all retire?
这便是我可以做的\NIt's the least I can do.
贝奥武甫，希望在曙光微露时见你\N从奥丁的愿\NBeowulf, I'll hope to see you in the morning, Odin willing.
记得让你的战士把屋门关紧\NAnd make sure your thanes secure the doors.
晚安，晚安\NGood night. Good night.
晚安，贝奥武甫，留神海中的怪兽\NGood night, Beowulf. Watch out for sea monsters.
它们定将在你的想像中聚集\NI'm sure your imagination must be teeming with them.
耐心等待\NJust wait
虽然天涯徜徉\NThough wide he may roam
英雄，终会还乡\NAlways a hero comes home
走遍无人之境\NHe goes where no one has gone
英雄，终会还乡\NBut always a hero comes home
真美\NThat was beautiful.
您该走了，王后殿下\NYou need to go now, Your Majesty.
是的，哥伦德\NOf course. Grendel.
那恶魔是我丈夫的耻辱\NThe demon is my husband's shame.
不是耻辱，乃是诅咒\NIt's not a shame, it's a curse.
不，耻辱\NNo, shame.
我的丈夫无人可以依靠\N没有子嗣\NMy husband has no other. No sons.
他也不愿有，依他所说\NAnd he will have no more, for all his talk.
噢，悍朔，她怎么样？\NOy, Hondshew. How was she?
不，不是我喜欢的\NNah. Not my type.
我知道你喜欢什么\NI know your type.
贝奥武甫大人，你要做什么？\NLord Beowulf, what are you doing?
这怪物没有剑持，没有盔甲护体\NThe creature has no sword, no armor.
我也没有可伤它的兵器\NAnd I have no weapon capable of slaying a monster.
我们将公平地斗\NWe shall fight as equals.
命运\NAnd fate
将做出裁决\Nshall decide.
好，多用些铁链捆锁\NGood. Tie it off with more chain.
不要再打闹！\NEnough frican' about!
你太疯狂了，知道吗？\NYou're mad, you know that?
知道\NYes.
什么事困扰着你，维格拉夫\NSomething vexes you, my Wiglaf?
我有不好的预感，大人\NI don't like the smell of this one, my Lord.
战士们毫无防备\NThe men are unprepared.
心思涣散\NThey're distracted.
这里渴望爱的女人太多！\NToo many untended women here!
战前必须节欲！\NAbstinence prior to battle is essential!
战士必须心无旁骛，大人\NA warrior's mind must be unblurred, my Lord.
晚安，维格拉夫\NGood night, Wiglaf.
你睡时我们要做什么？\NAnd while you're sleeping, what're we meant to do?
唱！放声唱！\NSing! Loudly!
好，都听见了，要我们唱歌\N唱！\NWell, you heard him. He wants us to sing. So sing!
奥拉夫，唱！\NOlaf, sing!
处女一十二个\NThere was a dozen virgins
弗里西，丹麦，法朗人\NFriesians, Danes and Franks
本想快乐成双，结果渎自身伤\NWe took them for some swifan And all we got were wanks
噢！贝奥武甫军壮\N个个万夫难当\NOh, we are Beowulf's army Each a mighty thane
踢你屁股，玩你婆娘\NWe'll pummel your asses And ravage your lasses
一遍又一遍\NThen do it all over again
处女中她最圆，婆娘数她最贱\NThe fattest of the virgins I knew her for a whore
用尽浑身解数，还要重来一遍\NI gave her all my codpiece And still she wanted more
妹妹来自挪威，换我二十银币\NHer sister was from Norway She cost me 20 groats
花样技巧百出，飘然上天入地\NShe showed me there was more ways Than one to sow my oats
妈妈来自冰岛，熊熊烈火燃烧\NHer mother was from Iceland And she was mighty hot
非得冰山出马，冷却……\NShe'd need a whole damn iceberg To cool her burning...
哥伦德，敲门\NGrendel. He knocks.
定是我的甜李子，厄萨\NThat must be my sweet plum, Yrsa.
要把她的汁果与我品尝\NShe's ready for me to taste her juicy fruit.
- 大人\N- 要把她的汁果与我品尝\NMy Lord.
莫急，莫急，我的爱\NPatience, patience, my love.
不！悍朔！别动\NNo! Hondshew! No!
天啊，就是这鬼怪兽\NSwife me! It's the frican' monster!
我证明，这浑货没有阴茎！\NI swear, the bastard has no pintel!
- 没阴茎\N- 是\N- No pintel. - Aye.
- 恶魔缩小了！\N- 它缩小了！\N- The demon shrinks! - It shrinks! It shrinks!
恶魔！\NDemon!
你杀戮的日子结束了，恶魔！\NYour bloodletting days are finished, demon!
你…是…地狱的…魔？
它说话了！说话了！\NIt speaks. It speaks!
你…是…谁？
我是，撕肝的钩，扯肺的镰\N断肠的刃，剜心的尖\NI am ripper, tearer, slasher, gouger.
黑暗的尖齿，深夜的魔爪\NI am the teeth in the darkness, the talons in the night.
我的名字是力量，欲火，和强权！\NMine is strength and lust and power!
我是，贝奥武甫!\NI am Beowulf!
哥伦德的手臂！\NGrendel's arm!
你成功了！\NYou've done it!
他成功了！\NHe's done it!
他扯下了恶魔的手臂！\N贝奥武甫打死了恶魔！\NHe's torn the limbs from the beast! Beowulf has killed him!
- 万岁，贝奥武甫!\N- 万岁，贝奥武甫!\N- Hail, Beowulf! - Hail, Beowulf!
陛下，贝奥武甫杀死了恶魔\NMy Lord, Beowulf has killed the demon!
赞美奥丁\NOdin be praised.
- 下命让诗人将此事传颂！\N- 是，陛下\N- Go tell the scops. Spread the word! - Yes, my Lord.
明天是欢欣荣耀的日子\NTomorrow will be a glorious day of rejoicing.
梦魇已经散去\NOur nightmare is over.
上床来吧，我的爱\NCome to bed, my sweet.
王国需要未来的国王！\N我要子嗣！此时你该把义务行使！\NMy kingdom needs an heir! I need a son! It's time you did your duty.
我已知你和她睡躺，如何再与你共床？\NHow can I ever lay with you, knowing you laid with her?
我不该告诉你\NI should never have told you.
不该告诉你\NI should never have told you.
哥伦德，吾子
我可怜的孩子\NMy poor son.
母亲
我受伤了，母亲
睡吧，我的孩子\NSleep now, my son.
他伤我，母亲
是谁伤你，我的孩子？\NWho murdered you, my son?
他把我的手臂撕下
他会补偿的，我的心肝\NHe will pay, meen darling.
这人是谁？
他是最强壮的
最强壮的
他是人？
是
那人是
贝奥武甫
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf.
他们曾是强大的战士\NThey were great warriors.
但死于邪恶\NThey died a foul death.
被生于地狱深处的秽物杀害\NThey were murdered by a foul creature from the depths of hell.
他们的光荣将被一代代诗人传颂\NThe bards will sing of their glory forever.
来，我们来饮酒，将他们纪念\NCome, let us drink to their memory.
我希望你第一个举起酒杯\NI want you to raise the first cup.
我没有心思寻乐\NI am not in the mood for merrymaking.
我要去停泊之地，把船备好\NI'll ride down to the mooring, prepare the boat.
明天潮起时，我们便离开，是不是这样？\NWe still leave tomorrow, on the tide, do we not?
是的\NAye.
我的王民，我的朋友，我的亲人\NMy thanes, my friends, brothers,
这个大殿曾是我伤心的地方\Nthis place for me has been a hall of sadness.
是你们\NAnd for all of us,
感受痛苦，流血，死亡的地方\Nit has been a place of misery, bloodshed, and death.
今天，怪兽的统治结束了\NBut today, the monster's reign has ended.
听说他撕下了那怪兽的胳膊，仅凭一双手\NThey say he ripped the monster's limb off with his bare hands.
不知贝奥武甫的力量是只在双臂\N还是同样充满了下肢\NI wonder if Beowulf's strength is only in his arms, or in his legs as well,
那三条腿\Nall three of them?
今天晚宴结束以后，你便可知道，吉塔\NWell, after the feast tonight, I'm sure you can find out, Gitte.
我吗？他想的可不是我，王后\NMe? It's not me he wants, my Queen.
拿上来！\NBring it here!
薇娥修，我的爱\NWealthow, my love,
不如你来把这荣耀传递\Nwhy don't you do the honors?
属于你，大人\NFor you, my Lord.
感谢，英明的王\NThank you, great King.
谢谢大家\NAnd all of you,
希望你们曾亲眼看到昨夜我把怪物杀死\NI wish you'd have been there last night to see me kill the monster.
他来时，我正在睡梦中\NI was asleep when he arrived.
大门被他的双手砸破\NHe ripped open the doors with his bare hands.
他立起二十余尺，力量足抵十人\N（原诗中贝奥武甫单手抵三十人）\NHe stood 20 feet tall, possessing the strength of 10 men.
我盯着他，说，我是贝奥武甫\NI looked at him and said, "I am Beowulf!"
勇猛的战士\NBrave thane.
王后\NMy Queen.
我爱你\NI love you.
我想属于你，我的王\NI want you, my King.
只想属于你\NOnly you.
我的英雄，我的爱\NMy hero, meen looviyend.
我不懂\NI don't understand.
你的丈夫呢？\NWhere's your husband?
死了\NDead.
死了？\NDead?
这一定是梦\NThis is a dream.
这不可能，你只是梦\NThis is not happening. You're just a dream.
我，亲爱的，是梦？\NMe, darling? A dream?
给我孩子，进入我，给我一个儿子！\NGive me a child. Enter me and give me a son!
奥丁神啊！\NIn the name of Odin!
难道哥伦德复活？\NIs Grendel not dead?
断臂重新长出？\NHas he grown his arm anew?
不是哥伦德\NIt's not Grendel.
不是哥伦德？那是谁？\NNot Grendel? Then who?
他的母亲\NHis mother.
因为你杀了哥伦德\NIt's Grendel you killed.
我本希望他的母亲早已离开这片土地\NI had hoped his mother had left the land long, long ago.
我到底要杀几只怪兽？\NHow many monsters must I slay?
哥伦德的母亲？父亲？叔叔？\NGrendel's mother? Father? Grendel's uncle?
要我把恶魔一家子连根拔起？\NMust I hack down a whole family tree of demons?
她是最后一个\NShe is the last of them.
她去了以后\NWith her gone,
恶魔一族将退回到他们出生的黑暗中去\Ndemonkind will slip back into the darkness from whence it came.
命定的地方\N（参见最后注释）\NWhere it belongs.
他妈妈的伴侣在哪？他的父亲\NAnd the mother's mate? Where is Grendel's father?
哥伦德的父亲不会害人\N（见最后注释）\NGrendel's father can do no harm to man.
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf,
之前对你质疑，是我的错，不会再犯\NI was wrong to doubt you before, and I shall not again.
你的鲜血中流淌着勇气\N我请求你的原谅\NYours is the blood of courage. I beg your forgiveness.
我原谅\NGranted.
该隐！该隐！\NCain! Cain!
带上我的宝剑，他曾属于我父亲的父亲\NTake my sword. It belonged to my father's father.
赫伦汀是它的名字\NIt's called "Hrunting."
这把剑无法与恶魔的魔法抗衡\NThat sword is no match for demon magic.
我抱歉曾经质疑你\NI'm sorry I ever doubted you.
不，我抱歉提起你弑兄的往事\NNo, I'm sorry I mentioned you murdered your brothers.
那是一时冲动的言辞\NThey were hasty words.
安浮斯，我可能无法回返\NUnferth, I may not return.
你祖先留下的宝剑也会随我而去\NYour ancestral sword might be lost with me.
只要他随着你，便永远不会逝去\NAs long as it is with you, it will never be lost.
强大的维格拉夫，你呢\NAnd you, mighty Wiglaf,
是否还与我一起\Nare you still with me?
至死为止\NTo the end.
看\NLook.
她可能是水中的魔怪\NShe's probably a water demon.
你不要与她在水中对抗\NYou don't want to meet her in her element.
我知道\NI know.
要我跟你一起吗？\NDo you want me to go in with you?
好\NGood.
我等在这\NI'll be here.
你好像为我带来了宝物\NI see you've brought me treasure.
现出身来！\NShow yourself!
你是什么东西？\NWhat are you?
你是所说的贝奥武甫吗？\NAre you the one they call Beowulf?
吃蜜蜂的狼（见注释）\NThe Bee-Wolf.
那熊\NThe bear.
你真的十分强壮\NSuch a strong man you are.
拥有着王者的力量\NWith the strength of a king.
有一天，你会成王\NThe king you will one day become.
你了解我什么，恶魔？\NWhat do you know of me, demon?
我知道你的魅惑力下隐藏着\NI know that underneath your glamour
邪恶，与我的儿子哥伦德一样\Nyou're as much a monster as my son, Grendel.
我的魅惑力？\NMy glamour?
人若要成王需要魅惑力\NOne needs glamour to become a king.
人如你这样可以成为最伟大的史诗的主角\NA man like you could own the greatest tale ever sung.
你的故事将流传下去\NYour story would live on
即便今日生的已落为尘埃\Nwhen everything now alive is dust.
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf.
已经过了很久\NIt has been a long time
自从有人来到这里，与我相会\Nsince a man has come to visit me.
我无需用剑便可杀你\NI need no sword to kill you.
你当然不需用，我的爱\NOf course you don't, my love.
你带走了我的儿子\NYou took a son from me.
给我一个儿子，勇猛的战士\NGive me a son, brave thane.
留下来\NStay with me.
爱我\NLove me.
爱我\NLove me
我会让你富有世人难以想象的资财\Nand I shall weave you riches beyond imagination.
我会让你成为\NI shall make you
永世间最伟大的王\Nthe greatest king that ever lived.
只要你在你的心里把我保存\NAs long as you hold me in your heart
并这把黄金角留给我\Nand this golden horn remains in my keeping,
你便会永生为王\Nyou will forever be king.
永远雄健\NForever strong,
强大\Nmighty
无所不能\Nand all powerful.
我向你许诺\NThis I promise.
对你发誓\NThis I swear.
陛下\NMy Lord.
已经死的，王后陛下\NIt's dead, my Lady.
我杀死了哥伦德母亲之后\NWhen I finished off Grendel's monstrous mother,
砍下了这畜生的头\NI severed the brute's head.
我们的诅咒解除了\NOur curse is lifted.
我们的诅咒解除了，赞美奥丁\NOur curse is lifted. Odin be praised!
赞美贝奥武甫！\NBeowulf be praised!
我们的诅咒解除了\NOur curse is lifted.
把这个从我面前拿开，安浮斯\NTake this out of my sight. Unferth!
扔进大海，快\NInto the sea, quickly.
我把赫伦汀刺进了哥伦德母亲的胸膛\NI plunged Hrunting into Grendel's mother's chest
待我把剑从尸体中拔出\Nand when I pulled the sword free from her corpse,
这怪物便又活过来\Nthe creature sprang back to life,
于是我再次把剑插入这女妖的胸膛\N剑留在了那里\Nso I plunged the sword back into the hag's chest and there it will stay.
直到世界末日\NTill Ragnarok, huh?
我们的族民也会永远感激你\N直到世界末日\NAnd our people shall be grateful till the Ragnarok.
是否还要蜜酒，大人\NMore mead, my Lord?
是\NAye.
那饮酒的黄金角，可在身边？\NAnd the drinking horn, do you have it?
不\NNo.
我料想那女妖贪婪，便把黄金角扔进沼泽\NI knew the greedy witch desired it, so I threw it into the swamp.
她追随而去，才被我趁机刺中\NAnd when she followed, that's where I struck,
用那把强大的赫伦汀剑\Nwith the mighty sword Hrunting.
杀死她后，我曾找寻过\N但那黄金角已消失不见\NWhen she was dead, I looked for it, but it was gone forever.
那么为我们的英雄另取一个杯，我的爱\NThen find our hero another cup, my love.
首先，英雄和我要有一番会谈\NFirst, the hero and I must talk.
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf.
你带回了哥伦德的头\NSo you brought back the head of Grendel.
他母亲的头在哪里？\NWhat about the head of the mother?
她已冰冷无生气地躺在池沼中\NWith her dead and cold in the bog,
难道一个怪物的头还不够？\Nis it not enough to return one monster's head?
你是否杀死了她\NDid you kill her?
你想听我再次讲述与那凶暴妖女的搏斗？\NWould you like to hear the story of my struggle against this monstrous hag?
她不是妖女，贝奥武甫\N你我二人心里明白\NShe's no hag, Beowulf. We both know that.
不过你要回答，你是否杀死了她\NBut answer me, did you kill her?
我如何能够逃脱，如果我没有杀死她\NWould I have been able to escape her, had I not?
哥伦德死了，我只关心这\NGrendel is dead. That's all that matters to me.
他不会再把我骚扰\NHe can bother me no more.
那母亲，“妖女”，并不是我的诅咒\NThe mother, "the hag," she's not my curse.
不再是了\NNot anymore.
听我说！\NListen to me!
因为贝奥武甫大人是无比的英雄\NBecause my Lord Beowulf is a mighty hero
杀死了哥伦德恶魔\Nand because he killed the demon Grendel
并将它的母亲放躺在坟墓之中……\N（放躺有性事之意）\Nand laid its mother in her grave...
- 敬贝奥武甫！\N- 贝奥武甫永生！\N- To Beowulf! - Long live Beowulf!
……而且，我没有后代\N...and because I have no heir,
没有子嗣\NI have no sons,
所以，我宣明，在我死后\NI declare that on my death,
我的一切，我的王国\Nall that I possess, my kingdom,
我的哀伤和耻辱的大殿\Nmy hall of sadness and shame,
甚至我年轻貌美的王后\Nand even my lovely young Queen,
我的薇娥修\Nmy Wealthow,
所有，所有\Neverything, everything
都将留给，我们的英雄\NI leave to this, our hero.
- 但是，吾王……\N- 我已说明！\N- But, my Lord... - I have spoken!
我已说明！\NI have spoken!
我故去之后\NWhen I am gone,
埃戈西奥之子贝奥武甫将为王\NBeowulf, son of Ecgtheow, shall be king!
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf!
吾王\NMy Lord.
时候还未到，贝奥武甫\NEverything in its time, Beowulf.
洛斯戈\NHrothgar!
他一定是跌下去了\NHe must have fallen.
- 贝奥武甫王万岁！\N- 贝奥武甫王万岁！\N- All hail King Beowulf. - All hail King Beowulf.
贝奥武甫王万岁！\NAll hail King Beowulf.
贝奥武甫王\NKing Beowulf.
弓箭手\NArchers.
弓箭手！\NArchers!
这不是战争，维格拉夫\NThis is not battle, Wiglaf.
这是屠杀\NThis is slaughter.
弗里兰人想当英雄，吾王\N（日耳曼部族）\NThe Frisians want to make themselves heroes, my Lord.
想被诗人传唱\NThey want the bards to sing of their deeds.
如果会也是很短的一段\NIt's going to be a short song.
怎么能怪他们呢\NNow, can you blame them?
你的传说遍扬，从大陆之间的海面\NYour legend is known from the high seas
冰雪的屏障，到强大的岛国（英国）\Nand the snow barriers to the great island kingdom.
你是怪物的杀戮者\NYou are the monster slayer.
我们已经成了怪兽\NWe men are the monsters now.
英雄的时代消亡了，维格拉夫\NThe time of heroes is dead, Wiglaf.
基督神已将她杀死\NThe Christ God has killed it,
给人类留下了一片虚无\N只剩下哭泣的殉道士\Nleaving humankind with nothing but weeping martyrs,
恐惧，和耻辱\Nfear and shame.
带我去见贝奥武甫，让我见贝奥武甫王！\NShow me to Beowulf! Show me to King Beowulf!
快，弗里兰人，说出来\NCome on, Frisian. Speak up!
放开他！\NLeave him!
你们这样侮辱对手难道有趣？\NYou think it sport to mock your opponents in this fashion?
让他痛快地死，趁他仍有荣誉留存\NLet him die quickly, with some honor still intact.
懦夫！\NCoward!
你来亲手杀我！\NKill me yourself!
一派胡言，王不可亲自战斗\NBalls! The king must never engage in direct battle.
杀死这入侵者，立刻！\N把他的头用枪挑起\NKill the invader now! Do it quickly! Put his head on a spear.
住手！\NStop!
吾王，王不可亲自战斗\NMy Lord, the king must not engage in direct battle.
让他起来\NLet him up.
你想在贝奥武甫之歌中刻上你的名字？\NYou want your name in the Song of Beowulf?
你以为我的性命会在一个没有名字的\N弗里兰入侵者手中葬送？\NYou think it should end with me killed by some Frisian raider with no name?
我是弗里西亚的斐恩\NI'm Finn of Frisia
我的名字将被永远铭记\Nand my name shall be remembered forever.
除非你杀死我！\NOnly if you kill me!
否则，你还是无名之辈\NOtherwise, you're nothing.
你以为你是第一个，或是第一百个\N想把我杀死的人吗？\NYou think you're the first to try to kill me, or the hundredth?
我来告诉你一件事，弗里兰人\NWell, let me tell you something, Frisian.
诸神不会让我的死亡，造于你无力的刀刃\NThe gods will not allow my death by your feeble blade.
诸神不会让我死于剑下，或沉于深海\NThe gods will not allow me to die by a sword, or be taken by the sea.
诸神不会让我在安眠中睡去\N或岁月中熟落\NThe gods will not let me pass in my sleep, ripe with age!
你的斧子向这里砍，弗里西亚的斐恩\N取走我的性命\NPlant your ax here, Finn of Frisia. Take my life.
谁给他一把剑，否则我……\NSomeone give him a sword, or I'II...
你要如何？杀死我？\NYou'll what? Kill me?
杀死我！动手！杀死我！杀死我！\NWell, kill me! Do it! Kill me! Kill me!
知道为什么你不能杀死我，朋友？\NYou know why you can't kill me, my friend?
因为，在很多年以前，我还年轻时\N我已经死了\N'Cause I died many, many years ago when I was young.
给他一块金币，送他回去\NGive him a gold piece and send him home.
他有故事可以讲述\NHe has a story to tell.
陛下？\NYour Majesty?
您伤到没有？\NAre you hurt?
一丝也没有\NNot a scratch.
多么美丽\NSo beautiful.
年青\NAnd so young.
知道吗，俄苏拉，在我年青时\NYou know, Ursula, when I was young,
我曾以为当王便是每个日出作战\NI used to think being a king was about battling every morning
每个日落清点黄金和战利品\Nand counting the gold and loot in the afternoon
每个深夜与美丽的女人缠绵\Nand swiving beautiful women every evening.
但是现在，一切都未如所想的那样美好\NBut now, well, nothing is as good as it should have been.
包括“每夜与美丽的女人缠绵”，陛下？\NNot even the "swiving a beautiful woman every night" part, Your Majesty?
有些晚上，俄苏拉，有些晚上\NWell, some nights, Ursula, some nights.
也许今晚？\NPerhaps tonight?
不，今晚，我感到年纪使我不便\NNo, tonight, I feel my age upon me.
明日，在庆典之后\NTomorrow, after the celebrations.
我们不会忘记明天是什么日子，是吧\NWe can't forget what tomorrow is, can we now?
属于你的，吟唱贝奥武甫之歌的日子\NYour day. When the Song of Beowulf is told
讲述你如何将这片土地的黑暗驱散\Nof how you lifted the darkness from the land.
明日之后\N还要庆祝终结宫殿的救世主的降生\N（指基督教终结了英雄和众神崇拜的时代）\NAnd the day after, we celebrate the birth of Hallend Christ.
我看见你活着回来了\NI see you've survived.
啊，王后\NAlas, my Queen,
弗里兰的入侵者已被赶回到海上\Nthe Frisian invaders have been pushed into the sea.
你还不是遗孀\NYou are not a widow,
目前\Nyet.
多么让我欣慰，丈夫\NHow comforting, my husband.
万岁，贝奥武甫！万岁，贝奥武甫！\NHail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
安浮斯\NUnferth.
今晚你来庆祝吾王的荣耀？\NYou're not celebrating your King's glory tonight?
我有东西呈献吾王\NI have something for the King.
什么东西？\NWhat is it?
我说我有东西呈献吾王\NI said I have something for the King.
- 让我看看\N- 我不让\N- Show it to me. - I will not.
你要先给我过目\NYou will show it to me first.
放屁，维格拉夫\NBollocks, Wiglaf.
我要先让贝奥武甫过目\N王想要看到它\NI'll show it first to Beowulf. The King needs to see it.
王\NThe King
想要看什么？\Nneeds to see what?
失去的，被找到了\NLost and now found.
与王相称的礼物\NA gift fit for a king.
你是否还记得？\NDo you recognize it?
你在哪里找到的？\NWhere did you find this?
我的奴隶该隐在沼泽里发现它\N那寸草不生、瘠薄的山上\NOn the moors. My slave Cain found it on the barren hill where nothing grows.
我打他，怪他踏进不洁的地界\NI beat him for treading near such an unholy place.
吾王\NMy Lord,
这难道不……\Nisn't this...
贝奥武甫王\NSo, Lord Beowulf,
它回到了你的身边，经过这么多年以后\Nit's come back to you, after all these years.
吾王，便是这奴隶寻到它\NMy Lord, this is the slave who found it.
不，不要杀我！\NPlease, please don't kill me!
你在哪里找到这珍宝？\NWhere did you find this treasure?
逃走是我的错，主人\N请不要再也伤害我\NI'm sorry I ran away, Master. But please don't hurt me no more.
- 回答你的王！\N- 住手！\N- Answer your King! - Stop!
住手\NStop.
哪里？\NWhere?
在沼泽之上\NUp, up on the moors.
但我正要把它送回，主人\N我发誓\NBut I was gonna bring it back, Master. I swear.
这样而已？\NIs that all?
没有恶魔？女巫？\NNo demon? No witch?
没有女人？\NNo woman?
万岁，贝奥武甫! 万岁，贝奥武甫!\NHail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
万岁，贝奥武甫! 万岁，贝奥武甫!\NHail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf! Hail, Beowulf!
看看你，什么都不是\NLook at you. You're nothing,
空空的，什么都不是\Nan empty nothing.
出来！\NCome forth!
现身！\NShow yourself!
即便你拥有无数财宝\NEven with all your riches,
王国，权利，荣誉\Nyour kingdom, your power, your glory
和女人\Nand your women.
我应该，先杀死哪一个？\NWhich one do you think I should kill first,
你那年轻漂亮的捂床睡伴\Nyour pretty little bedwarmer,
还是你富有智慧的王后？\Nor your wise Queen?
你是什么？\NWhat are you?
我是你留下的东西\NI'm something you left behind,
父亲！\NFather!
又一个不眠之夜？\NAnother restless night?
没关系，孩子\NIt's all right, girl.
我不会吃了你\NI'm not going to eat you.
他做噩梦了\NHe has bad dreams.
近来噩梦越来越频繁\NThey've been coming more often.
他是王，王的心里总存有很多事\NHe's a king, and kings have a lot on their conscience.
他在梦中喊起你的名字\NHe calls your name in his sleep.
是吗？\NDoes he?
我相信，他依然在心中把你保存\NI believe he still holds you in his heart.
真的吗？\NDo you?
我经常在想\NI often wonder
为什么？\Nwhat happened.
我们？\NTo us?
说不尽的秘密\NToo many secrets.
神啊，救我们\NGod, help us.
什么……你想要我做什么？\NWhat? What do you want of me?
我要你把消息带给我的父亲\NI have a message for my father.
说！是什么东西？\NTell me! What did this?
我看见整个村庄在燃烧\N听到孩童死亡时的尖叫\NI saw our whole village burn. Children screaming as they died!
我看见它，陛下，吞吐着火与烟\NI saw it, Your Majesty, vomiting fire and smoke!
可憎的！那到底是什么？\NDamn you! What was it?
龙！\NA dragon!
- 是安浮斯，陛下\N- 安浮斯\N- It's Unferth, my Lord! - Unferth.
你说这是龙的作为？停下！\NYou say a dragon did this? Stop!
你曾定下协议\NYou had an agreement.
保证你，不受到伤害\NYou would not be harmed.
但现在黄金角已经归还于你\NBut now the golden horn has returned to you.
那协议便已失效\NThe agreement is ended.
谁？谁说的！\NWho? Who said that?
“父辈的罪孽”\N"The sins of the fathers!"
这是我听见的最后的话语\NThat's the last thing I heard.
在我的全家被活活焚烧之前！\NThe last thing before my family was burned alive!
“父辈的罪孽”\N（见最后注释）\NThe sins of the fathers!
“父辈的罪孽”\NSins of the fathers!
“父辈的罪孽”\NThe sins of the fathers!
在险峻的峡谷，北面的山崖上列队\NTake up your positions along the northern edge of the great gorge.
那是我们仅存的希望，如果我失败\NIt is our only hope if I fail.
遵命，陛下\NMy Lord.
不要去，我求你！\NDon't go, I beg you!
你自由了，我将你释放\NYou are free. I release you.
找一个出色的男人，怀上他的子嗣\N带给他一个男孩\NFind a good man and bear him children. But bear him a son.
我不想要别人，我想要你\NI don't want anyone else. I want you.
我不是你想像中的那样\NI am not the man you think me to be!
你是伟大的人，英雄！\N我对这确信无疑\NYou're a great man! And a hero! This I know to be true.
那么你便和他们一样蒙昧无知\NThen you are as foolish as the rest of them!
很漂亮，亲爱的人\NVery impressive, dear.
但这盔甲更合你的身，当你年轻的时候\NBut the armor suited you better when you were younger.
当然如此\NI'm sure it did.
你为什么不收那可怜的姑娘\NWhy don't you take that poor girl
在安详中把余年度完\Nand live out your remaining years in peace?
让某位年青的英雄，拯救我们\NLet some young hero save us.
什么？\NWhat?
让那梦魇再次浮现？\NAnd let the nightmare start all over again?
不，是我将这恐怖带到国土之上\NNo. I visited this horror upon my kingdom.
- 必须由我，来把她了结\N- 她\N- I must be the one to finish her. - Her.
她真的有那么美？贝奥武甫\NWas she so beautiful, Beowulf?
值得如此的代价？\NA beauty so costly?
美丽，和无数美妙的誓言\NBeautiful, and full of fine promises.
我那时不坚定\NI was weak.
抱歉\NI am sorry.
十分的抱歉\NSo, so sorry.
我一直爱你，我的王后\NI have always loved you, my Queen.
我同你一样\NAnd I you.
在心中把我记住\NKeep a memory of me,
不要记那王，或那英雄\Nnot as a king or a hero,
记住我这个男人\Nbut as a man,
会犯错，不完美的\Nfallible and flawed.
就是这个地方\NThis is the place.
在这里，你曾将哥伦德的母亲斩杀\NWhere you slayed Grendel's mother.
维格拉夫，我没有子嗣\NWiglaf, I have no sons,
如果这恶魔将我杀死\N我已传命于使者\Nand if this demon kills me, I have arranged with the heralds
你将为王\Nthat you shall be king.
不要说这样的话，陛下\NDon't speak of such things, my Lord.
最好的朋友，有些事应让你知道\NGreat friend, there is something you should know.
不！我什么都不应知道\NNay! There is nothing I should know.
你是贝奥武甫，强大的贝奥武甫，英雄！\NYou are Beowulf. Beowulf the mighty, the hero!
魔族的杀戮者，毁灭者\NThe slayer and destroyer of demons!
我们现在去那飞翔的恶魔的睡房\N将他杀死\NNow, let us kill this flying devil where it sleeps
回来继续我们的生活！\Nand get on with our bloody lives!
- 要我跟你进去吗？\N- 不\N- Do you want me to go in with you? - No.
好\NGood.
贝奥武甫\NBeowulf.
已经过了很久\NIt has been a long time.
把这可咒的黄金角拿去，给我的土地和平\NTake your damned horn and leave my land in peace.
太迟了，我的爱\NToo late, my love.
奥丁的命根啊！\NOdin's swifan balls!
它向西奥鹿特去了！\NIt's heading for Herot!
放！\NNow!
洛斯戈\NHrothgar.
快，快！\N快！快！\NCome on, come on! Come on! Come on!
可咒的！\NDamn you!
我定要将你这蜥蜴脑袋钉上挂起！\NI'll have your lizard head on a spike!
不！\NNo!
陛下！\NMy Lord!
这儿！保护王后\NOver here! Attend the Queen.
- 保护王后\N- 保护王后\N- Attend the Queen. - Attend the Queen.
我告诉过你，我们太老，已做不成英雄\NI told you we were too old to be heroes.
该你为找位医士\NLet's get you to a healer.
这次不要，老朋友\NNot this time, old friend.
你是贝奥武甫\NYou are Beowulf.
这一点点小事不会让你死亡\NA little thing like this isn't going to finish you off.
你可曾听说过她？\NDo you hear her?
我从未听说\NI hear nothing.
哥伦德之母，我儿子的母亲\N我的……\NGrendel's mother, my son's mother, my...
- 不，陛下\N- 我的……\N- No, my Lord. - My...
你杀死了哥伦德的母亲\N当我们年轻的时候\NYou killed Grendel's mother when we were young.
人们将此事传唱\NThey sing of it.
欺骗已经太迟了，维格拉夫\NToo late for lies, Wiglaf.
太迟了\NToo late.
他曾是\NHe was
在我们当中最勇敢的\Nthe bravest of us.
他是领袖\NHe was the prince
胜过所有的战士\Nof all warriors.
他的名字，将永远流传\NHis name will live forever.
他的传说，将永远传颂下去\NHis song shall be sung forever.
注释
原诗写成于公元八世纪左右\N作者和后来的抄写修订者是基督信徒\N而所记叙的北欧世界则信仰英雄崇拜\N和北欧众神（如片中的奥丁神）
所以片中出现了两种信仰的交叉对立\N贝奥武甫等代表英雄，众神信仰\N安浮斯和晚年的王后等代表基督教信仰
原诗中，哥伦德一族是该隐的后代\N该隐是圣经中亚当夏娃之子\N因弑兄（原罪）被上帝驱逐\N受罚永生游荡（即“命定的地方”）\N众多罪恶均从该隐而起\N（片中安浮斯曾弑兄，他的奴隶叫该隐）
片中，歌伦德之母是龙或蛇一族\N原诗中龙贪婪护财，终生守护财宝\N只因财宝被盗，便残杀人类报复
而片中哥伦德之母为得到金龙角\N引诱王者洛斯戈和贝奥武甫（维格拉夫）\N生下了哥伦德和火龙
所以洛斯戈说哥伦德是他的诅咒\N而安浮斯说的“父辈的罪孽”即指\N作为父亲的该隐，洛斯戈，贝奥武夫的罪孽
原诗中哥伦德袭击人类是因为\N他忍受不了人类的欢乐\N未听懂的哥伦德话大意也应是如此
贝奥武甫的名字的含义有多种推测\N片中用的是《指环王》作者托尔金的解释
Beowulf=Bee（蜜蜂）+Wolf（狼，猎手）\N吃蜜蜂的狼，即指熊\N形容贝奥武夫的勇猛强壮
谢谢欣赏