m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
Previously on The Big Bang Theory
Sheldon, did you just figure out a method
for synthesizing a new stable super-heavy element?
Did I?
Well, that can't be right.
No one's ever done that before.
Except me, because I just did it!
Sheldon and his brain-- yeah!
I've made a horrible mistake.
What are you talking about?
This table-- it's in square centimeters.
I read it as square meters.
You know what that means?
That Americans can't handle the metric system?
Amy, I was off by a factor of 10,000.
But the Chinese team found the element.
Yeah, well, they shouldn't have.
My calculations were wrong.
the greatest scientific achievement of my life
is based on a blunder.
I'm not a genius,
I'm a fraud.
You know, Sheldon, in neuroscience,
we're forever finding something in one part of the brain
that we thought was someplace else.
Oh, great, now I'm worse than a fraud.
I'm practically a biologist.
This is Science Friday. I'm Ira Flatow.
My guest today is responsible for the discovery
of the first stable super-heavy element.
Welcome, Dr. Sheldon Cooper.
Thank you.
Uh, the university made me come here.
I didn't want to.
Uh, big fan of the show.
So, I understand that you actually discovered
this element by mistake.
Yes.
And some people in the science community are calling it
- "The Wonder Blunder." - Who?
Give me their names.
I bet it's Wolowitz.
It's just such a fascinating story.
Your calculations are way off,
but they find the element anyway.
It's like misreading a treasure map
and still finding the treasure.
Can we talk about something else?
Do you know that I yodel?
That's interesting, but this could be taking you
down the path toward a Nobel Prize.
And in chemistry, no less.
And wouldn't that be unusual?
Because you're a physicist.
Yes, yes, I'd be a physicist with a Nobel in chemistry.
Everyone laugh at the circus freak.
You know, I don't need to sit here and take this, Flatow.
It is because of bullies like you,
every day more and more Americans
are making the switch to television.
President Seibert, I don't know why you're yelling.
You're the one who made me go on the radio.
I was expecting a professional science interview,
not an attack by some morning zoo shock jock.
Well, if the university needs money so badly,
perhaps you should start a swear jar.
That one's worth a dollar.
I know you don't like it,
but every time you do an interview,
it raises the profile of the university.
That translates to funding.
Yeah, well, I'm not just some trained monkey
dancing for coins.
Of course you're not.
People love trained monkeys.
How can you not be happy?
You're tall, thin and famous.
Oh, my God, I'm jealous of Sheldon.
Look, you're gonna be doing this stuff for a while.
You're just gonna have to find a way to get used to it.
But none of you know what this is like.
Being celebrated for something you wish you never did.
Mmm... you clearly haven't been with me at Mardi Gras.
Want to pause the video game and help me clean up?
I am cleaning up.
Look at the mess the Joker made of Gotham City.
Come on, it's your friend who's coming to stay here.
Raj grew up in India.
Trust me, he's seen worse.
Howie.
I promise I'll help out the rest of the week.
The rest of the week?
You said it was just gonna be a night or two.
Yeah, but if I told you a week,
- would you have said yes? - No!
Then you left me no choice.
I love Raj, but that's a long time for a house guest.
I know, but they're tenting his building.
He can't find a hotel he likes that allows dogs.
He's bringing Cinnamon?
For a whole week!
The nerve of some people.
Here comes the Embarrassment Express.
With stops at Fraudville...
WonderBlunderberg...
and Kansas City.
Because it's a hub.
Sheldon, can I come in?
- Do you have cookies? - No.
Good. I don't deserve cookies. Come in.
- Wil...? - Hey, Sheldon.
It's been a while.
Why are you here?
Amy said you were having a rough time,
and I thought maybe we could talk.
Is that okay?
Certainly.
Although...
right now, I'm having a rough time
because there's three people in my room,
and it's starting to feel like a discotheque.
Sheldon, you said you were unhappy getting attention
for something you wished you never did.
Yeah, I know a little something about that.
Oh, nonsense, Wil.
Your endless tweets are not that bad.
I remember why it's been a while.
Sheldon, I was actually talking
about when I was a kid on Star Trek.
How could you not like getting attention
for playing Wesley Crusher?
You were wonderful.
A know-it-all boy genius with an eidetic memory.
Who couldn't relate to that?
Well, not everybody felt that way.
A lot of people really hated the character,
and some of them hated me because of it.
I would do interviews,
and people would be mean to me.
That just happened to me.
Next time you're stuck for a tweet,
feel free to say what a jerk Ira Flatow is.
Sheldon, the point is Wil learned to embrace that part of his life
and moved on to bigger and better things.
Yeah, I'm an author now,
I do public speaking,
and I have my own web series about board games.
We're trying to cheer him up, so...
I'm just saying that there was a time when I thought
I would never get out of Wesley Crusher's shadow.
But now,
it's just one small part of a pretty great life,
and it's a part that I'm happy is there.
I do see what you're saying.
That helps.
Good.
Would you two like to stay and play trains with me?
- Sure. - Okay.
Oh, great!
Now...
I work the controls.
I say "All aboard",
you sit quietly and watch.
Can I blow the whistle?
You should probably go.
You're gonna brush your teeth on my couch?
No, I'm gonna brush Cinnamon's teeth.
Why bother?
She spends half the time licking her butt.
And the other half licking my face.
That's why I'm brushing her teeth.
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm so late.
Did you already have dinner?
No, we were waiting for you.
Aw, that's so sweet.
Yeah. So what do you feel like making?
Howard, the poor thing just got home from work.
Let me get you a glass of wine.
I'll cook dinner.
- Oh, Raj, you're our guest. - Don't be silly.
Sit. You look like you've had a long day.
No, she always looks like that.
Because she married an idiot.
Thank you, Raj.
Please, this is my way of thanking you
for letting me stay here.
Now, tell us all about your day.
Okay, um, well, first, I was late to a meeting
'cause I was stuck in traffic.
Well, I keep telling you to put that traffic app on your phone.
Hey, when you got home today complaining that you felt sick
from eating too many jelly beans,
did I tell you how to fix it?
No.
I said, "Aw, that must hurt,"
and I rubbed your belly.
I thought of you the whole time.
All I'm saying is there's a time to just listen.
Thank you.
There's also a time to stop eating too many jelly beans.
And it's when you're ten.
Hello, President Siebert.
Thank you for taking my call.
I just wanted you to know that you can now expect
enthusiastic participation from me regarding my discovery.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
No need to thank me.
Thank my friend, Wil Wheaton.
For your information, I have nine friends, hmm?
Ten if we include you.
Nine it is.
Ah, it's ten. I'll count Wolowitz.
Hello, friend Leonard.
Hey, you're in a good mood.
I'm in a great mood.
Well, you're about to be in an even better one.
I didn't want to say anything until I knew for sure,
but...
I've been re-running the tests on your element in my lab
and I disproved it.
Your element does not exist!
Yeah, but what about the Chinese research team?
They found it.
Yeah, it turns out someone added
simulated signals to the data files.
They faked the results.
- Really? - Yes!
Do you know what that means?
That means all of this attention that you hate goes away.
So no more interviews?
No, it's all over.
I can't believe it.
Well, you're welcome.
You robbed me of my greatest achievement!
What?!
I'm back down to nine friends!
Make it eight-- I'm sick of Wolowitz, too!
I-I don't understand.
All you've done since you discovered
this stupid element was complain.
I was trying to make you happy!
By taking away my only claim to fame?
Well, if you wanted to make me happy,
you could have told me a joke.
Or shown me a cute video
of a koala and an otter
becoming unlikely friends.
Oh, there is no winning with you.
And koalas and otters don't even live near each other!
That's what makes their friendship unlikely!
What's with all the yelling?
Leonard disproved my element.
Now all the attention is going to go away.
Oh, that's great. You must be thrilled!
That's it! I'm down to seven friends.
He's counting hobbits and superheroes, right?
When I thought the element was real, I didn't want it.
But now that Leonard made it not exist,
I want it more than anything in the world.
The-the element never existed.
I didn't take it away, science took it away.
Be mad at science.
Don't you dare use science against me.
Science is my best friend!
Oh, good, I'm back up to eight.
Will you tell him he's out of his mind.
Actually, I get what he's saying.
Oh, yes! Nine!
Welcome back, buddy.
It's like if you're dating someone you're not that into,
and then they break up with you
and then you want them more than ever.
I have no idea what she's talking about.
but we're ganged up on you so I agree.
Okay, Sheldon, what do you want me to do,
hide the information?
If I don't publish it,
it's just a matter of time before someone else does.
No, no, of course you have to publish.
That's your responsibility as a scientist.
Doing otherwise would be unethical.
You have no choice.
Fine, I'll publish.
Can you believe this guy?
Aw! Raj did the dishes.
How do you know I didn't do them?
Because once, when all the knives were dirty,
you cut a bagel with your keys.
Good morning, everybody.
I picked up coffee while I was out.
Bernadette, here's your soy peppermint mocha.
Aw, you didn't have to do that.
Oh, my pleasure,
and don't worry about your presentation today.
You're gonna be great.
Yeah, you're gonna knock it out of the park.
What presentation do I have today?
Just go.
He loves you.
What are you doing?
Are you trying to make me look bad?
I'm just being a good house guest.
No, you're being a better husband than I am.
Doing the dishes, getting coffee,
knowing about her life--
who does that?
Oh, come on, I brought you one, too.
I don't want coffee.
That's why I got you hot chocolate.
Give me that.
Just stop showing me up.
Howard, listen to me.
You're a great husband.
Yes, your listening skills could use some work.
But it's amazing how far you've come
given that you're an only child
raised by an over-protective mom.
Um, is this getting weird?
Hang on.
So, yes.
I just wanted to let you know that I-I posted my findings.
I saw.
And I just posted a retraction of my paper.
Now the whole scientific community knows I was wrong.
These things happen all the time, Sheldon.
Not to me.
The only other retraction I ever had to issue
was when I was seven and I conceded that my brother
was the greatest ninja in East Texas.
But that was just a ploy
to get my face out of his armpit.
There he is!
It's my favorite superhero--
the Retractor!
Come on, don't give him a hard time.
I'm sorry, Cooper.
I retract it.
By the way, Hofstadter,
nice job disproving the Chinese team.
It's not a big deal.
It's a huge deal.
Cooper, maybe physics just isn't your thing.
Have you ever considered a career in retail?
That way you could take things back for a living.
Okay, Barry, that's enough.
Oh, no, that's okay.
I can fight my own battles.
Isn't that right, "Bawwy."
Is...?
Is that a reference to my speech impediment?
That's pretty hurtful.
I...
I can't control it.
You're right,
That was uncalled for.
I take it back.
Of course you do.
Because you're the Retractor!
Raj, this dinner was amazing.
If you're here much longer,
I'm gonna have to buy bigger clothes.
Nonsense.
You need a little fattening up.
You've been looking too skinny lately.
Howie, how come you never say anything sweet like that?
What are you talking about?
Remember last week, when I asked you
if you were wearing Spanx and you weren't?
How's that different?
Maybe you could try being more thoughtful,
like your friend Raj.
Yeah, well, maybe you could try being more like Raj.
- Oh, really? - Yeah, yeah.
He packed me a lunch this morning.
And there was a note inside that said, "Go get 'em"
Like I don't do enough around here.
Now I need to pack your lunch?
And by the way, why do you need a note telling you
to "Go get 'em"? You're a grown man!
You should know to "Go get 'em"!
I do know to "Go get 'em"
but sometimes it's nice to have emotional support
when I'm going and getting them!
Hey, hey, do you hear yourselves?
Let's just, you know, all calm down and take a step back.
This is stupid. Why are we fighting?
I don't know.
I guess I was just feeling like I'm a lousy husband.
You're not a lousy husband.
You're a great husband.
I was the one feeling like a lousy wife.
Are you kidding? You're the best.
I know what the problem is.
It's him!
Oh, what did I do?
You made us feel like we're not trying hard enough.
Yeah, we were totally fine half-assing our marriage
till you showed up.
Look, I'm sorry you're upset with me,
but I just have to say it's nice to see
the two of you on the same page.
Oh, it does feel good to have you
backing me up for once.
гн I back you up all the time! - That is not...
- He's doing it again! - What is wrong with you?!
I can't believe they kicked you out.
I can't believe they're still married.
Oh, no, I forgot Cinnamon's toothbrush at Howard's.
I guess you're sharing with Daddy again.
Bark once if you need me to call PETA.
What's that animal doing in our apartment?
Oh, relax, she's in her crate. She can't get out.
I have two words for you:
Jurassic Park.
This day just keeps getting worse and worse.
You know, if it makes you feel any better...
It probably won't.
You're probably right.
Sheldon, it's a beautiful night.
Why don't you and I go for a nice walk together?
Oh, everything is just sex with you isn't it?
Sheldon, I think you might find the support
you're looking for, if you realize that
relationships are a give and take.
She can only be there for you
as much as you are for her.
Thank you, Rajesh.
And, Amy, you need to be patient with Sheldon,
instead of pressuring him
to accept intimacy on your terms.
You should probably go.
I'm Ira Flatow, and this is Science Friday.
I'd like to welcome back Dr. Sheldon Cooper,
who thought he had discovered a new super-heavy element
only to have it disproved by my next guest,
Dr. Leonard Hofstadter.
Welcome to Science Friday, gentlemen.
- Thanks. - Thank you.
Ira, if I may, I'd like to apologize
for my behavior last week.
It's all right.
Now, isn't there something you'd like to say to me?
No.
Now, Dr. Hofstadter.
Can you walk us through the process
you used to disprove his theory?
- Well... - I believe I can answer that.
He asked me.
Fine.
As I was saying...
You're telling it wrong. Ira...
to really understand the story here,
you have to start at the very beginning:
A small town in East Texas, where a young genius named...
- Sheldon... - That's right, Sheldon Cooper.
He was bitten by his neighbor's dog,
leading to his first scientific breakthrough--
the doggie death-ray.
Which, sadly, he couldn't build
because Santa wouldn't bring him enriched uranium.
I mean, I'd really like to hear it from Dr. Hofstadter,
if it's okay with you.
What a surprise.
Did-did you invite me back just so you could ignore me?
Actually, I didn't invite you.
You came in, you took a seat,
and I'm not comfortable with confrontation.
Sheldon, this interview is supposed to be about me.
Well, that seems like a snooze.
Even for public radio.
You know, if we did a shot every time
they said something embarrassing,
this would be one hell of a drinking game.
A little early for alcohol, isn't it?
You know, I don't just say smart things about science.
I also yodel.
I'll get the vodka.