Are you alright?
l'm fine
What's wrong?
Nothing
He almost ran into me with the cart
Looks like he's sick
Pull him over!
You have stepped onto our side
l didn't mean to
l'm too sick and weak to handle the cart
Please let me go
Let him go...
Let me go...
How about it?
l'll let you go
Thanks
Not so fast...
Chop it off!
Fight!
Don't fight!
Meng Feng, that's too much
No one should be killed merely for crossing the border
How cocky you are!
What do you want?
Quiet, please!
Perhaps we have over reacted
But according to custom
Not only do we confiscate the offender's belongings
he has to go kowtow at our ancestral shrine
before we hack off his limbs
Cutting his leg off on the street
is indeed too much
but that's his rotten luck
This is outrageous!
Go!
Master!
Uncle!
Don't fight, stop!
Stop!
Meng Er Da, over the past decades
you refused to take down the boundary marker
and instigated mutual hatred and gang fights
l know exactly what you want!
No, you don't! You're an old fool!
Zhou Zhen Xian
Don't judge me with your narrow mindedness
Tell me...
The rules passed down from our ancestors
Should l change them?
lf you agree, l'll destroy our marker
Then we'll never have to fight over them!
What do you say?
We have yet to settle the matter at hand
let alone predict the future!
Meng Er Da, l urge you to
bury the hatchet and make peace
Unless the Mengs take over this town
Chief, let's set a fire
to all the Zhous' properties
lf you do that
they'll burn yours too!
He who strikes first will get the upper hand
that's what you said, father!
We can't just let this pass!
That's right!
l can promise you this...
This town...
will be ours in no time!
Yes!
Remember
don't do anything without my permission
Meng Fa, follow me!
Don't you feel bad that l'm hurt?
Don't do this!
What's the situation?
Will he come?
No, he is too arrogant!
He won't listen to my pleading
and he doesn't buy flattery!
None of the kung fu schools in Dama Bay
gets along with him
Men with true skills are like that
Versatile in all kinds of weapons
especially the Shaolin rod
l'd like to see that for myself!
lt won't be easy!
Unless you're willing to
seek him out personally
And convince him to come help us
He can teach our clansmen
And can be very useful to us!
We can kill 2 birds with 1 stone
Let's do it!
We'll leave tomorrow morning
Always remember
You must bear in mind during practice
you're fighting a real enemy
Copy a snake's writhe, a tiger's pose and hawk's eyes
A deer's speed and a monkey's climb
lt's about observing your opponent
Make good use of your limbs
Practice is the basics of kung fu
Higher...more force!
Master Ou, l wasn't expecting you
With all these students
you must be very busy!
Please come inside!
No!
We represent Dama Bay's
27 kung fu schools
to ask you something
Have l done something wrong?
Very smart you are to solicit students
by promising to teach them everything
You flaunt your integrity
And make a profit by taking in students
l only know the duty of an instructor
is to teach the students what l know
without reservation
This is the best way to propagate kung fu
lf every instructor holds something back
lt won't be long
before kung fu becomes extinct
You'd do well to remember that
it's the master's end if the student knows everything
We must have a contingency plan
Well, to each his own
How l teach my students is not your concern!
Catch, Master!
Pardon me!
Master Ou
l choose to be selectively stubborn
Stay back!
Stop!
Master Tan
Master Meng
What happened?
Wang Yang has gone too far
l bother no one if they leave me alone
You've offended everyone in Dama Bay
Master Ou
l must correct you
lt's a master's honor if the student knows everything
That's closer to the truth!
Please go!
Let's go!
Master Ou
Master Wang
l am impressed
This is the Chief of the Meng clan
He has always admired you
We're here to pay you a visit
Please accept it, Master Wang
''Civil and martial prowess''
l don't deserve this
But...
Please sit down
Meng Fa
l've already made myself clear last time
You should not have bothered Chief Meng
But he...
l must make this trip myself
l can't bear to see our clansmen
wait helplessly
for you to become their master
lf l go with you
my students here will be just as helpless!
Our clansmen...
are all promising young men
You should go see for yourself!
Yes...
That's not necessary
l welcome your clansmen
to come here and learn
l've come a long way, Master Wang
You shouldn't let me go back empty handed!
l guarantee
You'll feel differently when you meet them
Please come with me
l'm the instructor
Of course!
l'm willing to teach anyone
Yes!
But l will not serve any clan exclusively
Listen...
Uncle
Let's go back to the inn
and wait for Master Wang to change his mind!
Very well!
l'll take my leave now
Goodbye!
Let's go!
Meng Fa, please take these with you
Don't be like this, Master Wang!
Uncle! Let's go!
No, don't kill...
You can't do that, brother!
l'm not your brother, you shameless wench!
You've disgraced the family
How can l stay here in Dama Bay
Tell me, how can l stay here!
Please, brother, l beg you...
Come here, you bitch!
Come out, Wang Yang!
You impregnated my sister!
You're a bastard!
Friends, you're all blind
to this beast
You treated him like a god
and respected him
Only one of us will come out alive!
Come here!
Don't hit my brother!
Wang Yang, don't hit him!
Let go!
What shall we do?
Master Wang, you're at fault
You impregnated her
And beat up her brother
How can you do such a thing?
There must be some mistake
Appearances are so deceiving
Friends and neighbors
l'm not that kind of a man
All these years
l have abided by the law
l don't know why they want to frame me
and tarnish my name!
Wang Yang!
l don't even know them
You don't know her?
Tell me
When you got her in bed
did you know her?
l'm not afraid of you
l dare you to kill me
and silence me
Or l'll fight you to the bitter end
l'll fight you!
You can't do that!
Let go!
l'll fight you!
Blood...
Murder...
Brother...
He killed him!
Arrest him!
You raped his sister
Now you killed him! You're in trouble!
Take me to the district office
Don't bother
He'll be dead just the same! Kill him now!
Here come the officers!
What's the matter?
Wang Yang killed this man
Wang Yang killed him
Stand back!
Where is Wang Yang?
He's not here!
Search the premises!
You can't go back now!
Master Wang
lt's one thing to cause disturbance
but you killed someone!
You must leave here at once
l will not run away
and be a fugitive for the rest of my life
l'll turn myself in!
That's suicide!
They're ganging up on you
My uncle realized this
and told me to wait for you here
What should l...
Alright...
My uncle has friends in high places
But...
He'll take care of it
Maybe they'll close the case
Brilliant plan!
Thanks for your hard work
Such a great performance!
You must leave at once
You're supposed to be dead
l'll leave when l get the money!
Thanks for all your help!
Don't mention it!
You scratch my back, l'll scratch yours!
We want the same thing
That's why...
once Wang Yang leaves Dama Bay
Master Ou will profit from taking in students
Yes!
Your seat is up ahead, Master Wang!
Sit down, don't be shy!
What are you doing?
Master Wang is our guest
lt took us great trouble to get him here!
What's the meaning of this?
This is ridiculous!
Please forgive them!
You...
You certainly deserve your reputation
Great skills!
You've passed the celestial chair
Please come down
Your turn...
Master Meng, l'm leaving!
Wait!
l know they have insulted you
That's nothing! The important thing
is that we must have virtues
Your clansmen harbor evil intentions
l'm afraid once they learn kung fu
they'll bully others
l don't want students like this
lt's my fault that l haven't been strict with them
Meng Feng, kneel down...
All of you, kneel!
Kneel!
This is your instructor
You see, they never had a proper teacher
and know nothing about virtues
honoring the teacher or respecting the truth
l'll count on you from now on
Please stay, for my sake!
Yes, please stay!
Get up!
Zhou Ping, you're quite something!
l've finished bathing
and you're still standing there!
The guy at the temple
once told me
strong legs is the key to kung fu
l must practice my stance
More water!
Zhou Ping, come here!
This is not the proper way to practice
You need a proper instructor
You're just wasting your time
l...
Magnificent!
Lure the opponent by retreating
What?
Parthian shot
Parthian shot?
Careful, Meng Feng!
Watch closely!
This is strange...
he stops here every time
Why?
Maybe that's all to it
No!
You said you're not from the Meng clan
and that you have no relatives?
l'm an orphan. Jia Jia is the name...
given to me by the Chief
Why are you here?
To tell you something
lt's not easy being the instructor
You may not have the patience
Thanks! You're saying...
l should leave here?
You're thinking too much!
You've been hired by Chief Meng
you must be a very good instructor
You can handle the job
lf l were a boy
l can learn from you
You have something on your mind?
No!
l'm leaving!
Tell Jia Jia not to come here again!
Yes!
Don't be afraid
We grew up together
What were you doing at the drill ground?
Before Wang Yang arrived
you never went there
You've to remember
who's paying for your food and clothing!
l won't forget Chief Meng raised me
and that l've always been bullied by you
You'll be my wife soon
l'm warning you! Don't go near Wang Yang again!
Or l'll show you!
Master, there are fun places over there
Yes!
We should go back
Yes...
Come here!
Call him
Master Wang!
Call him what?
Did you call me?
Master Wang, my name is Zhou Ping
l'm a waiter at Zhou's Restaurant over there
Noodles is our specialty
Would you like to try?
Maybe next time...let's go!
Come on!
Master Wang
What's this?
A custom to hack-off limbs that cross the boundary
Who set the rule?
My father...
but not recently!
lt was set down a long time ago
Did you agree to this?
No!
Master Wang!
Yes?
Chief Zhou never agreed to this
Whoever took the wrong step
was dragged over and had their limbs cut off
This is both brutal and unreasonable
isn't it?
But that's the rule!
Alright!
Master, you're our instructor
how can you speak for them?
l'm an instructor, but not just for your clan
Besides, l hate bullies
Let's go!
Don't get involved with the Mengs again
they're beasts!
Come up...
Stand firm!
Slowly!
You two get up there!
Turn!
Faster!
More strength
Crouch down!
This is no way to learn the rod
This is suicide!
What is this?
We'll kill ourselves before we learn the rod
What did you say? Come here!
l said ''what is this''?
Repeat that line until dark. Do it now!
Come on
What is this?
Louder
lf you want to learn to use the rod well
this wheel is crucial in training your waist
The rod is the first long weapon
You circle, point, hit and sweep
You'll fail if your legs are weak
You'll never perfect the hit and sweep technique
Meng Feng! Your turn!
Turn!
Slowly!
Try harder!
Zhou Ping!
Boss!
You're still up?
How can l sleep with this racket?
You took that apart?
What are you doing?
Look!
What do you think?
What is this for?
This is how Master Wang taught the rod
l heard this gadget is for...
practicing the stance
All those Mengs...
are nothing but idiots
They all fell down and bruised themselves
lt was such ajoy to see them like that
Don't go there anymore
You'll get into trouble
Don't worry, l'll be careful
They won't find out
Let me show you!
Show me what?
Come, Fatty! Give me a hand!
Faster!
You'll kill yourself!
Watch this!
Faster!
ls this alright?
Yes, faster!
ls it fast enough?
Stay back...
Look at the notice!
For me?
Father, Uncle Sha is here!
l was worried something happened to you!
Father was afraid you won't make it!
l know what's going on
Nothing will happen to me!
Please have a seat!
Yes!
l'm a wanted man
l must lay low for a while
Will you blame me for your losses?
l only worry about your safety
Stay here and let us know if you need anything
Keep a low profile
Times are different now
l'm not afraid of anyone!
Wang Yang from Dama Bay
is now our kung fu instructor
Him?
Your punch carries 30% strength, your kick 70%
Watch your waist and stance
Alright! Start from the beginning!
Yes!
Watch out!
They've been practicing indoors
and have become lazy
Once they go outdoors
see how energetic they are!
Honestly...
When they urged me to speak to you last night
l was afraid you'd object
l'm open to good ideas
Excuse me...
Who is it?
That'll teach him a lesson!
Are you alright?
Do you know who that is?
Are you badly hurt?
Master!
The wound is too minor
You could have killed him if you stab him again!
That won't do
l can't kill him in one strike
lf l engage him any longer, he'll know who l am
That won't do us any good!
What is it?
Jia Jia is here again!
She's always with him
How can that be?
You must make up your mind
l brought you some tonic
Have it while it's still hot
l've figured it out
The assassin attacked me with a sickle
Judging from his skill, he should use a soft weapon
And not a hooked weapon
He almost pierced through your heart
Who cares what he used ?!
To know your opponent is a sure way to win
How can l not think?
Can't you think...
or talk about something else?
Other than martial arts, there's...
really nothing worth thinking
You need not think of anything else
Chief Meng told me
the Zhous have sent the assassin
Do you think so?
No. lf you say the Mengs did this
l'd believe it
What?
Don't ask me anymore
Finish this, l have to go!
Someone's watching!
Meng Fa, bring him in here!
Bring him in...beat him!
That's enough!
He spied on us!
Beat him up!
Stop!
lf you want to learn
You should come to me
instead of spying
l have wanted to tell you
but l never had the chance
because you live here...
Alright! Let him go!
Not so fast!
l'm outnumbered
l dare you to take me on one by one
Very well!
l'd like to see how much you have learned
Catch!
Stand back!
Come on!
Good!
Let me...
Stop! Step down!
Zhou Ping, come with me!
No!
You can't leave!
What's this?
Listen...don't let him leave!
Stand back!
lf you go, don't blame me
Father, that bastard Zhou Ping
spied on us at the drill ground
We caught him!
But Master Wang wants to escort him out
How dare you, Zhou Ping!
You crossed the boundary and came here
You're in big trouble now!
Master Wang, you know about our family feud
lt's not easy to mediate
Your feud is not my concern
l'm a kung fu instructor
l can choose my students
Yes, but not him
Because he's a Zhou
l have no bias
No matter what you say
This kid is staying
Stay here
so that you can hack off
his arms and legs?
There's no need to quarrel
Whatever is the matter
do not hurt our relationship
Shut up!
l always knew Chief Meng is a kung fu expert
You need not show mercy
lf l can't take him with me today
l only have myself to blame
Don't quibble over such small matters
You'll upset the bigger plan. You must reconsider
Stop!
Zhou Ping, it's your lucky day today!
Otherwise l'd have skinned you alive!
Master Wang
The chief wishes to make peace
You may go now!
He can't leave!
Zhou Ping
Come here!
Zhou Ping!
What's the big deal?
This is Master Wang!
Sir, Master Wang!
Master Wang!
Boss, l've invited Master Wang here
How are you?
Fatty, Master Wang is here!
Really?
Zhou Ping, you know we're busy
Where have you been?
Master Wang
Please be seated
Yes!
lmpressive!
Get out!
Bring some tea
Please!
Master Wang!
l went to the Mengs
and invited Master Wang to try your noodles
Nonsense! How many lives do you have?
Just one!
Please sit down!
No thanks!
He's addicted to martial arts
especially about your skill
Yes!
He goes to watch you whenever he has time
Really?
He made many gadgets for practice
They're all in the backyard
This way...
Right here!
l watched how you teach them
and l do the same when l come back
But l've made no progress
You've shown respect for martial arts
l'll take you in as my student
Master...
Boss
Be a good student
Master Wang, l must attend to business
Please
No!
Will you regret it?
Never!
l've tried that and l fell down hard!
Get on!
Let go!
Where are you, Master?
Zhou Ping's noodles are famous around here
Master Wang
He even dreams about learning from you
He's totally enchanted
How are the noodles, Master?
Not bad!
Come on!
What is it?
My melon!
Pay for my melon
l need to talk to Master Wang
Forget it, let him go!
Thanks!
Get lost!
Meng Fa!
l need to talk to Master Wang
What do you want?
What do you want? Get out!
l'm looking for Master Wang
Master Wang
Zhou Ping
My name is Fatty
Hello!
Master Wang
How dare you cross the boundary!
You're not afraid of
having your limbs chopped off?
Of course l am!
l need to speak to you
l'll take my chances
Chief Meng heard that you want to teach Zhou Ping
He has no right to meddle
But he still wants you to live with us
lt'll be more convenient
lf Chief Meng cares about his clansmen
l'll consider his offer
What's the meaning of this?
l have orders from the Chief
Master Wang, this is a mere token
of our sincerity, please accept it!
We'd like to discuss matters peacefully
Please go ahead
l know you don't want to stay here
As long as you agree to teach them
the Shaolin rod
The price is on the table
Price?
lf you'll agree
Sorry! l've taught them enough
but they're not worthy of the Shaolin rod
Don't forget you're still a wanted criminal
The murder case is not yet closed
l dare not say l've done you a favor
But l helped you out of a fix
How can you be so ungrateful?
l'm guilty of manslaughter
But did you really save me
or was it part of your trap?
You...
Chief Meng, will you
swear in front of this plaque
that it wasn't a trap?
lf l could find a better place to stay
l would never have troubled you
What l have seen and heard these 6 months
is enough to prove
how extraordinary the Meng clan is
What do you mean?
l'm afraid you can't leave!
You can come in but you can't go out!
You're welcome to try if you don't believe me
Listen, Uncle!
Why do this?
lf Master Wang wants to leave, you can't force him
Let's part as friends
l've misjudged you, Wang Yang!
Meng Fa, tell him to get out!
Master Wang, if you wish to leave
we can't make you stay!
Do you need help to pack?
No thanks. l can handle it
Goodbye, Master Meng
Remember you said
you'll bother no one if they leave you alone?
After him!
Yes!
You're hurt!
Hide in my room!
Aren't you afraid?
Don't say that now!
Go over there!
Get in!
Jia Jia
Wang Yang ran away after he wounded our men
The Chief thinks it's not safe here
l'm here to look in on you
There's no one here!
Yes!
You can't go in!
No one's here!
No?
l'll tell the Chief
about this situation
Bring more men and search the neighborhood
Wang Yang's wounded, he won' get far!
Go!
l was so scared!
Where were you?
Jia Jia, looks like...
l'll have to stay here for a few days
Can you do me a favor?
Zhou Ping, the boss is looking for you
l'm busy
Are you looking for me, Miss?
Don't worry, l know what to do
This is too easy
l'll go back and bring more men
We'll kill all the Zhous
No, that's not a good idea
You can't just target the Zhous
while the Mengs are spared
That's right!
l have thought this out
l'll rob the Mengs as well
Kill a few of your men who are disobedient
Then no one will suspect anything
Good! When are you leaving?
First thing tomorrow morning
Jia Jia
Get in!
What have you found out?
l saw Sha Er Lang
lt was him
They thought you were dead
and are plotting against the Zhou clan
When will they take action?
Sha Er Lang will leave early tomorrow
to get more help
l must arrest him
and expose their conspiracy
This is the only chance
lt will...
prevent a disaster for both clans
Go!
Master, do you know...
he's Sha Er Lang the robber?
He colluded with Meng Er Da
Chief Zhou heard about it
l know
l'll have Fatty alert the district office
and take him into custody
Remind Fatty
not to mention my name
Outside...hurry
Wang Yang, you're under arrest
Strange! They're here already!
Looks like they came for you
You're right!
Go outside before you get into trouble!
Hurry!
Sir...
Sitting over there
is Sha Er Lang the robber
Why are you after a Yang?
There's no one here by that name
ls Wang Yang inside?
See for yourself? There's no one here
except me
He's lying
Wang Yang is inside
You'll go tojail for abetting a criminal
We'll arrest you too
Arrest me?
Zhou Ping, come inside
They came for me
What's going on?
Go!
Help me, Master!
Hold on!
After them!
Go...
Maybe they didn't catch Wang Yang
l'll tell the Chief
Zhou Ping, looks like
we'll have to stay here
for at least 6 months
until things die down
During this period
l'll teach you my skill with the rod
Then l'll get Meng Er Da to clear my name
l hope you'll practice hard
and pass on my skill
You must obey 3 disciplines and 5 commandments
What are they?
Respect your teachers & ancestors, obey them
No adultery and treachery
No lies, no dishonesty
Do not be a bully and do not pass on your skill hastily
l understand!
The technique is to bind, point, strike and sweep
This circular gateway...
is to help you practice how to bind and point
The purpose is...
to confuse your opponent
Shroud his weapon within the circle
Take your chance to push it aside
Then scurry forward
And attack his vital organs
Now you'll be using all your strength
Later when you get a hang of the technique
You'll have better control
Here...
Your turn!
Catch!
This thing again?
Get started now!
Arms straight!
Stand upright!
Level your head
Control your breathing
Master
This is to bind and point
Your rod is lighter and longer
Keep practicing
Yes!
Use these bricks
to form a circle
The one holding the rod stays inside
Keep your opponent on the outside
Remember, don't ever let him
cut inside the circle
l understand!
Focus on the rod
Be decisive and don't stall
Yes!
Come!
Level the rod!
Guard all directions
That's an excellent block!
Shoulder the rod
Strike with both ends
Find a weak spot on the right
Turn and aim for the Ling Tai acupoint
l understand
Cut in from the left
Aim for the Qi Men acupoint
Yes!
Stand like ajoss stick, change your posture
Be dormant, yet alert. Speed is of the essence
Move only when your opponent moves
When he moves, you move even faster
Sweep with force
Point with strength
Treat me as your enemy and not your master
Move in!
Attack!
You said move only when you move
And l'll move faster than you
Good!
Here l come!
Aim for the chest when you attack
Aim for the legs when you retreat
Backward thrust
Backward thrust?
l didn't teach you this
Where did you learn this?
You were pressuring me
l improvised
Brilliant!
Look at you!
You forgot everything!
Your enemy will bite you if your corner him
Never forget this!
Point! Go!
Stay within the circle
Strike with force
Circle!
Don't move unless your opponent moves
When he moves, you move even faster
Circle! Point!
On the right
A small gift...thank you
Master Sha
You must have heard
the situation can go either way
lf you do as Chief Meng says
you'll get away scott free
Tell me!
You must testify in court that
you collaborated with Wang Yang to split the loot
Don't forget to implicate Zhou Zhen Xian
Tell them he's an accomplice
This is ruthless!
Wang Yang is finished
For sure!
A criminal's testimony carries weight
How can you call me a criminal?
No...
What's in it for me?
You'll be set free when the time is right
You may go anywhere you please
lt's a deal!
Pass a message to Chief Meng
lf he doesn't keep his promise
l'll change my testimony
We're in this together
Uncle, we have settled everything
But Sha Er Lang is still in jail
Do we still need him?
l don't think so, let's...
That's easy. l just need your consent
Have you located Jia Jia?
Not yet!
l heard that when Wang Yang was wounded
he hid in her room
l can't believe after all these years
she'll turn against me! Keep looking!
Yes!
Master Sha!
lt's me!
Meng Fa!
Master Sha!
When do l break out ofjail?
Today, but you're not breaking out
You're walking out of here
Have a drink first
Magistrate Wang is not here
l'll go wait for his reply. Help yourself!
Please!
Hurry!
See you later, Master Sha!
You...
Well?
Master, look
Master Wang
Jia Jia, how did you find us?
lt's destiny, Master!
Here we are, together again!
Let's sit down and talk!
Zhou Ping, run 10 laps around the tree
l'm tired already
Let me rest!
No! Run...
Please sit down! Run!
The Mengs are getting increasingly suspicious
l couldn't stay there any longer
So l ran away during the night
How is the situation?
Sha Er Lang insists you're together with Chief Zhou
to rob the village and split the loot
Notices were put out for your arrest
l overheard some news on the road
Zhou Zhen Xian and his sons
died tragically in jail
Many of the Zhou residences were closed
and their property confiscated
Outrageous!
Master, l can't run anymore!
l'll kill Meng Er Da
How many times did l tell you
to stay calm; look at you...
Even if l fight Meng Er Da
l may not defeat him, let alone you!
Then we're not avenging the Zhous?
Of course not!
Before we finish practicing
the double rod
we can't go back!
Look!
Here's the correspondence of Sha Er Lang & Meng Er Da
Where did you get these?
Stole them from the study
lf l can't find you
l'll report to the local authorities
l hate every one of the Meng clan
We need your help on this
Don't go to the local authorities
Take it up with Commissioner Yang
l'll be back in 2 weeks
to settle the score with Meng Er Da
Uncle, Wang Yang is back!
Meng Fa!
Now you know l can predict the future
Master Wang
You already left with Zhou Ping
Why did you come back?
Zhou Ping, have you seen this before?
No, but it looks like fun!
Stand still!
Master, sweep from the left
This is really useful
You have been practicing with a fixed target
Now you have a moving target, make use of it!
Thanks!
Steady...
Let me do this!
Alright!
Zhou Ping, step down!
Yes!
You're asking for trouble!
Wang Yang, you should just stay away
To avenge Chief Zhou and his family
To expose the conspiracy in Dama Bay
To find the instigator behind Sha Er Lang's plot
l must come back
l can't let the culprit go unpunished
Yes, l did all of that
Unfortunately your enthusiasm
will be wasted on the dust under my feet
l've seen this trick before
l won't fall for it!
Let me...
Why didn't you teach me this?
l am teaching you now
Stay back!
Here he comes
You're bound to lose!
Allow me, Master!
Come on! What's the matter?
Zhou Ping, let him take the initiative
You're not up to standard, don't move!
Level the rod!
l've used the backward thrust again!
lmprovising is good!
Zhou Ping
We have already crippled him
Let him rot in prison
Uncle...
The Commissioner is here...