Get them out!
All Tamils get out!
Leave me! Leave us!
No! I won't go!
Breaking news.
Sri Lankan president
has been assassinated.
The killing was carried
out using a human bomb.
According to the local police
this incident took place..
..when he was coming out of
Colombo's Army Headquarters.
It is being alleged that the
LTF could be behind this.
After this incident it is possible
that peace attempts will get deferred.
And the situation there
could get tense again.
Ruby!
I want to say everything.
The truth..
I cannot carry..
...this burden anymore.
You've been drinking again.
I've told you.
Whatever is bothering
you, share it.
You will feel lighter.
Otherwise, go home.
Betrayal..
Power..
Greed..
Can I talk about such
things before your God?
Yes, You can.
The last witness..
They killed him as well.
It was a game.
A conspiracy.
Who are you?
It's been three years since
you've been coming here...
And What's this conspiracy
that you are talking of?
What wrong did our
Prime Minister do?
Why did we let him die?
What?
We could've saved
our prime minister.
What do you know?
I was there, Father.
It was the darkest phase in
the history of Sri Lanka.
The clashes between the largest
ethic group Sinhalese..
..and the minority Tamils..
...had was going through
its worst crisis.
This ethic violence claimed thousands
of Tamilian civilian lives...
Abuses..
The supply of basic
necessities like food..
Water..
Everything was stopped.
A lot of families
were destroyed.
And thus thousands of Tamilian
youth turned rebellious..
And joined the
LTF leader Anna.
Long Live Eelam.
Anna refused to surrender
before the Sri Lankan forces.
And raised the demand for
a separate Tamil state.
And thus began, the
endless killings.
These bloodbath made many
Tamils lose their homes.
And they sought
refuge in India.
Indian government
expressed its concern..
...and decided to intervene.
Peace Accord is an important
political decision.
I will be going ahead with it.
We will be signing the
Peace Accord tomorrow.
To make sure that no inhumane
activity takes place..
...during the Provincial
Council Elections..
...I've decided to send a
peace force to the island.
Prime Minister signed the
historical Peace Accord..
...with the Sri Lankan
President today.
He also declared the
Provincial Council Elections..
So that once again there is peace
and normalcy in the island.
The first group of
the peace force.. '
..reached there with an intention of
making the rebels surrender arms.
In the hope that peace
and normalcy returns.
But Anna rejected
the Peace Accord.
19 LTF cadres committed suicide
in Sri Lankan custody.
And Anna blamed lndia..
...and Sri Lanka for it.
He said that this peace accord is
not in the favor of the Tamils.
He feared that if they
surrendered arms..
..then once the peace
force leaves..
..all the Tamils in the
island will be killed.
Hence.. 'He was not
ready to negotiate.
This is going to be a long war.
Indian Army launched an
operation to capture Anna.
But our soldiers got killed .
since Anna was already
in the know of..
...our operational
details and intels
And from here on, began a
gruesome guerilla war..
..between Anna and
the peace force.
Our soldiers are getting killed.
Operation details
are getting leaked.
RD, I hope you are aware of
what your boys are up to.
But we had warned you,
not to send the forces.
But it was your General
who assured the PM..
...that we'll disarm
them in 72 hours.
And here we are, after one year.
If this continues, we're
sure to get embarrassed.
PM needs is answerable
to the people.
Mr. Cabinet Secretary, we are not
fighting with a traditional army.
This is a locally
entrenched guerilla force.
We just can't make out who's a
militant and who's a civilian!
We don't even have proper maps!
But yes, if they attack
us, we will retaliate.
This shouldn't become
another Vietnam for us.
How much more can we
embarrass the PM?
RD?
The fact is,
Anna doesn't trust us anymore.
And Perhaps we ourselves are responsible
for creating this situation.
If we loosen the
grip any further..
...It will be a golden opportunity for
the west to get inside the island.
And this is already happening.
Guruji all of a sudden
going to Singapore..
...with Murthy for
a spiritual tour..
Is it a coincidence?
So, Mr. Murthy,
...you wish to be the lord
of the largest democracy?
I've always been saying..
...that there's a conspiracy
to overthrow the government.
One thing is clear now.
Only military action
won't suffice.
All these are clear cut signs.
Overt operations
won't be enough now.
RD, get all the
covert ops ready.
This Peace Accord needs
to succeed, at any cost.
That's all. Good luck.
RD..
Stay.
Enough of these discussions.
Media is asking a
lot of questions.
You'll have to intervene.
I'm ready..
...to use all the
intelligence at my disposal.
But who are we really fighting?
You, too, need to understand.
The situation is very sensitive.
Anna won't surrender arms.
He is adamant.
And others are waiting to
jump in to win his trust.
We will lose the island.
And that will be a serious
national threat for us.
Now is not the time
to go by the book.
The time to question..
...what is legitimate and
what is not, is over.
You know very well what
needs to be done with Anna.
Send in your best men.
We need to form a Provincial
Council there, before Diwali.
Swarup, get me Major Vikram.
I want him in Delhi
in the next 24 hours.
Urgent.
Ruby, I need to go.
Otherwise, you know..
Look,
I know, I am an army wife.
And I need to hold my
head high and all that.
And I will.
But it's been four years.
And I just keep missing you.
How do I stay normal?
Don't worry.
Everything will be normal soon.
Oh yes, and avoid
all these news.
And take care of yourself.
If you are so concerned
about me then don't go.
Six months, at least..
Till I hold you
again, like this.
So, what's happening?
Bala has been informed.
Jaffna safe house
has been activated.
Vikram..
Still as restless as ever?
Old habits die hard, sir.
Relax.
Swarup.
Additional director.
Of course, I remember, sir.
I had met you briefly during
the Mizoram operation.
Good memory.
Sir.
Anyway, talking about work..
Do you know anything about
lndo-Lankan situation?
I've done my homework, sir.
You know nothing.
You'll be solely responsible for all
covert operations of RAW in Jaffna.
Sir.
PM is concerned about
the situation there.
His clear agenda is to execute
Provincial Elections successfully.
The Small militant groups
there have surrendered.
But The most powerful group,
the most ferocious one, LTF..
Is still resistant.
Do we have a strategy, sir?
Step one: Break LTF.
The most likely candidate
for that: Mallaya.
He's Anna's Man Friday.
Very loyal.
Impossible to reach.
Step Two: Shri.
He's the only man in the island
who can stand against Anna.
Get him on our side.
For official matters you'll report
to the Madras Desk Head, Bala.
He's tough but knows
a lot about Jaffna.
But you'll report to me
personally, about everything.
Keep me in the loop.
Yes, sir.
Any questions?
No, sir.
Welcome aboard.
Come, Swaroop.
Jaffna?
But isn't a civil war
going on there, Vi?
Don't worry.
I'm leaving behind a contact.
Swarup's.
Call him in case
of any emergency.
Indian Prime Minister
today has categorically..
...stated that the
peace forces..
..will not be withdrawn until the
elections are successfully held.
And that India won't allow
any foreign powers..
...to interfere in her
regional matters.
Hi.
Vikram.
Jaya.
Pleasure meeting you.
Is this Your normal route?
I'm writing a piece
on the refugees.
You?
Chibber route.
Do you still operate
out of London?
No, here for some time now.
I've read your articles.
You are quite critical.
Criticizing our
national policies..
...doesn't make
me anti national.
Not at all.
It's the birth right of
all you journalists.
Whatever you print, it
becomes a bestseller.
You think you're more patriotic?
Of course.
Those with passports, proceed
to the passport division.
Those without passport, please
register at the army camp.
Men, stay at the back.
No matter between whom
the conflict is..
No matter what the reason is..
The first casualties are
always the Innocent civilians.
And This was happening
in Sri Lanka as well.
There was devastation
everywhere.
I've an authorized visa.
Sorry, ma'am.
I'm allowed to pass through.
I'm sorry.
What are you saying? I'm here.
I'm a journalist.
Sorry, ma'am.
What do you mean? I
have to get through.
Welcome to the land
of Buddha, sir.
KT. Kamal Tyagi.
Jaffna safe house
is 118kms away.
Passport? ID?
How could humanity ever
survive in all of this?
In this small island..
Civilization was dying.
This way sir.
This is our safe house.
Inform the high commission.
Yes.
Myself Sushil Pandey. SP.
Hi, SP.
Intercepts?
Yes, sir.
Call records for the past
two days and intercepts.
Sir.
Hello, boys.
Sir!
Sir, Major Vikram reporting.
I've heard about you.
Try this.
A local drink.
Sir.
LTF.
Most dedicated and disciplined.
They operate from deep within
the jungle, from bunkers..
...40 feet underground.
Hence, this map.
Memorize it.
Relax.
We'll be running our phase
two covert operations.
We need to weaken
LTF's top leaders.
Dead or alive.
LFT. Liberations of Tamils
Front, also known as Tigers.
The top leader:
Pandyan, Intel chief.
Mallaya, deputy leader
and army commander.
Rajsekharan, their
spokesperson, an arms dealer.
But our hero, Anna Baskaran.
He doesn't need an intro.
On the other hand, TPA.
Chief, Shri.
Once upon a time he
was Anna's partner.
He's soft. Wants to
get into politics.
Prime Minister wants that
Anna should surrender arms..
...and join the elections
before Diwali.
Make Shri powerful.
Make them fight each other.
Do we this all by ourselves?
Obviously.
You are not in the army anymore.
You are an agent of R&AW.
Hence use less brawn
and more brains.
You'll report everything to me.
I'll find out what I need
to through my own means.
I cannot afford mistakes.
Sir.
And most importantly,
you are a team leader.
So don't get caught.
Never get caught.
My primary task for
the next few days..
Turn left.
..Was to find Shree.
We identified a few
important links.
We got a breakthrough when
Narayanan agreed to meet us.
Hello, sir.
I got through Narayanan.
He's agreed to meet.
"Tomorrow, 7 " Imam.
7kms from safe house.
Sir, the one in white shirt.
This basket.
How much does it weigh? 30 kgs.
And This is for?
Local market..
70% of the earth is
covered with water.
It's not so difficult
to catch fish.
Oh really?
That really depends on the fish.
The deeper you go the
better fish you catch.
Tell me, which one do you want?
My bosses love the fish
you catch for them.
Which one do you want?
I told you this one belongs
to the local market..
Tell me which one do you want?
CIA, KGB, Tigers.
They're All the same for me.
I don't have time to waste.
Don't even try to negotiate.
Shri.
You an agent?
Everyone is the
same in a war zone.
Maybe.
But for me, no satisfaction
means no fish.
You see this Information
business has become too risky...
I'll have to give information
about you if anyone enquires.
I need to store that.
Now you may Leave.
SIOP
Go.
How will you and your
government support me?
The situation out here..
How will people sitting
in New Delhi control it?
New Delhi recognizes your TPA.
And our PM's agenda is
exactly to settle that.
Election and peace.
Peace?
Anna has made me his archrival.
We were like brothers.
He's being brutal to our people.
He wants total
control over Jaffna.
People want to see one leader.
Come to the point.
Sir,
we want you to counter LTF.
We need loads of arms
to counter Anna.
Loads of them.
Can your bosses
provide me with arms?
Will they promise?
Can you?
Sir, we'll support
you in this war.
We're with you.
Wait, Mr. Vikram.
I hate liars.
You won't get a second chance.
Remember that.
You need to relax, boss.
Shri neither trusts me, nor you.
I'm just waiting for
the right time.
He won't agree on anything
until he gets the arms.
Please understand, boss.
Who are you working for?
For Shri? Or for me?
Sir, I'll handle this my way.
Trust me.
Please, sir.
Keep me informed.
Down.. down..
Welcome, madam. This way.
So,
you did meet with
the Prime Minister.
He offered you the support
what you were seeking.
But then you backed off.
My soldiers surrendered
their arms.
They were killed.
I was backstabbed.
I want safety for my people.
What happens when the
peace forces leave?
Look, it's a clear order
for the peace forces..
...to ensure that the
elections go peacefully.
But you're also hell bent on
boycotting these elections.
By teaming up with Shri?
Double standard.
I'm already an elected leader.
I've a legitimate army.
Attention!
So this bloodbath,
there's no end to it?
I did not start it.
Salute!
Then if you don't agree for
a political solution..
...you'll have to
find a new partner.
Is there a new alliance?
This is my land.
ELAM is my final destination.
For that if I need to
seek help from the west..
...then I will.
LTF's leader Anna has
once again rejected..
...lndia's offer for
peace elections.
And has further stated that..
...he will not hesitate to
seek help from the west.
How does New Delhi
react to this?
How will this affect the
peace process in the island?
Only time will tell.
Rajsekharan,
you source funds and
arms from outside.
Go and meet our new
foreign friend.
We need..
...your help in our fight,
in our war.
So you need our support?
We need to be assured of
your support in the future.
I have to pass through.
There could be An ambush ma'am.
Rounds are being fired inside.
I can't allow you to go in.
Look, I've the
colonel's permission.
I've received no such orders.
Ma'am..
I have to pass through.
Captain. I know her.
Not bad. Thank you.
I read your interview.
How's Anna?
Hey, listen, he's not my friend.
But I will say this.
I've never met anyone with
so much clarity and purpose.
You can't buy him.
Then Anna must've also told
you about his new partner.
You're asking me?
Until last year LTF was
favored by New Delhi.
But now, their rival TPA Shri
seems to have taken their place.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Somebody has got to
be helping them.
Why tell me?
It's your job, isn't it?
"The date for arms deal
was decided as 6th July."
It was important that the arms
consignment reached Shri.
Hello. Capt. Murli.
Delivery will be
made from Singapore.
From here.
By using fishing boats,
we'll make the exchange.
And this here, is
the dropping point.
Point Pedro.
Delivery at 4:00pm.
'But I didn't know that..
This small arms deal will change
both the local politics..
..and my life forever.
Gifts are on the way
from Singapore.
Be sure they reach
our new friends.
Don't worry, Reed.
My man will be there
with our new friends.
Vikram, you will get a safe
passage from the old ship yard.
Sri Lankan army's Capt. Ratnayake
will be waiting for you.
Just pay him the money.
Landing will happen
at: Point Pedro.
Indians are on their way.
Leave now.
Okay. Over and out.
Let's go. Let's go.
Common hurry.
Let's move.
Move move, Fast.
What are LTF rebels
doing here, sir?
KT, something is wrong.
Let me check.
KT!
Take position.
SP! SP, KT is hit!
Send backup!
Lets go, lets go.
Get up, KT! Get up!
Attention!
Anna these are rocket launchers,
and these are AK-47 & AK-56.
Hello?
I'm KT's senior
calling from Jaffna.
KT is..
Please, ma'am.
We did all we could do.
Sir.
Happy?
We lost an important man.
Out! Get out!
What had I asked you?
"If you can't handle it
by yourself I can help.."
Did I or did I not say that?
What now?
A marching party?
Sir, someone double-crossed us.
Don't give me that bullshit!
Vikram, you know what your problem
is, you think you're too smart!
Sir. Trust me, sir. LTF was
not supposed to be there.
I don't know from where the
random firing started.
Do you know what be
the result of this?
Anna and Shri, both of
them will hunt us down.
Hello? Sir..
What!
RD sir is on the line.
Sure, sir.
I will take control.
Yes.
Now you get out of Jaffna.
Go straight to the
Colombo safe house.
And stay there.
Delhi still hasn't
altered its ways.
The same old strategy.
It's not so. We want
to support you.
You gave such a big arms
consignment to LTF.
This is how you'll support us!
There was an ambush.
I too lost a man.
The other guy, Vikram, he came
here and made big promises.
Do you know why he
is still alive?
I told my men that
he's your man.
It was a mistake.
Bullshit, This is how
I'll counter Anna?
I'll handle him personally.
24 hours.
Deal with him.
If you don't then I will.
He's gone to Capt. Mum's shop.
What happened at the jetty?
I don't know.
Who informed LTF?
I don't know. I
really don't know.
No one knew about the arms deal.
How did they find out about it?
I don't know, please, sir.
For God's sake.
I don't know, sir.
Right, sir.
Keep him alive.. don't kill him.
Jaya, the journalist's
room number please.
403.
Jaya.
Jaya, it's me.
I need to talk to you.
Anna would get the arms.
You knew about it, didn't you?
Is this an official
interrogation, Mr. RAW?
Because if it is,
my answer is no.
How did you know?
I need to know.
Excuse me?
Why are you asking me this?
I have my networks.
That's my job.
You should know how it works.
Jaya, please.
If Anna is being made more powerful
There will be repercussions.
The entire peace
process will fail.
There will be a whole new civil war.
Goddamn it. This is not a game.
Vikram, look around.
The peace process
has already failed.
And I'm not playing
games either.
I'm here because there
human lives are at stake.
Jaya, please.
What do you know?
Look, before I came here I
got a call from my source.
A foreign agency guy met
with an Indian official.
And the leak
happened in Bangkok.
Was that Indian
official from RAW?
I don't know.
Look, if he was Raw
then you know..
Let me tell you,
they know your next move much
before you even implement it.
So you should know
about it, not me.
Vikram,
this conversation
never happened.
Assets can't call
be called back.
Specially considering..
Sir, there's some urgent news.
Please have a look at it.
Latest news has just come in from
Sri Lanka that an Indian national..
..Vikram Singh has been
abducted by the LTF militants..
..in the Jaffna area.
Stay down, stay down..
The Indian High Commission
in Colombo has stated..
..they are not aware of the
whereabouts of Vikram.
This kidnapping is assumed to
be a political kidnapping.
How unstable will
the conditions be?
Or Will the Indian High...
Get me Bala now.
Ma'am, we understand this
is not easy for you.
But this is a
political kidnapping.
We are negotiating.
But we can approach the Indian
High Commission, right?
They can send in the army.
After all the army is
responsible, right?
Vikram was on official duty.
He was on official posting.
Ma'am, we need to understand
whom we are dealing with.
A dangerous and brutal
terrorist outfit, LTF.
Perhaps even you
know about them.
So you mean I should keep mum..
...and my husband's life
hangs in the bargain. Right?
Ma'am, we understand
your emotions.
But Vikram belongs to us.
We will try our best and
bring him back safely.
Hello.
What the hell is happening, Bala?
I don't know, sir. I just
returned to Madras this morning.
Our best boy gets kidnapped
right from under your nose..
And you're say that
you don't know!
I understand, sir.
You are responsible for
whatever happens there.
I had warned Vikram.
I told him to be careful.
And now LTF is angry..
If LTF is responsible
then talk to them.
Deploy the army if you have to.
Do what you have to but we
want our boy back safely.
Sir, I spoke to the High
Commission in Colombo.
You know they won't negotiate.
Fine, sir. I'll
leave right away.
I'll leave for the army
base camp right away.
Soldier's name: Vikram Singh.
Suspected location: Pallai town.
48kms east from Jaffna.
Bravo one.
Around 50 LTF holding up there.
Ask LTF to leave right now..
I have deployed the army.
Target visible.
60 degrees north.
Sir, He's alive.
Bravo one to base camp.
Location is empty. Repeat.
Location is empty.
Status: Injured but alive.
Here have this
you'll feel better.
How do you feel?
Look at your self.
Your New Delhi thinks
that it can sit there..
...and manage everything
through a remote control.
Nonsense!
In the field, in the jungle..
I'm in control here.
Jaffna is my territory.
You wouldn't have survived.
I saved you.
What next?
Oh, your work is done.
Your assignment's finished.
Your cover is brown.
You are on the hit-list
of both the camps.
You'll put the agency in
risk if you stay here.
So, you should leave.
Enjoy with your wife.
Go on a holiday.
And one more thing, your journalist
friend she should leave too.
It's not safe for her here.
SP. Here.
Will you help me?
Yes, boss?
Henceforth I want all the information
of Bala's movements and call records.
Okay, boss.
How are you?
I'm fine.
And your injury?
Ruby. The one whom I
always left back alone.
She just had only
this one hope.
That everything will be fine.
I might have been the one at war,
but she too was fighting a battle.
With herself.
With her fears.
I had the entire army with me.
But all she had
was her belief..
That I will come back.
Alive.
How are you?
Alive, for now.
You wouldn't have
survived this time.
LTF was very rigid.
And New Delhi,
you know them well.
Somehow we managed.
But, sir, I got framed.
Twice.
Somehow survived.
So,
what went wrong?
What do you think?
Sir, I was not wrong
about the arms deal.
There is a leak amongst us.
So what's your plan?
Thank you, sir.
That I need to figure out.
But before that, I'll
get you Mallaya.
You were right.
To pin down Anna, we
need to crack Mallaya.
How?
You can't go back in the jungle.
They'll kill you.
Sir, with your permission,
let me do it.
Off the record.
You mean no vacation?
I want Mallaya.
Mallaya is the most
dangerous shark.
You're taking a big risk.
You'll get both of us killed.
Fine, I'll see what I can do.
Double money.
Mallaya was Anna's
second in command.
Who controlled the
entire east region.
And getting him onto our
side for the elections...
...meant breking the lTF into 2
I want to meet Mallaya.
Who are you?
Where are you from?
I'm a reporter.
Why do you want to meet Mallaya?
I'm reporting on the war.
Myself Vikram, sir.
So you..
...want to interview me?
Yes.
I was waiting for you.
You know why?
For what purpose would
a RAW's journalist..
...out his life at
risk and come here?
Mr. Mallaya, let me get
straight to the point.
My senior wants to meet you.
In Colombo.
RD is coming to Colombo?
You know Anna will
be very angry.
He wants to meet you, alone.
First you spoke about
breaking the LTF.
Then you prepared
TPA against them.
Now you want us to
support the LTF again?
I think we should go ahead with
the Provincial Council Elections.
Pick any three representatives.
Go ahead with the
elections and end this.
"Any" meaning?
The ones no one knows about?
No one recognizes?
If we want peace...
we need the people with us.
And we all know that
people support LTF.
We will have to partner LTF.
And I don't mean Anna.
We partner LTF without Anna.
We have been able to penetrate to
his second in command, Mallaya.
He has enough backing of LTF
that he can stand on his own.
As a leader.
Now who the hell is Mallaya, RD?
Hold on.
If we can still have
the elections then..
...we might find a
face saving exit.
Otherwise, in the next 48 hours
the PM will have to resign.
Sir.
Try.
So... You went passed me?
Good.
You met Mallaya.
How did you manage that?
I was just following
orders, sir.
Oh, come on!
Don't give me that bullshit.
Conspiring with New Delhi,
that's what you are doing.
There is a leak in my team..
You.
We both are working for
the same government.
You cannot keep implicating me.
If you do that again,
I will not hold back.
And you know, no one
is innocent here.
Hi, Jaya.
Hi.
So you're leaving?
Obviously.
They think I work for you now.
But thanks for saving my life.
Look, I'm sorry that because of me..
Please.
Don't drag me into
this any further.
As a war correspondent it's important
that I'd be seen as unbiased.
It could ruin everything
that I stand for.
I just wanted you to know
that you are not safe here.
Yeah, I know.
These threats.
Anyway, don't worry.
I promise to remain
anti-national.
My office numbers and my
London's personal number.
And, Vikram, be care.
You too.
Please have your tea.
I don't enjoy such things.
I stay in the jungle.
That's why Anna
operates like a tyrant?
He's openly into brutality.
But it won't last for long.
No matter where Anna is hiding in
this island, we will find him.
And the elections will
be held peacefully.
But what after that?
Who will be the new leader? Have
you ever given that a thought?
It was a mistake coming here.
The mistake is that you
guys are addicted to war.
Hanging cyanide capsules around
the neck of small children,
making them into
turn militants...
Is this your war?
You are snatching
away their future.
The Tamilians can get
their rights back..
...only through a
political solution.
And you can do so, by
being their leader.
Not through war.
Our offer is clear.
And what if I refuse?
You have no option.
Enjoy your tea.
Vikram, phase three.
Get Anna.
Sir.
Mallaya will give you
Anna's location.
Brief the army special forces.
We want Anna at any cost.
Right, sir.
Mission Extract Anna.
Two platoons.
One will land in the east
and the other in north.
Vikram..
This is the position
of the LTF camp.
500 meters in diameter.
The whole region is
covered with landmines.
This will be our dropping point.
Pottai lake.
Remember, we have
only eight minutes.
Vikram, your job in Jaffna
is over for the time being.
Immediately station
yourself in Kerala.
Wait for further orders.
Leave now.
He's not here.. its empty.
Target locked.
Cover up! Cover up!
Come on!
Fast...
Anna.. southern side.. In the bunker..
this way.
I survived.
I came back to India.
But my job was
still incomplete.
Bala. I knew he was the leak.
But I needed concrete evidence.
What happened, Vikram?
Those faces,
those killings..
Something doesn't
seem right, Ruby.
Just let go.
As per the latest news received
LTF leader Anna is dead.
The news of Anna's death
spread like wild fire.
The whole island was in shock.
The whole world believed us.
And we too, believed
that our job was done.
Long live Mallaya!
Our leader Mallaya.
Mallaya declared himself
as the new leader of LTF.
But..
Anna was alive.
Why did you do this?
No one can betray our ELAM.
And now, it was
impossible to stop Anna.
He became the undisputed leader
of North-East Sri Lanka.
And now much more ferocious.
Prime Minister has
resigned today.
Due to an unexpected
development this morning..
..he took this step under
political pressure.
Because of the change in
the political scenario...
...in Delhi, PM resigned.
A week after the new
government came into power..
..our army was called
back from Lanka.
This was a victory for Anna,
against the world's fourth
largest military force.
From here on began the
grand conspiracy.
The final assassination plot.
So, is this the reason why
we lost our Prime Minister?
Fresh elections were announced
a year after his resignation.
During the election campaign,
at a press conference..
..ex-prime minister...
..announced his political
agenda for the next elections.
Tamil 'cause be an important issue
for you this time as well?
If we do come into power,
apart from economic growth..
...Tamil 'cause will be an
important issue for me.
That there is Peace
in the island.
That the Tamilians
should get their rights.
This is what we will aim for.
Peace in the island.
Tamilians should
get their rights.
This is what we will aim for.
My stand is clear. I want a
peaceful political solution.
A month after this speech,
our Madras Desk and
South-East Naval force..
..intercepted some
coded messages.
Reed, the meeting is fixed.
And perhaps from here on that the
grand conspiracy began took shape.
Guruji...
We need to act and this
is the perfect time.
You fix up the meeting.
You just wait there. I'll
tell you what. Okay.
Speak! a...
What is it?
Sir, these are the
Intercepts of last few days.
I've collected some from
the Naval intelligence.
Sir, since From the past few
days this the wireless chatter..
...between London, Jaffna and Singapore
has seems to have increased, sir.
Yes, it's okay. It's routine.
You may leave.
No, sir. One of the speakers
voices is that of Anna's.
Look, I'll see look into what's
important or what's not, in it.
But doesn't this sound
seem quite serious?
Go. Leave.
Listen, you're doing a good job.
Keep me in the loop.
Okay, sir.
Hello? Hello?
Vikram's residence, sir.
The file is missing.
Sir, spool..
Bloody hell..
They are both in Cochin.
Send your men there.
Hello?
Hello, Ruby?
Where are you, Vikram?
Why?
These pictures and articles..
Something is just not right.
Whom do you work for?
Listen, don't worry.
I'm coming home.
Don't open the door for anyone.
Okay?
Ruby!
Ruby...
Whom do you work for?
We aren't safe here.
In your absence our house is under
surveillance in your absence.
We're shifting to Delhi.
I'm being shadowed.
Trust me, we have to move on.
That's not the answer, Vikram.
These pictures, these killings, these
articles, the foreign journalist..
This is not army.
You killed civilians?
These killings are
political killings.
Jaya, she is a
foreign journalist.
Trust me, this is a setup.
I can explain this..
You jerk.
All these days, you lied to me.
Ruby, I do covert operations.
I monitor political and military
developments of different countries.
This country's security
is my responsibility.
We have been married for three years.
I know there is a responsibility.
But there is a protocol.
But I am not a..
I don't care about your
protocol, alright!
I'm your wife, damn it!
I have a right to know.
What about me..
How do I deal with all this?
Sri Lanka..
Your life was constantly
under threat there.
Do you have any idea
how I survived?
And today I got petrified, Vikram.
Sweetheart..
Just leave me alone.
Ru..
Ruby...
Hello?
Boss, SP.
I'm in Cochin.
We should need to meet.
It's urgent.
Right away?
Sorry, sir.
I don't have much time.
We'll talk when we meet.
At seven. Beach cafe.
Okay.
Ruby..
I know you have to go. Just go.
Hello, boss.
Something really seems to
be out of order in Madras.
A lot of intercepts and wireless
messages are being exchanged.
From Jaffna to London.
Madras, Singapore.
And One of the voices is
that of speakers is Anna's.
I've decoded some keywords.
Like.
Foreign friend. Negotiate. Middle-east.
Does Bala know?
Yes, I've shared them with him.
But he asked me not to
file or decode them.
And His behavior has
really scared me, boss.
I feel you are not
safe here either.
What should I do next?
Just stay safe.
I'll see what I can do.
Ruby...
Ruby! Ruby!
Ruby!
Why her?
Why?
Vikram..
I'm sorry.
Your loss..
What should I say?
Tough times.
You know my wife and my
children keep asking me:
"Why do you do this?"
"There's a lot of danger.
Your Life's always at risk."
How do I explain to them that our
country is surrounded by vultures?
We need to protect it...
How much will they understand?
That's why I don't say anything.
Vikram, you need to bounce back.
Anyway, you are not safe here.
I'm not safe anywhere, sir.
You cannot give up on
the system so soon!
System!
We Which we know it inside out!
I need you.
We've got your intercepts.
They are being decoded.
And what you've said about Bala
I hope you are right about Bala.
God forbid if you are wrong,
you'll be in great risk.
It's a big accusation.
I know, sir. I need
to sort this out.
If you don't start begin
surveillance in the next 24 hours..
...then I'll get the
evidence myself.
And I'll do it my way.
Sir.
We've got a fix on
Vasu's location.
He's constantly
shifting his base.
And But his last call was
traced to old Delhi.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
Get down! Get down!
Get down!
Bala recruited you for the agency
from the Jammu district jail.
Information was leaked
from our system.
They knew our
operational details.
What do you know?
You'll have to speak up, Vasu.
You know the consequences.
I just photocopied the files.
For whom?
I don't know.
My job was to drop them
to at the airport.
Bala sir's instructions.
And Shree's Shri's arms deal?
We lost a our man.
You were there as well.
Reverse the car.
Who informed the LTF?
You?
I've told you.
I just followed instructions.
What happened that night?
What happened on the night SP
brought the intercepts, Vasu?
That was the first time I saw
Bala sir getting panicked.
The file is missing!
He held me by my collar.
He was very nervous.
Why?
Don't worry. Those
intercepts are with me.
Your department
is moving along..
A few of his intercepts
were stolen.
He doubted suspected SP.
So he asked me to tail SP.
And?
He got a call from Singapore.
From?
Some Reed.
You just make sure those
intercepts do not reach anyone.
I've never seen him.
He used to call.
A foreign agency guy met
with an Indian official.
Did Bala know what did
those intercepts contain?
No.
Those intercepts
weren't decoded.
Where is SP now?
I don't know.
Who sent you to Delhi?
Bala sir asked me to...
...disappear from Madras safe
house after your incident.
And Who gave the orders...
...to kill me and SP?
Vasu..
While following orders from
Bala did you ever realize..
...that you'll be such a
disgrace for the system?
Such a shame.
Hello? Yes, you
want to speak to?
Jaya Sahni, please.
Jaya Sahni? And you're calling from?
India.
One moment please.
I understand, ma. Don't worry.
I'm fine.
I'll call you back.
Call from India.
Hello?
Hi, Jaya.
Hi.
How are you?
Jaya, I need your help.
I told you, Vikram.
I won't be able to help you.
I can't give you my sources.
All our intels
have been leaked..
To this guy called Reed.
So, it was one of your guys.
Yes.
And he is a national threat.
So what do you want from me?
I need evidence.
That's why, I need your sources.
Okay.
I'll call you back.
Thanks, Jaya.
And, Vikram, I'm really,
really sorry about your wife.
Thank you.
Reed, you your man
Bala is a risk for us.
His cover is blown and
he's being tracked.
You want me to lose him?
Yes.
Right.
Okay, Vikram. Reach Bangkok.
Take Taxi No. 5892.
He will take you to
Happyland fish market.
Ask for Shop No. 29.
My source will meet you there.
This way to shop no. 29
That way.
So you are Vikram?
And You need evidence?
Yes.
You are in the right direction.
According to my source there is a
tape and we'll get it by five.
Since when have you
been tracking Bala?
Before and after I retired a
lot of activity took place..
...between Madras,
Jaffna and Singapore.
I did some surveillance.
I reported it as well.
But I didn't have
concrete evidence.
When I found out that you're
investigating the case,
I agreed to meet you.
Vikram, you are very
close to reality.
Who is Reed?
I don't know.
It could be anyone.
Maybe a faceless handler.
Apart from there this...
...a lot of other activities took place
that too raise arouse suspicion.
Look at this.
Rajsekharan at Madras Café!
Yes. The meeting took
place in Singapore.
Two meetings took place there.
In the second meeting
Rajsekharan was introduced.
He was representing Anna.
So you need our support?
It means that developments of...
...that meeting changed
the whole politics.
Yes. Do you remember
the date of arms deal?
6th July. I was there.
This meeting took place
on the 2nd July.
Exactly four days
before the arms deal.
Gifts are on the way
from Singapore.
Be sure they reach
our new friends.
Don't worry, Reed. My
man will be there.
That's why the arms which
were meant to go to Shree..
...and after those
instructions, went to Anna.
Right.
Hey hurry up, common..
And perhaps Anna
found a new partner.
Who are these people?
Corporations, big countries,
big organizations.
Who seek They need
economic control,
business deals, large
arms contracts..
And Their executors are
ex-agency employees.
They are called economic hitmen.
Who are these people?
Where do they meet?
No one knows.
Remember, Vikram, India is
the fastest growing market.
India is the future.
That's why an attempt
there is to...
...pressure pressurize her
from everywhere all corners.
This is the modern day warfare.
That's why Trincomalee dock.
This Lankan coastline is
so strategic for everyone.
Yes. And that's why they
are supporting Anna...
...if Anna comes to power...
...then they will
gain control...
...over entire South East
Asia via Trincomalee Dock
...and that would a
national threat for India.
That's the reason why ex-PM
is not so popular with them.
He doesn't want war.
He wants a peaceful
political solution.
And that's why Anna.
Anna is an idealist.
And He'll he will continue the
war till he doesn't get freedom.
And they will exploit this.
Wait here.
Okay.
Package please.
Your evidence. Let's go.
Nasal.
Ilpa.
Pal.
Ant.
What have we got?
They are possibly discussing an
assassination of a national leader.
Sir, the intercepts. Two
of them have been decoded.
Have you informed RD?
Not yet, sir. I was
waiting for you.
Bala?
So they trapped him.
Honeytrap.
Oldest trick of the intel world.
I, too, doubted Had my
doubts about him but this..
So they exposed Bala.
Perhaps Bala had become
useless for them.
The And they either eliminate
or expose the useless.
This is how our world works.
This better be good.
This is serious, sir.
The intercepts we got from
Vikram have been decoded.
You better see it.
Sir, that's Anna's voice.
It originated from his camp.
The words, sir.
Garland. Important. Leader.
They are going for the
ex-prime minister.
Get me Vikram. ASAP.
Sir, there's one more thing.
Bala's surveillance report.
Bank accounts.
Income worth thousands of
dollars from unknown accounts.
Five fake passports. Eight
tickets to Singapore.
Everyone perceives the
truth differently.
It depends on where you
are choose to stand.
Remember, my friend. This
meeting never happened.
Bala, your tape has been
released, you must leave now..
Sir, I have evidence.
He was honey-trapped.
He compromised everything.
I believe they blackmailed him.
Yes, Vikram.
We, too, know about his
secret bank accounts..
...fake passports
and travel details.
He didn't just sell us out. He
sold out the entire country.
Now you let the
department handle him.
But you Come back
here immediately.
The intercepts between Jaffna
and Madras have been decoded.
There's There is a plot
to assassinate the ex-PM.
This is a serious threat
and we need to move fast.
You are drinking too much.
Are you okay?
You Go to sleep.
Don't worry about me.
Bala.
Why did you do this?
Why?
And my wife?
What was her fault?
It wasn't her fault.
That was a mistake.
You were the target,
but you survived.
You're lucky.
And the second arms deal?
My kidnapping?
You were behind it, Bala?
I have information that two
meetings took place in Singapore.
Where Rajsekharan
represented Anna.
It's obviously a
well-designed plan.
Here's a copy of decoded
intercepts for you.
We've very little time.
Brief your best team.
Find out, where is it
this going to take place,
who all are involved?
Who? How? What? When? Where?
I need all the information.
And Vikram..
Sir.
He is no longer the
prime minister.
He's out of power.
It won't be so easy to operate.
Keep that in mind.
We need solid evidence.
Okay! Guys
Ghosh, first code.
Between Jaffna and London.
Anna is instructing Rajsekharan.
It has no meaning.
Gibberish, right?
But if we reverse these words..
Tamil words, sir.
And Their English translation:
Tooth.
Ant.
Lizard.
Kangaroo.
First letter of each
word, TALK, talk.
This is how we decoded all
the intercepts and we got..
Talk foreign friend,
mutually beneficial deal.
From where was this generated?
Jaffna to London.
Anna and Rajsekharan.
Second code, quick.
Right.
Don't leave home.
We need to garland
an important prince.
Here, home means Madras.
And important prince, what we
guess, is our ex-prime minister.
From Jaffna to Madras.
In Jaffna we can hear.
Anna and Pandyan.
In Madras.
The call was made to a PCO in Madras.
We still haven't been able
to track the receiver.
But we're on it.
Activate Saba in Jaffna.
Rishi, you take charge of the South.
Right, sir.
Saba here, sir.
I've found an important link.
You sure about the link? Will
he provide us with information?
What if like last time...
No, sir. He's agreed to talk.
Okay. Where?
Sir, you'll have
to come to Jaffna.
Jaffna?
Okay. Keep him on surveillance
I'll be there by tomorrow.
His name is Selvam...
Go on.
He's scared, sir.
He hasn't left his
home since 15 days.
LTF is looking for him.
He was a part of the hit squad.
But he doesn't wish to die.
He said he doesn't
want to be a martyr.
Come. Sir.
You promised me you will save me.
Come on.
Speak up. What do you know?
I don't want to die.
Sir, I want to get
out of Jaffna.
Sir, you promised me
you will save me.
Listen to what he is saying.
What happened? Why
did you run away?
They said we will attack.
I didn't join the
movement for that.
Then?
People were selected
and trained.
How many?
Six different teams
for different cities.
Each team consisted
of five people.
Where are they?
I don't know.
They Left from the camp.
Did they tell you
who the target is?
I don't know, sir.
Sir!
You are lying.
They will kill me. You
said you would save me.
He says LTF will kill him.
Sir, save me sir..
How many people does
each hit squad contain?
Each contains 4 or 5 people.
6-7 different teams.
They left Jaffna a week back.
Where to?
We don't know.
Multiple cities.
But one team has definitely
landed in Tamil Nadu.
Okay, sir. 'He has started south
election campaign for South from today.
And he said that Tamil 'cause
will be his priority.
And he assured the people that..'
It's code red.
Issue high alert.
Ask them to seal the coastline.
Inform the naval intel
and the coastguards.
Ask them to hit any suspicious
activity in the sea.
Green light to tower one.
Confirm location.
Four knots enemy suspect.
Three fishermen boats.
Investigate. Over.
And crack down.
Let's go.
Capture every known LTF
person, sympathizer.
Those who have surrendered.
Everyone.
Get on to each damn one of them.
Now.
Today morning, in different
parts of South lndia..
Get them in the car.
Elhelocalpofice and
security agencies...
..took around 50 suspected
LTF rebels into custody.
It's believed that...
...the reason behind this is
the forthcoming elections.
Come on, backseat.
Get in!
Sir, did you get the photographs?
Yes.
He's This is Kanda.
LTF's sympathizers.
He's He is the one who received
Anna's second code from Jaffna.
But He's missing as of now.
And about the other one?
The one in on the
right is Kanankanan.
We caught him during the crackdown.
He's in Madurai jail.
We can get some
information from him.
When did you come to India?
Six months back.
He's Kanda.
How do you know him?
Sir, He's he is LTF's
local contact here.
He provides legal
help to refugees.
Passport, ration card.
He gave helped me one too.
I've been working
for him since then.
Where is Kanda now?
I don't know, sir. Since
I'm I have been in prison.
Lying?
No, sir.
One of LTF's seniors
came here some time ago.
Yes, Rajsekharan.
He came by a boat? From Jaffna?
No, sir. I and Kanda sir and I
picked him up from the airport.
Where was he coming from?
London.
Then what happened?
I'll set you up here for
the lifetime make...
...this your permanent residence.
Got it?
After he came here they had a
discussion at the farmhouse.
A discussion about
some assassination.
Whose assassination?
I don't know.
But Rajsekharan was
very angry that night.
Kanda sir asked me
to leave after that.
Then you know about the LTF groups
that came here a few days ago.
What do you know about it?
I was instructed to
pick up the refugees.
I thought they are
regular refugees.
But this time Kanda sir
personally received them.
Do you know them?
They weren't refugees.
They looked different.
Where did you drop them?
Beach road.
House No. 33.
Where are they now?
I don't know.
Hello, Vikram? It's Jaya.
Rajsekharan was
traced in London.
He holds four to five passports
under different names.
So in London, he did have a
crucial meeting in Madras café.
And there were others with him.
Who all?
No idea.
But I actually called
for something else.
It's really, really important
and you need to know this.
But I can't tell you
over the phone.
Fax?
No.
I need to see you in person.
I'm coming to New
Delhi, day after.
We'll meet day after tomorrow.
Hotel Imperial, at 9:00pm.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
A few people came
here some days ago.
How many?
2-3 people.
They bought a lot of
industrial chemicals.
Something normal people
usually don't buy.
From where had they come?
I don't know.
But they weren't locals.
Let me know if you
find anything else.
Okay, sir.
Exile Rama coming home,
lets celebrate Deepavali.
Sorry, sir, for
calling this late.
But we've intercepted
another wireless.
Between Jaffna and Madras.
What is it?
Sir, it goes
something like this.
Celebrate Diwali Ex-PM..
Diwali.. Ex-PM..
EX-PM..
Anything unusual?
I don't know, sir.
Perhaps they are
reconfirming the target.
Okay. Find out. Keep me informed.
Right, sir.
When do you think we
can have the delivery.
My contact will get
in touch with you.
What did you find, Arjun?
Sir, check this.
Whose call is it?
Vijayan. Vijayan Joseph.
Hello, sir.
Yes, Rishi?
Sir, we've traced
Vijayan's call.
From where?
What's the source?
Street one. Maduria. Mylapore.
MWapore.
Connect to Delhi.
Yeah.
Connect Madras.
Right, sir.
Delhi connected, sir.
Sir, Delhi connected.
Give me the details.
Sir, Madras connected.
Sir, picking up and delivery.
Sir, they are talking
about some delivery.
Call has been traced to?
Jaffna, sir.
Call has been traced
to Jaffna, sir.
Sir, Vijayan is the one
who came from Germany.
He's a bombmaker.
Number tracked, sir.
Fine. I'll be there by tomorrow.
Okay, sir.
That's Rajsekharan, at
Madras Café, London.
Look at this.
I couldn't share this
with you over the phone.
I don't think there's much time.
Four days back, this amount was
transferred into the LTF account.
This means this is the
final confirmation?
For any job,
money is the final confirmation.
Where did you get this from?
I was investigating these banks.
And realized such banks
only exist on paper.
They remain for a few
days, months and then,
they just disappear.
So, first the speech
by the ex-PM.
Then Rajsekharan goes
to Madras Café, London.
And that's where possibly
things happened.
Anna, he's coming
back to power.
He will not let us
do what we want.
He'll demand a
political solution.
Now we will only have to act.
Does anyone else know
that you are here?
No.
Abuda.
Does the jacket fit well?
Hope its not too tight?
No, its fine.
Okay. Okay.
Then we'll do the
rehearsal tonight.
Okay?
Okay.
Okay, Jaya.
So, what'll you do now, Vikram?
I don't know.
Be careful, Vikram.
Please proceed to Gate No. 3.
Security check begins
in ten minutes.
This is the final boarding
call for passengers of...
Flight No. 3728 to Kansas City.
Please proceed to Gate No.
3 immediately.
Security check will
begin in a while.
Hands up! Don't move.
Catch him!
Hands up! Don't move!
Stay : Stay down.
Sir, please!
Relax!
Sir, I'm not involved.
Go and check everywhere.
Yes, sir.
Check outside.
Come on.
Go!
Come on!
What were you thinking?
You'll make bombs here and your
family will stay safe in Germany?
This is your wife and
daughter, right?
Do you wish to see them alive?
Please, sir, do them no harm.
They are innocent.
What about the people
who live here?
What about them?
Whom did you supply
the explosives to?
I was hired.
I was told I'll be
paid well, sir.
I'm not a terrorist, sir.
I'm a chemical engineer.
I used to work in Germany.
I tested the
explosives in Germany.
I came to India
three months ago.
They supplied me with
the raw materials.
I just assembled it.
That's all, sir.
What did you assemble?
Plastic explosives.
First time in the world.
High quality explosives.
Rubber like material.
Advantage is that the metal
detectives can't detect it.
And kills it can kill everyone
anyone in the radius of 20-30 feet.
Where are they taking it?
How will they use it?
I don't know, sir.
It can happen anywhere
Delhi, Bombay, Madras. Anywhere.
When will they hit?
I don't know, sir.
While we are speaking, sir..
Can it be deactivated from here?
Somehow..
All the bombs? No. Not possible.
But my family, sir..
Ghosh, the third intercept?
Deepti?
Celebrate Diwali, Exile
Rama, coming home.
Get ex-PM's rally schedule.
Quick.
Right here, sir.
Excuse me, sir.
There's a technical
problem in the flight.
It'll take a bit longer.
How long?
About an hour.
Okay.
Sir, this last intercept is
between Jaffna and Madras.
Celebrate Diwali, Exile
Rama, coming home.
Sir, it has been decoded.
Exile.
Ex.
Rama... PM.
EX-PM.
His today's rally schedule.
10am.
Warrangal.
1:30pm. Vijaywada.
4:00pm. Hyderabad.
And 10:00pm Poothiyaddur.
What I want to say is, ex-PM.
X in roman is ten.
10:00pm.
Ex-PM. 10:00pm.
Poothiyaddur, 10:00pm.
You mean they are
striking tonight?
I think so, sir.
Where is he right now?
Hyderabad airport lounge, sir.
Oh God!
We can't take a chance.
We're already late.
We'll have to stop him.
Sir.
Get me Hyderabad airport.
All our intels are clearing stating
that LTF will target the ex-PM.
We've strong evidence.
First back switch,
then front switch.
Once more.
State governor went against
protocol and warned him.
That he shouldn't tour south.
No, I don't think LTF will
plan something this big. No.
First back switch,
then front switch.
We'll have to provide him with
full protection, at all cost.
Ex-PM or ex-minister, we
cannot provide NSG to anyone.
It is against the rules!
We cannot do it!
But if you insist, keeping
in mind the threat..
...we'll inform the state police.
They will look after it.
Fine. Whatever you deem fit.
Ghosh..
Sir.
Get me special access. I'm
about to reach the airport.
Now.
Okay, sir.
Good afternoon, sir. Robin Dutt.
I've a request to make, sir.
Kindly cancel your rallies for
today and for the next 2-3 days.
There's a threat. It will be
better if you avoid them.
You know I want to be with the
people for these elections.
There is security over there.
Yes, sir. It's there. But
it could be dangerous.
It's a request. Please
don't go there.
Sir, excuse me.
Pilot just informed. Flight
is ready for take off. Okay.
Robin, please don't worry.
I'll be fine. Okay?
He will be reaching
in ten minutes...
Everyone please co-operate
for the security check...
Please move behind
from the stage...
Ladies who will be garlanding,
please move to the front row.
Please maintain discipline...
...our leader will be
reaching in the next minutes.
Sir, here's the route map.
Rishi is already there.
Okay.
Vikram has reached. He's
on his way to the rally.
All units informed.
Routine scanning
is complete, sir.
Around 3000-3500 people.
He'll be here soon.
Keep checking, I'm coming.
Yes, sir.
Ex-PM has reached.
You're not allowed to go ahead!
We're sorry to inform you
that earlier tonight..
..lndia's former Prime
Minister was assassinated.
This dreadful blast
took place at 10:10pm.
He was in Poothiyaddur
district in South India,
to address an election rally.
In the south of India, this
sudden and tragic death..
..has left the whole nation
in a state of shock.
This is the first time a
human bomb has been used...
His unfortunate death has left
people in a state of shock.
The whole nation is mourning.
So far this blast has
claimed 25 people's lives,
and injured more
than 100 people.
A horrific blast took
place at 10:10pm.
This shocking incident has sent shock
waves across the entire nation.
Bringing the country to
a complete standstill.
The special investigation
squad has revealed..
..the use of plastic
explosives and RDX.
So far this blast has
claimed 25 people's lives,
and injured more
than 100 people.
They were those who
came to the rally...
...to support our
former prime minister.
Just like that.
What was his fault?
He was so young.
We tried.
But we lost.
President has requested
people to stay calm.
Leaders all across the world have
expressed their condolences.
After some time..'
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
The investigation team
arrested a few suspects.
And a few suspects committed suicide
before they could be arrested.
And I submitted my report to the
special investigation team.
This commission appreciates
your investigations.
And yes, we will consider them.
But, Mr. Vikram, we
need solid evidence.
I'd never realized that...
...the world is so threatened
by our Prime Minister.
RD sir resigned
after a few days.
I hope you've given this
decision of yours a thought.
Yes.
And I took a voluntary
retirement and came here.
Whatever you just said could
also be just a coincidence.
No, Father.
This conspiracy was played
out just as it was planned.
And I was late.
But I couldn't compete with him.
They were powerful.
And In this game we lost
our Prime Minister.
And the Lankan Tamils.
Their future.
Then who won?
I don't know.
Perhaps it was everyone's loss.
And Anna?
One man's revolutionary is
another man's terrorist.
Anna is revolutionary
for his people.
But I lost my Prime Minister.
What will you do now?
Ruby's father gave this to me...
...on our wedding day.
A wedding gift.
Where the mind is without fear
and the head is held high..
Where knowledge is free..
Where the world has not been
broken up into fragments..
By narrow domestic walls..
Where words come out from
the depth of truth..
Where tireless striving stretches
its arms towards perfection..
Where the clear stream of
reason has not lost its way..
Into the dreary desert
sand of dead habit..
Where the mind is led
forward by thee..
Into every-widening
thought and action..
Into that heaven of
freedom, my Father,
let my country awake..
Thank you.