I just missed your heart.
You are dead, right now.
I've killed you.
Use your hands.
Drag the deer back yourself.
What's wrong?
Are you hurt?
You were half asleep.
You must always be ready.
Even when you're sleeping.
Think on your feet.
- Adapt... - Or die.
I'll do better next time.
German.
Italian.
I'll do better next time.
Spanish.
Espanol.
Did you really want me to snap your neck?
How much did you pull off the deer?
In 120 parts.
200 pounds in total.
I think so.
That explains it.
What?
How you beat me.
You've getting stronger.
I'm glad you didn't snap my neck.
The great blue whale is the largest animal to have ever existed.
Its heart weighs 1300 pounds.
And the male has 7 gallons of...
testicles.
The blue whale's music can be heard for over five hundred miles...
A blue whale's tongue weighs over two and a half tons.
What does music feel like?
Music- a combination of sounds
with a view to beauty of form and expression of emotion.
I want to hear it for myself.
We've all we need right here.
It's not enough.
I'm ready.
Papa, I'm ready.
1  2  3  4  5  6
One, two, three, four, five, six.
I live in Leipzig German city.
Population: 0.7 million peoples.
Tell me again.
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Stra¦Âe,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Stra¦Âe,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
I like literature and sport.
In particular, tennis and athletics.
We live at number 7, Vicenza Platz.
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
I also have a dog called Trudy.
I'm ready.
I'm ready now.
3  4  5  6
Three, four, five, six.
Did you see it? Did you hear it?
It's like thunder! It was so beautiful!
What is it?
It tells Marissa Wiegler where we are.
If you think you're ready, and you want to leave here,
all you have to do is flip that switch.
But once it's done there's no going back.
She won't stop until you're dead, or she is.
You understand?
I won't be there to hold your hand.
So be sure.
Be sure it's what you really want.
It's here. There's no rush.
Laika, a mongrel dog from the street of Moscow,
was the first animal to orbit the Earth.
She was launched into outer space on the third of November, 1957.
Scientists believe humans
would be unable to survive the conditions of outer space.
So flights by animals were used
as experiments precursory to human missions.
A rocket was not designed to be retrievable,
and Laika has always been, intended to die.
But she didn't, did she?
They couldn't bring the rocket back, remember?
I remember.
But sometimes I wish you would read it differently.
When a star collapses,
the supernova explosion is ten billion times
brighter than the other stars.
Will you hunt with me?
If you want.
Well, it's up to you.
- Me? - Yes.
I'll stay.
Yes, good.
Marissa Wiegler...
come and find me.
You were lucky to have caught that deer.
There was nothing out there today.
The smell's good.
When will it be ready?
Soon.
We've picked up an unencrypted signal. One of ours.
- When? - 0632 Eastern Standard.
Triangulated about 60 miles below the Arctic Circle.
Near Kazuma.
We think it is Erik Heller.
- Erik Heller? - You're his handler, right?
Sure, the name sounds familiar.
Fuck Erik.
Why now?
How does it look?
Good...
Almost good.
Erik Heller, recruited in 1991.
Formal FSK operative.
He became integral to our counter Intelligence Ops
in Eastern europe and Central Asia.
His file ends in '94.
There was no sign of life until April 18, 1996,
when his fingerprints were found on a 22 calibre ruger,
found beside body of one, Johanna Zadek.
Johanna Zadek, born in 1970, German.
She was spotted and developed by Heller in 1994.
- Never recruited. - Why was she being developed?
That's not in the file. Let's keep on the past.
Heller is a rogue asset.
I propose we go and pull him out.
We got bigger problems, Marissa.
Let Interpol pick him up.
He's no longer our responsibility.
Interpol nabs him,
that exposes him to BND, FSB, France.
Do you really want every intelligence agency
in Europe scratching at this threat?
- Lewis? - I'm sorry,
but we need to keep this contained, gentlemen.
Keep it small. I've worked with this man.
He knows things I don't think you wanna know.
I appreciate your candor.
What do you need Lewis?
One man, one-day operation.
- Tell me again. - Marissa Wiegler.
- Then? - Postcard.
- Then? - What?
The address where we meet.
Wilhelm Grimm House, Stefan Stra¦Âe,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
- Then what else? - Adapt or die.
- Think on your feet... - Even when I'm sleeping.
Papa.
Remember what I taught you and you will be fine.
I'll see you there.
Macalahan, do you read me?
Macalahan.
Go, go, go.
Erik Heller escaped.
How did that happen?
Unclear. We think he got away in the snow storm or...
And something bigger than that I can manage.
One man, one day of operations.
Just find him, lewis.
Find him and bring him to me.
There was a kid. Things got out of our control!
Wiegler?
Wiegler, are you there?
Where is she now?
Hello, Hanna.
Hello.
My name is Dr. Burton. Would you like to talk to me?
I was told by my father to gain the upper hand.
That's very interesting.
What else did your father tell you?
Where am I?
You are in holding.
I've never been in a room like this.
Must all be very strange for you.
How long have you been in the forest?
Hanna?
- Are those cameras? - Uhuh.
They're taking our pictures right now,
to keep a record.
How does that make you feel?
Camera obscure...
It's Latin, for dark chamber.
It was first described by the Arabic scientist
Ibn al-Haytham in the year 1021.
Plug the cctv through to Langley.
Hey, you should have a visual on the psych evaluation there.
Can I get you something? What do you like?
Music, magazines.
Just ask, anything.
I want to speak to Marissa Wiegler.
- Tell her I'll be there tonight. - I can handle this.
Just do what you're told.
John, take a look at this kid's blood sample.
- Is that right? - Is it?
- Can't be right. - Got a sample of her hair.
Must be contaminated. Run it again.
My name is Marissa Wiegler.
You wanted to speak with me?
You can wait outside.
Where am I?
You are in a safe place, sweetie.
Where did you meet my father?
Erik.
You mean Erik?
Yes.
I met him by a news kiosk at Alexander Platz. East Berlin.
I met him at a news kiosk,
- Alexander Platz... - Say it was raining.
in the rain.
He'd just arrived from Prague.
You know where your father is?
Did he tell you where he was going?
We are worried about him.
It's okay.
Agent, keep your distance.
Do you want me to give her something?
I think that might be necessary.
Abort.
Open up.
I repeat, agent, abort!
Wiegler!
I want everyone here now.
Do not let it escape from the gallery.
- Do you think she got out? - She can't get out.
Detail every unit available.
Mama.
She will never be yours.
Hey, hello.
Don't you speak English?
It's not your fault if you can't.
Emma Ackery couldn't speak English until she was eight,
because she was like, a refugee or something from Sri Lanka.
But now she's a pop star, in America too.
So don't worry if you can't speak English yet.
Who's she?
I found her, she can't speak English.
She's from Sri Lanka.
I'm from Germany.
I live in Leipzig. Population: 0.7 million peoples.
We live at No. 7 Vicenza Platz.
I like literature and sport,
in particular tennis and athletics.
I go to school at The Klaus College Gymnasium.
And my best friends are Rudy Gunter and Clara Scheitz.
They sound fun.
I also have a dog called Trudy.
We had a dog called Vincent,
but he went mad and died.
Sophie, come on.
See ya.
I'm Sophie and that is my brother, Miles.
I am...Hanna.
Do you need a lift somewhere?
No. I prefer to walk.
Suit yourself.
Sophie, come on, we are all waiting for you.
Tacticle says she's in the desert,
south east of vessel we're in.
Focus all operations on Heller.
Are you saying the girl's not of interest to us?
Yes, of course she's of interest, Lewis.
But not an immediate threat
to the security of the United States of America.
Erik Heller is the immediate threat. Focus on Heller.
Where is your family?
- Are you Arabic? - I am Moroccan.
Morocco. Capital city: Rabat.
Places of interest: Marrakech, Essaouira.
Religion: Islam. Language: Arabic.
I like Arabic very much.
It's like Japanese, it's big.
You speak Arabic?
Yes, of course.
Where is your family?
I need a room for the night.
Can you help? I have no money.
It's the best we've got.
Thank you.
Do you have one of these in every room?
All the rooms are the same.
It's electricity.
Of course, all mod cons.
I know a little about electricity.
They say Edison invented it.
Or was it Franklin?
Some American I'm sure.
This is an electrical kettle.
It's for the English.
They like to make their own tea.
What is it?
It's the best we can do.
Where do you come from?
The forest.
It's the German girl.
It's Kraut in a big Djellaba.
Like quail or lesbo.
I think I'd quite like to be lesbian.
But not one of those fat ones, one who's like, a supermodel.
But who don't hold hands, and I think I'd probably marry a man.
What?
No kiss?
She's a bit old for you, isn't she?
She has male and female genetalias.
And you love her just the way she is.
I like to give people what they want.
Vera, make my friend something sweet.
I'll save it for when I need it.
What do you want, Marissa?
Erik Heller's still alive.
Of course.
And the girl.
Why are you here precisely?
I need you.
You need me? Little old me! I'm very flattered.
I need your talents, darling.
I need you to do things
my agency will not let me do.
Stop!
Again.
Start again.
The devil is in the details, isn't it?
It's the girl or Erik?
She is in Morocco.
It's all in the envelope.
Let me worry about Erik.
Shall I kill her?
Just find her.
Marissa.
Did she turn out as you hoped?
Better.
Once more.
Again.
...and gave me lots of advices
about how to spend these money do these taxes.
You see even though she is beautiful,
she is actually brilliant with money.
Get off.
Like for one of the anniversary, he said his 15 grand,
for a Hermes kelly bag or a boob job.
Now she said she knew that the
boob implant will have to be replaced every 10 years.
But that the Hermes kelly bag never depreciates in value.
That's enough for the boob job.
I mean that's not just common sense.
And that's why I really love her.
Mum is against plastic surgery.
- I am. - Mum doesn't even wear make-up.
I don't. I think it's dishonest.
This is my face, take it or leave it.
If you study History of Art, Anthropology...
Rachel got a first at Cambridge.
you'll learn that red lipstick mimics arousal
and suggests the geography of the labia minora.
- Puke! - Where as I have a lot of natural red pigments
in my lips and so I really don't need it.
- Vomitory - Sophie!
- It's embarrassing. - Just grow up! All right?
- Grow up? - Yeah
Oh, because yesterday mum was saying
how I shouldn't act beyond my years.
No, it does leave her with mixed messages, darling.
Because we're trying to
communicate to her how to enjoy childhood.
I just want her to stop saying vomitory, all right?
Oi, It's not funny.
So, Hanna. Hanna?
I'm quite impressed about you traveling around on your own.
My father encourages me to be independent.
You see, that's wonderful.
I was back packing at your age.
And where is he, your father?
I spent a heavenly summer, just island hopping around Greece.
Island hopping around Greece!
What? No. It's valuable.
Our experience makes us who we are.
Isn't that right, kids?
So Hanna, is your mum and dad still together?
My mother is dead.
Nice one, dad!
I'm sorry to hear that. I lost my mum when I was very young, so...
It's all right. It happened a long time ago.
Hanna,
what did your mum die of?
Three bullets.
Oh my god, That's appalling!
Combination of sounds
with a view to beauty of form
and expression of emotion..
"Abnormal."
What happen if it rains?
Well, you going to get wet. Aren't you?
Because someone broke the sunroof.
- The thing is me and your mother are... - Your mother and I...
The thing is me and your mother, your mother and I
are responsible adults... not as you two.
My fungus nail infection's back.
Who are you?
What do you want from the girl?
I am her uncle.
We are very concerned about her.
I don't know what you're looking for.
She came, she was nice, she left.
Bingo!
Voila!
The van has checked out?
Today.
North or south?
The ferry. They caugh the ferry to Spain.
Can you lend me your pen?
I've contacted Interpol.
On whose authority?
Walt. We can't keep this to ourselves anymore.
- Were you not listening? - He killed two policemen.
He's reframed the situation. It is out of our control.
Then we must regain control, Mr. Lewis.
I am the first and the last person Erik Heller will see.
Are we clear?
- Mr. Lewis? - Yes, madam.
Oh, my god! What are you doing here?
The sunroof, was it you?
Would it be very bad if it was?
You mean you were in the van, the whole time?
My dad would have a heart attack if he found out.
- Will you have to tell him? - Hanna, you are so mental!
Of course I'm not going to tell him.
I think it's brilliant.
- Have you got anywhere to stay? - No.
Yes, you do. You're staying with me.
I am?
Yeah, obviously.
I'm sneaking you in, on one condition.
What?
These boys. Spanish. Gorgeous.
No, don't look. Don't go all pruny about it, like footballers.
Haven't got their eyebrows waxed, or anything!
- Good. - Anyway, we're going out tonight and you have to come.
- All right. -God, you're not hard to convince! Perv.
Who?
Have you got anything to wear?
You can't wear those, you look like some mad German.
Are you scared?
Of what?
Are we going to kiss now?
Would you like to?
Kissing requires a total of 34 facial muscles
and 112 postural muscles.
The most important muscle involved
is the orbicularis oris muscle,
because it is used to pucker the lips.
Hanna, you mentalist!
Please tell your friend I wanted just a kiss.
Hanna!
- Should I let him go? - As opposed to what?
Yes, you should let him go!
I'm going to go now.
Okay.
It was nice.
Sophie, is that you?
It is the sandman.
Go to sleep.
Oh, my god. You acted like a bandit. It's embarrassing.
- Like what? - Oh, I can't believe you.
Hello, mama.
I know you're disappointed in me.
I know it. I am very sorry, Mama.
But... But maybe I've found a way to make it better.
I'm in a programme now.
A programme to make babies stronger.
It's an American programme, very scien...
How did you get into my house, Mrs. Wiegler?
I'm looking for Erik.
He said you were dead.
So you've seen him?
He sent word.
Where is Hanna?
Did you ever have children of your own?
I made certain choices.
Then you will never understand
what it is like to lose your child,
to not know what happened.
The years of waiting,
of watching from the window.
And waiting...
Waiting...
Have you seen her?
Hanna!
Can you tell me what she looks like?
Like her mother.
- Hanna? - Yes.
Where do you really come from?
Leipzig. I live in Leipzig.
If we're going to be friends,
you're going to have to be honest with me.
Those are the rules.
- Are we friends? - Yes.
I like you.
I'd like to have a friend.
I mean, you're a freak and everything, but I like you.
I like you too. I really do.
But.
There are things I can't tell you.
- Do you understand? - Yes
Actually, no, I don't.
There are peoples that want to harm me.
- Bad peoples. - I see.
- And they won't stop. - Right.
So, for your own safety.
Can we still be friends?
I don't know.
I mean I don't really know who you are, do I?
That's just it.
Neither do I.
- What is it? - It's something about me.
I know what DNA means, but I don't understand the rest of it.
- Are you sick? - I don't feel sick.
- What's wrong with you? - Nothing's wrong with me.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to Berlin.
I have to meet meet my father at the House of Wilhelm Grimm.
From Grimms fairy tales?
That's right.
If you say so.
Did I say the wrong thing again?
Keep this.
To remember me.
It's a friendship bracelet.
Thank you.
Where's Hanna?
Wow, you look rough! Do want some tea?
I had some. Who's Hanna?
The girl we ate dinner with in Morocco.
She's here, or was. She came out with me last night.
How did she get here? Is she with her father?
No, she came on her own.
What?
Look, other people have their own style of parenting.
He's promoting independence.
She's like an orphan! Call me conservative.
- Are you really conservative, darling? - No, I'm not.
I said we'll give her a lift to Lyon.
We are going to Lyon, aren't we?
I found breakfast.
That's gross!
We've got him! We have Heller.
Do you read me? Bring him to Wiegler.
She will id an interview.
Is that what she said?
Confirmed with her two minutes ago.
Marissa, damn it!
I feel so grounded in the countryside.
The city stifles me,
emotionally, creatively, spiritually.
Places like this bring us closer to God.
God?
Well, not any modernistic sense.
Buddha, Krishna, the God within.
Whatever you believe in.
What do you believe in, Hanna?
Nothing.
Everything alright?
I think so.
I'm not sure if it's true that the baby can hear me,
but at night I feel her.
I hope she hears me.
Was it like this for you, mama?
I think I know what she looks like.
I can see her when I close my eyes.
I can hear her inside me. Movings.
Do you think is that silly? Oh, I think it's a girl.
I hope so.
Erik ...
What?
Oh for Christ's sake, Lewis.
Hello, Marissa.
I heard you were dead.
Did your little girl tell you that?
- What are you listening to? - Self help.
Are you in need of help?
It's good to hear you.
I didn't imagine we'd have the chance to talk.
You don't have her, do you? You're not that good.
Oh, Erik! You're such a flirt.
Tech's on the way.
You were a good agent, Erik.
Sad to see you go dumb.
What did I miss?
I couldn't do it anymore.
The things we did.
I... I'm sorry with Johanna.
With all of them. With Hanna.
So, why come back now?
Tech guys.
I asked you a question, Erik?
Erik, are you still there?
Move. Get up.
Shit ... shit ... shit ...
Hanna, I think we're lost.
- I have to pull over. - No, don't.
Can't see the map.
Have we stopped? I need to pee.
Don't want you going too far right now, love.
I think you should stay where you are, Sophie.
Hanna, what's going on?
Keep calm.
- Are we are in Lyon? - No, we're not.
Whatever you do, don't follow me!
Promise not to follow me.
I promise.
Thank you for being my friend.
Hanna!
Come on, come on!
Silence! Shut up!
Hanna.
Definitely odd. Disconnected.
You know, I like to think that I have a rapport with kids.
You know, I get with them.
You know, sir, it's days like this
that I really hate my job.
Yeah, I'm sure you do.
This is very, very difficult.
But sometimes children are bad people too.
- Stop crying. - I'm not telling you anything!
- Do you know this boy? - No!
He knows you. Your friend is in a lot of danger.
I don't know anything!
She said she lived in Leipzig.
She went to The Klaus College Gymnazium.
Her friends were Rudy and Gunter
She likes tennis and she has a dog named Trudy.
- She lied to you. - Absolutely.
She is not lost.
But she needed taken care of.
I've got something to show you.
- A little help from mom. - This is Hanna's mother.
Biological mother.
15 years ago, she was shot to death
by Hanna's father on a camping trip.
Don't you wanna see what's inside?
- Say "Please." - Please.
You like her, don't you?
It's okay. I won't tell anyone.
She's very pretty.
- Where is she? - You tell me.
Is she in lots of trouble?
The worst kind, sweetheart.
Some very bad men are looking for her,
and I need to find her. I wanna protect her.
Do you want her to get hurt?
No.
She's going to Berlin. To Wilhelm Grimm's house.
To meet her dad.
Hanna. Hanna ... Hanna come, come.
This way.
Been waiting for you a long time.
What did Erik told you about me?
Wilhelm Grimm's House Stefan Stra¦Âe,
21610559, Berlin, Germany.
That's it.
He didn't tell you of my magic.
Klaus, 09/05. Be there Tuesday. Erik.
- What day is it? - It's today, my dear.
Come, come.
Sit.
Oh, you're hungry.
- Waffles. - May I have one?
An egg? Of course.
You can eat whatever you want, my dear.
My shoe!
Oh, I've almost forgotten.
A present.
For me?
You will need a fresh photograph.
But everything's in order, yes?
Why do I need a piece of paper to tell me my name?
Not you, not you, my dear.
But everyone else we need paper and computers,
so we don't have to ask people their names
to look them in the face.
You have a good face.
You look just like your father.
And you walk like him too, uh uh uh.
I don't walk like that.
Yes, you do! You do, my dear! Uh uh.
Did you know my mother too?
Of course.
She was a singer. A wonderful singer.
Do you sing?
Papa.. Erik, didn't teach me.
Oh, you poor child.
He has truely limited you from all the wonderful things
the world has to offer.
No magic.
No music.
I'll teach you.
Is that him?
Upstairs with you, my dear. Quickly.
Good day.
We're closed, boys and girls.
Where is Erik?
He doesn't know much
or he is a very good liar.
He knew Johanna.
Yes, of course.
Bits and pieces about the programme.
What does he know about the girl?
He thinks Erik's the father.
- Everybody thinks Erik's the father. - That's precious!
Yes? This is Marissa Wiegler.
Walt, I didn't recog....
Lewis is dead.
Do you think it's important to tell us?
Why didn't you call us yet?
One man, one-day operation.
Yes. Yes. Yes! We all want Lewis.
He was shooting through the door, Walt.
No, I'm not standing down...
No, I'm interest..
Well, yes. That is time.
No, listen, Walt.
Heizinger.
So off to grandmother's house, we go.
Have you seen her?
Hanna!
Sit down.
Are you my father?
Sit down, Hanna.
- Are you my father? - Please, sit.
Are you?
Hanna, of course I'm your father.
- I raised you. - But Marissa said ...
- Hanna! - Don't lie to me!
I'm your father. I've been with you your whole life.
Treated you like my own flesh and blood.
But I was not your flesh and blood.
- I am abnormal? - No!
Where was I born?
Tell me the truth.
You were born in a research facility.
In rural Poland, Galinki.
What was the research?
They took fertilized embryos
and made small changes to them to improve them.
To reduce the capacity for fear, for pity,
to increase muscle strength,
heightened senses. Anything to make a better soldier.
The perfect soldier.
I've recruited your mother in an abortion clinic.
I've recruited twenty women the same way.
- There were other children? - Yes.
When you were two,
Marissa Wiegler, she closed the whole programme
and all of this research,
it was disposed of.
Do you understand?
I love you, Hanna. You have to know that.
Because I'm a freak?
No.
Because you are my child.
Where are you going?
Stop this.
Let me go!
Hanna! Hanna, please!
I tried to prepare you for what your life'd be.
You didn't prepare me for this.
Run!
Take it.
That's all you got?
Run, pig!
Why now, Erik?
Kids grow up.
Mr. Grimm!
Mr. Grimm.
Hanna
I'm here, Hanna.
Oh, don't worry sweetheart.
Don't! Don't move any closer!
Hanna, I can help you.
Please!
I don't want to hurt anyone anymore..
I just wanna talk.
It's over now, Marissa.
Let me go.
Hanna!
Don't walk away from me, young lady!
I just missed your heart