Live from the Dolby Theatre
in Hollywood and Highland,
it¡¯s the Oscars!
Ladies and Gentlemen,
please welcome your host,
Ellen DeGeneres!
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much.
Thank you very much. Thanks.
Thanks so much. Welcome to the Oscars.
For those of you watching around the world,
it has been a tough couple
of days f or us here.
It has been raining.
Were fine.
Thank you for your prayers.
Tm happy to be back.
I hosted seven years ago
and I¡¯m so honoured and flattered
that they have been back so quickly.
Things are so different now.
Last time, for instance, when I was here,
Cate Blanchett was nominated,
Meryl Streep was nominated,
Leonardo DiCaprio was nominated,
Martin Scorsese was nominated.
So different.
There are some first time nominees
here tonight.
June Squibb is nominated for Nebraska.
At 84 years old, she is the oldest nominee.
She was wonderful in ¡°Nebraska¡¯.
Tm telling everyone that
you were wonderful in Nebraska¡¯.
The film that you did ... wonderful.
We have other first time nominees.
Lupita Nyongo is here. Amazing.
anazing performance in
¡®12 Years a Slave¡¯.
She is from Kenya, she is a Kenyan.
Md Barkhard Abdi is here.
He is nominated for Captain Phillips.
He¡¯s from Somalia, he is a sommelier,
so he knows a lot about wine
and that is impressive.
Whos the wine captain now?
Whos the wine captain, now?
The real Captain Phillips is here tonight
and the real Philomena is here tonight.
Mdl have to say one of the most amazing
Liza Minnelli impersonators
lye ever seen in my entire life.
Just, really, seriously.
Good job, sir. I mean, that is really
thats
Tonights theme is Heroes in Hollood
and we need heroes now more than ever.
People around the world
are going through hard times
and movies offer us an escape.
Movies inspire us.
Tm not saying that movies
are the most important thing in the world
because we all know the most important
thing in the world is yooth.
Now, we know that the most important thing
in life is love
and friendship and family,
and if people don¡¯t have those things,
well, then,
they usually get into show business. So...
Here we all, were one big frightened family
is what we are,
but I want you to know that I love you
and I think ynure talented. I do.
Md I think you should think of yourselves
as winners.
Not all of you,
but the people who have won before
should think 0f yourselves as winners.
Mdl know what you¡¯re thinking:
Ellen, that¡¯s easy for yoo to say,
youve been chosen the host
and thats sort of the highest award
there is.
Thank you. Thank you.
But lets try to focus on you tonight,
if we can.
Seriously, the work that you¡¯ve done
is incredible,
and I did a little bit of research,
and between all of the nominees
here tonight,
youve made over 1400 films.
1400 films, and you¡¯ve gone to
a total 0f sio years of college.
I¡¯m kidding. Kids, stay in school.
I¡¯m sure these people went to college.
I mean, Amy Adams,
you went to college, right?
No.
Well ... who cares?!
You¡¯re an amazing actress.
You¡¯re in, not one, but two nominated films
tonight you were in.
That¡¯s just
That is so, what is the word for it
selfish, I guess.
I really do think its
an exceptional year for movies,
of course, one of the nominees is ¡®Her¡¯,
and by her, I mean Meryl Streep.
Meryl has been nominated
for an Oscar a total of 18 times.
Now it sounds good,
but if you do the math,
between dresses, hair and makeup,
that¡¯s hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Simply put, Meryl cannot
afford to be nominated again.
That is...a lot of money.
Tm listing all these people like
youre up against each other...
and ynure all so talented
I dont want you to think 0f
any kind of a competition.
Its a celebration.
PJthough who are we kidding?
Its the Hunger Games.
I mean there are cameras evernhere.
Ynure starving.
Jennifer Lawrence won last year.
It is the Hunger Games.
Jennifer, by the way,
I¡¯m not gonna bring up what happened
last year when you¡¯re...you know...
It¡¯s ridiculous, I mean, you...
something like that happens,
and it¡¯s embarrassing and then
people just talk about it and...
it¡¯s just, you know...
For those of you who don¡¯t know
whst I¡¯m talking about,
when Jennifer, last year,
she fell on the way up, tripped...
I dont know if you got caught
on the tip of the dress.
Lets just show the clip,
because what happened...
Tm kidding.
Tm not going to show the clip.
Tm kidding. lam.
I¡¯m not. I¡¯m not. But let¡¯s just...
Md you know, the thing,
when you fell out of the car tonight,
when youre getting out of the car,
no one needs to know that.
Tm not going to mention that...
she fell on the way out of the car.
Like on an orange cone...
you tripped or something.
If you win tonight, I think
we should bring you the Oscar.
I don¡¯t wanns risk...unless somebody...
We can do that, right?
Can we do that?
No ones here.
Win or lose, you look beautiful.
Oh you all look beautiful tonight.
Sandy you look beautiful and Cate
you look...eoerybody looks beautiful.
I¡¯m not going to say
who looks the most beautiful,
but it¡¯s clear, it¡¯s Jared Leto,
I mean he¡¯s the prettiest.
Boy, is he pretty? I mean,
he is nominated for
Best Supporting Actor,
and Matthew McConaughey,
also pretty, by the way,
but different, like a rugged dirty...
a dirty pretty. Like a rugged dirty pretty.
No, good dirty, not bad dirty.
Both nominated for Dallas Boyers Club,
a very important movie.
It deals with the serious issue of
people who have sex at rodeos.
Dont do it.
It looks appealing, but...uhh...
Speaking of sex at the rodeos,
Bruce Dern is here tonight.
I had a repeated transition.
I had no idea.
A little background on Bruce. His
grandfather was the governor of Utah.
His great uncle was a
Pulitzer prize¡ªwinning poet.
and his godmother was
Eleanor Roosevelt.
Md here you are amongst us tonight.
What went wrong?
Jonah Hill is nominated for his amazing
performance in Wolf of Wall Street.
That...
I honestly, I have to say,
you showed us something in that film...
that I have not seen
for a very very long time.
Do you get it?
Well we should get started.
Its gonna bean exciting night.
Mything can happen.
So many different possibilities.
Possibility No. 1,
12 Years a Slave wins Best Picture.
Possibility No. 2, you¡¯re all racists.
Md now please welcome our first
white presenter, Anne Hathaway...
Donnie.
Epps, Muse, Rayon.
Richie.
Spanning decades,
continents and cultures,
these unforgettable characters...
reprexent vastly different facets
0f the human experience,
but have one thing in common:
The extraordinary talent of the
actors who brought them to life.
Here are the nominees for
actor in a supporting role.
Barkhad Abdi, Cuptain Phillips.
Bradley Cooper, American Hustle.
Michael Fassbender,
12 Years a Slave.
Jonah Hill,
The Wolf of Well Street.
Jared Leto, Dallas Buyers Club.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Incredible.
Ellen, I love you.
To my fellow nominees,
Tm so proud to share
this joorney with p00.
I¡¯m in awe, and I have so much
respect for you all.
To the Academy, thank you.
In 1971, Bossier City, Louisiana,
there was a teenage girl who was
pregnant with her second child.
She...
was a high school dropout end...
a single mom.
But somehow, she managed to make a
better life for herself and her children.
She encouraged her kids
to be creative, to work hard,
and to do something special.
That girl is my mother,
and she¡¯s here tonight.
Mdl just wanna say,
I love you, Mom. Thank you
for teaching me to dream.
To my brother, Shannon,
the best big brother in the world,
youre a true artist.
Thank you so much for sharing
this insane and amazing adventure...
that is 30 Seconds to Mars,
and for being my best friend.
I love you. Thank you.
To all of the dreamers out there
around the world watching this tonight,
in places like the Ukraine
and Venezuela, I wanna say...
We are here.
Md as you struggle to...
make your dreams happen,
to live the impossible,
were thinking of you tonight.
Md this is incredibly special,
as well,
because there¡¯s so many people
that helped me get here.
Mdl just wanna say thank you
to Focus Features,
to Mick Sullivan, to Jim Toth,
to Jason Weinberg,
to Emma Ludbrook,
to Collie Addams,
to the entire
Dallas Buyers Club team,
Matthew, I love you. Jean¡ªMarc.
Md this is for
the 36 million people...
who have lost the battle to AIDS.
Md to those of you out there
who have ever felt injustice...
because of who you are
or who youlove,
tonight, I stand here in front of
the world with you and for you.
Thank you so much,
and good night.
Beautiful.
I have to...before I go any further,
Tm gonna be Tweeting
throughout the night.
Mdlrealized
after my monologue, I went back,
and I was like,
¡®What I¡¯m looking at is incredible.¡±
I mean,
the view of everybody that...
If people could see
what I¡¯m looking at.
So if you don¡¯t mind, really quickly,
I¡¯m gonna take a picture
of myself looking at you,
because how you look...
Thaok you.
#Oscars.#Blessed.
Tweet it out.
Citizen Kane, Lawrence of Arabia,
Ace Ventura.
Our next presenter
was in one of those.
Please welcome Jim Carrey.
Dont patronize me.
It must be tiring
being a nominee.
So much you have to do, so many dinners,
so many people to talk to.
It can really zap your adrenals.
I would imagine.
I¡¯m so excited tonight,
and I¡¯ll tell you why.
Tm excited tx be here because
xne of my true heroes, Bruce Dern,
is nominated for an Oscar this year.
Md Fm so excited about that.
Bruce Dern,
nominated for an Oscar.
Can¡¯t keep a good man down,
can you, Bruce?
Can you?
You look at me
when Tm talking to you, son.
Kind of tough being on
the other side of that, isnt it?
Its intense, man.
For decades, HoIIsood has relied
upon a special kind of magic...
to conjure movie heroes
0f all shapes and sizes.
From genies, ogres,
and talking toys,
to lying elephants
and dancing penguins.
Oftourse, this magic
I¡¯m referring to is LSD.
I might be reading that wrong.
Its animation. Wow.
I was way off.
Sometimes when you watch
this stuff, it¡¯s like youre¡ª¡ª anay.
Its a dynamic art form
all its own.
A professional playground populated
with criminally creative minds.
Md without it,
some of our most beloved movie
heroes would never have existed.
Lets take a look
at our animated heroes, shall we?
Myone else feel that was
a little light on Finding Nemo?
Our next presenter may take home
a little men other own,
meaning, she may give birth
at any moment.
Please welcome the scandalous
Kerry Washington.
Our next entertainer here to perform
the first of tonight¡¯s four nominees
for Best Song,
is one of the most prolific
artists of his generation.
Md good luck not dancing in your seats
when he gets going.
Here to perform his infectiously
joyous song,
Happy,
from the tim Despicable Me 2,
please welcome the phenomenally cool
Pharrell Williams.
It might seem crazy
What Tm about to say
Sunshine, she¡¯s here
You can take a break
I¡¯m a hot air balloon
That can go to space
With the air like I dont care
Baby, by the way
Here we to.
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like a room without a roof
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like happiness is the truth
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you know
What happiness is to yoo
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like that¡¯s what you wanna do
Here come bad news
Talking this and that
¡ªWell
¡ª Give it all you got
Md don¡¯t hold it back
Well, I should probably warn you
I¡¯ll be just fine
¡ªWell
¡ª No offence to you, don¡¯t waste your time
Hey, here¡¯s why
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like a room without a roof
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like happiness is the truth
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you know
What happiness is to yoo
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along
If you feel like that¡¯s¡ª¡ª
I want everybody to get up.
Come on.
¡ª Happy
¡ª Bring it down cant nothing
¡ª Bring it down
¡ª Happy
-Cant nothing, hey, hey
¡ª Happy, happy, happy, happy
¡ª Bring it down, cant nothing
¡ª Happy, happy, happy
¡ª Bring it down
¡ª Happy, happy
¡ª My level¡¯s too high
To bring it down, cant nothing
¡ª Happy, happy
¡ª Bring it down
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like a room without a roof
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like happiness is the truth
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you know
What happiness is to yoo
¡ª Because I¡¯m
¡ª Happy
Clap along if you feel
Like theta what you wanna do
No.
No, I don¡¯t wanna see it.
Why not?
Please welcome Samuel L. Jackson
and Naomi Watts.
What¡¯s the big deal?
When a movie comes together just right,
it¡¯s something of a miracle,
but it feels as natural
and inevitable as the weather.
Pulsating with the skill and creativity
of artisans in their element,
pulling off the impossible.
In the case of costume, hair and make¡ªup,
this year brought a perfect storm
of creativity.
Its our pleasure to honour
the behind¡ªthe scenes heroics
of the people who make it all
look easy for us all,
and make us all look good.
Here are the nominees
for Achievement in Costume Design.
Costume design by Michsel Wilkinson.
Costume design
by William Chsng Suk Ping.
Costume design by Catherine Martin.
Costume design by Michsel OConnor.
Costume design by Patricia Norris.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Catherine Martin.
The Great Gatsby.
This is the third Oscar
for Catherine Martin.
She has six nominations
including two this year.
Catherine took home her first two Oscars
in the costume design
and art direction categories
for her work on Moulin Rouge.
Thank you.
I do have a few words tucked into my bra.
Its a very Australian thing to do.
Its where you put your tissues.
III be very short.
Its not a long list.
IY course, I¡¯d like to thank the Academy,
but mainly I¡¯d like
to thank my incredible team.
I have a group of ladies
who are sewing for me right now
in Sydney
on a show were making
Baz¡¯s first film, a musical.
They¡¯re my golden girls,
they have been working with me
for 25 years.
They bring me such incredible luck.
They will all be watching the TV
right now
and they know who they are.
There are two people I have to thank
very, very specially,
Kerry Thompson
and Silvana Ai Heras,
and of course my incomparable
husband, Baz Luhrmann.
He makes it all possible.
He dreams the dream.
Here are the nominees
for Achievement
in Makeup and Hairstyling.
Adruitha Lee and Robin Mathews.
Stephen Prouty.
Joel Harlow end Gloria Pasqua¡ªCasny.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Dallas Buyers Club.
Adruitha Lee and Robin Mathews.
This is the first Oscar
for Adruitha Lee and Robin Mathews.
Thank you.
Thank you so much to the Academy.
My goodness, you all fought...
for the heir end makeup at this tim.
You fought for it,
and even fulfilled every dream
weve ever had.
To our friends end family, thank you.
To Matthew McConaughey
and Jared Leto,
thank you so much for letting us
transform and torture you
through a million, bazill ion
hair and makeup changes a day,
and for your support with our makeup.
Jean¡ªMarc Vallee, you are a visionary.
You are so amazing,
and thank you for choosing the two of us
to take this crazy journey with you.
Md finally for all the victims of AIDS,
we are so lucky and blessed
to be able to bring your story
to the forefront
0f the younger generation today
that doesnt understand AIDS 85.
Were very blessed. Thank you.
Thank you.
Hello, Alex and Nathan.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome Oscar¡ªnominated
actor Harrison Ford.
Marion Brando said
if you want something from an audience,
you give blood to their fantasies.
Its the ultimate hustle.
The first three nominees for best picture
gave a lot of blood.
In American Hustle,
con artists collude with the FBI
in an undercover sting operation
targeting corruption,
politicians and the mob.
Some of this stuff really happened.
Its a euphoric mio of comedy
and crime,
an original stylish scam.
In Dallas Buyers Club,
an electrician blindsided
by an AIDS diagnosis
transforms himself into
an alternative drug smuggler
and entrepreneur
in a no hold ba rred...
no holds barred fight to survive.
Emotionally searing and finally uplifting,
it¡¯s a poignant transcendent journey.
Md in The Wolf of Wall Street,
an ambitious stockbroker dives
head long into debauchery
and deception
providing a compelling cautionary tale
about power, greed,
and the definition of success.
Riveting and raucous,
it¡¯s a wild exhilarating ride.
Everybody fasten your seat belts.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please give a warm Dolby Theatre
welcome to Channing Tatum.
For the second year in a row,
the Academy held a nationwide
contest to discover dynamic new voices
in the next generation of film¡ªmakers.
Mdl was honoured to be a part
of the process.
Over a thousand college students
across the country
submitted 60 second shorts
depicting their dreams
for the future of film.
Of these, six stand out...
six were chosen, sorry.
The winners are here with us
tonight to participate in the telecast.
Please join me in saluting
their fresh creative minds.
Here are Zaineb Abdul¡ªNabi,
Jeanpaul lsaacs,
Tayo Amos, Nathan Flanagan¡ªFranki,
Mackenna Millet and Bryson Kemp.
Ladies and gentlemen, Team Oscar.
More Oscar suprises after this.
Once again, this year,
theyre continuing with the theme...
of only one winner per category.
Mdl don¡¯t think that¡¯s fair.
So, I brought consolation prioes
for the runners¡ªup,
because I don¡¯t feel like anyone
should go home not winning something.
So, Bradley, lam going to gioe you
some scratcher lotto tickets.
Right now.
Give you like,
save some for other people.
There¡¯s three...two.
There¡¯s two and a quarter.
¡ª I¡¯m going to need that back.
¡ªOkay.
¡ª Can Ida it now?
¡ª You can do it now.
¡ª Or you can let me know.
¡ª Ill save them. Ill save them.
Okay but let me know
if you win a lot.
¡ª You know, split it. Okay.
¡ª Split it. Okay.
Heres a HoIIyood legend,
and my co¡ªstar from EdW.
Please welcome Kim Novak
and Matthew McConaughey.
¡ª How are you?
¡ª Tm doing well.
¡ª Happy to be here.
-Ithinkso.
You know, as actors, like we are,
there¡¯s one thing that we actually have
zero eoperience with.
¡ª And that¡¯s animation.
¡ª Animation. You?
Not ¡°Magic Mike.¡±
¡ª No way.
¡ª Thats a little animated.
You affected
a whole generation of men.
Got them quite animated
with your work in yeigo.
Yeah.
Md heres something that
I really love about animation.
Its whatever they dream up.
Md they just draw it.
There¡¯s no limits. There¡¯s no boundaries.
Total freedom.
Absolutely anything goes.
Yeah, well, they work
with unshackled minds.
I mean, they¡¯ve got so much freedom,
and it¡¯s beautiful to see.
Pure creativity,
incredible variety.
¡ªYeah.
Igottotakea minute
just to say,
that Em really glad
to be here.
¡ª It¡¯s been a long time.
¡ª Me too.
¡ª Definitely.
¡ªOkay.
¡ª Along, long time.
¡ª Absolutely.
Tm glad to be with the
Academy here tonight.
But my main reason to be here
tonight is to be here with you...
and to announce the nominees
for the Best Animated Short Film.
Daniel Sousa and Dan Golden.
Lauren MacMullan
and Dorothy McKim.
Laurent Witz
and Alexandre Espigares.
Shuhei Morita.
Max Lang and Jan Lachauer.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Mr. Hublot,
Laurent Witz
and Alexandre Espigares.
This is the first Oscar for Laurent WiLa
and Aleoandre Espigares.
Sorry. A lot of emotion.
Ihave to take a paper.
Thank you, the Academy,
for this award.
Thank you for supporting
shorts and new talents.
Its my first movie
as director and producer.
The first movie of Alevandre
as co director.
I feel its an Mnerican dream.
Thank you Stephane Halleux
your fantastic sculpture
and artwork.
You deserve an Oscar, my friend.
Thank you Mickael, Pascal,
David, Thierry, Ghahth, LI¡ªLO
and the rest of the team.
They worked with patience.
Many thanks to Film Fund Luoembourg,
Ghayth here.
The CNC, Ia region Lorraine, and Arte.
Thank you to my family
and especially Audrey.
Md my children.
Thank you, I love you.
Md finally, thank you
Mr. Hublot.
for making this dream become reality.
Thank you very much.
Merci.
Md here are the nominees
for Best Animated Feature Film.
Chris Sanders,
Kirk DeMicco and Kristine Belson.
Chris Renaud,
Pierre Coffin and Chris Meledandri.
Benjamin Renner and Didier Brunner.
Chris Buck, Jennifer Lee
and Peter Del Vecho.
Hayao Miyazaki
and Toshin Suzuki.
¡ª You want to say it?
¡ª Id like to try, yes.
Md the Oscar goes to...
ke you ready?
¡ª Frozen.
¡ª There we go.
Chris Buck and Jennifer Lee
This is the first Oscar
for Jennifer Lee and Peter Del Vecho.
It is the first Oscar win end...
second nomination for Chris Buck,
who is previously nominated...
in this category for Surfs Up.
We¡¯re gonna do this together
because we¡¯re collaborative,
but we¡¯ll be fast.
First we wanna thank each and every person
at Walt Disney Animation Studios,
our family.
Were so proud of you for making
the film as magical as it is.
Md were bringing this home
to you.
Md for our personal families
and dearest friends,
thank you so much for supporting
us through this hard work
and for really being
our inspiration.
Md finally, wed like to dedicate this
to our guardian Angel,
thats my son, Ryder Buck.
¡ª Thank you, Ryder.
¡ª Thank you.
There are so many things
that go into making films.
One of the most important things
is that you hit your marks...
and know exactly where to be.
Here isa talented actress that
is no stranger to the Oscars.
She is only a stranger to people
that dont know her.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Sally Field.
Every day, quiet acts of heroism
take place all over the world.
Ordinary people, who stand up
and push back.
Every now and then,
their films, their stories
get made into flms,
allowing them to be seen
in every corner of the globe.
Stories that inspire and challenge us,
that force us to think.
Stories that illuminate and remind us
what it is to be human,
and that were all connected.
Heres to the ordinary,
eotraordinary everyday heroes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome two extraordinarily
talented actors.
Emma Watson and Joseph Gordon¡ªLevitt.
If you want to make the audience
see something that¡¯s just not there,
youve got to go talk
to the visual effects artists.
Agreed.
They truly are the unsung heroes 0f films,
fashioning miracles with enviable ease.
Here are the nominees
for achievement in visual effects.
Tim Webber, Chris Lawrence,
David Shirk and Neil Cnrbould.
Joe Letteri, Eric Saindon,
David Clayton and Eric Reynolds.
Christopher Townsend, Guy Williams,
Erik Nash and Dan Sudick.
Tim Alexander, Gary Brozenich,
Edson Williams and John Frazier.
Roger Guyett, Patrick Tubach,
Ben Grossmann and Burt Dalton.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Gravity.
Tim Webber, Chris Lawrence,
David Shirk and Neil Cnrbould.
This is the first Oscar for Tim Webber,
Chris Lawrence and David Shirk.
This is the second Oscar win
and the fourth nomination
for Neil Corboold,
who took home
his first Oscar for ¡®Gladiator.
On behalf of all of os,
thank you so much to the Academy,
for this honour.
Md a year with such amazing
visual effects.
Visual effects in filmmaking
is all about the team.
Md there¡¯s far too many to thank properly.
But I¡¯d like to mention, David Hayman,
Nikki Penny, Emmanuel Lubezki.
PJI 0f the shooting crew, RSP
and the incredible team of Framestore.
It seemed like a crazy project
So, thank you to Warner Bros.
Md in particular, Chris deFaria,
for believing in it.
To George Clooney
and especially Sandra Bullock,
for filing our visual effects
with life and with emotion
but most of all, to Alfonso Cuaron,
for having within us the vision
of this breathtaking tim,
the audacity to make it happen
and the courage to trust us
to have such a big part
in making it come to life.
Md, finally, thank you to our families
and the families
0f all the visual effects artists.
Thank you very much.
Tm sitting in Zsc Efron¡¯s seat
because Zac Efron is going to be up there.
Ladies and gentlemen, Zac Efron.
Good evening, everyone.
It really is great to be here.
Our next performer is an artist,
and a rock star and an inspiring¡ª¡ª
and an aspiratinn
to young punk goddesses everywhere.
Here to perform her hauntingly
beautiful ballad The Moon Song,
from the movie Her,
accompanied by Ezra Koenig,
please welcome Karen 0.
Tm lying on the moon
My dear, Ill be there soon
It¡¯s a quiet, starry place
Times we¡¯re swallowed up in space,
were here a million miles away.
There¡¯re things I wish I knew.
There¡¯s no thing I¡¯d keep from you.
It¡¯s a dark and shiny place
But with you, my dear
I¡¯m safe,
and were a million miles away.
A million miles away.
A million miles sway.
Please welcome Kate Hudson
and Jason Sudeikis.
Feature¡ªlength films get most
of the glory.
But this years nominees
in the short film categories
prove the wisdom
of the old adage,
¡°I would¡¯ve made it shorter
itt only had the time.¡±
They had the time
and used it brilliantly,
proving that an inspiring amount
of genius and artistry
can be delivered in 40 minutes
or less.
Here sre the nominees
for Best Live Action Short Film.
That Wasn¡¯t Me,
Esteban Crespo.
Just Before Losing Everything,
Xavier LeGrand and Alexandre Gavras.
Mders Walter and Kim Magnusson.
Pitaako Mun Kaikki Hoitaa?
Do I Have to Take Care of Everything?
Selma Vilhunen and Kirsikka Saari.
Mark Gill and Baldwin Li.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Helium,
Mders Welter and Kim Magnusson.
This is the first Oscar for Anders Walter.
It is the second Oscar win
and fifth nomination for Kim Magnusson.
Wow, this is crazy.
I want to thank the Academy.
Md I want to thank the short brands
for keeping this category in the show.
It¡¯s amazing, it¡¯s an amazing window
for new talents to show their film.
I want to thank an amazing cast,
a fantastic crew who did this tim
for no money at all, who just showed op
and fell in love with this film.
Mdl want to thank my family.
I want to thank my beautiful wife, Anna,
and my beautiful daughter, Lara.
Mdl want to thank two great producers
who(were)always behind me.
One is Tivi Magnusson
and the other one is his son,
this guy, Kim Magnusson.
I just want to take a quick note
and thank everybody
who keep on making the shorts,
Our fellow nominees, thank you.
Congratulations to all.
Md then I would like to thank
my wife, Rebecca,
my four kids.
Md for my mother, this is for you.
I know you¡¯re watching at home, sick.
So this is for yoo, mom.
Here are the nominees for Best
Documentary Short Subject.
Jeffrey Karoff.
Jason Cohen.
Sara Ishaq.
Malcolm Clarke and Nicholas Reed.
Edgar Barens.
Md the Oscar goes to...
The Lady in Number 6:
Music Saved My Life,
Malcolm Clarke and Nicholas Reed.
This is the first Oscar for Nicholas Reed
and the second Oscar win
and third nomination
for Malcolm Clarke.
Thank you.
When I met Alice Sommer,
I was struck by two things.
Her extraordinary capacity for joy
and her amazing capacity for forgiveness.
For those of you who dont know it,
the amaoing Alice Summer died
one week ago today.
She was 110.
She died quietly.
Md so this really is, and that,
they¡¯re both for Alice.
She was a woman
who taught everyone on my crew
to be a little bit more optimistic
and a little bit more happy
about all of the things
that were happening in our lives.
Md see the film.
Shell help you live,
I think, a much happier life.
Thank you so much. Thank you, Nick.
Thank you to the crew, Chris Branch,
Phil Goldine.
Frederic, Tim, Kieran you
were brilliant, Carl.
Hi.
Hey, Jeffrey, how are you?
How is everybody doing?
Good? Oh, hi. Happy?
Yes, lam.
Good.
Its very catchy. I love that song.
Love the song.
Just checking.
Hi, Whoopi, how are you?
Hows it going?
Good. You look good.
Oh, thanks. You look good too.
Just walking around.
¡ª Marty, hi.
¡ª Hi.
¡ª How are you?
-Good.
Harrison. Hi. Kerry.
Is anybody hungry?
I just feel like everybody
has got to be hungry right now.
Tm wondering if¡ª¡ª Really? Hungry? Yes?
So good.
I was hoping youd say that
because I have this crazy idea
that twill zrder pizza.
Md so, if I do,
I dont want it to go to waste.
Who will eat pizza if I¡ª¡ª?
Jennifer? Yes. Harrison.
Yes, yes. Marty.
WI right.
Two large? What do you think?
I¡¯m gonna order some pizza.
That¡¯s what I¡¯ll do.
Please welcome our next presenter,
tonights big winner
of our scratcher lotto card,
Bradley Cooper.
Documentary filmmakers cast light
on fundamental facets
of the human condition
in rigorously honest ways.
Md this years nominees raised the bar
perhaps as never before.
The quality of these films is breathtaking.
Heres to the heroes
who tell the truth for a living.
The nominees for Best
Documentary Feature are...
Joshua Oppenheimer
and Signe Byrge Sorensen.
Zachary Heinzerling
and Lydia Dean Pilcher.
Richard Rowley and Jeremy Scahill.
Jehane Noujaim and Karim Amer.
Morgan Neville, Gil Friesen
and Caitrin Rogers.
Md the Oscar goes to...
20 Feet from Stardom,
Morgan Neville, Gil Friesen
and Caitrin Rogers.
This is the first Oscar
for Morgan Neville, Gil Friesen
and Caitrin Rogers.
Thank you.
I, first, want to thank
along with my producer, Cait,
our other producer, Gil Friesen.
This was his ides and it was his baby.
Md when I first met with him,
I remember he said,
I want to win an Oscar.
Mdl remember thinking,
¡®You¡¯re crazy.
That will never happen.¡¯
Gil passed away just weeks before he
premiered the tim at Sundance.
Md tonight,
I know he¡¯s celebrating with us,
along with his wife, Janet,
and his son, Then.
I just want to thank my backup singers,
my wife, Jeanette,
my kids, Sadie and Cameron.
I want to thank our amazing distributors,
DiUS and The Weinstein Company.
Md lastly, these incredible singers
like Miss Darlene Love.
Lord, God, I praise you.
Md I¡¯m so happy to be here
representing the ladies
of 20 Feet from Stardom.
Mdl sing because Tm happy
I sing because Tm free
Cause his eye
Is on the sparrow
Mdlknow
He watches me
yjison, I love you.
Please welcome two¡ªtime
Oscar winner Kevin Spacey.
Mdl sing because its so nice
to be out of Washington in here...
with all of my Hollywood friends.
This past November, the Academy held
its 5th Annual Governors Awards,
a special ceremony to honour...
the lives and careers
0f uniquely talented artists...
who have made indelible
impressions and contributions...
to the world of film,
and inspired us all with
their creativity and their skill.
This years recipients
0f the Academy¡¯s Honorary Awards...
were the deeply¡ªgifted
Mgela Lansbury...
who at 88 years old is about to
return to the London Stage.
Go, Angela!
Steve Martin...
whose craft and genius has kept us all
in stitches and in thought...
for a very long time.
Md Piero Tosi whose brilliant
costumes have won him five Oscars.
The Jean Hersholt Humanitarian
Award was given to Angelina Jolie,
who is right over there.
In recognition of her courageous
and compassionate work...
as a global advocate
for humanitarian causes.
The Academy congratulates
all these remarkable colleagues...
for giving so much to our
industry and to the world,
and as Jack Lemmon might say,
Thats.. terrific.
Watch this.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, Ewan McGregor,
and two¡ªtime Oscar nominee,
Viola Davis.
One of the beauties of film,
is that it knows no boundaries.
From three continents
and five different countries,
the nominees for
the best foreign language film
have reached audiences around the world
with heroic works of art
that speak a universal language.
Ps diverse as they are dynamic,
these films transcend borders
and connect us
with our collective conscience
and common creative spirit.
Here are the nominees
for best foreign language film.
From Belgium,
directed by Felix Van Groeningen.
From Italy,
directed by Paolo Sorrentino.
From Denmark,
directed by Thomas Vinterberg.
From Cambodia,
directed by Rithy Panh.
From Palestine,
directed by Hany Abu¡ªPssad.
Md the Oscar goes to...
The Great Beauty.
Italy, Paolo Sorrentino.
This is the 11th Oscar
and 28th nomination for Italy.
Its most recent Oscar win was in 1998,
for Life is Beautiful.
Italy received
three special honorary awards,
prior to the establishment
of the foreign language film
as a regular category in 1g56.
nj1 right. Okay.
Thank you to the Academy.
Thank you to Tony and Nicole
and all the actors,
producers and the crew.
Thank you to my sources of
inspiration, Federico Fellini,
Talking Heads, Martin Scorsese
and Diego Armando Maradona.
Md thank you to Roma and to Napoli
and my personal great beauty
Dainela, Mna and Carlo.
Md thank you to my brother, Marco
my sister, Daniels
and this is for my parents, Sorrentino.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome, Tyler Perry.
In our fourth nominee for best picture,
a simple road trip shines
an unflinching light on the angst of aging
under the weight of unrealized dreams.
Spare, sensitive, and svulful,
Nebraska.
Depicts a journey
from confusion and conflict
to compassion and connection,
proving that nothing in the end
is really black nor white,
but rather radiant shades of gray.
The near future beckons in
a gorgeously original love story
between a human and an operating system
in our fifth nominee,
simultaneously intimate and universal,
unsettling and engaging,
the film is an evocative
evploration of love, loss sod healing,
and high¡ªwaisted pants.
It¡¯s funny and fresh,
and strange and soothing,
and poignant and provocative.
It is Her.
Sudden disaster propels our
sioth nominee for best picture
on an adrenaline¡ªdrenched ride
into the deepest reaches
of space and consciousness.
Boomeranging between
explosive action and haunting stillness,
Gravity,
probes elemental questions of courage,
fear, and survival,
leaving us breathless
and leaving us inspired.
I put different clothes on.
That¡¯s right.
I¡¯m almost embarrassed
to introduce this man
because he needs no introduction
and yet, if I don¡¯t introduce him,
he would never know when to come out.
So here¡¯s a man, like I said,
needs no introduction,
please welcome, Brad Pitt.
Our next performers are the
biggest rock bend in the world.
So its only fitting
that theyve used their considerable gifts
to pay tribute to one of the most
profoundly good
and courageous heroes 0f our time.
Here to perform their song, Ordinary Love,
from the tim
Medela: Long Walk to Freedom,
please welcome, U2.
The sea wants to kiss
The golden shore
The sunlight warms your skin
PJI the beauty
That¡¯s been lost before
Wants to fnd us again
I cant fight you anymore
Its you I¡¯m fighting for
The sea throws rocks together
But time leaves us polished stones
We cant fall any further
If we can¡¯t feel ordinary love
We cannot reach any higher
If we can¡¯t deal with ordinary love
Birds fly high in the summer sky
Md rest on the breeze
The same wind will take care
of you and I
Well build our house in the trees
Your heed is on my sleeve
Did you put it there with a magic marker?
For years I would believe
That the world couldnt wash us away
We cant fall any further
if we cant feel ordinary love
We cannot reach any higher
If we can¡¯t deal with ordinary love
Ordinary love
We cant fall any further
if we cant feel ordinary love
We cannot reach any higher
If we can¡¯t deal with ordinary love
Ordinary love
We cant feel ordinary love
We cannot reach any higher
If we can¡¯t deal with ordinary love
We can¡¯t fall any further
if we cant feel ordinary love
We cannot reach any higher
If we can¡¯t deal with ordinary love
Darling love
Dont be scared of me.
Youre looking away
like Fm going to do something.
Tm not. Tm a huge fan.
Tm...
Come on.
Just real quick Liza. Lets just get...
Oh, yeah.
¡ª You like our hair?
¡ªIdo.
¡ª Do you hate it? Okay
¡ª No, I love it. I love it.
¡ª Ready?
¡ªHit it.
Youre shaking my arm.
iI right, I think we got it.
¡ª Thank you so much. Thank you.
¡ª Youre welcome.
Lupita, Lupita.
You¡¯re gonna have some pizza?
¡ªOkay.
¡ª Tm not.
Heres what Tm gonna... Youre not?
You gotta be eat(ing). Okay.
Meryl, here¡¯s my idea, okay?
So you were nominated the
record¡ªbreaking 18 times, right?
So I thought we would try to break
another record right now,
with the most Retweets of a photo.
Okay.
So right now,
I¡¯m gonna take a pictore of on.
Okay.
Md then well see
if we can break the record
¡ª for the most Retweets.
¡ªOkay.
¡ªAnd then...
¡ª Get her in.
Yeah, you need to get in here too, Julia.
¡ª Ill just do this...
¡ª No, lean in.
Channing, if you can get in also.
Chann log.
Bradley, will you come in.
I want you in it.
¡ª Jennifer, come in also.
¡ª Ill take it.
Brad, get in here.
¡ª III take it.
¡ª No, I¡¯m doing it.
Mgie. Lupita.
PJI right.
Okay, right.
Okay, good.
Move it this way. This way.
If we wanted to be re¡ªtweeted this
many times.
Meryl?
¡ª Meryl.
¡ª What made you do it?
No, Meryl can...
Can you take it, Meryl?
Meryl, can you take it?
I can¡¯t get everybody in here.
il right, I got it for you.
¡ª My arm further.
¡ª Okay, your arm.
¡ª All right. All right.
¡ª My arm this way.
¡ª My arm is definitely better.
¡ª Here we go. Thats it.
¡ª Hey, that¡¯s good. Look at us.
¡ª Ready? Ready?
¡ª Nice.
¡ªOkay.
Oh, yes.
¡ª We did it.
¡ª Thank you.
Oh, I¡¯ve never tweeted before.
We tweeted!.
This is the most re¡ªtweeted in history.
¡ª Chiwetel! Were you in here?
¡ª I wasn¡¯t. I...
Wait a second. Okay. Okay.
WI right.
I think we have it.
Oh, did you get in on that too?
God, you¡¯re a photo hog.
Please welcome,
the star of ¡®Fruitwle Station¡¯
Michael B. Jordan,
and the star of Frozen, Kristen Bell.
The movies that speak directly to our hearts
are diligently crafted by impressive minds.
Each year since 1931,
the Academy has honoured the scientists,
innovators and engineers
whose pioneering work
has made a difference in the world of film.
The tradition of celebrating
these extraordinary people
continued on February 15th
at the Academys Annual Scientific
and Technical Awards.
Here are some of the highlights
from this years ceremony
which Michael and I
were privileged enough to host.
The class of 2013 was a large one,
with 21 awards going to 54 honorees.
On the mechanical side,
the Achievements included two miniature
helicopter camera platforms,
and a safe, air¡ªpowered way
to lip cam over.
On the software side,
the honours went to companies
and individuals
whose computer programms
have revolutionized
virtually every phase of filmmaking.
Charles ¡®Tad¡± Marburg received
the John A. Banner Medal of Commendation.
Md Peter Anderson was given
the Gordon E. Sawer Award,
an Oscar, for his many achievements
in two¡ªdimensional
and three¡ªdimensional llmmaking.
A special Academy Award of Merit
was bestowed on all the men and women
who have worked in film laboratories
since movies were invented.
Director Christopher Nolan
accepted on their behalf.
This awsrd is in recognition of a very
special form of alchemy,
that is turning silver and plastic
into dreams.
Our next presenters
probably think theyre so greet
because they are.
Please welcome Chris Hemsworth
and Oscar winner Charlize Theron.
Movies are a fully sensory esperience,
heard and felt, as well as seen.
But without the handiwork of
sound mixers and sound editors,
theyd be lost.
Just by imagining Star Wars
without the hum and swoosh
of the lightsabers.
Or Jurassic Park
without the roar of the T¡ªrex.
Well, luckily,
we don¡¯t have to,
thanks to the gifted men and women
who bring the movies to life
through the magic of sound.
Is that me?
I think so.
Oh, and here are the nominees
for Achievement in Sound Mixing.
Sorry.
Chris Burdon, Mark Taylor,
Mike Prestwood Smith, and Chris Munro.
Skip Lievsay, Niv Adiri,
Christopher Benstead, and Chris Munro.
¡®The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug,¡¯
Christopher Boyes, Michael Hedges,
Michael Semanick and Tony Johnson.
Skip Lievsay, Greg Orloff
and Peter F. Kurland.
Mdy Koyama, Beau Borders
and David Browniow.
The Oscar goes to...
You think
thats so much better than me?
Gravity.
Skip Lievsay, Niv Adiri,
Christopher Benstead, and Chris Munro.
This is the first Oscar for Niv Adiri
and Christopher Benstead.
Its the second Oscar win for Chris Munro,
who is also nominated in this category
for ¡®Captain Phillips¡¯.
Md the first for Skip Lievsay,
who is also nominated
for Inside Llesn Davis.
Thank you, Academy members.
Md thank you very much
to our fearless leader,
inifonso, wherever you are.
We want to thank you
for your amaoing, incredible vision,
and also for your incredible patience.
Wed also like to thank David Heyman,
Nikki Penny, Warner Bros.,
and our fantastic team of production sound
people and postproduction people
who worked very hard on this movie.
Mdl would like
to thank my wife, Elizabeth,
and my children, Miranda and Henry,
wherever ynu are.
I Inve you very much.
Md of course, Sandra and George,
for bringing reality to the onreal.
Chris and Nm would like
to thank their families
for bringing us all down to Earth.
Md right now, were over the moon.
¡ª Thank you.
Thank you very much.
Here are the nominees
for Achievement in Sound Editing.
Steve Boeddeker and Richard Hymns.
Oliver Tarney.
Glenn Freemantle.
The Hobbit: The Desolation of Smaug.
Brent Burge and Chris Ward.
Wylie Stateman.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Gravity, Glenn Freemantle.
This is the first Oscar and second
nomination for Glenn Freemantle,
previously nominated in this category
for Slumdog Millionaire.
Wow. My hearts beating
faster than Sandras.
Md obviously I like to thank
yifonso Cuaron for an amazing film,
absolutely amazing film.
who then...the reason why Tm here
is he has given us such a great opportunity,
and all of us.
Md he brought us all together,
and he pushed us and he pushed us
right into the middle of the night.
sometimes longer, but it¡¯s brilliant.
Mdl also like to thank my crew, obviously.
They worked so hard.
Md David Heyman and Warner Bros.,
who, you know,
they were 100%behind us.
Md we couldnt have done it
without that commitment from
everybody and all the...
We have such a team on this film
and sort of...a big bond.
Mdl would like to thank everybody
else on the film as well for that.
So I would like to thank my wife, Alison,
and my boys, Danny, Nick and Ollie,
and my crew.
Thank you very, very much.
I added a scarf.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Christopher¡ª¡ª Christoph, sorry.
Christoph Waltz.
Christoph.
Tm honoured to salute
the exceptional performances
given by the five outstandingly
talented women
nominated for Best Actress
in a Supporting Role.
Three of them...three of them
are first¡ªtime nominees.
il of them are absolutely stunning.
Here are the nominees.
Sally Hawkins, Blue Jasmine.
Jennifer Lawrence, American Hustle.
Lupita Nyongo, 12 Years a Slave.
Julia Roberts, August: Osage County.
June Squibb, Nebraska.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Lupita Nyongo.
Yes!
Thank you to the Academy
for this incredible recognition.
It doesnt escape me for one moment
that so much joy in my life
is thanks to so much pain in someone elses.
Md sol wsnt to salute the spirit of Patsey
for her guidance.
Md for Solomon, thank you for
telling her story and your own.
Steve McQueen,
you charge everything you fashion
with a breath of your own spirit.
Thank you so much
for putting me in this position.
This hss been the joy of my life.
Tm certain that the dead are
standing about you and watching,
and they are grateful and so am 1.
Chiwetel, thank you for your fearlessness
and how deeply you went
into telling Solomons story.
Michael Fassbender, thank you so much.
You were my rock.
yifre and Sarah,
it was a thrill to work with you.
Joe Walker, the invisible
performer in the editing room,
thank you.
Sean Bobbitt, Kalaadevi,
Adruitha, Patty Norris,
thank you, thank you, thank you.
I could not be here without your work.
I want to thank my family for your training.
Md the Yale School of Drama,
as well, for your training.
My friends, the Wilsons, this ones for you.
My brother, Junior, sitting by my side.
Thank you so much. You are my best friend.
Md Ben, my other best friend,
my chosen family.
When I look down at this golden statue,
may it remind me and every little child
that no matter where youre from,
your dreams are valid. Thank you.
Guess what?
Pias here.
Hello.
Come on down. I lied.
We weren¡¯t going backstage.
Okay.
So, we have just vegetables,
with tomato sauce.
We have cheese.
We have different kinds...
Who is hungry?
Who is going to eat on this side?
Okay.
Come on.
lye never done this. You help.
You want the whole box? Really?
¡ª Well, not the whole box.
¡ª All right. All right.
PA right.
Brad? Angie? Yes?
¡ª Pepperoni.
¡ªOkay.
¡ª What kind do you want?
¡ª Cheese.
¡ª Cheese. That¡¯s a cheese.
Yup.
Julia wants cheese.
Who is your favourite movie star?
They¡¯re here.
¡ª Who do you went to talk to?
¡ª Julia Roberts
¡ª Oh, you know Julia Roberts?
-Yes...
Okay. Wait a minute.
Were going to run nut.
Okay. Great. Okay.
The whole thing?
iniright. Great, great.
Wait, Angie didn¡¯t even get anything.
Hold on.
Lets goon this side.
Okay. Wait.
Kerry Washington is pregnant.
She needs some.
Lets go.
Lets get...Mybody? Leo?
¡ª You got to be hungry. No?
¡ª Tm not.
Come on.
¡ª Somebody over here. Jared?
¡ªYeah...
Yeah. Jared.
Jared Leto.
He just won an Oscar.
¡ª All right.
¡ª Joe got to hook my mom op.
Okay. Here yoo go.
Hey, by the way,
Harrison, you said you wanted pizza?
Okay.
Kerry?
¡ª Elsa¡¯s pregnant too.
¡ª Oh, another pregnant.
Yeah.
Okay. Great. Okay.
Md then, I don¡¯t have any money.
Who here has...
Sandy?
Sandy, you have money.
You¡¯ve got a lot 0f money.
¡ª You can tip him, right?
¡ª I have a credit card.
Sure, I¡¯ll take it.
Where is Harvey Weinstein?
Harvey?
Harvey.
No pressure.
Only a billion people watching.
Whatever you feel is right.
Marty, you said you wanted some.
Jonah.
PJI right.
Some people need no introduction.
This neot woman is not one of them.
Shes the first African¡ªAmerican
to be the President
0f the Academy 0f Motion Picture
mats and Science.
Md shes the woman
who could ire me at any moment.
Please welcome, Cheryl Boone Isaacs.
Good evening, everyone.
The Academy of Motion Picture
Asts and Sciences
is a truly global organisation,
supporting film culture
through a wide range of programmes
and initiatives.
These initiatives reflect
three pillars of the Academy.
We preserve the past
honour the present
and shape the future of this medium.
The past is preserved
through our 86¡ªyear history,
our archives,
and the world famous
Margaret Herrick library.
The present is reflected
in tonights awsrds for excellence,
our science and education programmes,
the 17 branches of the Academy,
our increasingly diverse
and global membership,
as well as moviegoers around the world
who bought more than
5 billion mooie tickets last year.
Md the future will be shaped
by the Academy
Museum of Motion Pictures,
a world¡ªclass destination
set to open here in Los Angeles
by the end of 2017.
Imagine a museum
that captures the heart and soul
of movies and moviemaking.
Celebrating
the cultural power of movies,
their ability to bring stories to life,
invent new worlds,
touch our hearts end expand our minds.
Lets all meet there in 2017.
Thank you.
Good luck following that,
pony Adams and Bill Morray.
Baby, you look like 146 million domestic.
Thank you, Bill. Thank you.
Everybody over at Sony
thanks you, as well.
Maay, now, to the business at hand.
The cinematographers
are the technical heroes
0f the fllmmaking world,
boldly creating the looks that
transport us into the stories
that transform us.
Visionaries, magicians,
creative electricians,
they wire the images
that make all the difference.
Ynure a poet, Bill.
No, Amy, but the cinematographer
that wrote those words certainly was.
Don¡¯t you think?
il right. Youre the brains
0f the operation, too, baby.
Tell them who is up for best shooter.
Here are the nominees
for Achievement in Cinematography.
Philippe Le Sourd.
Emmanuel Lubezki.
Bruno Delbnnnel.
Phedon Papamichael.
Roger A. Deakins.
Oh, we forgot one.
Harold Ramis for Caddyshack,
Ghostbusters, and Groundhog Day.
Please forgive me, gentlemen.
The 2013 Oscar
for the Best Cinematography
in a major motion picture
is going to go home with...
Gravity.
Emmanuel Lubezki.
This is the first Oscar and sioth nomination
for Emmanuel Lubezki.
His previous nominations were
for the Tree Of Life, Children Of Men,
The New World, Sleepy Hollow,
aod The Little Princess.
I want to thank the Academy
for this amazing award.
I would like to share this
with the cast and crew.
I know everybody says that.
But I truly want to share it
with the cast and crew.
Especially with my friend
and my teacher,
Mr. Alfonso Cuaron. Hello.
To your passion
and your creativity, and your drive,
I mean, incredible.
Md with Tim Webber
and the team of Framestore nerds
that made this trip possible.
I want to share it, as well,
with David Heyman
and Warner Bros for making the movie.
Md with Sandy Bullock.
Sandita, you¡¯re absolutely amazing.
To my wife, Lorencita,
iejandra, and Dani, my daughters,
my parents, my family, my friends,
my teachers, not all of them
but some 0f them.
Md thank you so much.
Good night.
Md now, please welcome
two Oscar¡ªnominated actresses,
Mna Kendrick and Gabourey Sidibe.
Without the discerning eyes
of expert editors,
every movie would probably
be four hours long
and significantly less awesome.
Editors provide the pulse end pacing,
tirelessly honing
the creative rhythm 0f films.
Thanks to the skill and artistry
of these talented men and women,
from vast, shapeless poois of raw material
emerge beautifully crafted films.
Here are the nominees for
achievement in film editing.
American Hustle: Jay Cassidy,
Crispin Struthers, and Alan Baumgarten
Captain Phillips: Christopher Rouse
Dallas Buyers Club:
John Mac McMurphy, Martin Pensa
Gravity: Alfonso Cuaron, Mark Sanger
12 Years a Slave: Joe Walker
Md the Oscar goes to...
for Gravity, Alfonso Cuaron and Mark Sanger.
Including his nomination
this year for Directing
and Best Picture for Gravity,
this is the sixth Oscar nomination
for Alfonso Cuaron
and his first Oscar.
This is the first Oscar for Mark Sanger.
Thank you very much.
A great honour.
I¡¯d like to thank our amazing team,
headed by Tanya Goading, Debs Richardson,
Steve Pang, Steve Mates, Alastair Grimshaw,
yjex Fenn and Ruth Antoine.
I¡¯d like to thank my lovely wife,
When I was a kid,
there were a couple of things that I knew.
Christmas was coming.
But I knew before that was coming,
Thanksgiving was coming,
which meant The Wizard 0f Oz was coming.
You see, back in the olden days,
you only got to see it once a year.
So ittorns oot, yoo see, not all heroes
wear capes and masks.
Sometimes they wear...
ruby slippers.
Now in 1939,
moviegoers first fell in love
with s girl named Dorothy
who longed for a life
different from her own.
Md in one of the most beloved cinematic,
magic joorneys of all time,
and with the help
of some very memorable friends,
a tin man, a lion and a scarecrow,
Dorothy got her wish.
Now that year,
the incredible Judy Garland,
one of my personal heroes,
received an honorary Juvenile Oscar
after following the Yellow Brick Road
right into nor hearts.
Md tonight, here to commemorate
the legacy of The Wizard of Oz
and of Judy, are Judys kids.
Oscar winner Liza Minnelli,
the fabulous Lorna Luft
and the amazing Joey Luft.
Kids, stand up and take a bow.
So to celebrate the 75th anniversary
0f this magical film,
please welcome the gorgeous
and talented Alecia Moore.
Oh, I¡¯m terribly sorry.
That¡¯s what I call her
when we¡¯re at the house,
you know, hanging out.
Buti know the rest of you
probably know her as Pink.
When all the world is a hopeless jumble
Md the raindrops tumble all around
Heaven opens a magic lane
When all the clouds darken up the skvay
There¡¯s a rainbow highway to be found
Leading from your window pane
To a place behind the sun
Just a step beyond the rein
Somewhere over the rainbow
Way up high
There¡¯s a land that I heard of
Once in a lullaby
Somewhere over the rainbow
Skies are blue
Md the dreams that you dare to dream
Really do come true
Someday I¡¯ll wish upon a star
Md wake up where the clouds
are far behind me
Where troubles melt
like lemon drops
Up way above the chimney tops
That¡¯s where you¡¯ll find me
Somewhere over the rainbow
Bluebirds fly
Birds fly over the rainbow
Why, then, oh, why can¡¯t I?
If happy little bluebirds fly
Beyond the rainbow
Why, oh, why cant 1?
Did I miss it?
Is it over?
Not cool, guys. They were gonna call me.
III do it by myself.
You had the power¡ª¡ªOh, never mind.
Our next presenters are both
incredibly talented actors
She¡¯s one of the most
beautiful actresses ever,
and he has the best name ever.
Jennifer Garner and Benedict Cumberbatch.
Herculean efforts are the everyday task
0f dedicated storytellers.
Md no one knows that
better than production designers,
who craft the worlds that transport,
delight,
challenge and inspire us.
Heres to the brilliantly talented
men and women
who create the realms that
give life to worthwhile stories.
Here are the nominations for
Achievement in Production Design.
Production design by Judy Becker
and set decoration by Heather Loeffler.
Production design by Andy Nicholson
and set decoration by Rosie Goodwin
and Joanne Woollard.
Production design by Catherine Martin
and set decoration by Beverley Dunn.
Her, production design by K.K. Barrett,
and set decoration by Gene Serdena.
Production design by Adam Stockhausen
and set decoration by Alice Baker.
Md the Oscar goes to The Greet Gatsby,
Catherine Martin, production design,
Beverley Dunn, set decoration.
Including her nomination
this year for Costume Design
for The Great Gatsby,
this is the sixth Oscar nomination
for Catherine Martin
and fourth Oscar win.
This is the first Oscar for Beverly Dunn.
Thank you. Thank you to the Academy.
Thank you to our fellow nominees.
We were among a great group of people.
I accept this award on behalf
of the truly many technicians
who fall under the umbrella
of the art department.
Md believe you me, on Gatsby,
there were many,
many very talented technicians
who worked on the film.
Id like to thank Karen Murphy,
my associate production designer.
Neither Ben nor I would be standing here
if it wasnt for you.
Our supervising art¡ª¡ª
Our supervising art director, Ian Gracie.
You rock and you swear a lot.
Thank you.
Md Foe just got to shout¡ªout
to my children
or they¡¯ll never forgive me.
Hi, Lily. Hi, William.
Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please welcome the talented Chris Evans.
since the dawn of stoitelling,
weve been joining heroes on journeys.
Finding entertainment and
inspiration in their epic arks.
Their trials speak to our common struggle.
Their triumphs inspire a collective hope.
Lets take a look at some
of the most unforgettably
defining moments in our journey
of most popular heroes.
Ladies and gentlemen, please
welcome multiple Oscar nominee,
Glenn Close.
Through their artistry, wherever
they wrought their magic,
they made us believe...
in place, time, light,
story, or emotion.
They mentored us, challenged us,
inspired us, elevated us,
and made us
only want to be better.
Because of their particular gifts,
they gave usa greater understanding
0f the human condition,
and the human heart.
We lost too many of them this year.
Bot because of the great gift 0f film,
they will live forever.
To those who are featored here tonight,
and to the many deseming others
who are in our hearts,
we looe you, we honour you,
we miss you.
But, most of all, we thank you.
It must have been cold there
In my shadow
To never have sunlight
On your face
You were content to let me shine
That¡¯s your way
You always walked a step behind
So I was the one
With all the glory
While you, you were the one
With all the strength
A beautiful face without a name
For so loot
A beautiful smile
To hide the pain
Did you ever know
That youre my hero?
Youre eveithing
I would like to be
Mdl can fly higher
Than an eagle
Because you, you are the wind
Beneath my wings
It might have appeared
To go unnoticed
But I¡¯ve got it, I¡¯ve got it
nj1 here in my heart
I want you to know
I know the truth
O course I know it
I would be nothing without you
Did you ever know
That youre my hero?
Youre eveithing, eveithing
I wished I could be
Whoa, and I
I could fly higher then an eagle
Because you, you are the wind
Beneath my wings
God bless you,
You are the wind beneath my wings
Youre the wind beneath my wings
Oh, you you, you
You are the wind beneath my wings
Fly
Fly so, so high against the sky
So high I almost touch the sky
Thank you, thank you
Thank God f or you
The wind beneath my wings
So I changed again.
So this is true, we just crashed Twitter.
We tot an email from Twitter
and we crashed and broke Twitter.
We have made history.
See, Meryl, what we did?
You and 1?
It¡¯s amazing, we really just made history.
It¡¯s fantastic.
Md it¡¯s back up again
suit has most re¡ªtweets ever.
Md we are all winners tonight.
That¡¯s what it means.
That¡¯s what I was trying to say early on.
Md now I finally get to introduce someone
whose name I didnt have to practise,
please welcome, Oscar winner Holdie Gawn.
Goldie Hewn.
Our seventh nominee for Best Picture
is an odd couple drama,
a gripping detective story
and a moving meditation
on the transcendant power
of the love of a mother, for her child.
Humoor and pathos intertwine
throoghout Philomena,
weaving a captivating tapestry
of love, loss, perserverance
and the healing power of forgiveness.
Our eight nominee depicts
a harrowing standoff
between hostages and hijackers
on the high seas.
Real, raw and utterly riveting,
Captain Phillips isa story
of cultural collisions
that elicits empathy for all sides
not only for the hero onder siege
but also for his trapped
and troubled captors as well.
Our ninth and final nominee
is the story atone man¡¯s
heart¡ªwrenching journey
from freedom to slavery and back again.
Determine to regain his basic human rights
and unite with his family,
Solomon Northup endures
unimaginable suffering.
But his spirit is never broken.
It is a stark unforgettable
and deeply emotional study
0f the depths of depravity
and the incredible
resilience of the human spirit.
It is 12 Years a Slave.
Please welcome, two¡ªtime Oscar
nominee, John Travolta.
Thank you. I love you.
There were always be
a special place in my heart
for the movie musical
and for the songs that create
their most memorable moments.
Here to perform the Oscar nominated,
gorgeously empowering song, ¡®Let It Go¡±
from the Oscar¡ªwinning animated
movie, Frozen.
Please welcome, the wickedly talented,
one and only, Adele Dazeem.
The snow glows white
On the mountain tonight
Note footprint to be seen
A kingdom of isolation
Md it looks like Fm the qoeen
The wind is howling
Like this swirling storm inside
Couldnt keep it in
Heaven knows I tried
Dont let them in
Dont let them see
Be the good girl
You always had to be
Conceal, don¡¯t feel
Don¡¯t let them know
Well, now they know
Let it go
Cant hold it back anymore
Turn away and slam the door
I dont care
What theyre going to say
Let the storm rage on
My power flurries
Through the air into the ground
My soul is spiraling
In frozen fractals all around
Md one thought crystallizes
Like an icy blast
Tm never going back
The past is in the past
Let it go
Md III rise
Like the break of dawn
Let it go
The perfect girl is gone
Here I stand
In the light of day
Let the storm rage on
The cold never bothered me anay
Idina Menzel, beautiful,
that was beautiful. Idina Menzel
I dont know how he does it.
But tonight,
our musical director is conducting
live from Capitol Records.
He must have a very long baton.
This is the...He is the fantastic
William Ross, everybody.
Md the Oscar orchestra.
Cut him off fore change.
Please welcome Jamie Fox
and Jessica Biel.
Great stories can change your life.
Great stories with great scores
will blow...your mind.
I see you, Will.
There¡¯s nothing like the right music...
at the right place,
at the right time.
Back me up, Biel.
¡ª Twill back you upon that, Foxx.
¡ª Score music.
Music is a language that
speaks straight to our souls.
We feel it, we love it
and were grateful for
the geniuses who do it right.
Here are the nominees
for Best Original Score.
Philnmena,
by Alexandre Desplat.
Her, by William Butler
and Owen Pallett.
Saving Mr. Banks
by Thomas Newman.
The Book Thief
by John Williams.
Gravity
by Steven Price.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Steven Price, Gravity.
This is the first Oscar for Steven Price.
Thank you. Thank you, Academy.
Thank you so very much.
snifonso, I share this with you.
Md you inspired every frame of this,
every certainly every note lever wrote.
Thank you for this
remarkable opportunity.
To all of the musicians
and friends,
who lent their talent
to this score, thank you.
I get to stand here but this
really belongs to all of us.
Thank you to all at Warner Bros.,
Thank you to GSA.
Everyone in this film,
for their incredible support.
One of the amaoing things
about working on this film, is that,
in telling the story of Ryan Stone,
we got to ultimately bring her home
and celebrate life.
and this is dedicated to
the people with whom I share my life,
my family, thank you.
Mom, Dad, Jenny, sorry I made
so much noise when I was growing up.
My wife, Gemma,
our lovely children, Amy and Eva.
Thank you so much, everyone.
Weve heard four incredible
performances tonight.
Oscar¡ªnominated songs.
To refresh, the nominees are...
Happy, from Despicable Me 2,
Music and lyric
by Pharrell Williams.
Let it go, from Frozen,
Music and lyric by
Kristen Anderson¡ªLopez,
and Robert Lopez.
The Moon Song, from Her,
Music by Karen 0,
Lyric by Karen 0 and Spike Jonze.
Ordinary Love, from
Mandela: Long Walk to Freedom.
Music by Paul Hewson,
Dave Evans, Adam Clayton,
and Larry Mullen,
Lyric by Paul Hewson.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Kristen Anderson¡ªLopez
and Robert Lopez
for Let it Go, Frozen.
this is the trot Oscar...
for Kristen Anderson¡ªLopez
and Robert Lopez.
Robert Lopez, has now become
one of the very few people...
to ever have won an Emmy,
Grammy, Oscar, and Tony,
which is referred to as the EGOT.
Oh, wow.
Thank you, Academy.
Md to our fellow nominees,
you are all rock stars.
Literally.
We have so many people to thank.
Luckily, everybody¡¯s name rhymes.
¡ª Idina Menzel.
¡ª Kristin Bell.
¡ª Jennifer Lee.
¡ª Peter Del V.
¡ª Chris Buck.
¡ª Chris Beck.
John Lasseter.
Happy Oscars to you
Lets do Frozen 2
¡ª Tom MacDougall.
¡ª Chris Montan.
¡ª Oremus.
¡ª Meger.
¡ª Besterman.
¡ª The Andersons.
Md the Lopez clan.
¡ª Jon Groff.
¡ª Josh Gad.
Mom and Dad.
John Buzzetti and our team back East.
and Kate, Brooklyn.
Md last but not least...
¡ª Our girls.
¡ª Katie and Annie.
This song is inspired
by our love for you.
Md the hope thatyou never
let fear or shame...
keep you from celebrating
the unique people that you are.
¡ª Thank you. We love you.
¡ª We love you. Thank you.
So I borrowed Pharells hat,
Md Id thought Id pass it around
and get some money for the pizza,
because nobody ever really...
What do you have, Bobby?
¡ªTwo hundred?
¡ª Two hundred. Two hundred.
¡ª Thats a start.
¡ª Does that cover it?
¡ª That¡¯s a start.
¡ª Oh, that¡¯s a start.
Let¡¯s see, what do you have,
John? Would you have 20?
¡ª Kevin?
¡ª Twenty. That¡¯s for you.
Thanks so much.
Okay.
Your stock just went up,
You¡¯ve tot some money now for pizza.
Ill take that. What is that?
¡ª A lip balm.
¡ª Lupitas lip balm.
That¡¯s worth somethin¡¯.
Brad?
Twenty?
You were in two pictures.
Chiwetel?
¡ªTwenty.
¡ª Twenty, thank you very much.
What else you got?
ni1 right, that¡¯s good.
Thank you.
Meryl, no, we¡¯re fine,
we¡¯re good, Meryl.
PJl right, please welcome,
Robert De Niro and Penelope Cruz.
The mind of a writer can be
a truly terrifying thing.
Isolated, neurotic,
caffeine¡ªaddled,
crippled by procrastination and
consumed by feelings of panic.
self¡ªloathing
and soul¡ªcrushing inadequacy.
Md thats on a good day.
Yes, but if everything toes well,
in the end,
there is s screenplay.
Here are the nominees
for Best Adapted Screenplay.
Richard Linklater,
Julie Delpy and Ethan Hawke,
for Before Midnight.
based on characters created
by Richard Linklater and Kim Krizan.
Billy Ray for Captain Phillips,
based on the book
A Captain¡¯s Duty,
Somali Pirates, Na Seals and
Dangerous Days At Sea,
by Richard Phillips
with Stephen Talty.
Steve Coogan
and Jeff Pope for Philomena,
based on the book
The Lost Child of Philomena Lee,
by Martin Sixsmith.
John Ridley for 12 Years A Slave.
based on the book 12 Years A Slave
by Solomon Northup.
Terence Winter
for The Wolf of Wall Street.
based on the book
by Jordan Belfort.
Md the Oscar goes to...
John Ridley, 12 Years a Slave.
This is the first Oscar for John Ridley.
Thank you all.
I started writing in sitcoms
a long time ago.
Md at that time, I was fortunate
to meet a script coordinator
who was gracious enough
to read everything I wrote.
Md when she thought it was ready,
she puts smiling face at the end
that I knew that it was job done.
Md, Gayle,
seeing you here tonight, smiling,
you take away all
that soul¡ªcrushing inadequacy.
il the praise goes to Solomon Northop,
those are his words, that is his life.
PJI of the thanks goes to the entire crew,
the entire cast,
To everyone at Fox Searchlight,
at River Road, at New Regency,
at Plan B, Mr. Pitt
Md most especially to
Dede and Jeremy Garner..Jeremy Kleiner,
you made this film happen.
Jeremy, you made it happen.
Thank you so much.
Mom, Dad, Lisa, Beth,
John, Jason, all my love.
Thank you very much. Thank you.
Md now, lets take a look
at Original Screenplay.
Here are the nominees.
Eric Warren Singer and David 0. Russell
for American Hustle.
Woody Allen for Blue Jasmine.
Craig Borten and Melisa Wallack
for Dallas Buyers Club.
Spike Jonze for Her.
Bob Neloon for Nebraska.
Md the Oscar goes to....
Spike Jonze.
Including his nominations this year
for Original Song and Best Picture for Her,
this is the fourth Oscar nomination
for Spike Jonze
and his first Oscar win.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
This is an amazing moment.
I appreciate it.
I have 42 seconds to speak.
So Ibetter hurry.
Tm not up here alone.
I¡¯m up here
with all of my friends and family,
who support me...
and help me make what we make.
Everybody, many of them in the room.
But they¡¯re all up here in this room,
upon stage with me right now.
Md 1...appreciate everyone.
There¡¯s Hoyte, he¡¯s over there laughing
next to Robert De Niro.
There¡¯s Natalie crying, Brian smiling.
Megan Eli ison who is very shy,
She¡¯s hiding in the back.
Md it¡¯s all of my friends,
everyone that I love.
We made a movie
about relationships and intimacy,
and thats what we share together.
Md so this is for all of us up here.
Md thank you, guys, for this.
That¡¯s fantastic, Spike Jonze.
Hes a former skateboarder,
and he wrote and directed Her.
Md hes a guy who has hit his head
against concrete countless times.
So to be able to accomplish that
is amazing.
Well be back in a moment.
Shes an Oscar¡ªwinning actor.
This years recipient of
the Jean Hersholt Humanitarian Award
and mother of six.
Hes a decorated actor
and humanitarian and cultural icon,
to celebrate the 50th anniversary
of his historic Oscar win for Best Actor.
Plesse welcome Angelins Jolie
and Sidney Poitier.
There we go.
¡ª There we go.
¡ªYeah.
Thank you. Good evening.
It is my honour to present
the Oscar for Best Director
alongside a legendary artist.
Since you graced our screens
more than 60 years ago,
your talent and integrity
have shattered barriers
and inspired audiences everynshere.
Md for that, my friend,
we are very, very much in your debt.
Md...
it is my pleasure to be here
in such inspiring company
to help celebrate
all the extraordinary talent
represented tonight.
Its encouraging...
and invigorating.
Please.
Keep up the wonderful work.
Here are the nominees
for Achievement in Directing.
¡ª All right.
¡ªYeah.
Here you go.
Ido this.
Md...
the Oscar goes to...
¡ª The Oscar toes to...
¡ª Do I get this one?
-Yes.
¡ª All right.
ifonso Cuaron.
(Spanish)
Well, thank you.
Thanks to the Academy.
Like any other human endeavour,
making a film can be
a transformative experience.
Mdl want to thank Gravity because for
many 0f uninvolved in this tim,
it was a definitely
a transformative experience.
Md it¡¯s good because it took so long
that if not, it would be a waste of time.
What really sucks is that,
well, fore lot of these people,
that transformation was wisdom.
For me, it was just the colour
of my hair.
I want to share this
with all these wise people
who made this movie happen.
My amazing son
and co¡ªwriter, Jonas Cuaron.
Sandra Bullock.
Sandy, you¡¯re Gravity.
You are the soul, the heart of the film.
You¡¯re the most amazing collaborator
and one of the best peopie
lever met.
George Clooney, for your absolute trust,
David Heyman, Chivo, and Tim Webber
for making this film happen.
The wise guys of Warner Bros.,
the wise people of Warner Bros.,
Kevin Tsujihara, Sue KrolI,
Dan Feliman, Greg Silverman
Lynn Harris, Chris De Faria.
Md the Him took so long
that we went through
two different administrations,
so, I have to honour as well
stan Horn and Jeff Robinov.
iejandro Gonzalez Inarritu
and Guillermo del Torn
et Gabriela Rodriguez.
et Steve Rabinesu,
Henry Holmes et Jim Berkus
and Tracey Jacobs.
Md, Cristina,
Sheherazade, Bu, Olmo.
Md this is for you, Mom(in Spanish(.
Bye guys.
Well, we did it, everybody. That¡¯s it.
Thank you so much
for letting me be your host.
Hopefully you had as much fun as I did.
Md¡ª¡ª Hmm?
Its not. Okay. Theres more.
I guess, well be back.
Serious? Really?
You lost all of it sweating to the oldies.
That is amazing.
I thought that there was a whole¡ª
It was a dance¡ªoff.
¡ª Wow, very impressive.
¡ª Thank you.
You look greattonight, bythe way.
Please welcome Daniel Day¡ªLewis.
There are five sublimely¡ªgifted women
nominated for Best Actress
in a Leading Role.
The nominees are...
Mny Adams, ¡°American Hustle¡¯.
Cate Blanchett, ¡°Blue Jasmine¡¯.
Sandra Bullock, ¡®Gravity¡¯.
Judi Dench, ¡®Philomena¡±.
Meryl Streep, ¡®August: Osage County¡±.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Cate Blanchett
Sit down. Youre too old to be standing.
Thank you, Mr. Day¡ªLewis.
From you, it exacerbates this honour to...
and it blows it right out of the ballpark.
Thank you so much to the Academy.
Ps random and as subjective as this award is
it means a treat deal.
In a year of extraordinary,
yet again, extraordinary
performances by women.
Mny Adams, eveithing you do,
but your performance in American Hustle
blew my mind.
Md, Meryl, what can I say?
Sandra, I could watch
that performance until the end of time.
Md I oort of felt like I had.
Julia,#Suck it! You know what I mean?
Md, Judi Dench, I mean, what a career.
Shea not here tonight
because at the age of 79,
her tim was so successful
that she¡¯s in India doing a sequel.
I mean, what a career that is,
ill could hope.
Md me...
Tm here accepting an award
in an extraordinary screenplay
by Woody Allen.
Thank you so much, Woody, for casting me.
Tm truly appreciative.
Tm so very proud that Blue Jasmine
stayed in the cinemas for as long as it did.
Md thank you to Sony Classics
to Michael and Tom
for their extraordinary support,
torso bravely and intelligently
distributing the film.
Md to the audiences who went to see it.
Md perhaps those of us in the industry
who are still foolishly clinging to the idea
that female films with women at the centre
are niche experiences.
They are not.
Audiences went to see them
and in fact, they earn money, so¡ª¡ª
The world is round, people.
Thank you to my mom,
to my sister, to my brother,
to my three glorioos Sons.
I would not be standing here without you.
To my husband, Andrew, you are a legend.
So thank you to my agent, Hylda Queally.
You¡¯re behind the pillar somewhere up there.
You are a goddess.
To my agent in Australia, Robyn Gardiner,
I love you so very much.
To my publicist, Lisa Kasteler.
To the sublime Sally Hawkins
and to the extraordinary cast
0f Blue Jasmine.
I don¡¯t know how to do this
without other actors,
and this, I share with you.
To the heir end makeup people,
who sweated me up and tried
to make me look attractive,
thank you for the attempt,
To Carla Meyer for getting Sally
and I together,
for your incredible support.
To Helen Robin,
to everyone involved
in Blue Jasmine, I thank you so much.
Md finally, I would like
to thank every single member
0f the Sydney Theatre Company,
One of the great theatre
companies in the world.
For me, working on Blue Jasmine,
it was a real synthesis
of my work in the theatre and on film.
Md not only working with you
for the lest sin years
has been the most enormous
privilege of my career,
but it has made me a better actress.
There is so much talent in Australia.
Md Michael Wilkinson and C.M. and I
are just tonights tip of the iceberg.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Md now, here¡¯s America¡¯s
other sweetheart,
Oscar winner, Jennifer Lawrence.
why are you laughing?
What? Was this funny?
Oh, okay.
Its such an honour
to present this next award.
The five men¡ª¡ª
Tm still watching you.
The five men nominated
in this category
delivered resonating, evocative,
and captivating performances.
Here are the nominees
for performance by an Actor
in a Leading Role.
Christian Bale, American Hustle.
Bruce Barn, Nebraska.
Leonardo Dicaprio,
The Wolf of Well Street.
Chiwetel Ejiofor, 12 Years a Slave.
Matthew McConaughey,
Dallas Buyers club.
Md the Oscar goes to...
Matthew McConaughey.
Yeah. Thank you.
Thank you, thank you,
thank you, thank you.
to the Academy for this.
PJI 6,000 members.
Thank you to the other nominees.
yji these pernrmances
were impeccable, in my opinion.
I didnt see a false note anywhere.
I want to thank,
Jean¡ªMarc Vallee, our director.
I want to thank Jared Leto
and Jennifer Garner,
who I worked with daily.
There¡¯s a few things, about
three things to my account,
that Ineed each day.
One of them is something to look up to.
Mother is something to look forward to.
Md another is someone to chase.
Now, first off, I want to thank God
because that¡¯s who I look op to.
He has graced my life with opportunities
that I know are not of my hand
or any other human hand.
He has shown me
that its a scientific fact,
that gratitude reciprocates.
In the words of the late Charlie Laughton,
who said, ¡®When you got God,
you got a friend.¡¯
Md that friend is you.
To my family, that¡¯s who
and what I look foooard to.
To my father who I know
he¡¯s up there right now,
With a big pot of gumbo.
Hes got a lemon meringue pie over there.
He¡¯s probably in his underwear
and he¡¯s got a cold can of Miller Lite.
Md he¡¯s dancing right now.
To you, Dad, taught me
what it means to be a man.
To my mother, who¡¯s here tonight.
Who taught me
and my two older brothers,
demanded that we respect ourselves.
Md what we, in turn, learned,
was then we were better able
to respect others.
Thank you for that, Mama.
To my wife, Camilla,
and my kids, Levi, Vida
Mr. Stone, the courage
and significance you give me
every day Igo out the door
is unparalleled.
You are the four people in my life
that I want to make the most proud of me.
Thank you.
Md to my hero.
That¡¯s who I chase.
Now when I was 15 years old,
I had a very important person
in my life come to me and say,
whoa your hero
and I said I dont know
Igot to think about that
give me a couple weeks.
I come back two weeks later
this person comes says
Whos your hero?
I said, I thought about it.
Md you know who it is I said,
it¡¯s me in 10 years.
So I turned 25, 10 years later.
That same person comes up to me
Md goes ¡®So are you a hero?¡±
Mdl was like, ¡®not even close.¡±
No, no, no. She said, why? I said,
because my hero¡¯s me at 35.
So, every day, every week, every month
and every year of my life,
My hero¡¯s always 10 years away.
Tm never gonna be my hero.
Tm not gonna attain that.
I know Tm not.
Md thats just fine with me
because that keeps me with
somebody to keep on chasing.
So, to any of us,
whatever those things are,
whatever it is we look up to,
whatever it is we look forward to
and whoever it is were chasing,
to that, I say amen.
To that, I say, all right,
all right, all right.
In that I say, just keep living, huh?
Thank you.
mu right. It is time.
Tm not going to make you wait any longer
because we have waited long enoogh.
Md when things are...
youre waiting for something,
you dont want to wait longer.
So Fm going to get to it end not make...
Because why would you went to welt
when this is really
what you¡¯ve been waiting for?
Here it comes.
But first, heres Will Smith.
The nine films nominated
for Best Picture tonight
are exhilarating and original,
inspiring and unforgettable.
They represent the best 0f whet we do,
and prove that incredible stories
told with talent, vision and style
invigorate our imaginations,
broaden our minds,
humble our hearts
and stir our souls.
Here are the nominees for Best Picture.
Md the Oscar goes to...
12 Years a Slave.
Brad Pitt, Dede Gardner,
Jeremy Kleiner, Steve McQueen
and Anthony Katagas, Producers.
Thank you, all.
Thank you for this incredible honour
youve bestowed on our film tonight.
I know I speak for everyone...
standing behind me
that its been an absolute privilege
to work on Solomons story.
Md we all get to stand up here tonight
because atone man
who brought us all together
to tell that story.
Md that is the indomitable
Mr Steve McQueen.
Tm sorry.
I apologize for the paper,
but othervise, Ill just bore you all.
Well, maybe Ill do the same now,
but I¡¯ll try not to.
I first want to thank the Academy.
Thank you so much.
There¡¯s a lot of people I need to thank
so I¡¯ll just push on.
To my wonderful cast and crew,
Plan B,
Brad Pitt, who without him,
this film would just not have been made.
Dede Gardner, Jeremy Kleiner
and Anthony Katagas.
River Road, Bill Pohlad,
New Regency, Arnon Milchan
and Brad Weston.
FiIm4, to the treat Tessa Ross.
Md Fox Searchlight
by Steve Gilula and Nancy Utley
and their fantastic team.
My publicist, for the words...
Tm sorry about this.
For the hard work, ril Lamb,
and my magnificent agents.
I have to say this, all these are women.
I mean, I have all women in my life,
and theyre all the most powerful.
My mother, obviously...
Maha Dakhil...I cant even pronounce it.
Forgive me. Fm just nemous.
Ma...You know who you are...
Beth Swofford, Jenne Casarotto
and Jodi Shields.
Just give me one more minute.
Id like to thank this amazing historian,
Sue Eskin, whose life,
she gave her life¡¯s work
to preseming Solomon¡¯s book.
I like to thank my partner, Bianca Stigter,
for unearthing this treasure for me.
Finally, I like to thank my mother.
My moms up there.
Thank you for your hardheadedness, Mom.
Thank you.
My children, Alex and Dexter.
Md my father, thank you.
But this is the last word.
Everyone deserves
not just to survive, but to live.
This is the most important legacy
of Solomon Northup.
I dedicste this award to all the people
who have endured slavery
and the 21 million people
who still suffer slavery today.
Thank you very moch. Thank you. Thank you.
That¡¯s it. Good night, everybody. Bye¡ªbye.