1
00:00:47,230 --> 00:00:52,450


2
00:03:08,460 --> 00:03:12,280


3
00:03:16,410 --> 00:03:18,000
You see how it's done?

4
00:03:18,180 --> 00:03:20,740
Yeah, I think I got the hang of it.

5
00:03:20,910 --> 00:03:23,520
You better. The boss will chew my head off i

6
00:03:23,520 --> 00:03:25,580
f these cores get messed up.

7
00:03:25,750 --> 00:03:27,410
Don't worry.

8
00:03:41,400 --> 00:03:43,560
We're at 26 feet.

9
00:03:43,740 --> 00:03:45,500
You let Jason operate the drill?

10
00:03:45,670 --> 00:03:47,730
Yeah, he can handle it.

11
00:04:38,460 --> 00:04:40,580
I didn't do anything.

12
00:04:46,930 --> 00:04:50,160
Give me your hand! Let go of the drill!

13
00:04:57,840 --> 00:05:00,570
Forget it, Jack! It's too late!

14
00:05:12,820 --> 00:05:14,090
You're not gonna make it!

15
00:05:25,240 --> 00:05:26,460
Jack!

16
00:05:37,020 --> 00:05:39,780
Jack! Give me your hand!

17
00:05:43,990 --> 00:05:46,010
I've got you!

18
00:05:48,730 --> 00:05:50,160
What were you thinking?

19
00:05:52,100 --> 00:05:56,500
-What's happening? -The whole damn shelf is breaking off!

20
00:05:56,770 --> 00:05:58,860
That's what's happening!

21
00:06:16,950 --> 00:06:23,800
We found evidence of a cataclysmic climate shift, which occurred 1 0,000 years ago.

22
00:06:20,890 --> 00:06:23,220


23
00:06:24,200 --> 00:06:28,060
The concentration of these natural greenhouse gases in the ice cores...

24
00:06:28,230 --> 00:06:31,600
...indicates that runaway warming pushed Earth into an ice age...

25
00:06:31,770 --> 00:06:34,030
...which lasted two centuries.

26
00:06:35,370 --> 00:06:37,270
I'm confused.

27
00:06:37,440 --> 00:06:41,400
I thought you were talking about global warming, not an ice age.

28
00:06:41,580 --> 00:06:44,590
Yes, it is a paradox, but global warming can trigger a cooling trend. Let me explain.

29
00:06:44,590 --> 00:06:47,980
trigger a cooling trend. Let me explain.

30
00:06:48,420 --> 00:06:53,190
The Northern Hemisphere owes its climate to the North Atlantic Current.

31
00:06:53,360 --> 00:06:57,560
Heat from the sun arrives at the equator and is carried north by the ocean.

32
00:06:57,830 --> 00:07:03,360
But global warming is melting the polar ice caps and disrupting this flow.

33
00:07:03,530 --> 00:07:07,100
Eventually it will shut down. And when that occurs...

34
00:07:07,270 --> 00:07:09,170
...there goes our warm climate.

35
00:07:09,340 --> 00:07:13,460
Excuse me. When do you think this could happen,

36
00:07:13,460 --> 00:07:15,110
professor? When?

37
00:07:15,280 --> 00:07:19,240
I don't know. Maybe in 1 00 years, maybe in 1 000. But what I do know is...

38
00:07:19,420 --> 00:07:21,980
...that if we do not act soon,

39
00:07:21,980 --> 00:07:24,750
our children and grandchildren will have to pay the price.

40
00:07:26,390 --> 00:07:29,450
And who's going to pay the price of the Kyoto Accord?

41
00:07:29,630 --> 00:07:33,500
It would cost the world's economy hundreds of billions of dollars.

42
00:07:34,070 --> 00:07:36,600
With all due respect, Mr. Vice President,

43
00:07:36,600 --> 00:07:39,130
the cost of doing nothing could be even higher.

44
00:07:39,840 --> 00:07:41,630
Our climate is fragile.

45
00:07:41,810 --> 00:07:45,000
At the rate we're burning fossil fuels and polluting the environment...

46
00:07:45,180 --> 00:07:47,410
...the ice caps will soon disappear.

47
00:07:47,580 --> 00:07:50,910
Professor Hall...

48
00:07:51,080 --> 00:07:54,140
...our economy is every bit as fragile as the environment.

49
00:07:54,320 --> 00:07:58,350
Perhaps you should keep that in mind before making sensationalist claims.

50
00:07:58,760 --> 00:08:02,060
Well, the last chunk of ice that broke off...

51
00:08:02,230 --> 00:08:04,390
...was about the size of Rhode lsland.

52
00:08:04,560 --> 00:08:07,360
Some people might call that pretty sensational.

53
00:08:09,670 --> 00:08:12,970
Stop global warming! Stop global warming!

54
00:08:13,670 --> 00:08:16,300
I'm at the Global Warming Conference in New Delhi...

55
00:08:16,470 --> 00:08:19,000
...where, if you can believe it, it's snowing.

56
00:08:19,180 --> 00:08:22,770
The coldest weather on record has thrown the city into chaos...

57
00:08:22,950 --> 00:08:25,710
...with numbers of homeless people freezing to death.

58
00:08:25,880 --> 00:08:27,370
Taxi!

59
00:08:27,550 --> 00:08:31,220
I enjoyed your testimony, professor. It was very spirited.

60
00:08:31,390 --> 00:08:33,830
Oh, thank you. That's what we're here for, right?

61
00:08:33,830 --> 00:08:34,880
Put on a good show?

62
00:08:35,060 --> 00:08:38,330
Quite. I was wondering if I could talk to you

63
00:08:38,330 --> 00:08:40,960
about your theory on abrupt climate shift.

64
00:08:41,130 --> 00:08:43,400
The name's Rapson. Terry Rapson.

65
00:08:43,970 --> 00:08:46,630
-Professor Rapson? Of the Hedland Center? -That's me.

66
00:08:46,800 --> 00:08:49,500
I've read your work on ocean currents.

67
00:08:49,670 --> 00:08:52,230
What do you say to a spot of tea?

68
00:08:52,230 --> 00:08:54,340
Absolutely. If we can hail a cab.

69
00:08:57,320 --> 00:08:59,010
Over here.

70
00:09:17,670 --> 00:09:19,900
Welcome back to Glasgow, Scotland,

71
00:09:19,900 --> 00:09:20,730
where Manchester United...

72
00:09:20,910 --> 00:09:23,530
...Ieads 3- 1 over hometown Celtic.

73
00:09:23,530 --> 00:09:25,910


74
00:09:25,910 --> 00:09:29,610
We return 63 minutes into the second half as Manchester United...

75
00:09:29,780 --> 00:09:32,000
...Iooks to put the game out of reach.

76
00:09:32,000 --> 00:09:33,680
Let's get back to our commentator...

77
00:09:33,850 --> 00:09:35,680
...Donald MacFarland.

78
00:09:36,920 --> 00:09:39,250
What? Yeah.

79
00:09:39,420 --> 00:09:42,220
-I just closed my eyes for a sec, man. -Yeah.

80
00:09:42,390 --> 00:09:44,830
The baby kept us awake all night.

81
00:09:45,000 --> 00:09:47,790
-And still. -Yeah!

82
00:09:58,740 --> 00:10:02,460
Dennis? NOMAD buoy 431 1 is showing a

83
00:10:02,460 --> 00:10:04,650
temperature drop of 1 3 degrees.

84
00:10:05,020 --> 00:10:08,280
-Yeah? Where is 431 1? -Well, it's....

85
00:10:12,520 --> 00:10:15,290
-Georges Bank. -It's rough seas out there.

86
00:10:15,460 --> 00:10:17,150
Must have knocked it about.

87
00:10:29,210 --> 00:10:31,830
Kick that bloody ball. Come on!

88
00:10:32,010 --> 00:10:34,480
Come on, kick it now. Kick it!

89
00:10:34,850 --> 00:10:36,510
-Kick it! -Are the lads winning?

90
00:10:37,750 --> 00:10:40,480
Hello, professor. How was lndia?

91
00:10:40,650 --> 00:10:43,210
Oh, you know what these scientific gatherings are.

92
00:10:43,390 --> 00:10:46,360
All dancing girls, wine and parties.

93
00:10:47,100 --> 00:10:50,890


94
00:10:50,900 --> 00:10:53,760


95
00:10:50,990 --> 00:10:58,760


96
00:11:01,810 --> 00:11:03,810


97
00:11:03,980 --> 00:11:06,390


98
00:11:06,390 --> 00:11:08,600


99
00:11:10,430 --> 00:11:12,120


100
00:11:12,360 --> 00:11:13,920


101
00:11:16,130 --> 00:11:18,550


102
00:11:22,700 --> 00:11:24,810


103
00:11:25,200 --> 00:11:26,240


104
00:11:28,600 --> 00:11:29,600


105
00:12:00,680 --> 00:12:04,640


106
00:12:28,830 --> 00:12:32,560
The fury of Hurricane Noelani stunned weather experts yesterday...

107
00:12:32,730 --> 00:12:37,760
...slamming into the island chain with a cataclysmic force never before witnessed.

108
00:12:37,940 --> 00:12:42,300
Meteorologists already believe this to be the strongest hurricane ever recorded....

109
00:12:43,410 --> 00:12:44,870
Are you gonna get that?

110
00:12:45,040 --> 00:12:47,200
It will surely leave a wake of death....

111
00:12:47,380 --> 00:12:51,840
-Hello? -I just saw that Sam got an F in calculus.

112
00:12:52,020 --> 00:12:55,320
I'm aware, Jack. I get a copy of his report card too.

113
00:12:55,490 --> 00:12:58,550
Sam is a straight-A student. He doesn't fail classes.

114
00:12:58,720 --> 00:13:00,820
I don't have time to talk about this now.

115
00:13:00,990 --> 00:13:03,820
Well, maybe you ought to make time.

116
00:13:04,030 --> 00:13:08,020
Excuse me, I'm not the one who's away for months and months at a time.

117
00:13:08,200 --> 00:13:09,890
I just don 't understand.

118
00:13:10,100 --> 00:13:13,800
I'll let him explain it. Can you take him to the airport in the morning?

119
00:13:13,970 --> 00:13:17,740
-Sam's getting on a plane? -He joined the Scholastic Decathlon Team.

120
00:13:17,910 --> 00:13:22,540
-They're competing in New York. -Sam joined a team?

121
00:13:23,010 --> 00:13:25,380
-Yeah, I think there's a girl involved. -Oh.

122
00:13:25,550 --> 00:13:27,280
Look, can you pick him up at 8:30?

123
00:13:27,620 --> 00:13:29,780
I gotta go because I'm on call tonight.

124
00:13:29,950 --> 00:13:32,680
Don't be late. I don't want him taking a taxi again.

125
00:13:32,860 --> 00:13:36,950
All right. Okay. I'll be there. Okay? I'll be there.

126
00:13:40,530 --> 00:13:44,470
This morning's weather staff meeting has been moved to level four, room B.

127
00:13:45,090 --> 00:13:47,440


128
00:13:47,570 --> 00:13:49,160
Jack?

129
00:13:54,110 --> 00:13:56,770
I know you're good at rubbing people the wrong way...

130
00:13:56,950 --> 00:14:00,140
...but why would you aggravate the vice president?

131
00:14:00,320 --> 00:14:03,290
Because my 1 7-year-old kid knows more science than he does.

132
00:14:03,450 --> 00:14:06,120
Your 1 7-year-old kid does not control our budget.

133
00:14:06,290 --> 00:14:08,880
-Who cares if he hates you. -My son doesn't hate me.

134
00:14:09,060 --> 00:14:10,990
If Raymond Becker pulls our budget--

135
00:14:11,160 --> 00:14:15,500
-Oh, shit! -Wait-- Will you--? Jack.

136
00:14:21,240 --> 00:14:23,400
Oh, my God.

137
00:14:29,410 --> 00:14:32,080
-I'm sorry I'm late. -Dad, the cab's already here.

138
00:14:32,250 --> 00:14:34,220
That's okay. I'll take care of it.

139
00:14:34,390 --> 00:14:35,720
-What are--? -Here you go.

140
00:14:38,190 --> 00:14:41,450
I'm not angry. I'm disappointed.

141
00:14:41,630 --> 00:14:44,820
-Do you want to hear my side of it? -How can there be two sides?

142
00:14:45,000 --> 00:14:48,730
I got every question right on the final. Mr. Spengler failed me...

143
00:14:48,900 --> 00:14:51,420
-...because I didn't write the solutions. -Why not?

144
00:14:51,970 --> 00:14:54,160
I do them in my head.

145
00:14:54,340 --> 00:14:57,140
-Did you tell him that? -I did. He didn't believe me.

146
00:14:57,310 --> 00:15:00,110
He said if he can't do them in his head, I'm cheating.

147
00:15:00,540 --> 00:15:03,640
Ridiculous. How can he fail you for being smarter than he is?

148
00:15:04,050 --> 00:15:06,350
That's what I said.

149
00:15:06,820 --> 00:15:08,250
You did?

150
00:15:10,020 --> 00:15:12,510
-How'd he take it? -He flunked me, remember?

151
00:15:13,860 --> 00:15:15,760
Oh, yeah.

152
00:15:18,430 --> 00:15:22,920
Sam, I'm sorry. I jumped to conclusions.

153
00:15:23,630 --> 00:15:27,090
I'm gonna call this guy and have a word with him.

154
00:15:27,270 --> 00:15:28,600
We'll straighten this out.

155
00:15:28,770 --> 00:15:30,470
Hey, you can't park there.

156
00:15:30,640 --> 00:15:32,870
-Don't worry about it. -Sam?

157
00:15:33,380 --> 00:15:35,070
Sam.

158
00:15:49,160 --> 00:15:51,560
Parker, this is Houston.

159
00:15:51,730 --> 00:15:54,460
We're seeing some bad weather over Canaveral.

160
00:15:54,630 --> 00:15:57,260
It doesn 't look like you're coming back this week.

161
00:15:57,430 --> 00:15:59,490
Your wife's gonna give me an earful.

162
00:15:59,670 --> 00:16:01,300
Roger that.

163
00:16:01,470 --> 00:16:05,640
Hey, come take a look at this storm system. It' s enormous.

164
00:16:39,010 --> 00:16:40,840
You all right?

165
00:16:43,450 --> 00:16:45,380
He's afraid of flying.

166
00:16:45,550 --> 00:16:47,280
I'm fine.

167
00:16:55,330 --> 00:16:59,130
Statistically, the chance of a plane going down because of turbulence...

168
00:16:59,300 --> 00:17:03,820
...is less than, what, one in a billion? Or is it a million?

169
00:17:04,800 --> 00:17:07,200
-I can't remember if it's a-- -Shut up, Brian.

170
00:17:07,370 --> 00:17:08,800
Listen, Sam...

171
00:17:08,970 --> 00:17:11,870
...don't pay attention to him, okay? Everything's fine.

172
00:17:12,040 --> 00:17:14,840
They're still serving drinks.

173
00:17:28,330 --> 00:17:32,460
Folks, it appears we're gonna have a bit of a bumpy ride for the next few minutes.

174
00:17:32,630 --> 00:17:35,660
Please fasten your seat belts and put your tray tables...

175
00:17:35,830 --> 00:17:40,330
...and seat backs in their upright positions until we get through this. Thank you.

176
00:17:41,140 --> 00:17:42,440
Whoa!

177
00:17:42,610 --> 00:17:44,600
Grab it. Watch out!

178
00:18:15,570 --> 00:18:16,940
Sam?

179
00:18:18,310 --> 00:18:19,940
Sam.

180
00:18:23,280 --> 00:18:24,910
Can I have my hand back?

181
00:18:41,500 --> 00:18:43,730
I can't believe I'll be alone with my mom.

182
00:18:43,900 --> 00:18:47,100
Be patient with her. She's been looking forward to this holiday.

183
00:18:47,270 --> 00:18:48,740
I know.

184
00:18:49,040 --> 00:18:50,970
I love you.

185
00:18:51,840 --> 00:18:53,140
I love you too.

186
00:18:55,210 --> 00:18:56,680
Hey.

187
00:18:56,980 --> 00:18:59,350
Hey, hello. Bye-bye.

188
00:18:59,520 --> 00:19:01,900
The cause of this extreme weather remains a mystery,

189
00:19:01,900 --> 00:19:03,780
although some meteorologists...

190
00:19:03,950 --> 00:19:06,890
...believe sunspots are to blame. Hundreds are missing....

191
00:19:07,060 --> 00:19:09,950
This is very odd. There' s a buoy registering

192
00:19:09,960 --> 00:19:12,190
a 1 3-degree drop in ocean temperature.

193
00:19:12,360 --> 00:19:16,490
Oh, yeah, that's right. That buoy malfunctioned the other day.

194
00:19:16,670 --> 00:19:19,570
I'll see if there are ships near Georges Bank to get it.

195
00:19:19,740 --> 00:19:22,860
This buoy isn't in Georges Bank. It's just off Greenland.

196
00:19:23,040 --> 00:19:24,410
What?

197
00:19:27,180 --> 00:19:30,840
-What are the odds of two buoys failing? -Remote.

198
00:19:36,820 --> 00:19:38,650
Make that three.

199
00:19:49,300 --> 00:19:54,360
Just another typical day in New York City. Traffic jam, 1 0 blocks long.

200
00:19:54,540 --> 00:19:59,810
Look here, Buddha. These people, and their cars, and their exhaust...

201
00:19:59,980 --> 00:20:02,000
...and they're polluting the atmosphere.

202
00:20:02,180 --> 00:20:05,810
Excuse me, sir. We're really late.

203
00:20:06,080 --> 00:20:08,180
We're almost there.

204
00:20:08,350 --> 00:20:12,520
-We're only two blocks away. -Let's walk.

205
00:20:39,150 --> 00:20:40,810
What's gotten into them?

206
00:20:40,980 --> 00:20:45,480
I have no idea. They're all worked up today.

207
00:20:46,690 --> 00:20:51,860
In 1 532, Spanish conquistador Francisco Pizarro...

208
00:20:52,030 --> 00:20:57,630
...defeated this lncan emperor at the Peruvian highland town of Cajamarca.

209
00:20:57,970 --> 00:21:00,700
What is his name? Time.

210
00:21:01,770 --> 00:21:03,260
Montezuma.

211
00:21:03,440 --> 00:21:06,170
No, no, Montezuma was in Mexico, not Peru.

212
00:21:06,340 --> 00:21:09,280
It's, like, Anta-something.

213
00:21:11,220 --> 00:21:13,120
-Atahualpa? -That's it!

214
00:21:13,280 --> 00:21:15,110
Time's up. Correct answers, please.

215
00:21:18,220 --> 00:21:23,890
That's five points for Woodmont and five points for Pinehurst Academy.

216
00:21:24,960 --> 00:21:26,430
Next question.

217
00:21:28,170 --> 00:21:34,230
In what year did Louis Quatorze ascend to the throne of France?

218
00:21:38,540 --> 00:21:44,340
This place is so retro, it might actually be cool if it were on purpose.

219
00:21:45,880 --> 00:21:48,210
Yeah, look at all these nerds.

220
00:21:48,390 --> 00:21:50,010
Hey.

221
00:21:50,920 --> 00:21:52,450
Hey.

222
00:21:54,090 --> 00:21:56,150
You look beautiful.

223
00:21:56,860 --> 00:21:59,020
Thanks. This place is incredible.

224
00:21:59,200 --> 00:22:01,190
Do you believe this is their cafeteria?

225
00:22:01,370 --> 00:22:03,130
You played a great first round.

226
00:22:03,570 --> 00:22:05,260
So did you.

227
00:22:05,440 --> 00:22:08,200
These are my teammates, Sam and Brian.

228
00:22:08,370 --> 00:22:10,430
-I'm Laura. -Oh, I'm J.D.

229
00:22:10,610 --> 00:22:14,140
-Your school's amazing. -Would you like a tour?

230
00:22:17,010 --> 00:22:19,640
Sure. That'd be great.

231
00:22:19,820 --> 00:22:21,780
Could you hold this for a sec?

232
00:22:22,550 --> 00:22:24,710
Yeah, sure.

233
00:22:24,960 --> 00:22:26,350
Thanks.

234
00:22:32,460 --> 00:22:34,830
Man, you got some serious competition.

235
00:22:35,430 --> 00:22:37,330
Please.

236
00:22:37,500 --> 00:22:41,200
-And I'll bet he's really rich too. -Shut up.

237
00:22:53,480 --> 00:22:56,820
-Who is it? -Terry Rapson here.

238
00:22:56,990 --> 00:22:58,450
Sorry to call you so early.

239
00:22:58,620 --> 00:23:00,750
No, professor, it's all right. What is it?

240
00:23:01,660 --> 00:23:06,620
Well, we've found something extraordinary. Extraordinary and disturbing, that is.

241
00:23:06,800 --> 00:23:10,230
You recall what you said in New Delhi about how polar melting...

242
00:23:10,400 --> 00:23:14,200
-...might disrupt the North Atlantic Current? -Yes.

243
00:23:14,670 --> 00:23:16,140
Well...

244
00:23:17,140 --> 00:23:18,700
...I think it's happening.

245
00:23:22,180 --> 00:23:23,440
What do you mean?

246
00:23:23,610 --> 00:23:27,640
One of our NOMAD buoys registered a 13-degree drop...

247
00:23:27,820 --> 00:23:30,750
...in surface temperature. I've sent you an e-mail.

248
00:23:30,920 --> 00:23:32,750
Hold on.

249
00:23:34,120 --> 00:23:36,520
A t first we thought it was a malfunction.

250
00:23:36,690 --> 00:23:40,750
But there are four more across the North A tlantic showing the same thing.

251
00:23:40,930 --> 00:23:43,130
This is unbelievable.

252
00:23:43,870 --> 00:23:45,560
You predicted it would happen.

253
00:23:45,740 --> 00:23:49,430
Yes, but not in our lifetime. This is too fast.

254
00:23:49,610 --> 00:23:53,040
There are no forecast models remotely capable...

255
00:23:53,210 --> 00:23:56,540
...of plotting this scenario, except yours.

256
00:23:56,710 --> 00:23:59,880
My model is a reconstruction of a prehistoric climate shift.

257
00:24:00,050 --> 00:24:02,140
It's not a forecast model.

258
00:24:02,320 --> 00:24:04,550
It's the closest thing we have.

259
00:24:05,620 --> 00:24:08,390
Nothing like this has ever happened before.

260
00:24:08,760 --> 00:24:11,790
At least not in the last 1 0,000 years.

261
00:24:37,720 --> 00:24:40,460
As I predicted yesterday,

262
00:24:40,460 --> 00:24:43,630
the swell off Hurricane Noelani is incredible.

263
00:24:43,790 --> 00:24:48,200
These waves are even bigger than I imagined. Just take a look.

264
00:24:49,670 --> 00:24:51,960
Shouldn't you be monitoring the weather?

265
00:24:51,960 --> 00:24:54,430
This is L.A. What weather?

266
00:24:56,440 --> 00:24:59,100
Wait. What's that noise?

267
00:24:59,280 --> 00:25:01,140
What noise?

268
00:25:12,690 --> 00:25:14,450
Honey, I'll be right back.

269
00:25:16,290 --> 00:25:21,560
The Coast Guard closed the beaches, as waves have grown too big for....

270
00:25:21,730 --> 00:25:23,560
-L.A. Weather Center. -It's Tommy.

271
00:25:23,730 --> 00:25:26,530
I'm in the middle of something, Tommy. What do you need?

272
00:25:27,970 --> 00:25:31,000
There's hail the size of golf balls coming down here.

273
00:25:31,170 --> 00:25:33,700
A low-pressure system along the California coast...

274
00:25:33,880 --> 00:25:36,640
...is creating a cyclonic system across the L.A. Basin.

275
00:25:44,190 --> 00:25:46,350
- Yeah? -Boss, turn on The Weather Channel.

276
00:25:46,820 --> 00:25:50,520
-I think we have to issue a tornado warning. -What are you talking about?

277
00:25:51,360 --> 00:25:54,460
Palmdale and Lancaster are reporting wind speeds in excess....

278
00:25:54,630 --> 00:25:57,930
-Hold on a second. -Conditions highly unusual for California.

279
00:26:17,990 --> 00:26:20,550
We' re building a forecast model, we need-- What?

280
00:26:20,720 --> 00:26:23,960
Priority access to the mainframe for two days, maybe three.

281
00:26:24,130 --> 00:26:26,990
-Oh, is that it? Anything else? -We need it immediately.

282
00:26:27,160 --> 00:26:29,190
I would say that you've lost your mind...

283
00:26:29,370 --> 00:26:31,700
...but you've been this way for the past 20 years.

284
00:26:31,900 --> 00:26:36,830
-Tom, this is important. -What's this forecast model you're building?

285
00:26:37,010 --> 00:26:39,320
Janet Tokada, this is Jack Hall.

286
00:26:39,320 --> 00:26:41,640
Janet's a hurricane specialist with NASA.

287
00:26:41,810 --> 00:26:46,440
Jack's a paleoclimatologist, and I have absolutely no idea what he's up to.

288
00:26:46,880 --> 00:26:49,550
Booker. What's going on here?

289
00:26:49,720 --> 00:26:52,590
They just issued a tornado warning in Los Angeles.

290
00:26:52,760 --> 00:26:55,820
Breaking news as we prepare to go live to Los Angeles.

291
00:26:55,990 --> 00:26:59,930
Mixed reports are coming in about some extreme weather occurring in the area.

292
00:27:00,100 --> 00:27:03,730
Okay, we're now going live to our Fox affiliate in Los Angeles.

293
00:27:07,400 --> 00:27:11,700
We have live coverage now from our Fox 1 1 chopper. Are you there, Bart?

294
00:27:11,880 --> 00:27:15,170
Yes, I'm here. These tornados are forming so fast--

295
00:27:15,350 --> 00:27:18,410
-Bart! -What? Oh! Oh, my God.

296
00:27:18,580 --> 00:27:20,980
Lisa, are you getting this on camera?

297
00:27:21,150 --> 00:27:23,680
This tornado just erased the Hollywood sign.

298
00:27:23,850 --> 00:27:27,120
The Hollywood sign is gone. It's just shredded.

299
00:27:38,940 --> 00:27:41,030
Bart, what can you see? Is anyone hurt?

300
00:27:41,200 --> 00:27:44,110
I wouldn't be surprised. There is so much damage.

301
00:27:44,310 --> 00:27:47,040
And there are people down there taking pictures.

302
00:27:47,210 --> 00:27:50,200
Hey, what the hell are you guys doing? Go for cover!

303
00:27:50,380 --> 00:27:52,870
You can't stay here! Get out of here!

304
00:27:55,450 --> 00:27:58,450
What you're seeing are two actual tornados

305
00:27:58,450 --> 00:28:00,450
striking Los Angeles lnternational Airport.

306
00:28:00,620 --> 00:28:03,890
Wait. It looks like they've joined and formed one large tornado.

307
00:28:04,060 --> 00:28:05,650
-Tommy! -Oh, my God!

308
00:28:06,900 --> 00:28:08,860
Holy shit!

309
00:28:09,700 --> 00:28:12,290
I'd like to urge all of our viewers to stay away....

310
00:28:12,470 --> 00:28:15,910
-Jeff, where are you? -I'm on Yucca and Vine.

311
00:28:16,070 --> 00:28:19,170
-I'm on my way. -You're on TV. You're in the middle of it.

312
00:28:19,340 --> 00:28:22,900
God! Oh, my God!

313
00:28:29,020 --> 00:28:31,010
You gotta get out of there, man.

314
00:28:35,490 --> 00:28:38,020
That bus just got dropped on top of that Porsche!

315
00:28:38,190 --> 00:28:40,460
Oh, my God. I hope no one was in that car.

316
00:28:40,630 --> 00:28:43,120
For our national audience just joining us now...

317
00:28:43,300 --> 00:28:46,830
... we are going live to downtown Los Angeles right now. Tommy?

318
00:28:47,000 --> 00:28:49,940
If you look over there behind me, that's a tornado.

319
00:28:50,110 --> 00:28:52,540
Yes, a twister in Los Angeles.

320
00:28:52,710 --> 00:28:56,840
It's one of many tornados that are destroying our city.

321
00:28:57,010 --> 00:29:00,280
There's another one. That's the Los Angeles skyline.

322
00:29:00,450 --> 00:29:04,110
It's unbelievable! It's huge! I've never seen anything like it.

323
00:29:16,730 --> 00:29:17,960
What's happening?

324
00:29:18,130 --> 00:29:21,000
It looks like some sort of...

325
00:29:21,170 --> 00:29:26,230
...huge, horrific, terrifying nightmare, only this is the real thing.

326
00:30:35,180 --> 00:30:37,410
Yes, I'm looking at it right now.

327
00:30:38,050 --> 00:30:39,710
-Yes, it is. -What's happening?

328
00:30:39,880 --> 00:30:41,320
I'll call you back.

329
00:30:42,320 --> 00:30:46,480
Mr. President, Los Angeles has been devastated by a series of tornados.

330
00:30:48,460 --> 00:30:52,190
On top of that, the FAA wants your approval to suspend all air traffic.

331
00:30:52,360 --> 00:30:55,530
-What do you think we should do? -Until we can figure it out...

332
00:30:55,700 --> 00:30:57,860
...I don't think we have much choice, sir.

333
00:30:58,030 --> 00:31:01,630
What you're seeing is what's left of downtown Los Angeles.

334
00:31:01,810 --> 00:31:04,370
Hey, man, I just got off the phone with my mom.

335
00:31:04,540 --> 00:31:08,500
Excuse me, you guys. I'm really sorry, but we need to change the channel.

336
00:31:08,910 --> 00:31:13,350
The FAA has grounded all air traffic in the United States.

337
00:31:13,520 --> 00:31:16,420
Unfortunately, the order came too late for two planes...

338
00:31:16,590 --> 00:31:19,580
...brought down by severe turbulence in the Midwest.

339
00:31:19,760 --> 00:31:22,730
-The first flight.... -So much for " one in a billion. "

340
00:31:26,260 --> 00:31:29,490
All right. All right, listen up, everybody. Listen up, please.

341
00:31:29,670 --> 00:31:32,730
We've got a lot of work to do, and we don't have much time...

342
00:31:32,900 --> 00:31:36,500
...so let's get started, please. Vorsteen?

343
00:31:37,070 --> 00:31:38,800
All our grid models are worthless.

344
00:31:38,980 --> 00:31:41,910
I don't think grid models are gonna be a lot of help here.

345
00:31:42,280 --> 00:31:45,540
Canadians report tremendous circulation moving from the Arctic.

346
00:31:45,720 --> 00:31:48,910
In Siberia, there's a low-pressure system never before seen.

347
00:31:49,090 --> 00:31:52,050
And Australia just saw the strongest typhoon ever recorded.

348
00:31:52,220 --> 00:31:55,820
-These things are interconnected? -We have to consider the possibility.

349
00:31:55,990 --> 00:31:59,930
The only force strong enough to affect global weather is the sun.

350
00:32:00,400 --> 00:32:02,830
-What's NASA have to say? -We've already checked.

351
00:32:03,000 --> 00:32:04,760
Solar output is normal.

352
00:32:04,930 --> 00:32:09,100
-What about the North Atlantic Current? -What about it?

353
00:32:10,140 --> 00:32:14,340
I got a call last night from Professor Rapson at the Hedland Center.

354
00:32:14,510 --> 00:32:16,840
He thinks the current has changed.

355
00:32:18,250 --> 00:32:20,240
Oh, come on, Jack. How could that be?

356
00:32:20,750 --> 00:32:23,740
The current depends upon a balance of salt and freshwater.

357
00:32:23,920 --> 00:32:26,480
-We all know that. -Yes...

358
00:32:26,660 --> 00:32:30,490
...but no one knows how much freshwater has been dumped into the ocean...

359
00:32:30,660 --> 00:32:33,150
...because of melting polar ice.

360
00:32:33,500 --> 00:32:37,260
I think we've hit a critical desalinization point.

361
00:32:39,370 --> 00:32:42,030
It would explain what's driving this extreme weather.

362
00:32:42,210 --> 00:32:45,000
Hedland had some pretty convincing data.

363
00:32:45,170 --> 00:32:46,820
They've asked me to feed it into

364
00:32:46,820 --> 00:32:49,300
my paleoclimate model to track the next events.

365
00:32:49,480 --> 00:32:52,850
Are you suggesting these weather anomalies are gonna continue?

366
00:32:53,320 --> 00:32:55,940
Not just continue. Get worse.

367
00:33:00,090 --> 00:33:03,990
I think we're on the verge of a major climate shift.

368
00:33:09,070 --> 00:33:11,360
What are you gonna tell the Administration?

369
00:33:11,530 --> 00:33:15,490
-What do you expect me to tell them? -The government has to make preparations.

370
00:33:15,670 --> 00:33:18,640
-You have a theory. -Give me the mainframe. I'll prove it.

371
00:33:18,810 --> 00:33:20,710
No.

372
00:33:23,580 --> 00:33:25,480
You have 48 hours.

373
00:33:26,550 --> 00:33:28,040
-Professor Hall. -Yes.

374
00:33:28,220 --> 00:33:31,120
-I think your theory may be correct. -Walk with me.

375
00:33:31,290 --> 00:33:34,750
Just a few weeks ago, I monitored the strongest hurricane on record.

376
00:33:34,920 --> 00:33:37,620
The hail, the tornados, it all fits.

377
00:33:37,790 --> 00:33:40,420
Can your model factor in storm scenarios?

378
00:33:40,600 --> 00:33:43,830
-We haven't had the time. -Well, maybe I can help.

379
00:33:44,000 --> 00:33:45,660
-Welcome aboard. -Thanks.

380
00:33:45,840 --> 00:33:47,860
Hi, I'm Jason.

381
00:33:48,040 --> 00:33:50,270
-Hi. -Hi.

382
00:33:52,310 --> 00:33:54,170
Do you have Peter's CT scan results?

383
00:33:54,340 --> 00:33:56,940
Yeah. The treatments shrunk the tumor 20 percent.

384
00:33:57,110 --> 00:33:59,910
-ls his eyesight better today? -No. No change.

385
00:34:09,990 --> 00:34:13,690
-Hi, Peter. How are you doing today? -A little better.

386
00:34:13,860 --> 00:34:15,490
Good.

387
00:34:16,170 --> 00:34:18,260
Let me listen here.

388
00:34:19,570 --> 00:34:20,830
Can you read that?

389
00:34:21,100 --> 00:34:25,400
No, but I remember the story from the pictures.

390
00:34:25,780 --> 00:34:27,070
You do?

391
00:34:27,340 --> 00:34:29,370
My mother used to read it to me.

392
00:34:29,850 --> 00:34:33,870
She must be very proud of you. You've been such a brave, big boy.

393
00:34:34,650 --> 00:34:37,590
-Thank you. -You're welcome.

394
00:34:38,250 --> 00:34:41,120
-Here you go. -Thank you.

395
00:34:45,600 --> 00:34:49,030
Jack, you've been working for 24 hours straight.

396
00:34:49,200 --> 00:34:51,930
You're the only one who hasn't taken a break.

397
00:34:53,240 --> 00:34:55,860
Maybe I'll try to shut my eyes for a while.

398
00:34:56,110 --> 00:34:58,200
Call me when you get the results.

399
00:35:02,550 --> 00:35:04,600
Frank, is he always so obsessive?

400
00:35:04,780 --> 00:35:06,750
-Yeah. -Yes.

401
00:35:08,890 --> 00:35:10,280
Does he ever lighten up?

402
00:35:10,450 --> 00:35:12,110
-Not really. -No.

403
00:35:15,630 --> 00:35:17,840
How long have you been working together?

404
00:35:17,840 --> 00:35:20,060
Well, Frank's been working with him...

405
00:35:20,230 --> 00:35:25,630
...since the Stone Age, but I've only had to endure two years of servitude.

406
00:35:33,310 --> 00:35:34,830
Jack.

407
00:35:35,010 --> 00:35:37,040
Jack, we got the results.

408
00:35:45,460 --> 00:35:47,790
Six to eight months? That can't be.

409
00:35:48,760 --> 00:35:51,590
That time scale isn't in months. It's in weeks.

410
00:35:55,630 --> 00:36:01,040
Flooding has caused numerous closures, including the Lincoln and Holland Tunnels.

411
00:36:01,300 --> 00:36:03,670
The plumbing in the school is really old.

412
00:36:03,670 --> 00:36:06,040
With this rain, the sewage got stopped up.

413
00:36:06,210 --> 00:36:07,680
Where are you staying?

414
00:36:07,840 --> 00:36:10,370
They're finding a place for us with kids here.

415
00:36:10,550 --> 00:36:13,010
You can't get home any sooner than tomorrow?

416
00:36:13,420 --> 00:36:17,150
Well, look, Dad, I would if I could, you know. It's just....

417
00:36:18,860 --> 00:36:21,220
This smell is unbearable, Dad.

418
00:36:21,390 --> 00:36:23,360
Stop kidding around! I want you home.

419
00:36:23,530 --> 00:36:25,220
Dad, I'll be on the train.

420
00:36:25,390 --> 00:36:28,490
Do me a favor. Just don't worry about me. I'll figure it out.

421
00:36:29,470 --> 00:36:32,730
All right, son. I'll see you tomorrow.

422
00:36:35,510 --> 00:36:37,840
Hey, Sam, guess what?

423
00:36:38,040 --> 00:36:40,200
We got a place to stay.

424
00:36:41,240 --> 00:36:42,540
Great.

425
00:36:42,710 --> 00:36:46,230
So far, the terrible weather hasn 't hit D.C.,

426
00:36:46,230 --> 00:36:48,080
but local residents aren 't taking chances...

427
00:36:48,250 --> 00:36:51,850
...as people stock up for what is already being billed as...

428
00:36:52,020 --> 00:36:54,510
-... the worst storm season on record. -Better be sure.

429
00:36:54,690 --> 00:36:56,820
-My ass is on the line. -You saw the model.

430
00:36:56,990 --> 00:36:59,360
And I hope to God it's wrong.

431
00:36:59,800 --> 00:37:01,490
-Mr. Vice President. -Tom.

432
00:37:01,660 --> 00:37:04,330
-You know Professor Hall. -Yes, we've met.

433
00:37:04,500 --> 00:37:07,730
Professor Hall has some information I think you should look at.

434
00:37:07,900 --> 00:37:10,740
We just got these results from our simulation model.

435
00:37:10,910 --> 00:37:14,070
-They explain what's causing this weather. -I'll read it later.

436
00:37:14,240 --> 00:37:17,540
-I have to meet with the director of FEMA-- -This is very urgent.

437
00:37:17,710 --> 00:37:22,080
Our climate is changing violently. It will happen over the next six to eight weeks.

438
00:37:22,250 --> 00:37:24,850
You said this wouldn't happen for another 1 00 years.

439
00:37:25,020 --> 00:37:27,680
-I was wrong. -Well, suppose you're wrong this time.

440
00:37:27,860 --> 00:37:31,020
I wish I were, but you're aware of what's happening everywhere.

441
00:37:31,190 --> 00:37:33,990
We're making all the necessary preparations for

442
00:37:34,000 --> 00:37:35,560
this storm. What more do you expect?

443
00:37:35,730 --> 00:37:39,600
You have to start thinking about large-scale evacuations right now.

444
00:37:39,770 --> 00:37:41,500
Especially in the Northern states.

445
00:37:41,670 --> 00:37:43,230
-Evacuations? -Yes.

446
00:37:43,410 --> 00:37:46,860
Have you lost your mind, Hall? I have to go.

447
00:37:47,940 --> 00:37:52,110
Mr. Vice President! If we don't act now, it's going to be too late.

448
00:37:56,150 --> 00:37:58,090
Come on, Jack.

449
00:37:58,450 --> 00:38:00,080
Thanks for bringing us here.

450
00:38:00,260 --> 00:38:04,120
I couldn't let you leave New York without seeing the Natural History Museum.

451
00:38:04,290 --> 00:38:07,160
Of course not. It's a fine collection of stuffed animals.

452
00:38:07,330 --> 00:38:08,660
Hey, guys, check this out.

453
00:38:09,070 --> 00:38:10,830
"The body of this mammoth was

454
00:38:10,830 --> 00:38:13,830
found perfectly preserved in the Siberian tundra...

455
00:38:14,500 --> 00:38:18,460
...with food still in its mouth and stomach...

456
00:38:18,810 --> 00:38:23,800
...indicating that it froze instantly while grazing."

457
00:38:28,850 --> 00:38:33,020
It's been 24 hours now since the snow started falling across the British Isles...

458
00:38:33,190 --> 00:38:36,250
...and over Northern Europe. It shows no signs of letting up.

459
00:38:36,430 --> 00:38:39,220
No, no, no. You ' ve got to stop worrying. No, no.

460
00:38:39,400 --> 00:38:43,160
It' s fine. We' ve got plenty of supplies. We're just snowed in.

461
00:38:43,570 --> 00:38:45,970
Yeah. No, it's all right. It's all right.

462
00:38:46,140 --> 00:38:48,160
No, you stay where you are. I'll be fine.

463
00:38:48,470 --> 00:38:51,240
Yeah, I love you too. Okay, bye.

464
00:38:52,580 --> 00:38:56,510
-Hey. How's Jeanette? -Oh, fine.

465
00:38:56,680 --> 00:38:58,650
The ferry just landed.

466
00:38:58,810 --> 00:39:00,810
Must be nice in Spain. Wish I was there.

467
00:39:00,980 --> 00:39:04,510
An elite RAF search-and-rescue team has been deployed by helicopter...

468
00:39:04,690 --> 00:39:07,350
...to airlift the royal family to safety.

469
00:39:07,690 --> 00:39:11,390
-Yeah, you think they'll come get us? -Not likely.

470
00:39:12,130 --> 00:39:16,570
Luckily we've got our own genny, enough tea and biscuits to sink a ship.

471
00:39:16,730 --> 00:39:18,670
Oh, we'll be fine.

472
00:39:18,830 --> 00:39:21,330
As long as the loo doesn't back up again.

473
00:39:41,520 --> 00:39:44,680
We've got zero visibility. Maintain heading and speed.

474
00:39:44,860 --> 00:39:47,260
-What's our heading? -035, sir.

475
00:39:47,330 --> 00:39:50,270
Approximately 40 kilometers from Balmoral Castle.

476
00:39:50,430 --> 00:39:53,030
We've lost visual contact with you.

477
00:40:16,890 --> 00:40:19,920
-This gauge can't be right. -Wind speed has dropped to zero.

478
00:40:20,100 --> 00:40:23,070
We have vertical walls of cirrus cloud formations.

479
00:40:23,470 --> 00:40:28,370
-What the hell is going on? -The bloody fuel lines are starting to freeze.

480
00:40:38,210 --> 00:40:41,950
Port engine pressure is dropping. The rotor rpm is dropping.

481
00:40:42,120 --> 00:40:45,280
We've got a flameout on the starboard side as well.

482
00:40:48,760 --> 00:40:50,850
Prepare for crash landing.

483
00:40:52,400 --> 00:40:54,890
Select emergency fuel.

484
00:40:55,430 --> 00:40:57,590
Come on, you bastard!

485
00:40:58,130 --> 00:40:59,970
Come on!

486
00:41:23,290 --> 00:41:26,090
What I'm about to say is supposed to be confidential.

487
00:41:26,260 --> 00:41:29,990
Several hours ago, three helicopters went down over Scotland.

488
00:41:30,170 --> 00:41:33,600
They crashed because the fuel in their lines froze.

489
00:41:34,470 --> 00:41:38,670
-At what temperature does--? -Negative 150 degrees Fahrenheit.

490
00:41:38,840 --> 00:41:40,140
We had to look it up.

491
00:41:40,310 --> 00:41:42,830
The temperature dropped phenomenally fast.

492
00:41:43,010 --> 00:41:46,710
On the ground, people froze before they could get out of their cars even.

493
00:41:46,880 --> 00:41:49,820
Can you get a satellite picture of Scotland two hours ago?

494
00:41:49,990 --> 00:41:52,150
We've got mountains of data...

495
00:41:52,320 --> 00:41:54,490
...but nowhere near enough computer power to

496
00:41:54,490 --> 00:41:56,120
analyze it. Can you help us?

497
00:41:56,490 --> 00:41:58,480
Send us what you got. We'll do our best.

498
00:41:58,660 --> 00:42:01,650
Thanks, Jack. Bye for now.

499
00:42:02,630 --> 00:42:06,120
This is Scotland at the time the temperature dropped.

500
00:42:08,570 --> 00:42:10,870
This thing looks just like a hurricane.

501
00:42:11,040 --> 00:42:14,010
Only hurricanes don't form over land.

502
00:42:21,480 --> 00:42:23,920
-Good evening, sir. -Hey, Harold.

503
00:42:24,090 --> 00:42:26,820
-Thanks, Victor. See you in the morning. -Right, sir.

504
00:42:26,990 --> 00:42:28,920
-Terrible weather. -Tell me about it.

505
00:42:33,500 --> 00:42:35,050
Wow.

506
00:42:36,800 --> 00:42:38,290
You live here?

507
00:42:38,470 --> 00:42:40,300
Just on the weekends.

508
00:42:40,470 --> 00:42:43,170
It's my dad's place. He's kind of never around, so....

509
00:42:43,340 --> 00:42:44,700
Where is he?

510
00:42:44,870 --> 00:42:48,040
Skiing in Europe with my stepmom.

511
00:42:50,850 --> 00:42:52,580
Is this you and your brother?

512
00:42:52,750 --> 00:42:55,880
Yeah, that's when we took a bike trip together.

513
00:43:00,120 --> 00:43:03,390
It's been raining like this for three days now.

514
00:43:13,940 --> 00:43:16,400
Come on, hurry up.

515
00:43:30,250 --> 00:43:31,620
I'm just standing here.

516
00:43:32,350 --> 00:43:33,620
You can't stay here.

517
00:43:34,060 --> 00:43:36,050
I never liked this neighborhood anyway.

518
00:43:36,230 --> 00:43:38,790
It's a mob scene here at Grand Central Station.

519
00:43:38,960 --> 00:43:44,160
Over half the platforms are flooded and service has been suspended on all trains.

520
00:43:44,330 --> 00:43:47,430
With planes still grounded and trains now out of service...

521
00:43:47,600 --> 00:43:49,330
... that's bad news for the....

522
00:43:49,510 --> 00:43:53,600
Victor' s coming to pick me up. You guys want a ride to the train station?

523
00:43:53,780 --> 00:43:55,040
Not anymore.

524
00:43:55,210 --> 00:43:57,210
In Nova Scotia earlier today the ocean

525
00:43:57,210 --> 00:44:00,610
rose by 25 feet in a matter of seconds.

526
00:44:00,780 --> 00:44:04,410
What we have feared for the past few days has indeed happened.

527
00:44:04,590 --> 00:44:06,680
The cold front moving from the Arctic...

528
00:44:06,860 --> 00:44:09,520
...has created an enormous storm system in Canada...

529
00:44:09,690 --> 00:44:13,530
... which, incredible as it sounds, looks more like a tropical hurricane....

530
00:44:13,700 --> 00:44:17,030
I gotta go pick up my little brother. Do you guys want a ride?

531
00:44:17,200 --> 00:44:20,430
-Where is he? -He's in a boarding school in Philadelphia.

532
00:44:20,600 --> 00:44:22,090
If this system moves south...

533
00:44:22,270 --> 00:44:26,870
...we could see a wind-driven storm surge threaten the entire Eastern Seaboard.

534
00:44:28,810 --> 00:44:30,070
Okay, bye.

535
00:44:30,250 --> 00:44:32,770
Victor' s stuck in traffic over on Fifth Avenue.

536
00:44:32,950 --> 00:44:36,110
It'll be easier to head out of town if we meet him over there.

537
00:44:36,290 --> 00:44:39,120
-You mean walk? -No, not in this.

538
00:44:42,990 --> 00:44:44,760
We should take the stairs.

539
00:44:44,930 --> 00:44:47,560
We're on the top floor.

540
00:44:50,530 --> 00:44:52,160
I guess we're walking.

541
00:45:05,310 --> 00:45:07,210
Maybe we should just stay here.

542
00:45:07,380 --> 00:45:08,980
I think the young lady is right.

543
00:45:09,390 --> 00:45:11,880
No. We need to get home.

544
00:45:36,510 --> 00:45:38,480
Hey, Cesar, come here.

545
00:45:39,080 --> 00:45:40,710
What are you doing?

546
00:45:45,820 --> 00:45:48,520
The wolves, they're gone.

547
00:45:48,690 --> 00:45:50,890
Just to give you an idea of the situation...

548
00:45:51,060 --> 00:45:54,190
...which seems to be becoming worse with each passing minute:

549
00:45:54,360 --> 00:45:57,920
A t the moment, we have flooding in most parts of the island.

550
00:45:58,100 --> 00:46:01,470
We've got traffic snarl-ups because the electricity is now out...

551
00:46:01,640 --> 00:46:05,160
... to almost every part of Manhattan. No traffic signals.

552
00:46:05,340 --> 00:46:07,670
Car accidents, at least two hundred.

553
00:46:07,840 --> 00:46:12,250
And lower Manhattan, we've been told, is virtually inaccessible.

554
00:46:33,470 --> 00:46:35,990
Can you call Mom? Will you please phone her for me?

555
00:46:36,170 --> 00:46:37,970
Hey.

556
00:46:38,610 --> 00:46:40,040
That dog can't come in here.

557
00:46:40,210 --> 00:46:42,700
Come on, man. It's pouring out there.

558
00:46:42,880 --> 00:46:45,070
I don't care. Read the sign.

559
00:46:45,070 --> 00:46:46,870


560
00:46:47,020 --> 00:46:49,810
It's supposed to be a public library.

561
00:46:56,090 --> 00:46:58,120
Come on, guys, this way.

562
00:46:58,690 --> 00:47:00,420
Excuse me. Your bad.

563
00:47:00,600 --> 00:47:03,790
Goddamn 1 500-dollar waterproof raincoat.

564
00:47:03,970 --> 00:47:06,870
-Please, shut up, man. -There must be rats everywhere.

565
00:47:07,040 --> 00:47:08,530
That's because it's New York.

566
00:47:08,700 --> 00:47:11,370
Hey! Hey!

567
00:47:11,740 --> 00:47:14,330
-Open up, big papa. -It's out of service.

568
00:47:14,940 --> 00:47:16,640
It's out of service.

569
00:47:16,810 --> 00:47:19,680
-I'll give you a 1 00 dollars. -You don't have to do that.

570
00:47:19,850 --> 00:47:22,510
No, really. 200 dollars. I won't have it.

571
00:47:22,680 --> 00:47:26,020
God, I love buses. This is so much fun. This is gonna be the bomb.

572
00:47:26,960 --> 00:47:28,250
Hello?

573
00:47:28,420 --> 00:47:31,090
-I can't reach my driver. No signal. -This is insane.

574
00:47:31,260 --> 00:47:33,920
We're not gonna be able to drive. We should go back.

575
00:47:34,100 --> 00:47:35,150
Yeah, I vote for that.

576
00:47:35,150 --> 00:47:37,500
Are you kidding? We have to get higher!

577
00:47:37,900 --> 00:47:39,330
Come on.

578
00:47:39,500 --> 00:47:41,700
Up to the library.

579
00:47:41,870 --> 00:47:44,500
Calm down.

580
00:47:44,670 --> 00:47:46,610
I can't understand what you're saying.

581
00:47:49,080 --> 00:47:51,240
If you stay calm, ma'am, I'll get you out.

582
00:47:56,850 --> 00:47:59,180
The door is jammed!

583
00:48:00,220 --> 00:48:01,550
I don't speak French!

584
00:48:37,130 --> 00:48:38,420
Hey, where's Laura?

585
00:48:40,500 --> 00:48:44,630
-She was just right there. -She's right there! Right there, see?

586
00:48:44,800 --> 00:48:46,270
What is she doing?

587
00:48:46,440 --> 00:48:49,170
Tell them to cover their eyes.

588
00:49:12,460 --> 00:49:16,990
There is a wall of water coming towards New York City. Everybody--

589
00:50:01,710 --> 00:50:04,010
-What? -Her bag's in the cab. Their passports.

590
00:50:04,180 --> 00:50:06,240
Forget about it.

591
00:50:06,410 --> 00:50:08,580
-I'll get it for her. -Come on.

592
00:50:15,160 --> 00:50:16,420
Oh, my....

593
00:50:22,560 --> 00:50:24,660
Laura!

594
00:50:29,440 --> 00:50:31,060
Laura!

595
00:50:32,070 --> 00:50:34,010
-Sam. -No! Brian, no!

596
00:50:34,180 --> 00:50:36,370
Laura! Laura, look!

597
00:50:36,550 --> 00:50:38,210
Come on. Come!

598
00:50:39,010 --> 00:50:40,610
Come on!

599
00:50:43,080 --> 00:50:44,480
Sam!

600
00:51:24,130 --> 00:51:25,690
Professor.

601
00:51:26,700 --> 00:51:28,100
Thank you.

602
00:51:29,500 --> 00:51:32,830
-ls that Neville's handiwork? -Neville's way beyond stick figures.

603
00:51:33,000 --> 00:51:34,800
-He's 6 already. -Oh.

604
00:51:34,970 --> 00:51:37,940
No, this masterpiece belongs to my second grandson, David.

605
00:51:38,110 --> 00:51:41,270
God. I can't believe Neville's 6 already.

606
00:51:45,110 --> 00:51:47,050
You won't believe how fast they grow.

607
00:51:49,390 --> 00:51:51,220
I've got Jack Hall on the phone.

608
00:51:51,620 --> 00:51:53,780
They've run the data we've sent them.

609
00:51:55,320 --> 00:51:56,880
Here he is.

610
00:51:59,730 --> 00:52:03,190
Jack, were you able to recreate the thermal cycle?

611
00:52:03,370 --> 00:52:05,230
Yes. The storm's rotation...

612
00:52:05,400 --> 00:52:09,570
...is pulling super-cooled air all the way down from the upper troposphere.

613
00:52:11,570 --> 00:52:15,570
But shouldn't the air warm up before it reaches ground level?

614
00:52:15,750 --> 00:52:20,050
It should. But it doesn 't. The air's descending too rapidly.

615
00:52:21,050 --> 00:52:23,580
Is this an isolated incident?

616
00:52:26,120 --> 00:52:28,020
I'm afraid not.

617
00:52:28,190 --> 00:52:30,310
We've located two supercells in addition to

618
00:52:30,310 --> 00:52:31,560
the one over Scotland.

619
00:52:31,730 --> 00:52:33,350
One over Northern Canada...

620
00:52:33,530 --> 00:52:36,520
...and another one over Siberia.

621
00:52:36,700 --> 00:52:39,330
And do we know their projected paths?

622
00:52:39,500 --> 00:52:40,800
Yes.

623
00:52:40,970 --> 00:52:44,240
Our previous estimates of six to eight weeks weren 't even close.

624
00:52:44,410 --> 00:52:47,930
This one storm is going to change the face of our planet.

625
00:52:48,110 --> 00:52:51,980
Here's a projection of 24 hours out.

626
00:52:56,720 --> 00:52:58,980
This is 48 hours out.

627
00:53:00,720 --> 00:53:03,620
And in seven to 1 0 days....

628
00:53:06,730 --> 00:53:08,990
When this storm is over...

629
00:53:09,170 --> 00:53:11,960
... we 'll be in a new ice age.

630
00:53:16,010 --> 00:53:17,870
My God.

631
00:53:36,130 --> 00:53:38,030
Professor...

632
00:53:38,190 --> 00:53:40,190
...it' s time you got out of there.

633
00:53:42,200 --> 00:53:45,360
I'm afraid that time has come and gone, my friend.

634
00:53:50,410 --> 00:53:52,700
What can we do?

635
00:53:55,910 --> 00:53:58,440
Save as many as you can.

636
00:54:13,360 --> 00:54:15,060
Jack...

637
00:54:15,230 --> 00:54:17,460
...something's happened in New York.

638
00:54:28,040 --> 00:54:30,880
No, the power is out. I've been in here all day.

639
00:54:31,050 --> 00:54:34,140
-Who needs help? -Here. Over here.

640
00:54:40,890 --> 00:54:42,550
What?

641
00:54:43,430 --> 00:54:46,690
This is the last one. Enjoy it.

642
00:54:46,860 --> 00:54:48,390
Greedy.

643
00:54:49,600 --> 00:54:51,970
All circuits are busy at this time.

644
00:54:52,130 --> 00:54:54,130
Listen, thanks for coming back for me.

645
00:54:55,940 --> 00:54:57,630
It was really brave.

646
00:55:09,720 --> 00:55:12,120
I guess I better return her bag.

647
00:55:29,410 --> 00:55:30,770
Sam?

648
00:55:31,270 --> 00:55:33,330
Just tell her how you feel.

649
00:55:37,380 --> 00:55:38,870
Yeah.

650
00:55:43,990 --> 00:55:47,650
-Did you reach your little brother yet? -No, there's still no service.

651
00:55:47,820 --> 00:55:49,850
Damn cell phones.

652
00:55:54,060 --> 00:55:57,360
Excuse me. Are there any pay phones on the upper floors?

653
00:55:57,530 --> 00:55:59,130
No, no, no.

654
00:55:59,300 --> 00:56:01,330
-There are some on the mezzanine. -Great.

655
00:56:01,500 --> 00:56:04,530
-But I think it's underwater. -Where you going? Power's out.

656
00:56:04,710 --> 00:56:07,200
Older payphones draw power directly from the line.

657
00:56:07,380 --> 00:56:09,320
There will be an emergency meeting of all

658
00:56:09,320 --> 00:56:10,900
NOAA department heads....

659
00:56:11,680 --> 00:56:14,550
Oh, God. I've been trying to reach Sam.

660
00:56:14,720 --> 00:56:16,450
So have l.

661
00:56:17,120 --> 00:56:19,050
I tried to call and couldn't get you.

662
00:56:19,220 --> 00:56:21,250
It's been a madhouse here. Come on.

663
00:56:26,900 --> 00:56:29,130
Are you sure about this?

664
00:56:39,210 --> 00:56:40,510
It works.

665
00:56:45,920 --> 00:56:47,410
I love that picture.

666
00:56:47,580 --> 00:56:49,780
Yeah, so do l.

667
00:56:50,750 --> 00:56:52,120
Where was that taken?

668
00:56:52,290 --> 00:56:53,590
Miami.

669
00:56:54,060 --> 00:56:56,420
Well, where was l? I don't remember that trip.

670
00:56:56,590 --> 00:56:59,390
Sam and I went with my sister. You were in Alaska...

671
00:56:59,560 --> 00:57:02,460
...doing research on your doctorate.

672
00:57:06,270 --> 00:57:09,240
Remember what he was like when he was that age?

673
00:57:09,740 --> 00:57:11,930
Everything was "one more."

674
00:57:12,110 --> 00:57:15,340
One more bedtime story. One more ride on my shoulders.

675
00:57:15,340 --> 00:57:17,050
"One more, Daddy."

676
00:57:18,880 --> 00:57:23,110
Jack. Sam's on the phone. Line four.

677
00:57:23,290 --> 00:57:25,150
-Sam? -Dad!

678
00:57:25,320 --> 00:57:29,420
-Where are you? Are you all right? -I'm all right. We're at the Public Library.

679
00:57:29,590 --> 00:57:32,490
-Sam, it's Mom. I'm so happy you're okay. -Mom.

680
00:57:33,330 --> 00:57:35,230
Can you call Laura and Brian's parents and tell

681
00:57:35,230 --> 00:57:36,790
them we're all right?

682
00:57:36,970 --> 00:57:38,460
Yes, of course.

683
00:57:39,670 --> 00:57:41,900
-Sam, what's that noise? -Sam?

684
00:57:42,340 --> 00:57:44,100
Sam?

685
00:57:46,310 --> 00:57:48,900
What is going on out there, Dad?

686
00:57:49,080 --> 00:57:51,210
Sam. Sam, listen to me.

687
00:57:51,380 --> 00:57:52,810
Listen very carefully.

688
00:57:52,980 --> 00:57:55,080
Forget what I said about heading south.

689
00:57:55,250 --> 00:57:57,450
It's too late. The storm is gonna get worse.

690
00:57:58,220 --> 00:58:00,310
It's gonna turn into a massive

691
00:58:00,310 --> 00:58:03,250
blizzard with an eye in the center, like a huge hurricane.

692
00:58:03,730 --> 00:58:05,190
Only the air will be so cold,

693
00:58:05,190 --> 00:58:06,820
you could freeze to death in seconds.

694
00:58:10,670 --> 00:58:11,930
Sam?

695
00:58:12,100 --> 00:58:14,700
-Well, what should we do? -Listen to me, son.

696
00:58:15,200 --> 00:58:16,870
Do not go outside.

697
00:58:17,040 --> 00:58:19,970
Burn what you can to stay warm, and try to wait it out.

698
00:58:20,140 --> 00:58:24,140
I will come for you. Do you understand me? I will come for you.

699
00:58:27,280 --> 00:58:28,510
Sam?

700
00:58:29,190 --> 00:58:31,710
-Sam, come back! -Sam?

701
00:58:32,350 --> 00:58:34,320
Sam, did you hear me?

702
00:58:34,490 --> 00:58:35,750
Did you hear me?

703
00:58:38,360 --> 00:58:39,830
Sam?

704
00:58:41,000 --> 00:58:44,960
-Tell me he's gonna be okay-- -He's gonna be all right.

705
00:58:45,130 --> 00:58:47,160
He's gonna be all right, you understand?

706
00:59:14,130 --> 00:59:16,890
I thought you'd drowned.

707
00:59:22,040 --> 00:59:25,470
Let's find some dry clothes for you. Come on.

708
00:59:31,450 --> 00:59:33,210
Where'd you store the arctic gear?

709
00:59:34,350 --> 00:59:36,180
You can't make it to New York, Jack.

710
00:59:36,350 --> 00:59:38,680
I've walked that far before in the snow.

711
00:59:39,560 --> 00:59:41,280
This is not the same.

712
00:59:41,460 --> 00:59:45,690
Jack, this is not the same. Lucy, tell him.

713
00:59:48,060 --> 00:59:50,220
I have to do this.

714
00:59:52,400 --> 00:59:54,390
I know.

715
01:00:01,140 --> 01:00:03,170
My hands are shak--

716
01:00:03,350 --> 01:00:06,780
-Shaking. -That's okay. Here.

717
01:00:06,950 --> 01:00:08,920
Here. Come here.

718
01:00:12,660 --> 01:00:14,490
What are you doing?

719
01:00:14,660 --> 01:00:17,130
I'm using my body heat to warm you.

720
01:00:17,390 --> 01:00:22,520
If we let the blood from your arms and legs rush back to your heart too quickly...

721
01:00:22,700 --> 01:00:25,220
...your heart could fail.

722
01:00:30,240 --> 01:00:32,730
Where did you learn that?

723
01:00:34,880 --> 01:00:38,750
Some of us were actually paying attention in health class.

724
01:00:41,150 --> 01:00:43,120
How are you feeling?

725
01:00:45,520 --> 01:00:47,350
Much better.

726
01:00:54,300 --> 01:00:56,700
Frank told me about Sam.

727
01:00:56,870 --> 01:01:01,030
I'm not gonna try to talk you out of going, but there's something I need first.

728
01:01:01,200 --> 01:01:03,970
You have to explain your results to the Administration.

729
01:01:04,140 --> 01:01:07,010
-I already tried that, Tom. -I know. It'll be different.

730
01:01:07,710 --> 01:01:09,840
You're gonna brief the president directly.

731
01:01:12,510 --> 01:01:14,610
-ls that the last of it? -Pretty much.

732
01:01:14,780 --> 01:01:16,380
Okay.

733
01:01:16,550 --> 01:01:19,580
We also found this radio, but I don't think it works.

734
01:01:19,990 --> 01:01:21,720
Let me see it.

735
01:01:28,200 --> 01:01:29,990
Buddha, keep quiet.

736
01:01:30,170 --> 01:01:32,860
You ain't even supposed to be in here anyway.

737
01:02:28,460 --> 01:02:29,860
Come on, guys.

738
01:02:37,000 --> 01:02:38,730
Oh, my God.

739
01:03:01,520 --> 01:03:03,720
The basic rule of storms is they continue...

740
01:03:03,890 --> 01:03:07,230
...until the imbalance that created them is corrected.

741
01:03:07,400 --> 01:03:10,160
In this case, we're talking about a global realignment.

742
01:03:11,300 --> 01:03:14,240
This superstorm will last seven to 1 0 days.

743
01:03:14,400 --> 01:03:19,500
When it's over, ice and snow will cover the entire Northern Hemisphere.

744
01:03:19,680 --> 01:03:22,240
The ice and snow will reflect sunlight.

745
01:03:22,410 --> 01:03:24,540
The Earth's atmosphere will restabilize...

746
01:03:24,710 --> 01:03:28,010
...with an average temperature close to that of the last lce Age.

747
01:03:30,350 --> 01:03:32,290
Well, what can we do about this?

748
01:03:33,820 --> 01:03:35,760
Head as far south as possible.

749
01:03:36,490 --> 01:03:38,080
That is not amusing, professor.

750
01:03:38,460 --> 01:03:40,520
Where do you suggest they go?

751
01:03:40,700 --> 01:03:43,130
The farther south they go, the safer they'll be.

752
01:03:43,300 --> 01:03:45,630
Texas. Parts of Florida that aren't flooded.

753
01:03:45,630 --> 01:03:47,960
Mexico would be best.

754
01:03:48,140 --> 01:03:51,730
Mexico? Maybe you should stick to science and leave policy to us.

755
01:03:51,910 --> 01:03:53,430
Well, we tried that approach.

756
01:03:53,610 --> 01:03:57,640
You didn't want to hear about the science when it could have made a difference.

757
01:03:59,480 --> 01:04:01,610
What exactly are you proposing, professor?

758
01:04:08,090 --> 01:04:13,220
Evacuate everyone south of that line.

759
01:04:18,890 --> 01:04:20,880
What about the people in the North?

760
01:04:23,230 --> 01:04:25,600
I'm afraid it's too late for them.

761
01:04:25,770 --> 01:04:27,930
If they go outside...

762
01:04:28,100 --> 01:04:30,040
...the storm will kill them.

763
01:04:33,340 --> 01:04:35,140
At this point...

764
01:04:36,210 --> 01:04:38,980
...their best chance is to stay inside.

765
01:04:40,080 --> 01:04:42,210
Try to ride it out.

766
01:04:42,980 --> 01:04:44,450
Pray.

767
01:04:49,520 --> 01:04:51,050
What do you think he'll do?

768
01:04:51,230 --> 01:04:53,090
I don't know.

769
01:04:53,260 --> 01:04:54,560
Jack...

770
01:04:55,460 --> 01:04:56,860
...thanks...

771
01:04:57,030 --> 01:04:58,400
...and good luck.

772
01:04:58,570 --> 01:05:00,300
You too.

773
01:05:02,370 --> 01:05:04,460
We're all gonna need it.

774
01:05:07,440 --> 01:05:11,130
We can't evacuate half the country because one scientist

775
01:05:11,130 --> 01:05:12,500
thinks the climate is shifting.

776
01:05:12,680 --> 01:05:15,100
Every minute we delay costs lives.

777
01:05:15,100 --> 01:05:16,620
What about the other half of the country?

778
01:05:16,780 --> 01:05:19,080
If Professor Hall is right about this storm...

779
01:05:19,250 --> 01:05:21,690
...sending troops north will create more victims.

780
01:05:21,860 --> 01:05:24,260
We need to save the people we can right now.

781
01:05:24,430 --> 01:05:27,490
We take the same approach in triage on the battlefield.

782
01:05:27,660 --> 01:05:30,690
Sometimes it's necessary to make difficult choices--

783
01:05:30,870 --> 01:05:33,770
I don't accept abandoning half the country as necessary.

784
01:05:33,940 --> 01:05:36,270
Maybe if you listened sooner, it wouldn't be.

785
01:05:36,440 --> 01:05:38,870
Bullshit. It's easy for him to suggest this plan.

786
01:05:39,040 --> 01:05:42,370
-He's safely here in Washington. -His son is in Manhattan.

787
01:05:45,880 --> 01:05:49,280
I thought you should know before you start questioning his motives.

788
01:05:51,790 --> 01:05:53,520
We're going to follow Hall's plan.

789
01:05:55,890 --> 01:05:57,320
-General. -Sir?

790
01:05:57,490 --> 01:06:00,820
Give the order for the National Guard to evacuate Southern states.

791
01:06:01,000 --> 01:06:02,620
Yes, sir.

792
01:06:17,140 --> 01:06:18,740
Vivian...

793
01:06:18,910 --> 01:06:20,740
...get me my wife.

794
01:06:39,700 --> 01:06:43,160
Sorry, mates, but we're just about out of petrol.

795
01:06:46,440 --> 01:06:47,870
Hey.

796
01:06:48,410 --> 01:06:50,000
Is there any chance...

797
01:06:50,610 --> 01:06:52,080
...that it'll run...

798
01:06:53,350 --> 01:06:55,250
...on this?

799
01:06:55,420 --> 01:06:57,010
Are you mad?

800
01:06:57,180 --> 01:06:59,550
That's a 1 2-year-old Scotch.

801
01:07:21,340 --> 01:07:22,600
Gentlemen.

802
01:07:23,540 --> 01:07:25,710
To England.

803
01:07:26,580 --> 01:07:28,450
To mankind.

804
01:07:30,520 --> 01:07:32,380
To Manchester United.

805
01:07:40,230 --> 01:07:41,520
I just....

806
01:07:41,700 --> 01:07:45,630
I just wish I could have seen him grow up. You know?

807
01:07:49,300 --> 01:07:52,140
The important thing is he will grow up.

808
01:07:57,140 --> 01:07:58,940
Amen.

809
01:08:15,500 --> 01:08:18,260
Maybe you should have somebody help you with that.

810
01:08:18,900 --> 01:08:21,700
Sir, I am president of the Electronics Club...

811
01:08:21,870 --> 01:08:24,130
...the Math Club and the Chess Club.

812
01:08:24,310 --> 01:08:27,370
Now, if there's a bigger nerd in here, please, point him out.

813
01:08:29,740 --> 01:08:32,680
I'll just leave you alone to work on it, okay?

814
01:08:33,950 --> 01:08:36,970
Come on, Buddha, come on. Do your business.

815
01:08:37,150 --> 01:08:39,950
Look, there's nobody around.

816
01:08:40,120 --> 01:08:42,990
You know what? I'll turn around. I won't look. I promise.

817
01:08:47,190 --> 01:08:48,860
What?

818
01:08:55,570 --> 01:08:57,400
Hey, man, there's people out there.

819
01:08:57,840 --> 01:08:59,140
I was walking my dog.

820
01:08:59,310 --> 01:09:03,330
There's hundreds of them. They're walking on the snow.

821
01:09:11,320 --> 01:09:12,840
Where they all going?

822
01:09:13,020 --> 01:09:15,890
They're getting out of the city before it's too late.

823
01:09:19,060 --> 01:09:22,030
All right, everybody. Quiet down.

824
01:09:22,200 --> 01:09:25,170
When was the last time anyone got a signal on a cell phone?

825
01:09:25,330 --> 01:09:27,930
I got through to my cousin in Memphis an hour ago.

826
01:09:28,100 --> 01:09:29,970
They're being evacuated to the South.

827
01:09:30,140 --> 01:09:31,660
We should get moving too.

828
01:09:31,840 --> 01:09:34,470
The water is frozen over enough to walk on.

829
01:09:34,640 --> 01:09:37,870
We should get going before the snow gets too deep.

830
01:09:38,050 --> 01:09:41,670
Everyone, wrap yourselves up as fast as you can.

831
01:09:41,850 --> 01:09:43,280
We shouldn't go.

832
01:09:43,450 --> 01:09:45,320
Why not, Sam? Everyone's leaving.

833
01:09:45,490 --> 01:09:48,180
When I talked to my dad, he told me to stay inside.

834
01:09:48,360 --> 01:09:50,080
The storm will kill anybody in it.

835
01:09:50,260 --> 01:09:53,020
-Then you have to say something. -I know.

836
01:09:57,130 --> 01:09:59,660
Excuse me, sir, you're making a mistake.

837
01:09:59,830 --> 01:10:02,770
What? Listen, we're all scared, but we've got no choice.

838
01:10:02,940 --> 01:10:04,530
-That's not it. -Get ready to go.

839
01:10:04,710 --> 01:10:08,160
If these people go outside, they will freeze to death!

840
01:10:09,040 --> 01:10:10,810
Okay, what is this nonsense?

841
01:10:10,980 --> 01:10:14,640
It's not nonsense. All right? Look, this storm is gonna get worse.

842
01:10:14,820 --> 01:10:17,250
The people caught outside will freeze to death.

843
01:10:17,420 --> 01:10:20,180
-Where are you getting this? -My dad's a climatologist.

844
01:10:20,350 --> 01:10:22,980
-He works for the government. -So what do we do?

845
01:10:23,160 --> 01:10:25,820
We stay inside, we keep warm, and we wait it out.

846
01:10:25,990 --> 01:10:28,120
The snow is getting deeper by the minute.

847
01:10:28,300 --> 01:10:30,860
We'd be trapped here without food, supplies....

848
01:10:31,030 --> 01:10:33,120
-It's a risk, yeah-- -An unnecessary risk.

849
01:10:33,300 --> 01:10:34,560
No, no. It's not.

850
01:10:34,740 --> 01:10:37,140
We've wasted enough time talking. Come on.

851
01:10:37,300 --> 01:10:38,640
Let's go.

852
01:10:38,810 --> 01:10:42,170
-Look, look. Just look for a second. -Come on, everybody--

853
01:10:42,340 --> 01:10:45,780
This storm is gonna get bad. It's gonna get really, really bad.

854
01:10:45,950 --> 01:10:48,070
You're not gonna be able to survive it.

855
01:10:49,350 --> 01:10:50,650
Believe me.

856
01:10:50,820 --> 01:10:55,120
Sir, please just stay. Just stay.

857
01:10:55,960 --> 01:10:58,120
Just don't....

858
01:11:27,220 --> 01:11:30,350
-She's set to go. -Come on, straight to the back, guys.

859
01:11:30,520 --> 01:11:32,580
It'll be impossible to reach each other.

860
01:11:32,760 --> 01:11:35,420
Leave a message for me at the embassy in Mexico City.

861
01:11:35,600 --> 01:11:36,820
Okay, I will.

862
01:11:38,470 --> 01:11:39,960
I love you.

863
01:11:43,340 --> 01:11:45,740
I love you, Jack.

864
01:11:46,570 --> 01:11:49,470
Tell Sam I love him so much.

865
01:11:50,980 --> 01:11:52,910
God be with you.

866
01:12:00,090 --> 01:12:02,110
-Doctor Hall? -Yeah.

867
01:12:02,290 --> 01:12:04,660
We haven't been able to reach Peter's parents.

868
01:12:04,830 --> 01:12:08,420
-I'm gonna try later, okay? -Okay. Thank you.

869
01:12:15,800 --> 01:12:17,630
I got it.

870
01:12:18,610 --> 01:12:21,230
You're supposed to be on a bus heading south.

871
01:12:21,410 --> 01:12:25,900
I've been watching your back for 20 years. You think I'd let you go alone?

872
01:12:26,080 --> 01:12:29,310
And all these years I thought I was watching your back.

873
01:12:29,480 --> 01:12:31,250
Where are the keys?

874
01:12:31,420 --> 01:12:33,180
In the truck.

875
01:12:33,750 --> 01:12:36,150
Where do you think you're going?

876
01:12:36,320 --> 01:12:38,760
Neither one of you can navigate worth a damn.

877
01:12:38,930 --> 01:12:40,920
Without me, you'll end up in Cleveland.

878
01:12:43,130 --> 01:12:46,360
I'll try to give you updates on the storm as it heads your way.

879
01:12:46,900 --> 01:12:48,830
Good luck, Jack.

880
01:13:02,580 --> 01:13:05,280
Breaking news from the U.S.-Mexico border.

881
01:13:05,450 --> 01:13:08,820
Just half an hour ago, Mexican officials closed the border...

882
01:13:08,990 --> 01:13:12,650
...in the light of so many U.S. refugees who are fleeing south...

883
01:13:12,830 --> 01:13:15,060
...in the wake of the approaching storm.

884
01:13:15,230 --> 01:13:18,220
These people came in anticipation of crossing into Mexico.

885
01:13:18,400 --> 01:13:20,590
Instead, they've been met with closed gates.

886
01:13:20,770 --> 01:13:24,070
And now, in a dramatic reversal of illegal immigration...

887
01:13:24,240 --> 01:13:27,800
...thousands of people are crossing the Rio Grande into Mexico.

888
01:13:27,980 --> 01:13:31,670
The scene unfolding here behind me is one of desperation and frustration.

889
01:13:31,850 --> 01:13:35,340
People have abandoned their cars, grabbed their belongings...

890
01:13:35,520 --> 01:13:40,110
...and they are wading across the river illegally into Mexico.

891
01:13:42,520 --> 01:13:44,120
Here it is.

892
01:13:45,630 --> 01:13:48,990
This fireplace probably hasn't been used in about 1 00 years.

893
01:13:51,730 --> 01:13:53,390
All right.

894
01:13:59,940 --> 01:14:02,700
-What are you doing? -What did you think we would burn?

895
01:14:03,080 --> 01:14:06,200
-You can't burn books. -No, absolutely not.

896
01:14:06,380 --> 01:14:08,140
You want to freeze to death?

897
01:14:11,250 --> 01:14:13,310
I'll go get some more.

898
01:14:13,490 --> 01:14:14,950
I'll help you.

899
01:14:15,420 --> 01:14:17,520
I'm going with them.

900
01:14:18,830 --> 01:14:21,290
Okay, do you have a cafeteria or a lunchroom?

901
01:14:21,460 --> 01:14:24,300
Just an employees' lounge with a few vending machines.

902
01:14:32,210 --> 01:14:34,800
We're not gonna last long on M&M's and potato chips.

903
01:14:34,980 --> 01:14:37,100
What about the garbage cans?

904
01:14:37,280 --> 01:14:39,840
There's always something to eat in the garbage.

905
01:14:43,950 --> 01:14:46,610
Friedrich Nietzsche? We can't burn Nietzsche.

906
01:14:46,790 --> 01:14:49,780
He was the most important thinker of the 1 9th century.

907
01:14:49,960 --> 01:14:52,930
Please. He was a chauvinist pig in love with his sister.

908
01:14:53,160 --> 01:14:54,720
He was not a chauvinist pig.

909
01:14:55,230 --> 01:14:57,220
But he was in love with his sister.

910
01:14:57,400 --> 01:14:59,060
Excuse me? You guys?

911
01:14:59,230 --> 01:15:03,400
Yeah, there's a whole section on tax law down here that we can burn.

912
01:15:03,570 --> 01:15:06,970
After hours of uncertainty, the traffic is now moving smoothly...

913
01:15:07,140 --> 01:15:09,340
...from the United States into Mexico.

914
01:15:09,510 --> 01:15:13,380
This is only possible because the president was able to negotiate a deal...

915
01:15:13,550 --> 01:15:15,910
...to forgive all Latin American debt

916
01:15:15,920 --> 01:15:17,950
in exchange for opening the border.

917
01:15:18,120 --> 01:15:22,280
Now, multitudes of American families are feeling a rush of relief....

918
01:15:25,960 --> 01:15:27,650
Lucy?

919
01:15:33,570 --> 01:15:35,060
Is Peter' s ambulance here?

920
01:15:35,240 --> 01:15:36,900
No.

921
01:15:42,110 --> 01:15:44,580
-Why? -They' ve all gone.

922
01:15:44,750 --> 01:15:46,300
-What? -ln the confusion...

923
01:15:46,480 --> 01:15:48,130
... I don ' t know what happened.

924
01:15:48,130 --> 01:15:50,180
People started to panic, and they left....

925
01:15:50,350 --> 01:15:52,610
-God. -There's a policeman with a snowplow.

926
01:15:52,790 --> 01:15:55,220
-He's waiting outside. -God.

927
01:15:55,390 --> 01:15:57,880
Peter can't be moved in anything but an ambulance.

928
01:15:58,660 --> 01:16:02,930
I called and left a message for the county ambulance service.

929
01:16:10,600 --> 01:16:12,130
Okay.

930
01:16:14,440 --> 01:16:16,810
Okay, you should go, and I'll stay and wait.

931
01:16:17,380 --> 01:16:18,640
Lucy, no.

932
01:16:18,810 --> 01:16:20,640
-No. -No, you should go.

933
01:16:20,810 --> 01:16:22,750
He's not gonna wait forever.

934
01:16:22,920 --> 01:16:24,820
It's okay.

935
01:16:27,350 --> 01:16:29,350
I'm sorry.

936
01:16:30,120 --> 01:16:33,060
-It's okay. -All right.

937
01:17:01,390 --> 01:17:02,980
You all right?

938
01:17:03,160 --> 01:17:06,150
Yeah, I'm fine. I just-- I cut my leg the other day.

939
01:17:10,300 --> 01:17:11,590
Did you get a signal?

940
01:17:11,770 --> 01:17:13,860
Yeah, for a minute.

941
01:17:14,030 --> 01:17:15,330
And?

942
01:17:19,310 --> 01:17:21,500
Man, this storm is everywhere.

943
01:17:21,680 --> 01:17:24,080
It's hit the entire Northern Hemisphere.

944
01:17:24,780 --> 01:17:27,340
Europe is buried under 1 5 feet of snow...

945
01:17:27,510 --> 01:17:30,240
...and they say it's gonna get just as bad here.

946
01:17:30,820 --> 01:17:33,580
I mean, I don't think your dad's gonna make it.

947
01:17:37,420 --> 01:17:39,020
No, he'll make it.

948
01:17:43,760 --> 01:17:45,630
He'll make it.

949
01:17:50,200 --> 01:17:53,040
The White House has ordered a national disaster alert...

950
01:17:53,210 --> 01:17:54,610
...for all Northern states.

951
01:17:54,780 --> 01:17:57,510
Continued exposure to the approaching storm is deadly.

952
01:17:57,680 --> 01:18:01,670
Remain indoors and take all measures to stay warm, burning any fuel sources...

953
01:18:01,850 --> 01:18:05,550
...until the storm is over. Roads are impassable across New York State...

954
01:18:05,720 --> 01:18:08,020
...as far south as Pennsylvania....

955
01:18:08,190 --> 01:18:10,160
Where are we?

956
01:18:12,160 --> 01:18:15,030
Looks like we' re just north of Philadelphia.

957
01:18:18,300 --> 01:18:19,930
Look out!

958
01:18:24,270 --> 01:18:26,030
You guys okay?

959
01:18:26,210 --> 01:18:27,570
-Yeah. -Yeah.

960
01:18:33,650 --> 01:18:36,640
-Once again, roads across the.... -Sorry, boss.

961
01:18:37,580 --> 01:18:39,980
Unpack the snowshoes.

962
01:18:40,150 --> 01:18:42,090
We're walking from here.

963
01:18:43,660 --> 01:18:46,490
Come on, ma'am. Let's get up and get going.

964
01:18:47,660 --> 01:18:51,360
We've only made it to Brooklyn. Maybe we should just turn back.

965
01:18:51,530 --> 01:18:55,130
Why? Half the city's frozen under water. There's nothing to go back to.

966
01:18:55,300 --> 01:18:56,860
Time to get up and keep moving.

967
01:18:57,040 --> 01:18:59,870
What we should've done is stayed in the library.

968
01:19:01,480 --> 01:19:04,210
Okay, guys, let's get moving.

969
01:19:13,750 --> 01:19:15,720
Wake up.

970
01:19:33,310 --> 01:19:34,770
What are you doing?

971
01:19:34,940 --> 01:19:36,670
Insulating.

972
01:19:36,840 --> 01:19:39,310
Newspaper's best, but this'll do.

973
01:19:39,610 --> 01:19:43,480
You know, you spend some years on the streets and you learn how to keep warm.

974
01:19:44,550 --> 01:19:46,380
Hey.

975
01:19:51,660 --> 01:19:53,420
Thanks.

976
01:19:57,160 --> 01:19:59,130
I got one.

977
01:19:59,300 --> 01:20:01,360
Your favorite vacation.

978
01:20:03,070 --> 01:20:05,040
Besides this one?

979
01:20:06,010 --> 01:20:07,300
All right.

980
01:20:07,470 --> 01:20:11,710
I went to Greenland with my dad on one of his research trips a few years ago...

981
01:20:14,080 --> 01:20:18,610
...and the ship broke down, and we got stuck.

982
01:20:19,690 --> 01:20:22,250
And it rained constantly.

983
01:20:24,120 --> 01:20:26,420
That sounds really boring.

984
01:20:27,590 --> 01:20:30,090
But actually really nice, you know?

985
01:20:30,260 --> 01:20:33,660
Just me and my dad hanging out for 1 0 days.

986
01:21:46,310 --> 01:21:48,000
Frank!

987
01:21:48,380 --> 01:21:50,000
Are you all right?

988
01:21:50,180 --> 01:21:51,400
I'm fine.

989
01:21:53,150 --> 01:21:55,840
I just dropped in to do a little shopping.

990
01:21:57,180 --> 01:21:58,740
I gotta lose this sled.

991
01:22:15,000 --> 01:22:17,830
Hold on! We'll pull you up.

992
01:22:20,270 --> 01:22:23,270
Jason! You've got to support Frank's weight.

993
01:22:23,440 --> 01:22:26,210
Okay, I'll try.

994
01:22:32,590 --> 01:22:35,210
Okay, I think I have his weight now.

995
01:22:35,390 --> 01:22:37,120
I'm coming to you.

996
01:22:49,840 --> 01:22:52,430
The glass is breaking!

997
01:22:54,610 --> 01:22:56,070
Too much weight.

998
01:22:59,980 --> 01:23:01,500
It's not gonna hold.

999
01:23:11,320 --> 01:23:12,550
No. No.

1000
01:23:12,990 --> 01:23:15,890
Frank. I can get you out.

1001
01:23:18,260 --> 01:23:19,750
Don't do it!

1002
01:23:19,930 --> 01:23:22,330
-No, Frank, no! -Frank, no!

1003
01:23:24,000 --> 01:23:25,870
Frank!

1004
01:24:09,380 --> 01:24:11,280
What have you got there?

1005
01:24:12,190 --> 01:24:14,590
A Gutenberg Bible.

1006
01:24:14,790 --> 01:24:17,090
It was in the rare books room.

1007
01:24:18,390 --> 01:24:20,090
You think God's gonna save you?

1008
01:24:20,860 --> 01:24:23,620
No. I don't believe in God.

1009
01:24:24,300 --> 01:24:26,960
You're holding onto that Bible pretty tight.

1010
01:24:27,130 --> 01:24:29,120
I'm protecting it.

1011
01:24:32,640 --> 01:24:36,130
This Bible is the first book ever printed.

1012
01:24:36,980 --> 01:24:41,940
It represents the dawn of the age of reason.

1013
01:24:42,320 --> 01:24:46,340
As far as I'm concerned, the written word is mankind's greatest achievement.

1014
01:24:46,690 --> 01:24:48,240
You can laugh.

1015
01:24:49,220 --> 01:24:52,350
But if Western civilization is finished...

1016
01:24:52,990 --> 01:24:56,990
...I'm gonna save at least one little piece of it.

1017
01:25:33,730 --> 01:25:35,860
We heard somebody was left behind.

1018
01:25:36,800 --> 01:25:40,500
-We brought an ambulance. -Thank God.

1019
01:25:42,980 --> 01:25:45,710
Thank you so much for coming.

1020
01:26:06,630 --> 01:26:08,160
Hey.

1021
01:26:09,070 --> 01:26:11,260
Hey, are you all right?

1022
01:26:12,510 --> 01:26:14,700
You look like you have a fever or something.

1023
01:26:14,870 --> 01:26:18,000
I'm fine. I just can't sleep.

1024
01:26:20,910 --> 01:26:26,440
My mind keeps going over all those worthless decathlon facts.

1025
01:26:28,050 --> 01:26:30,350
-It's pretty stupid, huh? -No, it's all right.

1026
01:26:30,520 --> 01:26:34,020
I guess you just haven't had time to adjust yet.

1027
01:26:35,800 --> 01:26:38,390
How am I supposed to adjust, Sam?

1028
01:26:38,970 --> 01:26:42,900
Everything I've ever cared about, everything I've worked for...

1029
01:26:43,440 --> 01:26:47,070
...has all been preparation for a future that no longer exists.

1030
01:26:50,540 --> 01:26:54,570
I know you always thought I took the competition too seriously.

1031
01:26:55,880 --> 01:26:57,710
You were right.

1032
01:26:58,320 --> 01:27:01,290
-lt was all for nothing. -No, no. I--

1033
01:27:02,220 --> 01:27:06,490
No, I just-- I just said that to avoid admitting the truth.

1034
01:27:07,890 --> 01:27:09,560
Truth about what?

1035
01:27:13,600 --> 01:27:16,970
About why I joined the team.

1036
01:27:22,110 --> 01:27:24,270
I joined it because of you.

1037
01:27:37,360 --> 01:27:38,820
Hey.

1038
01:28:04,620 --> 01:28:06,350
I know.

1039
01:28:06,690 --> 01:28:07,910
I know.

1040
01:28:08,090 --> 01:28:10,180
-Mr. President. -All right.

1041
01:28:10,890 --> 01:28:13,290
I'm sorry, sir, we can't wait any longer.

1042
01:28:13,860 --> 01:28:15,850
We're the last ones.

1043
01:28:16,760 --> 01:28:18,320
All right.

1044
01:28:33,350 --> 01:28:36,710
Mexicali Control, this is Delta 26.

1045
01:28:35,110 --> 01:28:36,710


1046
01:28:36,720 --> 01:28:38,680
We've got an urgent message for high command.

1047
01:28:38,850 --> 01:28:41,050
Request priority for landing zone one.

1048
01:28:41,220 --> 01:28:45,180
Roger that, Delta 26. Transport will be waiting.

1049
01:28:50,260 --> 01:28:51,630
-Sir. -Thank you, corporal.

1050
01:28:51,800 --> 01:28:53,990
-Sorry for the delay, sir. -Carry on.

1051
01:29:06,780 --> 01:29:08,640
Madam Secretary.

1052
01:29:18,190 --> 01:29:19,820
Raymond.

1053
01:29:20,760 --> 01:29:23,250
The president's motorcade got caught in the storm.

1054
01:29:28,330 --> 01:29:29,930
They didn't make it.

1055
01:29:36,310 --> 01:29:38,830
And she wouldn't wake up this morning. I--

1056
01:29:39,010 --> 01:29:41,450
She only had a fever. I don't understand.

1057
01:29:41,610 --> 01:29:43,780
She's awfully pale.

1058
01:29:44,020 --> 01:29:46,480
None of us has had anything real to eat in days.

1059
01:29:46,650 --> 01:29:49,640
-It's hypothermia. -But how can it be hypothermia?

1060
01:29:49,820 --> 01:29:51,880
-We've all been in-- -Maybe it's the flu.

1061
01:29:52,060 --> 01:29:54,360
No, no, it's not the flu.

1062
01:29:55,600 --> 01:29:56,790
And how do you know?

1063
01:29:57,300 --> 01:30:00,890
Books can be good for things other than burning. What are her symptoms?

1064
01:30:01,070 --> 01:30:04,800
I told you that she has a fever and her-- She's got a really cold sweat.

1065
01:30:04,970 --> 01:30:06,730
How's her pulse?

1066
01:30:07,170 --> 01:30:09,570
-It's really fast. -Does she have any injuries?

1067
01:30:09,740 --> 01:30:12,270
Like a cut that might have gotten infected?

1068
01:30:12,450 --> 01:30:15,940
She was complaining about a cut on her leg a few days ago.

1069
01:30:16,480 --> 01:30:19,320
I didn't think anything of it.

1070
01:30:23,790 --> 01:30:25,490
Oh, my gosh.

1071
01:30:26,730 --> 01:30:29,850
That's blood poisoning. Septicemia.

1072
01:30:30,030 --> 01:30:32,160
She could go into septic shock.

1073
01:30:32,330 --> 01:30:34,420
I've seen that before. That can get bad.

1074
01:30:34,600 --> 01:30:36,630
She needs a massive dose of penicillin...

1075
01:30:36,800 --> 01:30:40,400
...or a broad-spectrum antibiotic immediately, or....

1076
01:30:46,180 --> 01:30:47,770
Or what?

1077
01:31:07,600 --> 01:31:09,900
I've never seen anything like it.

1078
01:31:10,100 --> 01:31:13,730
There's no point of reference. All I can see is cloud cover.

1079
01:31:13,910 --> 01:31:15,400
What are you doing?

1080
01:31:15,580 --> 01:31:17,910
Taking infrared image of thermal currents.

1081
01:31:18,080 --> 01:31:22,810
Send to Houston, Korolev, your weather service.

1082
01:31:22,980 --> 01:31:24,570
I'll help you.

1083
01:31:25,650 --> 01:31:28,090
Tom? Tom, wake up.

1084
01:31:28,250 --> 01:31:32,620
I just received some satellite images from the space station. You better take a look.

1085
01:31:44,170 --> 01:31:45,690
How big is this thing?

1086
01:31:45,870 --> 01:31:47,900
The vortex is 50 miles in diameter.

1087
01:31:48,070 --> 01:31:51,740
And growing. The two cells over Europe and Asia are even bigger.

1088
01:31:51,910 --> 01:31:53,210
Good God.

1089
01:31:53,380 --> 01:31:56,310
This one's gonna hit New York inside an hour.

1090
01:32:12,800 --> 01:32:14,290
Jason!

1091
01:32:14,470 --> 01:32:16,090
Are you all right?

1092
01:32:16,570 --> 01:32:18,370
Jason!

1093
01:32:34,320 --> 01:32:37,620
-What are you doing? -There's gotta be medicine on that ship.

1094
01:32:38,160 --> 01:32:41,320
I thought you said it was too dangerous to go outside.

1095
01:32:41,490 --> 01:32:42,830
I know I did.

1096
01:32:49,140 --> 01:32:51,540
Where did you find those chairs?

1097
01:32:52,870 --> 01:32:54,240
Why?

1098
01:32:55,110 --> 01:32:56,630
I'm going with you.

1099
01:32:58,140 --> 01:32:59,610
Me too.

1100
01:34:03,110 --> 01:34:05,010
Come on, damn it!

1101
01:34:53,690 --> 01:34:56,130
-It's all in Russian. I-- -I know.

1102
01:34:56,530 --> 01:34:59,760
-Hey, hey, hey, guys. I found it. -What? How do you know?

1103
01:35:00,270 --> 01:35:02,560
Because it says "penicillin" on the bottle.

1104
01:35:07,940 --> 01:35:09,640
Hey, wait. This is the mess hall.

1105
01:35:09,810 --> 01:35:12,180
-We should find some food. -We don't have time.

1106
01:35:12,340 --> 01:35:16,340
Listen, none of us are gonna survive much longer without food. Including Laura.

1107
01:35:17,620 --> 01:35:18,910
Okay.

1108
01:35:23,790 --> 01:35:26,380
-Sam, over here. -What?

1109
01:35:26,930 --> 01:35:28,620
Bingo.

1110
01:35:39,670 --> 01:35:41,300
Brian?

1111
01:35:42,010 --> 01:35:44,700
-I'm okay. -What happened?

1112
01:35:45,710 --> 01:35:47,770
All I did was open up the cupboard.

1113
01:35:48,650 --> 01:35:51,120
-Well, we can use it. -Put food in it.

1114
01:36:04,030 --> 01:36:06,000
Pull him in, Brian!

1115
01:36:08,570 --> 01:36:11,900
-You all right? -Oh, my God, there's more.

1116
01:36:14,110 --> 01:36:15,900
My leg.

1117
01:36:19,750 --> 01:36:21,680
Here, use this.

1118
01:36:29,320 --> 01:36:31,290
It should be over New York by now.

1119
01:36:32,160 --> 01:36:36,650
Satellite readings are showing a temperature drop of 1 0 degrees per second.

1120
01:36:52,240 --> 01:36:53,640
You guys...

1121
01:36:53,810 --> 01:36:55,870
...I think we're in the eye of it.

1122
01:36:56,980 --> 01:36:58,850
We gotta get back right now.

1123
01:37:00,250 --> 01:37:04,380
Look, I'm gonna go outside, and I'm gonna lure the wolves out of the room.

1124
01:37:04,560 --> 01:37:06,890
When they leave, you lock the door.

1125
01:37:07,460 --> 01:37:08,690
Good luck.

1126
01:38:14,660 --> 01:38:17,250
-Brian, hurry. -I need something.

1127
01:38:18,000 --> 01:38:19,930
Come on, hurry!

1128
01:38:29,710 --> 01:38:31,840
Brian! Brian, open the door!

1129
01:38:36,650 --> 01:38:38,510
We have to get out of here now.

1130
01:38:38,680 --> 01:38:40,850
Brian, get the supplies.

1131
01:39:38,340 --> 01:39:39,970
Oh, shit. Let's go!

1132
01:39:40,810 --> 01:39:41,870
Pull, Brian!

1133
01:40:18,120 --> 01:40:20,210
Take the medicine to Laura.

1134
01:40:51,720 --> 01:40:54,650
We're almost there. Come on!

1135
01:40:55,750 --> 01:40:58,620
Brian! Close the door!

1136
01:41:09,800 --> 01:41:12,130
Don't let the fire go out!

1137
01:41:12,300 --> 01:41:14,030
What's happening?

1138
01:41:21,780 --> 01:41:23,480
Buddha, come away from the door.

1139
01:41:23,650 --> 01:41:25,140
Come, Buddha, come!

1140
01:41:26,020 --> 01:41:28,610
More books! More books!

1141
01:42:22,240 --> 01:42:24,400
How long have I been out of it?

1142
01:42:25,540 --> 01:42:27,240
Couple hours.

1143
01:42:27,410 --> 01:42:28,940
How do you feel?

1144
01:42:29,110 --> 01:42:31,950
Okay. What happened?

1145
01:42:32,120 --> 01:42:36,820
Well, we had to get inside in kind of a hurry, so I sort of pushed you in.

1146
01:42:37,960 --> 01:42:40,050
I should be used to you pushing me around.

1147
01:42:41,560 --> 01:42:43,530
Good to have you back.

1148
01:42:48,830 --> 01:42:50,530
What are you doing?

1149
01:42:51,700 --> 01:42:55,870
The eye of the storm has passed, and we're 40 miles from Manhattan.

1150
01:42:56,040 --> 01:42:57,740
Shouldn't we wait one more day?

1151
01:43:00,550 --> 01:43:03,110
Sam may not have one more day.

1152
01:44:15,190 --> 01:44:17,680
What do you think's gonna happen to us?

1153
01:44:18,090 --> 01:44:19,920
What do you mean?

1154
01:44:21,160 --> 01:44:25,690
I mean us. Civilization. Everybody.

1155
01:44:27,870 --> 01:44:30,960
Mankind survived the last lce Age.

1156
01:44:31,140 --> 01:44:34,400
We're certainly capable of surviving this one.

1157
01:44:35,740 --> 01:44:39,200
All depends on whether or not we're able to learn from our mistakes.

1158
01:44:41,810 --> 01:44:45,110
I sure as hell would like a chance to learn from mine.

1159
01:44:46,220 --> 01:44:48,520
You did everything you could.

1160
01:44:51,590 --> 01:44:53,680
I was thinking about Sam.

1161
01:44:59,670 --> 01:45:02,600
Jack, you know the chances of Sam....

1162
01:45:14,180 --> 01:45:16,670
I made my son a promise.

1163
01:45:17,880 --> 01:45:19,780
I'm going to keep it.

1164
01:45:43,410 --> 01:45:46,380
Parker, this is Houston. Do you read?

1165
01:45:46,550 --> 01:45:48,510
Roger, mission control. Go ahead.

1166
01:45:48,680 --> 01:45:52,550
We've got scattered reports that the storm is dissipating over North America.

1167
01:45:52,980 --> 01:45:54,920
Can you confirm?

1168
01:45:56,290 --> 01:45:59,820
Affirmative. It's finally clearing.

1169
01:46:00,460 --> 01:46:02,020
We're over Europe right now.

1170
01:46:02,190 --> 01:46:05,360
I can see landmass for the first time in days.

1171
01:47:55,570 --> 01:47:58,040
How much further is it to the library?

1172
01:47:58,210 --> 01:48:00,040
It should be...

1173
01:48:02,850 --> 01:48:04,680
...right here.

1174
01:48:08,920 --> 01:48:10,980
I'm sorry, Jack.

1175
01:48:48,730 --> 01:48:50,390
Sam?

1176
01:49:59,760 --> 01:50:01,320
Who is that?

1177
01:50:07,240 --> 01:50:09,140
My father.

1178
01:50:13,980 --> 01:50:15,380
You made it.

1179
01:50:19,780 --> 01:50:21,680
Of course I did.

1180
01:50:49,050 --> 01:50:53,510
EMBASSY OF THE UNlTED STATES OF AMERlCA

1181
01:51:12,640 --> 01:51:14,570
Mr. President.

1182
01:51:16,610 --> 01:51:19,980
I've just received a shortwave radio transmission from Jack Hall.

1183
01:51:20,150 --> 01:51:22,170
He made it to New York.

1184
01:51:22,910 --> 01:51:24,750
He says there are survivors.

1185
01:51:26,520 --> 01:51:28,250
Thank you, Tom.

1186
01:51:29,290 --> 01:51:30,850
That's....

1187
01:51:31,860 --> 01:51:33,690
That's good news.

1188
01:51:43,100 --> 01:51:48,160
These past few weeks have left us all with a profound sense of humility...

1189
01:51:48,340 --> 01:51:51,600
...in the face of nature's destructive power.

1190
01:51:51,780 --> 01:51:55,470
For years, we operated under the belief that we could continue...

1191
01:51:55,650 --> 01:52:01,280
...consuming our planet's natural resources without consequence.

1192
01:52:02,220 --> 01:52:03,950
We were wrong.

1193
01:52:05,390 --> 01:52:07,220
I was wrong.

1194
01:52:08,160 --> 01:52:09,840
The fact that my first address

1195
01:52:09,840 --> 01:52:12,290
to you comes from a consulate on foreign soil...

1196
01:52:12,730 --> 01:52:16,100
...is a testament to our changed reality.

1197
01:52:16,400 --> 01:52:18,160
Not only Americans...

1198
01:52:18,470 --> 01:52:21,870
...but people all around the globe are now guests in the nations...

1199
01:52:22,040 --> 01:52:24,840
... we once called The Third World.

1200
01:52:25,010 --> 01:52:29,340
In our time of need, they have taken us in and sheltered us.

1201
01:52:29,980 --> 01:52:33,580
And I am deeply grateful for their hospitality.

1202
01:52:55,110 --> 01:52:59,270
We mourn the loss of a spirited leader whose courageous order to evacuate....

1203
01:52:59,440 --> 01:53:04,180
Peter? Hey, you feeling okay today?

1204
01:53:04,350 --> 01:53:07,220
For days, we 've despaired about the fate of the people...

1205
01:53:07,390 --> 01:53:09,720
...who are trapped in the North.

1206
01:53:09,890 --> 01:53:13,380
Today, there is cause for hope.

1207
01:53:14,460 --> 01:53:18,020
Only a few hours ago, I received word that a small group of people...

1208
01:53:18,200 --> 01:53:21,500
...survived in New York City against all odds...

1209
01:53:21,670 --> 01:53:24,500
...and in the face of tremendous adversity.

1210
01:53:24,670 --> 01:53:27,370
I've ordered an immediate search-and-rescue mission...

1211
01:53:27,540 --> 01:53:31,410
... to bring them home and to look for more survivors.

1212
01:54:02,240 --> 01:54:03,730
Jack!

1213
01:54:04,210 --> 01:54:07,700
It' s good to see you. Come on, let' s go get on board.

1214
01:55:03,030 --> 01:55:05,000
Look at that.

1215
01:55:05,340 --> 01:55:06,800
What?

1216
01:55:07,940 --> 01:55:10,930
Have you ever seen the air so clear?
