[DOLPHINS CLICKING]
COACH:
Come on!
Come on! Let's go! Kick!
Come on, now!
Go! Kick!
- Go!
- Kick!
He's really good, huh?
COACH: Let's go.
- Not as good as you.
COACH: Push hard!
WOMAN: This is Sandra Sinclair...
...poolside at the Long Center.
Last year, when Clearwater High's
swimming star Kyle Connellan graduated...
...leaving behind five state records...
...it appeared the glory days
of the Tornadoes might be behind them.
But rising star Donovan Peck...
...recently invited
to the Junior National Championships...
...is now on the verge
of smashing those records.
Come on, finish hard! Finish hard!
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BUZZER SOUNDS]
Yeah!
Nice job, you guys.
Hey, hey, hey. Good work. Good work.
MAN: There he is.
- Hey, guys. Hey, good race out there, huh?
Good job, man.
Nice. Good job.
- Kyle, how you doing?
- Good, good.
You know, just dropping in
to say my final goodbyes.
Coach,
you remember my cousin Sawyer?
COACH:
Oh, sure.
So you gonna come win some trophies too
for me someday? Huh?
[COACH CHUCKLES]
So Monday, huh?
Yes, sir.
- You know where they're sending you?
- No, sir.
I hope there's a pool there...
...because the Army's getting themselves
one heck of a swimmer.
Thank you.
You take good care, son.
Well, well.
Soldier boy. What are you doing here?
I had to come see for myself
how bad things had gotten.
[CHUCKLES]
Catch my time?
Yeah.
You know your records are mine, right?
I mean, by the time you get back,
your name is gone.
Oh, is that a challenge?
Any time, any place.
Whoo!
[CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
[THE DOOBIE BROTHERS' "WORLD GONE
CRAZY" PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
MAN:
Oh, right here, man! Right here!
All right, go deep!
I don't wanna live in the street
Like some folks do
- I'll put that there.
- Let's move these.
I've always known this day would come.
His dad, his grandpa...
I guess you are the smarter sister.
You didn't marry the military.
Over the top!
So how's Sawyer doing?
LORRAINE:
Not so well. D's and F's in everything.
And somehow being in summer school
is all my fault.
KYLE:
Aww. Come on, man!
MAN: Deep! There you go!
KYLE: Here we go, end zone! Oh!
MAN:
Hey, Kyle.
[LAUGHS]
Is that a new one?
No, just fixing up an old one.
Nice.
So...
Pretty excited about summer school,
huh?
[KYLE CHUCKLES]
I'm just kidding.
Well, seriously, though. I mean,
at least it gets you out of here, right?
Hey, make me a promise.
You're not gonna sit in here all summer.
All right, now why don't you go out
and make some friends.
Why?
Hey.
Look at me, Sawyer.
This isn't like your father, all right?
I'm not disappearing.
I'm just going over there for like
10 minutes, then I'll come right back...
...and you and I can win some gold medals
together. How about that?
That's what I mean. I thought you were
gonna try for the Olympics someday.
Well, I'm planning on it.
It's just training costs money.
So I do a little time for the Army
and they pay for everything.
Hey.
I got you something.
Are you serious?
Now you can take your workshop
with you wherever you go.
Hey, come on, dude.
Come back to the party with me.
We gotta hang out before I leave. Right?
Maybe a little later.
Okay.
[CHATTERING OUTSIDE]
[SIGHS]
ALYCE:
Be safe.
Call.
KYLE: I will. I love you, Mom.
ALYCE: I love you too, Kyle.
MAN [OVER RADIO]:
This is Tampa Bay's country station.
SINGER [OVER RADIO]:
Knee deep in the water somewhere
Got the blue sky, breeze
And it don't seem fair
The only worry in the world
Is the tide gonna reach
Sunrise, there's a fire in the sky
Never been so happy
Never felt so high
And I think I might've found me
My own kind of paradise
Holy smoke.
Watchin' over me
It's a sweet, sweet life
Livin' by the salty sea
Hey!
Hey! Hey, kid!
Have you got a telephone?
A phone, have you got one?
WOMAN [OVER PHONE]:
911, what's your emergency?
Hello. Uh...
I don't know. I don't know who to call.
I'm at Neeman's Cove off the A90
and it's in the water.
Wait, don't get any closer than that.
Looks like a dolphin.
- Are you a doctor?
- No, no, no. I didn't say...
[FISHING ROD WHIRRING]
Oh, for crying out loud.
Ah!
[GRUNTS]
I'm mad at you.
[DOLPHIN GRUNTS]
[DOLPHIN TRILLING]
Shh. No, it's okay. It's fine.
I just have to get this off you.
MAN:
Hey!
What are you doing? Get out of there.
Wait for me. I'll be right there.
[WHISTLING]
[DOLPHIN TRILLING]
CLAY:
Okay, guys.
It's right over there.
Hazel, be careful.
You cut it free?
PHOEBE:
Take it easy, Hazel.
Sweetie, let me just get you
to move right over here.
CLAY:
Careful, now. Keep it sternal.
- Be careful of the fin, Hazel.
- I know.
CLAY:
Let's get something to cut these ropes.
She's a female.
Oh, she's really shaking.
It's okay. Shh, shh.
Hey, how long has she been here?
I don't know.
[TRILLING]
Oh, listen, Dad.
She sounds like Tweety Bird.
Yeah, she does sound like Tweety Bird,
doesn't she?
Bring the stretcher.
MAN:
All right, Clay. On our way.
CLAY:
Okay, you guys can hop off now.
And on three we'll lift, all right?
One, two, three.
PHOEBE:
Her eyes are clenched.
Nice job with the knife.
REBECCA:
My side, drop your poles just a little bit.
PHOEBE:
All right, my side, lift.
MAN: "Preposition" is a word
that indicates location.
Now, can anyone tell me:
What constitutes
a prepositional phrase?
All right? Would be a preposition.
And the object of the preposition
would be a noun, a pronoun, a gerund...
Ah. Thank you for joining us, Mr. Nelson.
By the way, you left some
of your schoolwork the other day.
Come here.
Now have a seat.
I think I just told you
prepositional phrase was...
Remember?
"I got the cookies from my granny."
[BELL RINGS]
[LOUD SQUAWK]
[SQUAWKING]
[SQUAWKS]
What?
How did you get in here?
[SQUAWKS]
Shh! Shoo.
Shh. Go. Shh.
Move. Scram.
[GIRL HUMMING]
[BOTH GASP]
[SQUAWKING]
Rufus, no. No, help. Get the fish.
Shoo, shoo!
- Go away. Go!
- Rufus, no.
No, no, Rufus. Shoo, shoo. Go away.
Give me the lid!
[GULPING]
Bad, Rufus. Bad.
I named him Rufus
because he lives on the roof.
One day he just shows up and now
he thinks he owns the place.
- I should just...
- Where are you going?
Don't you wanna see the dolphin?
Isn't that why you came?
You're the boy from the beach, right?
- Uh...
- Okay. But don't tell my dad.
He doesn't like civilians
near the sick ones.
How'd you get in here anyway?
Uh... The back door was unlocked.
- Oh, shoot.
- Unh!
[TRILLING]
It's my job to keep it locked
but I always forget.
Come on.
Is all this for the dolphin?
Winter? No, she can't eat this yet.
She can barely move.
I named her that.
We had a Summer and Autumn.
They got put back in the ocean.
I figure season names are good luck.
These were for the other dolphins,
but since they were on the floor...
...now they're for turtles.
We're picky about what the dolphins eat.
We get them from the same place
as restaurants.
My dad says they eat better than we do.
That is if you like sushi, which I hate.
You don't talk much, do you?
And these are the upstairs pools,
where our dolphins are.
And that's Krista and Panama.
[CLICKING]
Wave.
What?
[CLICKING]
Pretty smart, huh?
Do you know that dolphins
need to be in a pool with other dolphins?
It's a law, because they're so social.
Like us. Or me, anyway.
[WHISPERS]
Come on.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
She hasn't moved since she got here.
She hasn't even opened her eyes.
Ooh!
PHOEBE:
Hazel.
Hi, Phoebe.
Who's that? You know your dad doesn't
like people back here, honey.
I know, but he's the one
who got the ropes off her.
He just wanted to see how she's doing.
She's not good.
There's a lot of dead tissue.
Circulation to her tail was cut off
for quite a long time.
Okay. Thanks.
[WINTER TRILLING]
Tweety Bird.
Quick, you gotta go. Don't tell Dad.
Oh, hey.
I'm Hazel, by the way.
Like the eye color?
Oh.
Sawyer.
[DOLPHIN SOUNDS
PLAYING OVER COMPUTER]
[SIGHS]
I'm home, Sawyer.
Ah! Sawyer.
How many times do I have to ask you,
ple...
Come on, son. Let's go to bed.
- What?
- Come on.
DOYLE:
Homework, tomorrow.
Take the sentences, diagram them.
Separate out what?
The prepositional phrases.
[BELL RINGS]
PHOEBE: Looks like it's just getting worse.
KAT: I got it.
CLAY: Well, the circulation was cut off
for so long.
PHOEBE:
What do you think is the problem?
CLAY:
We've done everything we can for her.
It's just a massive infection.
PHOEBE:
Increase the topical antibiotics?
CLAY: They're not really working.
There's just too much dead tissue.
PHOEBE: Poor thing.
It just looks like she's giving up.
We can't make her wanna live. She's
gonna have to do that part on her own.
[RUFUS SQUAWKS]
Hey. Hey. Go. Shoo. Stop it.
Stop. Let go.
Go. Go. Shh.
Stop it. Go. Get out of here.
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
CLAY:
Hey.
Come here.
Come over here.
Now who are you?
How did you get in here?
Dad, Dad.
He's the boy from the beach, remember?
Hazel, you know the rules.
Okay? No one is allowed
in this part of the hospital.
If you wanna come back
during visiting hours...
PHOEBE:
Clay?
She's awake.
[WINTER TRILLING]
It's that Tweety Bird sound.
She makes that for him.
[TRILLING]
Come on over here for a minute,
will you?
Come on, it's okay.
I want you to help me out
with something.
Guys, bring her over to the edge
of the pool, will you?
[TRILLING CONTINUES]
PHOEBE:
That's more than she's moved all day.
CLAY:
Go ahead and put your hand on her.
It's okay.
[WINTER CLICKING]
Dad, come here.
She really likes him.
Is it okay if he comes back?
I don't know.
[WINTER SQUEAKS]
[ALL LAUGHING]
Come on, son.
Get dressed, you're gonna be late.
Hey, Mom. I thought I'd go early today,
get a jump on my studies.
Early bird gets the worm.
Have a nice day.
Hazel?
Dr. Clay?
[HAZEL SOBBING]
Hazel?
What's wrong?
PHOEBE:
It's okay.
HAZEL:
Her tail was too infected.
My dad said it had to come off.
But that's how they swim.
How is she gonna live if she can't swim?
I don't know.
I didn't have a choice, guys.
Least now she has a chance.
[HAZEL SOBBING]
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
Want a lemonade icicle
before you go home?
Make them myself.
No, thanks. Probably should get going.
MAN:
I don't know.
Nothing goes down with crappy news...
...like one of my granddaughter's
lemonade icicles.
Come on.
I'm buying.
Have you guys always lived
near the water?
My grandpa says we have saltwater
in our veins.
Which I actually believed
till I was like 6.
That's his boat over there.
When my dad was a boy,
they sailed all over the world in that.
What does your dad do?
I don't know.
He left like five years ago.
We don't know where he is.
He never calls, never writes.
Oh.
So, what does your mom do?
She died when I was 7.
Never calls, never writes.
Come on.
I spend whole days up here.
Doing schoolwork, whatever.
I'm homeschooled.
That's why I'm such a chatterbox.
Do you like school?
Well, I fail almost everything.
You probably just haven't found a subject
that interests you yet.
Is Winter gonna die?
I hope not.
SAWYER: Hey, Virginia.
VIRGINIA: Morning, Sawyer.
REED:
There he is.
SAWYER:
Morning.
- Hi, Hazel.
HAZEL: Hey.
- How is she?
- We're trying to get her to eat.
Pedialyte. Baby formula.
CLAY:
She doesn't want it.
Let's give it a rest.
[TRILLING]
Can you swim?
Me?
Phoebe's been up all night with her.
She needs some sleep.
Can you swim?
[WINTER TRILLING]
Come on in.
It's okay.
Come on. I got you.
There you go.
All right, just come over here by Phoebe.
See how she's holding her?
Okay, put your right hand under there.
Great.
She's kind of heavy now, so...
SAWYER: Like this?
CLAY: Okay, yeah.
Okay, just keep her blowhole above water.
Watch her eye.
- You got her?
- Yeah.
CLAY:
Just walk her around.
- I'll see you guys in a little while, okay?
- Where you going?
I got a board meeting.
Should I just shoot you now?
Just keep an eye on the kids, will you?
Why? They're fine.
You're the one needs looking out for.
GLORIA:
It's not just us, it's all non-profits.
Anyone who relies
on government grants.
Gloria, they don't have animals
whose lives depend on them.
But we're swimming in debt here.
And in the last six months
we lost our two biggest grants.
There is good news.
We still have a strong offer on the table.
- May I please go back to work?
- He's not a bad guy.
Above and beyond the price...
...he's willing to offset the costs
of relocating all the animals.
That's what Florida needs, another hotel.
We can wipe out our debts
and get the animals placed.
Then, maybe someday, regroup.
- We certainly can't go on the way we are.
- That's true.
There's still time.
Maybe a corporate sponsor will step up.
Or maybe Rufus will win the lottery.
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
Bring her a little closer, guys, will you?
Come on, Winter.
[WINTER CLICKING]
CLAY:
She's refusing.
Let's try the tube.
Why don't you let Sawyer try.
- You wanna try?
- What do I do?
CLAY:
Put it in front of her eye.
There you go.
Talk to her.
Okay.
Come on, Winter.
[CLICKING]
I know you feel lousy...
...but you gotta eat.
I mean, if you don't eat,
you'll never get better.
It's good too.
Hazel made it herself.
All natural ingredients.
See?
Delicious.
My dad's jealous.
Usually he's the favorite.
I'm not jealous.
Now, come on.
She's drinking.
She's drinking, Dad, she's drinking.
[HAZEL CHUCKLES]
Thattagirl.
She wants more.
All right, now I'm jealous.
Hey, Mom.
Uncle Max. Aunt Alyce.
How was school?
Fine.
Interesting.
Because Mr. Doyle called and said
you have not been there all week.
Sawyer, where on...?
What is that stench?
[SNIFFING]
Ugh.
Have you been fishing?
Mm. Get back in there.
Fine. But I'm not going back to school
tomorrow.
We're not discussing it. Get in there
and wash up some more.
- But Winter needs me. And if I stop now...
- I am not asking you.
You are going to school tomorrow
and that is it. Period.
[DOOR SLAMS]
[SIGHS]
What?
- I didn't say anything.
LORRAINE: No.
Come on, Max, what?
It's just hard to remember the last time
Sawyer was excited about something.
LORRAINE:
This is not how we do things, Sawyer.
We do not disappear
for a week at a time...
...going to some strange place
with a bunch of strangers.
Put your belt on right.
How many times do I have to tell you?
- You're making me a nag.
- It rubs.
It's better than face-planting
in an airbag.
- Oh, my gosh, Mom. Nice image.
- Well, whatever, okay?
Anything could've happened.
You could've drowned...
...or gotten stabbed by a swordfish,
for heaven's sakes.
- That's it?
- Yeah.
You know, it used to be a sewage treatment
plant before they converted it. Cool, huh?
Come on, Mom.
Sawyer, wait!
[CAR ALARM HONKS]
Whoa!
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
Oh!
Aah!
Go. Shoo, shoo, shoo.
Oh! What are you doing? Leave me alone.
Shoo.
Help! Help!
[LORRAINE SCREAMING]
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
Oh.
Hi, Mom.
Where did you go?
So these are our nurse sharks.
There are our groupers, and moonfish,
and sheepshead.
Hey, Sawyer.
Oh, hey, Virginia.
And these are our river otters.
All of them are either sick or injured.
But as soon as they get better,
we'll return them to the wild.
They're cute, huh?
But if you put your finger there,
they can bite it right off.
I'll bear that in mind.
- Hey, Sawyer.
- Hey, Rebecca.
She looks after the fish.
And this is the tide pool.
There's a starfish,
and conch and a sea urchin.
And this is Fred, our sea slug.
You can touch him if you want.
- That's okay. I'm good.
- You sure?
- Mm-hm.
- Okay.
Oh.
And this is the dolphin pool.
Hmm. I'm not seeing anything.
Just wait a sec.
That's Panama.
She's pretty old and deaf,
and can't catch fish...
...because they echolocate, you know.
So she lives here.
And that's Krista.
She was just run over by a boat.
So when she heals,
we can send her home.
- Neat, huh?
- Yes.
And that's Winter.
[TRILLING]
- Welcome. I'm Reed.
- Hi, I'm Lorraine.
We've heard so much about you.
I wish I could say the same about you.
That's my son, Clay...
...and Phoebe, and Kat, there.
Dolphin specialists.
HAZEL:
Hi.
And that's Hazel, my granddaughter.
- How old is she?
SAWYER: She's just a kid.
Dolphins stay with their moms for years,
though.
Sawyer's her mom now.
Well, actually, we're all her mom.
- Sawyer, I don't know what to say.
- I'll do extra classes, write an essay.
- I'll do anything.
- I believe you.
I get this. I mean, it's... It's amazing.
- I'll talk to Mr. Doyle.
- Yes!
That's a yes. Yes. Thank you. Thank you.
You're welcome.
- Hazel, she said yes.
- Yes.
- Hi. I'm Clay.
LORRAINE: Hi.
- Lorraine.
- Nice to meet you.
I had no idea you didn't know.
I'm really sorry about that.
It's okay. It's certainly not your fault.
He's a great kid, you know?
I mean, he has a connection
with Winter that's amazing.
I've never seen anything like it.
Well, that's good news.
Maybe humans are next.
[CHUCKLES]
I have to scoot.
Sure. Come back any time.
LORRAINE: See you at home, pal.
- Bye, Mom.
LORRAINE: So nice to meet you, Hazel.
- You too.
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
What are you looking at?
No, I can't.
If I do that for him,
how is that fair to the other kids...
...whose summers I'm ruining?
Well, that's exactly my point.
Sawyer is having the best summer
of his entire life.
And he is willing to do whatever it takes.
He could give a report, write an essay,
make a collage.
The experience he is having
is so much richer...
...than anything you could teach him
in this classroom.
I'm a very good teacher.
I didn't mean it that way, Mr. Doyle.
Look, I wasn't happy about it
at first either.
But I am seeing something that a mother,
a teacher...
...dreams of seeing:
A turned-on kid.
He is so engaged,
and it's not with a Game Boy.
It's with something that is alive
and beautiful and real.
He wants credit for the class,
he has to be in the class.
I'm sorry.
You should be.
- Morning, Mom.
LORRAINE: Hi, son.
SAWYER: Thank you! Thank you.
LORRAINE: You're welcome.
Let's make sure it fits.
Your mom seems really nice.
Yeah, she's cool.
- Your dad is too.
- Yeah.
[WINTER TRILLING]
- Winter, stop it.
- Cut it out.
Stop.
What's with her?
I don't know.
Help me grab... Winter!
- Winter!
Winter! Help us!
Dad! Phoebe!
SAWYER:
Dr. Clay!
CLAY: Hazel?
HAZEL: Dad!
[MUFFLED SHOUTING]
- Wait, hold it!
- What?
She's trying to swim.
Come over here, guys.
Come here, come here.
She's wiggling around
like a snake or something.
[TRILLING]
PHOEBE:
Good girl, Winter. Way to go.
[PHOEBE CHUCKLES]
- Bye, Mom.
- Bye, hon.
Whoa! Oh, my goodness, that is so cool.
Winter, look at all this stuff.
Look at all these things
Sawyer brought you.
He brought you so many toys. I know.
It's like a chocolate milkshake for them.
SAWYER:
Hazel?
[BOTH SCREAMING]
[BOTH LAUGH]
[TRILLING]
Don't make it too tight. Ah!
[LAUGHS]
There we go. Little to the left.
Winter, look at your rubber duck.
Do you want your duck?
Look, here you go.
- Go get it, Winter.
SAWYER: Here you go.
HAZEL:
Thattagirl.
Hey, Mom.
Guess what happened today.
Kyle.
There's been an explosion, honey,
and, apparently, it's pretty bad.
Is he gonna be okay?
They think so.
- He's coming home.
- Yeah.
What you working on?
- Sawyer made it. Cool, huh?
CLAY: Yeah.
It's really cool.
I heard about your cousin.
The good news is he's alive.
That's what matters, right?
Yeah.
Hey, I need a little help
on the night shift tonight.
Help keep an eye on Winter for me.
Really?
Sure. That'd be great.
Hey, Dr. Clay?
I think you can call me Clay now.
Okay.
Do you think Winter remembers things?
Like the ocean...
...or her family?
It's really hard to say.
They're pretty smart, you know.
Some people think they're smarter
than we are.
Some people think dolphins
actually are people.
Tell him the story.
CLAY:
Okay.
In California,
the Chumash tribe has a legend.
They believe that a long time ago,
their goddess, Hutash...
...wanted everyone who lived on the islands
to move onto the mainland.
So she built them a bridge
out of a rainbow.
Everybody was crossing the rainbow,
excited to get to the mainland.
The kids were jumping around
having a great time, dancing, singing.
You know, being kids.
[WATER SPLASHING]
Well, they fell off the rainbow, and they
went tumbling down toward the sea.
Well, the parents were
just scared to death...
...that Hutash was gonna be really mad
at them and let their kids drown.
But no.
She took pity on them,
because she loved the way they played.
So right at the moment when
the children hit the water...
...she turned them into dolphins...
...so they could play forever.
SAWYER:
Wow.
Thanks.
[PLAYING "EVERYTHING
HAPPENS TO ME"]
[WINTER TRILLING]
I don't know if you know this,
but my cousin Kyle's pretty hurt.
Yeah, we don't know how bad yet.
But he's strong.
So he's gonna be okay.
You both are.
[TRILLING]
Winter, what are you doing?
Want a snack? Over there?
[TRILLING]
Hey.
[CLICKS]
Hey. Stop.
[TRILLING]
What do you want?
You wanna play?
Want a toy? Okay.
We got plenty of toys.
Bowling pin?
[WINTER SQUEAKS]
No. Okay.
We got...
How about the duck?
You like the duck, right?
Duck?
It's good. Here.
Here you go, Winter.
Come on, Winter.
See the duck? See the duck? Come on.
You want the duck?
Want the duck?
Come on, Winter, do you want it or not?
Whoa! Whoa!
[WINTER CLICKING]
Winter.
[LAUGHS]
[WINTER TRILLING]
Winter!
Okay, is that what you wanted?
You wanna splash?
Take it!
Stop! Stop! No! Okay, I surrender.
I surrender.
You won. You won.
Okay, okay.
You win.
[GASPS]
[TRILLING]
Where's Kyle?
Your Aunt Alyce called, sweetheart.
He decided to go straight
to the VA hospital.
But we're his family.
And I wanted to show him some stuff
and invite him to meet Winter.
I know. I know.
[CRYING]
He just needs some time.
All right, will you please tell him
I called him again?
Yeah. Sawyer.
His cousin.
All right. Thank you.
[HAZEL IMITATES
HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
Come on, you promised you'd teach me
to fly it. Remember?
Maybe it'll cheer you up.
[IMITATES HELICOPTER WHIRRING]
SAWYER: Okay, so I get it up in the air,
then you can fly it.
But you gotta be careful, okay?
[TOY BEEPS]
[WHIRRING]
Oh, my gosh. That is so cool.
All right, so this is up, and down,
and sideways.
HAZEL:
Let me try, let me try. Come on!
No, hold on.
- All right, very little movements.
- Got it.
Sweet.
Okay, watch it.
- Hey, watch it. Quit it. Hey!
- Oh!
Oh, my gosh! Slow it down!
Hazel!
HAZEL:
Sorry, sorry, sorry. Oh, no.
Where do you think it went?
- What do you see? I don't see it!
- I don't see it either.
- I'll fix it.
SAWYER: Give it to me. Stop...
Stop it.
[CLICKING]
[SQUEAKS]
[SQUAWKS]
[SQUAWKING]
SAWYER:
There it is!
Here it comes.
Look out!
[PANTING]
That was awesome!
Oh, Phoebe, I flew a helicopter.
Come see.
Your dad called.
Something's up with Winter.
CLAY: See this bulge right here?
It's hard to see.
- What is it? Is it bad?
- These muscles are enlarged.
They're pulling on her vertebrae
and it's causing damage right here.
It's from swimming.
Yeah, a dolphin's tail
is meant to flex up and down.
It's not supposed to go side to side.
But that's the only way she can swim.
I know, but they're not designed
to move that way.
Well, what's the worst that can happen?
So she'll have a bulge. That's not so bad.
Yeah, but her spinal cord's
exactly like ours, right?
It's controlling everything. It's controlling
her breathing, her heartbeat, movement.
So if it gets damaged...
So you're saying swimming like that's
gonna kill her?
I mean, we can give her some exercises
to try to improve it, but...
Oh, hey, can we help you?
- Yeah, we're looking for Private Connellan.
MIKE: Kyle?
I think he's in the lab across the way.
Okay.
I'm always telling him it's not polite
to point with that thing.
Thanks, guys.
TIM:
You're welcome.
Sawyer. Come on.
Oh, hey, does Kyle know you're coming?
[GRUNTS]
They didn't machine the darn thing
the way I asked them to.
It's not like I'm trying to send a man
to the moon, for heaven's sake. Unh.
[DOOR CLOSES]
Well, come on in. Don't just stand there.
I'm Cameron McCarthy. And you are?
I'm Lorraine, Kyle's aunt.
Hi.
And this is Sawyer, his cousin.
Family. Very healing.
Or so I'm told.
Mine always makes me
wanna sharpen the cutlery.
God does quality work, doesn't he?
I'm not sure I can beat that. Hold on.
Let me see.
That's a left foot, a right foot and...
Oh, oh.
Here's the beauty.
- High five.
- Ha, ha.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Please leave.
We just wanna make sure
you're okay, Kyle.
Well, I'm not, all right?
Shrink is down the hall.
I don't do heads, I do bodies.
So I'm gonna let you all do Jerry Springer
without me.
Kyle, we'll finish this up later on, okay?
Chili burger.
Best American invention since jazz.
KYLE:
Look...
...I didn't ask you to come see me.
Now you saw me, so just please leave.
Fine.
You know, whatever.
Did you ever think that this might be
hard for other people?
People besides you?
Did you?
[DOOR OPENS THEN SLAMS]
What do you say we get an ice cream.
KYLE:
Sawyer.
I'll wait for you in the car.
Look, it's not you.
Okay?
I just need some time.
Yeah, Mom said that your back was hurt.
That you can't move your legs
or something?
Yeah, I mean, my left leg,
it's coming back.
But it's my right side
they're worried about.
Will you be able to walk again?
With a brace...
...maybe.
What about swimming?
Just tell my mom and dad
I'm doing okay.
[MEN YELLING]
Excuse me?
Hi.
Can I ask you a weird question?
All right, I'm looking and I'm listening.
I understand.
No promises.
Hey, Dr. Clay. This is Dr. McCarthy.
- Oh, hi, doctor.
- Hi.
What can I do for you?
Well, I was under the impression
I was here to do something for you.
I was afraid you'd say no.
All right. Let's see here.
[CLICKING]
Right.
Well, to begin with,
she's as smooth as wet silk.
But how would you keep the daggone thing
on her when there's nothing there?
There's nothing to attach anything to.
It's preposterous anyway,
trying to put a tail on a fish.
And nobody in his right mind
would even try.
Luckily...
...I'm not.
Not what?
In my right mind.
CLAY:
So, what does that mean?
You're gonna...? You're gonna try?
McCARTHY:
Well, ahem...
I've got some vacation time coming up.
But I'm not making any promises.
Dr. McCarthy.
[WINTER TRILLING]
That means she likes you.
Well, imagine my delight.
Not much different from us, really.
Same vertebral structure.
But their skin is hypersensitive. She
might not tolerate anything against it at all.
That's the first step then.
You're doing okay.
Nice and tight.
There's too much power
for what you're proposing to do.
No, there isn't.
We're not gonna be worried about that.
You were talking about the abrasion
part of it. Will you let me finish or what?
[ALL CHATTERING]
[PHONE RINGS]
McCARTHY:
Good idea. Good idea.
[TRILLING]
McCARTHY:
Fine, I think, if this would stay up.
- Like this?
- Ha, ha.
McCARTHY: So this is all gonna be moving
at the same time.
This part is making the tail
kind of go like that.
Exactly.
[TRILLING]
Please understand
that we're strapped for cash.
PHOEBE:
It's amazing.
Amazing. Thank you.
Thank you.
High five.
MAN:
So, what do you need, Cam?
I want you to custom-make some parts
for me.
Not like anything we've done before.
It may not work...
...and I can't pay you.
Other than that, I should be excited, right?
Ha-ha-ha.
Who's the patient?
Bad news?
- Doesn't matter.
- Hmm.
How's the brace holding up?
It's fine.
- What am I supposed to do with that?
- Kick it.
Hard as you can.
Oh, don't worry about breaking
anything.
I own savings bonds.
Something breaks, the government just
buys more. I make money.
I don't think that's how
savings bonds work.
Probably not.
Kick it anyway.
I can't.
Hmm.
Tell me, what hurts more?
Your leg or your pride?
My whole life,
all I wanted to do was one thing.
Well, now you're just gonna have to
want to do something else.
Fortunately, there are about
a million things to choose from.
Look, Kyle, just because you're hurt
doesn't mean you're broken.
No, trust me, I'm broken.
No.
That's broken.
Go home, Kyle.
Go home to your family.
Now, this is the same stuff we use
for humans. It'll protect the skin.
You just slide it right over the stump
and we'll put the prosthetic right over that.
This is something I cooked up
from parts from an old Buick.
It's a little stiff, but it should work
until the real parts are made.
PHOEBE:
Okay, I got her.
- Let's try it.
CLAY: There you go.
All right, hang on, Winter.
[WINTER CLICKING]
[SAWYER WHISTLES]
As tight as you can get it.
SAWYER:
No, no, it's okay.
[WINTER TRILLING]
CLAY: Shh, shh, shh.
PHOEBE: It's okay, Winter.
CLAY:
Pheebs, let's get these straps.
PHOEBE:
Is it tight enough?
CLAY:
It's on.
Okay.
- Back her up.
PHOEBE: Let's go.
[WINTER CLICKING]
Come on, fish.
Go ahead and give her some signals,
Pheebs.
PHOEBE:
It's okay, it's okay.
SAWYER: It's okay.
PHOEBE: It's okay, Winter.
Tail up. Tail down.
SAWYER:
You got this.
PHOEBE:
Tail up. Tail down.
Up and down.
No, Winter. Up and down.
No, Winter.
She doesn't like it.
[CLICKING]
- Winter. Winter.
- Get it off her.
[WINTER SQUEALING]
I can't do anything.
Dad, you gotta make her stop.
PHOEBE: Winter, no. Stop.
HAZEL: Dad, do something.
PHOEBE: Winter.
- Dad.
[WINTER SQUEALS]
[WINTER TRILLING]
SANDRA [OVER TV]:
Thanks, Jerry. This just in:
Tropical Storm Leroy, now churning
across the Gulf of Mexico...
...with winds of up to 80 miles an hour...
- Phoebe.
... has just been upgraded
to a Category One hurricane.
Stay tuned, as we'll bring you
the very latest details as they come in.
CLAY: Phoebe, help me here, please.
PHOEBE: Okay.
- Okay, I got it.
CLAY: You got it?
PHOEBE:
Yeah, let's go.
CLAY: Hey, guys,
I need all of this stuff downstairs.
Everything goes downstairs.
[INDISTINCT SHOUTING]
[WIND HOWLING]
CLAY:
Sawyer.
Sawyer, your mom's here.
You gotta go home.
- What about the animals?
- Don't worry about them. Go home.
Kat, you go too. Go.
Come on, let's get in our spot.
Hi, Mom.
No, no, no, I got it, son.
CLAY:
Come on, Phoebe.
We gotta get inside.
PHOEBE:
Okay. Good girls.
[TRILLS]
CLAY:
Hazel.
HAZEL:
Dad. Here I am.
Mom?
It's okay, honey.
It's just a big old storm. We'll be okay.
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
HAZEL:
He's scared.
[WATER TRICKLING]
[MACHINE WHIRRING]
CLAY: Hey, when you're finished up there,
come on down, will you?
Got some other things
I need your help with.
Kyle.
Figured you could use a hand.
And maybe one good leg.
Hey, Dr. Clay, Hazel, Reed.
This is my cousin Kyle.
And my Aunt Alyce.
- Hey, how you doing? Nice to meet you.
KYLE: Hi.
[WINTER CLICKING]
It's okay. I can do this.
Ah, ahh...
Hold your hand out.
[WINTER CLICKING]
Come on.
[TRILLING]
[CHUCKLES]
GLORIA:
The best guess is what?
Including structural damage...
...the truck, rescue equipment,
electrical systems...
...something in the range of 500,000.
So this is it.
Gloria, I really feel like we've exhausted
all of our options here.
So we're all in agreement, then.
We go ahead with the sale?
In favor?
I'll call Mr. Hordern and tell him.
We found homes for all the fish
and the animals.
Including Winter?
[SIGHS]
Clay...
The plain truth is no one wants
an animal with her disability.
No dolphin has ever been known
to lose its entire tail and survive.
Every aquarium in the country
says it's hopeless.
Well, they haven't met Winter.
Listen, Dr. McCarthy is looking into
some new materials, right?
He says he can have
a new tail ready by...
What if she rejects that one too?
She won't. Two weeks.
Just give me two weeks.
I can't.
There is no money.
We have to start thinking
about putting Winter down.
It's the kindest thing we can do.
- No.
- I don't have a choice.
Of course you do.
Dr. McCarthy said we only need...
Dr. McCarthy stopped work.
I asked him to.
Why?
[SIGHS]
Come over here.
I'm out of time.
I'm out of money.
I have to close down.
Dad, how could you let this happen?
I don't keep secrets from you, Hazel.
I never have.
I'm telling you kids this because I think...
Because I think it's time
you start saying your goodbyes.
[SOBS]
[CAR DOOR OPENS]
Excuse me.
Is this the Clearwater Marine Hospital?
Oh, yeah. Sorry, our sign blew down.
Thank you. We drove all the way down
from Atlanta.
If y'all were closed,
I don't know what I would have done.
- We've come to see the dolphin.
- Her name's Winter, Mommy.
Her cousin was here with a school group
and told us about her...
...and ever since then,
it's all my daughter talks about.
After the storm,
we went online to see if she was okay...
...but we couldn't find anything.
She's fine. All the animals are.
You think it'd be okay
if we just had a little peek?
Sure, I guess.
Thanks.
Hi.
Wow.
Oh, my goodness.
Look at that huge skeleton.
- Wow.
Oh, look up there.
You see it?
Come over here, guys.
MOM:
Wow.
It's cool, huh?
Where's Winter?
Just wait a sec.
Mommy, she's just like me.
But you said there wasn't a solution.
This is a solution.
CLAY: You don't understand...
SAWYER: I do.
You need money. I get that.
But Winter can raise a lot of money.
That lady drove eight hours
to bring her daughter here.
And other people would do that too.
- We need a website.
- With a webcam.
SAWYER: Make donations.
HAZEL: A big carnival.
Everybody could see her new tail.
Guys, I'm really proud of you.
I love the ideas...
...but they're just not realistic,
you know?
It wasn't realistic to save Winter
in the first place, but you did it.
I am really sorry, guys. I really am.
It just wouldn't be enough.
Remember that poem I used to read you
when you were little?
I must down to the seas again
To the lonely sea and sky
And all I ask is a tall ship
And a star to steer her by
You're a good sailor, Clay.
You know the sea and sky
better than any man I ever met.
But you are sorely lost now, son.
You're giving up.
Because you're afraid you can't save her.
And you don't want to watch that
happen again.
Well...
...Winter might die.
I don't know.
But I do know you can't give up on her.
You never did on Holly.
It was the bravest, most beautiful thing
I ever saw.
Just because we haven't got
to where the star's pointing us...
...doesn't make it the wrong star.
That dolphin's taking us all somewhere.
We just haven't figured out where yet.
Sawyer?
So you want to talk me through
this fundraising stuff again?
Okay, you're gonna help me with
the baking and food committee.
I need you
on the decorations committee.
Yeah, Gloria, I know. Ha, ha.
I know it sounds crazy.
I need you to stall him.
As long as you can.
It's a big benefit for the Marine Hospital.
We're calling it "Save Winter Day."
You can? Great.
- Hey.
This is quite the operation
you got going on here, huh?
Yeah. I just hope we can
sell enough tickets.
[PHONE RINGS]
Dr. McCarthy?
Thank you so much for calling me back.
I just wanted to make sure that...
MAN: Have a good weekend, Sandra.
SANDRA: Thanks.
So...
I wondered if I could ask you a favor.
Sure.
[WINTER TRILLING]
Okay, move it to the left.
Farther, farther.
Okay.
Okay, slide it out more.
More.
A little more.
Little more.
- Uh-oh.
- Ah!
Never mind.
SAWYER:
Maybe we should make it a little bigger.
Hey, guys.
You might want to come see this.
- See what?
KYLE: It's a surprise.
SANDRA [OVER TV]:
Thanks, Jerry.
Just months ago, little Winter was found
tangled in the ropes of a crab trap.
Her tail seriously damaged.
Rushed to Clearwater Marine Hospital,
it appeared she might not survive.
But the plucky animal did,
although her tail did not.
And without a tail, how could she swim?
Well, she taught herself to
with a wiggling motion, side to side.
But it's not a happy ending yet.
That unusual swimming motion
is damaging her spine...
... which could lead to paralysis.
The solution? Make her a prosthetic tail.
And with the help of prosthetic designer
Dr. Cameron McCarthy...
... they're doing just that.
But it will take time and money.
So Winter's best friend,
11-year-old Sawyer Nelson...
... has created a website,
SeeWinter.com...
... with a live webcam where you can
log on and meet her for yourself.
Or better yet, meet her in person on
Save Winter Day, Saturday the 27th.
And, as an added bonus...
... you'll be treated to a very special
sporting event.
Two of America's top young swimmers...
... Florida's Kyle Connellan
and Donovan Peck...
...have agreed to race head-to-head...
- Really?
... with all proceeds going to benefit
Winter and the Marine Hospital.
So come and meet two...
... of our finest athletes
and one heroic little dolphin.
I guarantee she'll steal your heart,
just like she did mine.
SAWYER:
All right, a little more.
Farther.
All right, down.
WOMAN:
All right.
Sawyer. Sawyer. He's here.
- Good work, guys.
- Come on.
McCARTHY: All right. Cross your fingers
and toes if you got them.
[HAZEL GASPS]
HAZEL:
Oh, it's beautiful.
McCARTHY:
Yeah, the joints are a little more flexible.
So it should feel more natural. Hmm?
[WINTER TRILLING]
CLAY:
Here you go.
PHOEBE:
Can we show this to her?
SAWYER:
It's okay.
You okay?
PHOEBE:
Hold it in front of her eye. Let her see it.
KAT:
Here.
You ready?
PHOEBE: Okay, let's do this.
SAWYER: Good girl.
Come on.
CLAY:
I got it.
McCARTHY: Clay? Make sure you snug it
right up close to the stump. Real close.
CLAY:
Okay.
PHOEBE:
You got it?
CLAY:
Well, it fits, that's for sure.
That's about as snug as I can get it.
Can you see?
Just try to get her attention, Phoebe.
PHOEBE: You can do it. Up and down.
Up and down.
Good girl.
Up and down, Winter. Up and down.
Up and down. Up and down.
[WINTER TRILLING]
You ready?
All right, let's do this, Winter.
PHOEBE:
She's good. Keep her steady.
Good job.
You can do it.
Oh, lookie there.
Winter.
Winter, no.
[WINTER SQUEALING]
Winter, stop.
Hey, Mom.
I'm sure you're busy
with lots of other stuff.
But if there's anything you can do
to help Winter and her tail...
...we'd all really appreciate it.
[WINTER TRILLING]
Winter, no. Just stop.
Winter, no.
I don't want to play right now.
You don't understand, do you?
I thought dolphins
were supposed to be smart.
Why won't you understand?
Don't you get it?
If you don't wear the tail,
you're gonna die.
Why won't you just wear the tail?
[WINTER GRUNTS]
[WINTER CLICKING]
Winter, what are you doing?
[TRILLING]
Hey, cut it out. I don't want to play.
Dr. Clay.
- I know what it is now.
- What?
It's not the tail, it's the sock.
It's like a seat belt.
Wait a minute. What?
No, no. When it rubs.
It's not the tail we have to fix, it's the sock.
MAN:
Okay, Sandra, we're live.
Five, four, three, two...
SANDRA:
I'm Sandra Sinclair with Bay News 9...
...here at Clearwater Marine Hospital
for Save Winter Day.
COACH:
How you doing?
- How you doing, coach?
- Good. You look good.
- Thanks for being here.
- Man, I wouldn't have missed it.
I'll be darned if I'm gonna tell anyone this
whole thing was organized by 11-year-olds.
[CHUCKLING]
Thank you. That's very generous.
Well, let's just say that Winter and I
are old friends.
[CHUCKLES]
Hey, Kat, have you seen Dr. McCarthy?
No, not yet.
[RUFUS SQUAWKING]
[DOYLE MUTTERING]
Go away. Please.
Good grief.
LORRAINE:
Hey, Mr. Doyle.
Oh. Oh, hi. Um...
Hi.
I read Sawyer's essay...
Ha! It's quite good, actually.
And considering everything
that he has done here, I figured that...
...I could get him credit
for summer school.
Considering that news,
I'll call off the pelican.
Shoo, Rufus. Go on.
- Have a wonderful afternoon, Mr. Doyle.
McCARTHY: Beep-beep-beep-beep.
Beep-beep. Hoo-gah. Hoo-hoo-hoogah.
Excuse me. Bye-bye.
Excuse me, excuse me. Excuse me.
Dr. McCarthy.
What a mob.
- Is it done?
- Is it ready?
Can't a man catch
his breath for a minute...
...before you start bombarding him
with questions?
It's in here.
SAWYER:
Yes.
I must've tried 20 different formulas,
but I think we got something.
It's a silicone elastomer.
Saltwater-proof. Extra sticky.
- And softer than a lamb's bottom.
SAWYER & HAZEL: Wow.
McCARTHY:
I call it "Winter's gel."
I'll tell you what:
If the fish doesn't like it...
...I'm putting the tail on
and swimming with it myself.
JOHN:
Gloria.
Wait up.
All right, thanks very much.
That was the lawyer.
The deal's closed.
It all belongs to Hordern now.
Gloria, a bake sale wouldn't fix this.
We did the right thing.
Did we?
I'm not so sure.
Not too tight?
I don't think so.
SAWYER:
It's okay, it's okay. Shh, shh, shh.
Attagirl. Attagirl.
CLAY: You got it, Pheebs?
- I got it.
All right, it's on.
PHOEBE: Does that feel better?
Does that feel good?
CLAY:
All right, just give her a second.
[TRILLING]
CLAY:
Give her the signals, Pheeb.
Can you lift it, just a little bit?
Up and down, Winter. Up and down.
Good girl. Good girl. I know. Okay.
Let's try this, okay?
Come on.
Come on, girl. Come on.
Come on, Winter.
No.
- No, Winter.
- Come on, Winter.
Good girl, Winter. Up and down.
She's doing it.
She's swimming.
[CLAY LAUGHS]
- Go, Winter.
- Swim, you stupid fish. Swim.
[TRILLING]
[LAUGHS]
Good girl. Good girl, Winter.
Yes, yes, you did it.
- Good girl.
- You did it.
I know.
Hey, guys. Everything ready?
Yeah.
All right, now, listen.
No matter what happens,
today belongs to you two.
You never quit on Winter
and you never quit on yourselves.
You'll always have that.
Hello.
I'm Clay Haskett.
Welcome to the Clearwater
Marine Hospital.
[CROWD CHEERING]
I'm so thrilled
that everyone could come today.
I'd also like to introduce
two very special guests.
First, state swimming champion
Donovan Peck.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Donovan.
And Private Kyle Connellan.
[CROWD CHEERING]
- Whoo!
WOMAN: Kyle!
So proud of him.
[HAZEL SQUEALS]
Yeah, Kyle.
KYLE:
Thank you.
Thank you very much...
...but I'm not the reason
we're all here today.
Come on, Sawyer.
Go. Go.
Ladies and gentlemen, my cousin...
...Sawyer Nelson.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Sawyer.
[LAUGHING]
[FEEDBACK SQUEALS]
Wow. I don't know what to say.
But I do know...
...it wasn't me
that made this day happen.
We're here because of the most amazing
animal, and friend, that I've ever known.
And I hope you love her as much as I do.
Because Winter and I are family now.
And family is forever.
[CROWD CHEERING]
All right. You good?
Yeah.
All right, 400 meters out,
around the buoy and back.
- You got it?
- Uh-huh.
Now, I may not be able to kick so well...
...but don't you dare take it easy on me,
all right?
COACH:
Okay, guys, take your mark.
And by the way...
...did I forget to mention
this is a relay race?
DONOVAN:
What?
HAZEL:
Come on, Kyle.
[HAZEL SQUEALS]
- Whoo!
Come on.
MAN: Where's he going?
- What?
[CROWD CHEERING]
SANDRA:
Oh, look. Guys, I think that's Winter.
Phoebe.
PHOEBE:
Careful.
Go, Winter.
KAT: Go, Winter.
PHOEBE: Whoo-hoo!
Let's go. Come on.
You can do better than that.
Now it's a fair fight.
There you go. Come on.
[WINTER TRILLING]
[CROWD CHEERING]
Yeah, there you go, Winter.
I think she's getting the hang of it.
- I think you're right.
- Whoo!
Thanks, buddy. Thank you. Whoa!
- Come on, Winter. Whoo!
- Good girl.
Whoa!
[HAZEL SQUEALS]
BOY:
Come on.
[CHILDREN YELLING]
Man, I gotta tell you,
I didn't see that coming. Ha, ha.
- A little help?
- Nice job.
- Doing all right?
KYLE: Yeah.
Good girl, Winter. Good girl.
- Ah.
- Hey, doc.
Thanks for everything.
It's been my great pleasure, Kyle.
Clay.
Oh, hey, Gloria.
I'd say she's a hit.
Ha, ha. I think so.
Dr. Haskett.
Phil Hordern.
I just wanted to tell you all how excited
I am about buying this place.
So it's official.
Yes, sir, it is.
GIRL 1: Grandpa.
GIRL 2: Grandpa, we saw the pelican.
The pelican was chasing us.
I know, I saw. That was fun, huh?
Come here.
Trouble is, I got this terrible
Planning Department.
They are truly awful.
It could take those people 20 years
to design this hotel. Maybe more.
Meantime, looks to me like you're
doing some good work here.
So why don't you stick around.
I'll fund your whole operation.
As long as you run the place your way.
I suggest you say yes.
- Yes. Yes.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- I would love that.
- All right, we got a deal.
Come on, girls, let's find that pelican.
Let's go.
GIRL 1: Yes!
GIRL 2: Uh-huh.
HORDERN:
Run, run, run.
[GLORIA CHUCKLES]
Winter.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[English - US - SDH]