For the New Jack City
You are about to witness
the strength of street knowledge.
Yo, this is Queen Latifah
Bringing a song to you
About a place you might live
In case you don't understand
It's called New Jack City
In case you still don't understand
I brought along Levert and Troop
To kick the ballistics
Unemployment is up,
says the Department of Labor...
... with nearly 200,000 more claims
for unemployment last month.
Americans with income below the
poverty line has risen to 2 million...
...compared to 1. 6 million in 1979.
Economists say economic inequality...
...is at its worst level since
the Great Depression.
The percentage of after-tax income
for the rich rose 3%...
... while after-tax income
for the poor fell .2%.
Homelessness is high.
A shooting in Harlem resulted
in the death of a 7-year-old boy.
Police say the shooting
was drug-related.
Said the police,
"The kid got in the way. "
The bodies of 3 young black men
were discovered in Marcus Garvey Park.
Police believe they were victims
of a drug deal gone bad.
Identity of the victims
has been withheld.
Firemen were summoned to extract a man
from a ventilator duct.
The man became trapped when he entered
the duct to rob the premises.
The deficit now stands
at an astounding $221 billion.
A reputed crime lord and ten of his
henchmen were gunned down today.
Witnesses said the gunmen
rode past Mr. Armeteo...
...and sprayed the group with gunfire.
The shooting was the result
of an ongoing turf war.
Biff...
...look at you now.
Nino, please!
Don't bitch up.
You don't have my product
or money.
You got to give me another chance!
Please!
Brothers don't wait to get paid.
Money talks.
Bullshit runs the marathon.
So see you,
and l wouldn't want to be you.
The number of addicted
infants born in Manhattan...
...has risen over the past few years.
Hospital officials say...
... that the care required by these
victims of the cocaine epidemic...
...has severely impacted the
available resources for pediatric care.
In other news, an unidentified man
found floating in the East River...
...is believed to be another victim
in an ongoing drug war...
... that continues to plague our city.
Get out of my shit!
Thine is the kingdom, the power
and the glory, forever and ever. Amen.
l like to pray before l scramble.
Keeps people honest.
Say that shit, say that shit.
Do this now. What's your price?
Yo, man. For you, Bob Marley, 17.
For a key? You must be
doing the dope. Bring this down.
Be realistic.
l want a lower price.
Down.
This ain't Delancey Street.
That's my price. Take it or leave it.
Check this out, homeboy.
God's on your side, right?
Why don't we do this reasonable?
14K, bam.
You want to do this
correct or not? 17.
Let me see the money.
Come on. Let's do this, man.
What you know about that?
Everybody out! Get down!
Everybody down! Police!
You think you slick, you little punk,
blasphemous, dope-fiend bitch!
Spit in my face, l'm going to kill you!
-You fucking that kid up.
-He's kicking his monkey ass.
Ease back, goddamn it! l'm a cop!
Shut the fuck up!
lt's over. You have the right
to remain silent.
Anything you say can and will be used
against you in a court of law.
l'm going to get paid.
lf l make this, you're going to have
to come out your pockets.
-Ain't made that shot in years.
-Pay your taxes.
l'm like the lRS.
That's it! l love it.
What's up? Where you going?
It's the sign of the times
I got to get mine
All I live is a life of crime
They got my back against the wall,
And my dick is in the dust
Remember when we was kids...
...we played for Reverend Oates
Moab Bitty Squad?
l was 11, you was 13.
We was the baddest backcourt...
...and Each-One Teach-One.
We wasn't making no money then.
And now that we are, you're here
living your Michael Jordan fantasy.
Business must be good.
lt will be, brother.
Peep this out.
Freebase. So what?
Yo, man, you know the rules.
Us brothers don't be getting high.
Shut the fuck up and drive the car,
you non-talking bastard.
You been making money
outside the family?
l just been doing a little
experimentation-type thing.
A little experimentation-type thing.
Like what?
At the clubs, guys step away
from the blackjack table or the bar...
...to buy $50 or $100 worth of sniff.
l set them up with a hit
of the base.
Fifteen minutes after leaving,
they be back with 2 and 3 people.
So what?
They ain't come back for the cocaine.
They came back for the base.
You sound like
this shit'll change the world.
l don't know about all that
"change the world" shit, but l know...
...they be going crazy over this.
And the bitches... .
Oh, Lord! Them bitches!
They do anything for this, man!
l had my jimmy waxed every day
last week. You understand?
Several times a day.
Get the fuck out of here!
l know damn well ain't nobody
sucked your shriveled-up dick.
You trying to dis me?
l'm just telling the truth.
That's all l'm doing.
Several times a day, my ass.
All right, let me think about this
a little bit.
Money, you think this base...
...is the high-powered shit?
We going to come off like the Mob.
You understand what l'm saying?
Welcome to the Spotlite,
where we make the beat right...
...and we can't fight.
So leave your drugs and go home.
DJ Clark Kent.
Rocking from turntable number one
to turntable number two.
Just like he want to do.
You going to frisk me too?
Yo, my boy, Nino in the house.
Yo, Nino. What's up?
You want a flower?
l think you'll like him.
Here he is.
What's up, crew?
Nino, your girl looks good.
You must like slumming, Kareem.
Why would a guy like you leave
a good computer job at the bank...
...come all the way uptown
by gypsy cab...
...to work among a den of thieves?
l'm no dummy.
lt's basic common sense and arithmetic.
The difference between
them paying me $800 a week...
...and you paying me $8,000 a week.
l think my cousin also likes the fact...
...that you're in the tradition
of Joe Kennedy.
Who?
Good. Because you got to rob
to get rich in the Reagan era.
They running a strange program.
More poor and disenfranchised folks
than this place has ever seen.
They try to act like it don't exist.
-Meanwhile, the rich get richer--
-And the poor get nothing.
Times like these, people want
to get high. Real high and real fast.
And this is going to do it.
And make us rich.
l mean, what?
People going crazy over this?
lt look like cracked-off
pieces of soap.
The Colombians and Dominicans
have shown us the way.
The shit is large.
But we'll do it differently.
No more selling on street corners.
Change the product,
you change the marketing strategy.
l've seen the future.
And its name is The Carter.
Hold up. The Carter Apartments,
that joint is big.
We're talking about
combinating and consolidating.
You're taking over The Carter?
We taking over The Carter. We going to
bum rush the whole damn thing.
Now just imagine,
if the tenants cooperate, it's lovely.
They become loyal customers.
lf they don't, it's like Beirut.
They become live-in hostages.
We going to set up a lab here,
to make the product.
You hook up the computer, watch the
workers, the money and the product.
The Duh Duh Man, Keisha,
we need security...
...to ward off the rival crews,
to screen out customers.
We also need lookouts...
...here, here and here.
Alert us of five-o.
One place to make the product.
One place to collect our money.
We will own this fucking city.
You's a genius, man. A pure, un--
Unadulterated. Would you please shut
the fuck up before you have a seizure?
Hey, man, suck my...
...dick!
lt's a brilliant plan.
But one thing concerns me.
That curry-goat-eating, skinny-ass,
Fat Smitty.
He controls The Carter.
Time to sing that fat bitch a lullaby.
Rock-a-bye baby.
He'll be hanging with Elvis.
Damn.
Crack.
Sell my stuff
and stop talking to that bitch!
Let me speak with you.
Rastaman, l'm here to tell you
Nino Brown says...
...your services are no longer
needed in the community.
That's how you kill somebody.
Get up on the motherfucker and blam!
Blow his brains all over the sidewalk,
in broad daylight.
Rock-a-bye baby.
Brother, l think there's been
a little misunderstanding.
Now look, you are going to give up
those apartments, huh?
And you are going to turn over
control of The Carter.
Because if you don't...
...this shotgun blows your big,
fat head off...
...before you can get
your clothes back on.
ls that clear?
Living
Living just enough
Living just for the city
Living, living, living just enough
And now we're living
Living
Just enough
For the city
For the New Jack City
Do things, do things, do things,
Bad things with it
Almighty dollar
People don't let money
Don't let money change you
Don't let money change it
For the love of money,
People will steal from their brother
People will rob their own mother
Money, money
Just enough
For the city I live in
Living in a New
Jack
City
lf you just say "no,"
what will you say "yes" to?
We say "yes" to education.
We say "yes" to dedication.
We climb up...
...to a higher station
of new spiritual motivation...
...to make a positive impact
on our nation.
Sergeant, I'm talking to you.
l want to know how drug pushers can
take over an apartment building...
...right under your noses.
lf you lived in The Carter Apartments,
there'd be cops all over the place.
Hey, don't walk away. Listen to me!
l fought for this country. We pay taxes
and we're prisoners in our home.
l told the commissioner
you were running late.
-You got those files?
-Right here.
Let's hope he buys it.
Peretti and Appleton?
No way, Stone.
Who else you got?
-They're the ones l need.
-You kidding me?
Nick Peretti almost killed
his partner.
Scotty Appleton's on suspension.
Probation.
Semantics, Stone.
These two are trouble.
You and l know the system
wasn't ready for this epidemic.
Crack came on the scene
and spread like wildfire.
Now l got the mayor
and the governor on my back.
l need some results.
Fast!
You get me Nino Brown!
Forget Peretti and Appleton.
The risk is too high.
With all due respect, sir...
...you still don't get it.
You're not giving me what l need
to win this war:
Cops that know these streets.
l need new jack cops
for a new jack gangster.
What you call a risk,
l think is our only shot.
Let's go.
You got your men.
But l don't want any waves.
Not a goddamn ripple.
Who the hell is this
psychedelic, blotter-acid fool?
Be cool.
This is Detective Nick Peretti,
a motorcycle-freak, reject cop like you.
A wild man that no one wants.
He means l'm expendable.
Whatever, man. What did you
come here for? To watch me exercise?
l came here to lay a name on you.
Nino Brown?
His sidekick, Gerald "Gee Money" Wells?
-The "Cash Money Brothers. "
-Stuck up two-bit jewelry stores.
Yeah, thrill-seekers, wannabe
gangsters. l hate them. So what's up?
What's up is this:
We need some evidence.
Evidence of murder,
drug trafficking...
...racketeering, tax evasion.
Anything.
We've never been able
to make anything stick on Brown.
No shit. One-third of the department's
on Nino's payroll.
The other two-thirds don't care
unless it affects their community.
What you saying?
Listen.
l've been authorized to set up...
...an independent drug-fighting unit
and l'm picking you.
-Why me?
-What do you mean, why you?
You're from the neighborhood.
l can trust you.
And l know you give a shit.
So what's the catch?
There's no catch.
Why you got to say that?
-Because l know your ass, Stone.
-Peretti goes with you.
This big, biscuit-head looking--
Listen! lt won't be another
one of your wild-ass solo acts.
Peretti's the only cop l could find
crazy enough to team with you.
This is my shot.
And you fuck up, it's all on me.
l want to thank you because you know
l want to get back in this war.
But this guy, man... .
You in or out?
l'm in, all right?
What do you mean,
Frazier won't give up the apartments?
l'm not asking him, l'm telling him!
l'll handle that fat bastard myself.
-We're honored.
-No, l'm honored. Really.
We understand you have
a new Peruvian connection.
So what of it?
We know you're centralizing
operations at The Carter.
And you didn't notify Don Armeteo,
who takes such things as an insult.
Your point?
My point is you fucking guys are cutting
us out of our agreed upon 10% .
lt's time we renegotiate.
l tell you what, message boy.
You go back and tell Don Armeteo:
"No renegotiating. " Fuck that!
The Cash Money Brothers
are a self-contained unit now.
But you come see me next week.
And l'll hook you up with some
collard green linguinis and shit.
Chicken Alfredo. Chitlins Alfredo.
Maybe get a better suit!
Fuck you.
Nino, l don't know.
Frankie's an all-right guy.
Fuck them scungili -eating
motherfuckers.
This is ours. They don't want
to roll with it, we'll roll over them.
This moolanyan...
...must have an MX missile instead
of a cock, he gets up so high.
Our snitch was right.
Nino and his Cash Money monkeys...
...are dealing with the spicaroos
up on Broadway and 171 st.
He don't even deny it.
Nor does he accept
our partnership no more.
Now, Gee Money, he was cool.
lt was that testa dura, Nino.
You know what l say?
Lay down with Peruvian dogs,
you get Spanish fleas.
Soon Nino will itch.
We'll be there
to scratch the hell out of him.
1700 hours.
Suspects hand out consumables
and the natives are restless.
Yo, shut the fuck up, man!
Ten years as a low-life,
murderous bum.
Nino's purchasing a conscience.
l ain't buying this Robin Hood shit.
Oh, shit!
That's the kid l shot!
Why don't you lose weight? You look
like a boiled yam wearing a belt!
What's up? Glad to see
somebody cares about the needy.
Why don't you give me a turkey?
Look at your funky, black ass.
First you want to be a stickup kid.
But then you got shot.
Now you's a basehead.
You're messed up.
Your life is crap.
l know l look like stir-fried shit.
Hook me up with some food.
There's a line. You got to wait.
Give him something to eat.
Hook me up.
This all l get?
You want more?
l'm a veteran.
Here. How's that, all right?
Clean yourself up,
maybe l'll give you a job.
All right, man.
Want to buy a turkey?
l'm keeping an eye on him.
You don't deserve that turkey.
l hooked you up for that last get-high.
Why l got to be owing you?
l was prom queen of King High School.
This is beneath me.
You used to be prom queen, now you're
the prom fiend. Look at you!
Hey what?!
Didn't l hook you up?
Didn't l get that pipe from the lranian
who tried to beat me out of $5?
Didn't l speak to your mother after
she called me a homeless bastard?
Add all that up...
...and the fact that l can beat
your ass. l say it's my turkey!
Get away!
Get the fuck away!
Stop beating on her!
Stop it!
Let go of me, man.
Beat her up over a turkey.
You're a poor excuse for a brother.
Shit, man! Fuck! Shit!
lt's a cop! lt's a cop!
Shut up!
Shut up or l'll blow your brains out.
Don't hurt me.
-Shut up!
-l know l was wrong to beat that girl.
Crack has got me.
l got no control over it.
l tried to kick...
...but the shit be calling me.
lt calling me. l got to go to it.
-l need help, man.
-Come on, man.
-We got a crack monster.
-Your mother's a monster!
-Hold him.
-What you writing?
"Pookie" Benny Robinson. Your name.
-l'm trying to help you.
-You ain't helping nobody!
-lt's for your own good.
-Fuck you, man!
They'll hook you up.
l'm going to die!
They're going to help you.
They'll help you.
l had pretty much
everything l ever wanted.
Everything l thought l wanted.
l always had a need for acceptance.
All my friends were doing it.
Thought l could quit anytime.
That's when l woke up in the hospital.
lt's a very simple program.
We only ask that you don't use
or drink, one day at a time.
Don't leave before the miracle happens.
This program has revolving doors.
But just because you go out,
don't mean you can come back in.
lt's crazy, because...
...l did everything. l whored.
l ripped my family off.
l was so scandalous,
l would even sell my baby's Pampers.
l have a crack baby.
He was born blind.
l know why he's blind.
Everybody knows why he's blind.
l kept telling myself l was
going to kick, but l never did.
l'm a junkie.
l'll be a junkie the rest of my life.
lt's the first time
l've been away for so long...
...and personally, l hope l never see
you motherfuckers again.
When l get out, l'll just take
everything one day at a time.
One day at a time.
Chill out. You been out two minutes
and already you want a job.
lt's not just a job.
You saved my life.
Let me pay you back.
Let me help you bring Nino down.
He promised me a job.
l'll take his money...
...and report to you.
l don't know.
You know what will happen
if l stay on the streets.
l need to be a part of something.
lf you don't believe in me, who will?
Cool. You been inside,
checked out the operations.
All right, Pookie.
Parks, come help me out.
Tell me what goes on in this dump.
lt took me awhile,
but l've been through the whole joint.
First, you got to show
a membership card to this runner.
It's like a video club.
Nino's got it hooked up
like Mission: lmpossible.
Walking through that courtyard's
like a nightmare.
It's a nation full of zombies.
On the 2nd floor, a worker
rings a buzzer and a code.
A little panel on the wall opens up,
you get the crack.
The code, the buzzer, where that go?
The call goes to "The Drug Store"
where they make the crack.
I heard they got everybody in there
butt-naked. Titties hanging....
Nino don't trust a motherfucker.
Nino's one sick genius.
A mind is a terrible thing to waste.
What happens at The Drug Store?
You can take your goodies home,
or stay at The Enterprise.
What's The Enterprise?
What am I, your ghetto tour guide?
They got all this equipment
and you don't know shit.
When you're smoking crack, they say
you're "beaming up to Scotty. "
You're going to another world.
Crack is the "final frontier. "
That's why they call that room
"The Enterprise. "
People sit down and light that
glass dick and take a hit.
It's scary. Their eyes look like
a rocket, getting ready to blast off.
Nino has most of the apartments?
Man, are you deaf, or what?
The boy controls the whole place.
Nino Brown's a mad scientist.
Marvin said it. "The boy that made
slaves out of men. " That's Nino!
That's deep.
Six, five, four, three,
two, one... .
Happy New Year!
Welcome to the Spotlite
with the Flavor Flav.
Everybody say "Happy...
...New Year! "
This is the fruit of our hard work.
The belief in entrepreneurial spirit.
The new American dream.
A toast.
A toast to my family, in life...
...until death.
Happy New Year.
To CMB. On and on.
-Am l my brother's keeper?
-Yes, l am!
Am l my brother's keeper?
l am!
Look at it.
A big reason for this success is you.
But this ain't about success.
This is about survival.
We ain't going out like Puss Head,
shot up over a $10 bag. You know?
You got to be smarter than that.
We got to look out for one another.
l feel the same way.
Nothing and no one
will come between you and me.
Never.
Right?
l love you.
l love you too.
Let's go get busy.
Frank Needles out here.
Let him in.
My ace boon coon!
How you doing?
Happy New Year.
What's a matter...
...too rich to toast the New Year
with an old friend?
lf it isn't the thinking man's Rocky.
How are you doing?
Great. Love the hair.
The Don and l, we was thinking,
let's let bygones be bygones.
We congratulate you on your new success.
To show our good faith...
...a gift from the Don.
Open it.
To the moolanyan in charge.
All the best, babe.
You motherfucking creep!
Think you'll get away with that?
l just did.
Step off, Gigantor!
Now get their silly, spaghetti-eating
asses out of my office.
Frank, come on. Let's go.
Let's get out of here!
It's total slamboyancy
in the Spotlite tonight.
You're about to get rocked by some cool,
mellow fellows from Brooklyn.
l'm talking about Aaron, Damien,
Teddy, Slim, Guy.
Give it up.
Slim, give a little bit of bass.
This is the sound
That get harder and get down
Everyone must know
We've been here before
And we're going to give you more
It's time to let it show
Music is funky
Girls are so fly
So sweet and fine
Gee Money, come here,
come here, come here.
That the skeezer you met
at Frankie's?
Yeah, Uniqua.
What's up?
You fucking her correctly or what?
Once, but l just met her.
l need time to get to know her.
l heard that.
Lord, have mercy.
You want to play rough?
Say hello to my little friend.
The world is mine.
And the brothers too, now.
Don't forget us.
The world is yours, Nino.
Only you won't be as careless
as Tony Montana, now will you?
You absolutely right.
l like this girl of yours.
He ain't got no papers,
or a leash on me.
You know what happens
when dogs don't have a leash?
They run the streets
and fuck everything in sight.
lt's true. l ain't got no papers
or no leash on her.
But nothing comes between us.
The world is mine!
All mine!
What the fuck are you doing up there?
A man like you, Nino,
needs to leave a legacy.
A son. A mark to let the world know
that he was here.
You know, you absolutely right.
Shit. lt ain't like l ain't
been trying. Ain't that right?
She can't have kids.
She can't fuck, either.
Maybe that's why
she can't have kids.
That ain't right, man.
That ain't right.
-She can't?
-She can't.
Too bad.
You're goddamn right that's too bad.
Nino, you need to go get your girl.
You're right. l tell you what.
lf l was you, l'd be looking
for the pimples on her booty.
Why the fuck did you have
to say that shit?
l told you before she couldn't
make no babies!
l love you!
And now you're taking me for granted.
How can you do that?
This is corny!
This is soap opera shit!
-You act like l owe you something.
-You do.
l don't owe you jack!
Okay, you did give me
a couple of books to read.
And you helped build the brothers.
But l was your ticket out of boredom.
When your rich doctor daddy was
making house calls at Harlem General.
What's up with that? Right?
When your kleptomaniac mother
was housing shit in Bloomingdales.
Don't throw shit in my face--
You ever touch me again,
l'll--
Yeah, l'm aware of that situation.
Your man hired an ex-dealer.
l know it seems unconventional.
Appleton and Peretti report to me.
-Is it out of control?
-No.
Don't blow this.
-Does the commissioner know about it?
-Not yet.
Good.
l told you about
that new jack cop shit.
l give you a chance, and you hire
a crackhead. What's with you?
Why don't you get off my dick?
When you're ready to put yourself
on the frontline, let me know.
Excuse me. ls this a black thing?
lt is, so keep your
toy Mafia-butt out of it!
Fuck the Mafia! l'll wax
your high-yellow, narrow-ass butt!
Cool it!
Relax, all right?
lf you won't handle this,
send the white boy...
...inside The Carter with
the National Guard.
What we need is a videotape
of this whole operation.
We need evidence of the
financial records to make it work.
l'm the lookout there from
7 p.m. to 7 a.m... .
...in one of the apartment windows.
l had to fill out an application.
Asked if l still got high.
They remember me from before.
l was one of their first customers.
l used to get fucked up.
Cracker barrel, cracker ass.
l got it, l got it.
This belt is really a video camera.
These wire transmitters will be
taped to you.
lt'll send your
communication to us...
...as well as sounds and images
around you.
lt will also pick up
shit you can't even hear.
You'll be great.
You're the best man for this job.
You're a fucking genius.
Your mother.
Pookie, we're counting on you.
You can help us bring down CMB.
Try this on.
You with it?
l'm with it, man.
Let's roll with it.
Put it on.
Pookie, come here, man.
Come here.
You know, I told Gee Money
how good you been.
How you've been bringing in
lots of customers.
And you're just a lookout.
Anything that makes them
more money, they like.
This might be it.
We're promoting you.
Check it out.
Soon. Let's get going with it.
Jackpot! System!
He's inside! Yes!
This kid's been
bringing us business.
I'd like to take a shot
at one of those computer terminals.
-Can you program Pascal?
-Can a white man dance?
I guess not.
But people lose interest.
Today's your lucky day, homeboy.
I'm promoting your ass.
You still on the pipe?
No way.
Good. Real good.
Because you'll be working
in The Drug Store.
l'm glad you got confidence in me.
See you.
-Keep an eye on that kid.
-Why? What's wrong?
He's light-fingered.
Keep an eye on the product.
l don't think Pookie's ready
to be in a room full of crack.
l'm ready. Don't l look ready now?
l was born ready.
-Ready to be dead.
-Stay out of this.
He's already on the inside.
With a little more time...
...we'll have enough information
to put Nino away for good.
ln my opinion, we get him out--
l don't want your opinion.
l'm against it.
-But it's your call.
-And your funeral.
We told them, man.
Ready? Shit.
You better be ready,
because you owe a lot of people.
You owe me. You owe yourself.
You owe the whole community.
You even owe my mother.
Yeah, that's right.
A junkie just like you
killed my mother in 1974.
Didn't take money or jewelry.
Just took her life.
l don't know what you got left
in your so-called rehabilitated body.
But you better find something,
because you owe a lot of people.
A lot of people. You owe, Pook.
You got skim milk
in them titties?
One and a-two and a-three
and a-four... .
I'll give you something
to look at.
Superfly, there's something wrong
with your boy.
What's happening with Pookie?
l have no idea.
You should, he's your plant.
Cool out. You're jumping the gun.
Something's wrong with your guy.
Fourscore seven years.
-ls that code for help?
-lt's a black thing.
l'm tired of your stuff.
l'm tired of this dude.
What's wrong?
Just doing a workout. This is
a tough job. Got to stay in shape.
A workout boosts worker morale.
You think l'm stupid.
You're a high motherfucker.
You five-o?
-His cover's blown!
-Let's go!
Are you five-o?!
Take him out and kill him!
And blow the building!
Scotty help me! I'm going to die!
Let's go!
Let me through!
l'll do her!
Clear!
Police! Get out!
Come on!
Shit!
Shit! Nothing here!
Let's get out of here!
Come here. Hold on.
Keep your head down.
Here we go!
Scotty!
Where the hell are you?
-Shit!
-Touch Pookie, it blows.
-Do this.
-There's too many wires.
Pick one.
Come on!
l can't see.
Give me a light!
Hold it there.
Scotty, on three...
...l want you to slowly,
gently pull out the blue wire.
Slow!
One...
...two...
...three!
-One is the ground.
-Which?
-l don't know!
-Three seconds left!
l knew it! You ain't nothing
but a high-priced whore.
Put Nino on, bitch.
lt's for you.
What's up?
I know you're having a good time,
but we were infiltrated.
We shut down The Carter.
Get your ass here now!
Now!
Stop!
What happened?
Don't nobody know nothing?
Don't everybody speak at once.
How the motherfucker get in?
Out of all you motherfuckers,
nobody knows jack shit?
The Duh Duh Man.
Duh Duh, what happened?
l'll be a motherfucker.
Don't nobody know nothing?
What up with this?
Somebody got to know something
was going on.
See what l'm saying?
Ain't that right, Gee Money?
l think Gee Money definitely
knows something.
Gee Money knows something.
You fucked up.
You fucked up bigtime.
You're incapable of running this shit.
Sit your five-dollar ass down,
before l make change.
Kareem brought him to my attention.
We got 300 employees.
l can't keep my eye on all of them.
lf you was taking care
of business--
What? lf l was what?
Say it again!
What?!
Nothing.
That's what l thought you said!
Because that's what l got, nothing!
A million-dollar-a-week business
reduced to rubbish!
lt's your responsibility.
l never liked you anyway,
pretty motherfucker.
What's the matter, Gee?
What's up with you?
You're letting some shit like who
l'm laying the pipe to, fuck with you?
You're bigger than that.
Something like this
can never happen again.
Now...
...leave me.
Get the fuck out.
What Gee Money has brought together...
...let no man put asunder.
l now pronounce us man...
...and wife.
You may kiss the bride.
Be not deceived.
Neither fornicators, nor idolaters...
...nor adulterers, nor abusers
of themselves with mankind...
...shall inherit the kingdom of God.
May your soul rest in peace.
Goodbye, Pookie.
The commissioner's been on my ass.
Washington is blaming us for losing
thousands of dollars in man-hours.
Not to mention all the cops
we got killed.
The operation was a failure.
We didn't arrest anyone.
No one, man.
We didn't get any evidence. Nothing.
No financial records, nothing.
We still could be out there
fighting scum like Nino Brown...
...except for two things:
l gambled on you,
and you gambled on a crackhead.
Fuck that!
That's enough, man!
l'm sorry you lost your budget.
But l lost a friend.
Let it go.
Operation's over.
lt's over.
lt ain't over.
Pookie didn't die for nothing.
Operation's gone...
...Nino's loose, Pookie is dead.
l got Pookie killed.
Cut out this self-pitying shit
about you killing Pookie.
lf anyone killed him, it was me.
l could see it.
How you going to tell me
you killed Pookie?
Remember when you said
l didn't care?
When what the hell was l doing
at Pookie's funeral anyway? Remember?
l used to be Pookie.
How the hell you used to be Pookie?
l was a poor white trash Pookie.
This whole drug shit, it's not
a black thing, it's not a white thing.
lt's a death thing.
Death doesn't give a shit about color.
You don't have to like me.
l don't even know if l like you.
But we're in this together now.
You know, a drug dealer
is the worst kind of brother.
He won't sell it to his sister
or his mother.
But he'll sell it
to his boys in the street.
l don't know about you...
...but l'm ready to kill Nino Brown.
Are you with me?
l'm ahead of you.
Behind door number one,
your head explodes like a melon.
Behind two, you hook us up with
Gee Money and get the prize, Nino Brown.
Let's make a deal.
You and me always had an understanding.
Besides, l needed a haircut.
My cugino and his friend
are hungry.
And l got a feeling
they'll cut you a sweeter deal...
...than any Peruvian.
Enough to maybe throw in
a finder's fee for me.
lf l swim with this--
You wanted to meet the main man.
From now on, you deal with me...
...and me only.
You will cut me a side deal.
Twenty percent.
And you will be obligated
to report to me...
...and me only.
Give me your number.
Don Armeteo.
Nino is about to itch.
-What the fuck is up?
-What's up? Play ball, that's what.
Check!
Can l help you?
l'm here to see Gee Money.
-What's up with these elbows?
-Sucker!
l don't know you.
You know him?
Hold up. l know him. He's cool.
Ease back, playboy. Ease back.
How you feeling, Gee Money, my man?
What's up with your man?
Pat him down.
Pat him down!
lt's like that?
What the fuck is this?
l don't know you, that's what.
l know you're my man's new contact,
but l don't trust you.
So since you're interrupting my game,
get the fuck out.
Mr. Money...
...please escort Mr. Washington
off the court. Take him down the block.
And if this dreadlocked
bomboraas even blinks wrong...
...you lullaby his ass.
Don't forget what we talked about
before at Frankie's.
l'm definitely going to be
the next king.
Yo, Keish, l seen that boy
somewhere before.
That's right, l checked him out myself.
He cooler than a fan.
And the product is 60% cheaper
than what the brothers is paying.
That will free up
a whole lot of money...
... to do a lot of other things.
Like, maybe take over
another city project?
All right, let's roll with it.
Rebuild and get stronger.
Most definite. Most definite.
Money, I'll tell you something.
lf he's not who he says he is...
...l'll kill him.
Then l'll kill you.
I don't trust Mr. Washington.
I want him to stick to me
like flies to shit.
When l was young, l was a member
of a gang, the L.A. Boys.
-Lennox Ave.
-You know it.
The leader, Jughead,
told me to prove my loyalty...
...l had to snuff somebody out.
lt was like, "No problem. "
l said, "An enemy?"
He said, "No, that's too easy.
lt's got to be an ordinary mo. "
So l rode down to 23rd.
Copped me a bag of that
red devil angel dust.
l got so zooted.
l walked up on this lady.
She must have been a schoolteacher.
l was so fucking crazy,
l didn't even care.
l stepped to her.
l didn't even stay
to see her drop.
l just ran.
You must think l'm a demon.
l guess what you was doing...
...it was like business, right?
lt wasn't personal.
My brother...
...it's always business.
Never personal.
-Tell your moms l want some bean pies.
-Can l get some?
Come on in, little man.
Two for you.
-Hold up, Pop.
-Get out of here now.
l can take care of you too.
Take care of yourself,
because you an ignorant bastard.
You committing genocide on your people
with your fancy suits and cars.
Step off, grandpa.
ldol worshiper!
Killing your people with the
white devils you put in that bottle.
You an idolater.
Reverend Oates,
why are you with this scum?
Shut up!
Nino, let me smoke this old dude.
Look at you. ln two years,
they'll be marking your gravesite.
Me?
l'll be right here.
Kids, get out of here!
These kids... .
All these people gather around you
like you God almighty.
Like you love them.
Devils ain't got no love.
You're killing your people.
What can you offer them?
Another l-have-a-dream speech?
Some of that same shit
you ripping off to me?
Look at us. Not a pot to piss in,
nor a window to throw it out of.
You's the fool, old man.
Don't try it.
Don't even think about it!
You don't understand.
ldolater, you reap what you sow!
This is some fly shit.
Some George Raft,
some James Cagney-type shit.
You know what l'm saying?
-That's how you living.
-Living large!
Good looking out this afternoon.
Gee Money should've seen it coming.
Old man really wanted to do me.
Old bastard.
But here's something
that's not so funny.
Gee Money tried to cut
a side deal with me.
You can't trust anybody these days.
You can trust me.
l got your back.
Thank you.
Now Reverend Oates will say
a few words to the happy couple.
You got to wait till somebody else
gets some too, okay?
Before we eat this cake,
we ought to toast...
...my daughter, my new son-in-law
and our gracious host...
...Mr. Nino Brown.
Shit!
Fuck!
Good dog.
Oh, baby.
Come on.
l got something for you.
That's my business card.
Call me sometime.
What's up?
You still mad at me?
Fuck you, then.
-Where is the Duh Duh Man?
-Probably after that skeezer.
What's with Selina?
l don't know. Losing her mind.
Think l care?
This is my world, my money...
...and that's my skeezer.
You'll get it all over your dress.
Hi, Daddy.
Hold up a minute.
Thank you, mister.
Cover me!
Throw me a gun!
Get down!
Motherfuckers!
You're a murderer, Nino!
l've seen you kill too many people!
Cancel that bitch.
l'll buy another one.
l hate you!
l hate you, Nino!
Don Armeteo's on the phone for you.
We made you. We gave you everything.
Shagazzy's, the Spotlite,
the street corners.
So you got cute.
You had to get spanked.
Now you listen to me.
l made this. Me.
l own this city, you slicked-back,
greasy-haired...
...son of a bitch!
You're fucked!
This bulletin just in.
In a scene to rival the famed
St. Valentine's Day Massacre...
...of 1920s Chicago...
...Don Armeteo, reputed crime lord,
and ten of his henchmen...
... were gunned down this afternoon....
I put you two together.
You guys go off on your own.
Now you come back to me?
You're telling me
the disk isn't important?
l'm telling you
l hope it is important.
This is Hawkins.
We go back to law school.
She's the prosecuting attorney.
The son of a bitch used a little girl
as a bulletproof vest.
Watch your language.
Nino is going to fall.
-What about the Pookie video?
-lt helps, but it's not enough.
Nino isn't in the tapes
at The Carter.
He's Mr. Untouchable.
How many more got to die?
l could have smoked him myself.
Can we catch him in a buy?
Or get a witness to testify...
...and connect all the dots?
Nino's got great connections.
Can we nail any and tie them to Nino?
Check this out.
We got it set up so the
CMB brothers will buy from us.
And l also got it so Nino Brown
definitely doesn't trust Gee Money.
And we'll get it on videotape.
What's up, fellas?
Got the bucks?
Nice of you to make it.
Know what l'm saying?
What can l say?
What's taking so long?
Nino's not moving.
Shit.
-Let's do this.
-Open the briefcase.
Easy!
Very easy.
l thought we was friends.
l told you, it's never personal, B.
Friends is friends. This is business.
Let's see the sample.
Whatever.
All here, baby.
l knew l knew Washington.
He's five-o!
Suck-ass motherfucker!
Punch it! Just do it!
You cut a deal
with that motherfucker.
Yes, you did. Yes, you did, Gee.
Fucking Cain.
My brother's keeper.
Was it this...
...glass dick you've been sucking on?
Was that it? Now l see how you
let that motherfucker infiltrate.
He used you, Gee.
Whatever happened to
"Am l my brother's keeper?"
You know what happened to it.
"The world is mine. "
Remember that?
"Everything is mine. Everything! "
Even my woman.
ls that what this is about?
That fucking skeezer?
You think l give a fuck about her?
Fuck that ho bitch!
l don't give a fuck about her!
lt ain't about her.
lt's about us.
l love you, man.
You embarrassed me, man!
ln front of all them people,
you treated me like l was soft.
You treated me like l was spineless!
We built this shit!
You didn't do this shit by yourself!
You forgot about me, man.
Your brother.
What has this done to us?
Keisha.
Dead.
The Duh Duh Man.
Let's just make it like it was.
Let's be a family.
Let's make it like it was.
Fuck them cars. And them bitches.
And all that shit.
Fuck that shit!
Let's do us, me and you.
Let's be a family again.
l'm on the run.
lt can never go back
the way it was.
But l'll tell you how
we can make it right.
CMB.
CMB!
We all we got.
Am l my brother's keeper?
Yes, l am.
You know where Nino Brown lives?
You heard my man.
l ain't telling you shit!
Last summer, we won
this basketball tournament.
Bought the whole team new red scooters.
So kiss my ass.
Kiss my ass with that.
You know something, B?
This dude is a cop. Five-o! B, out!
Come here, punk!
l know where Nino lives.
He beat this kid with
a baseball bat.
Poured gas on him,
set him on fire...
...after he shorted him $5.
l hope you kill his black,
hardened ass.
He's in apartment 6C.
But watch out.
He got bodyguards on the roof.
Say hello to my little friend.
Buckwheat.
Punk!
Kill him!
How can you wear this and sell poison
to our people? You ain't shit!
Toss him to me.
That teacher you killed?
That was my mother!
Kick his black ass!
You've squashed and killed
these people with no retribution.
Get your ass up.
This ain't business.
This is personal.
Do it! Do it!
l want to shoot you so bad,
my dick's hard.
Coming through!
Come on, Scotty.
We'll do it the right way.
l'll testify.
Even if it means my life,
l will testify.
Come on.
We can't go out like this.
Put the gun down.
Don't throw your life away
on a piece of shit.
Give me the gun.
l'll do it!
l'll be out in a week.
You're a dead man.
Was the defendant, Mr. Nino Brown,
head of the CMB?
Remove the hat and the sunglasses.
Detective Appleton, when you
infiltrated the CMB...
...did the defendant, Mr. Nino Brown...
...attempt to buy two and a half kilos
of cocaine from you?
Can Michael Jordan slam dunk?
Of course he did.
He's a dope dealer.
That's what they do,
buy and sell dope.
l'm not guilty.
You're the one who's guilty.
Lawmakers, the politicians,
the Colombian drug lords.
All you who lobby against
making drugs legal.
Just like with alcohol
during Prohibition.
You're the one who's guilty.
Let's kick the ballistics here.
Ain't no Uzis made in Harlem.
Not one of us in here
owns a poppy field.
This thing is bigger than Nino Brown.
This is big business.
This is the American way.
l'm sure that the court
was enlightened...
...by your geopolitical tirade.
Unfortunately, society at large
is not on trial here.
You are, Mr. Brown.
Were you or were you not...
...head of the narcotics consortium,
the murderously bloody...
...CMB?
l could not hear you.
Would you please speak up?
Yes, l was a member.
But l was forced into
this way of life.
l've been dealing drugs
since l was 12.
l didn't have the chances
that you have, Miss Hawkins.
l wasn't born with a silver spoon
in my mouth, Miss Hawkins.
l wanted to get out,
but they threatened to kill my mother.
Who are you talking about,
Mr. Brown? What "they"?
They.
Look at him. Kareem Akbar.
The educated brother from the bank.
He's the head of the CMB.
The brains behind the whole thing.
This is bigger than Nino Brown,
and l got a list to prove it.
lf l'm going down, l'm taking
a lot of people with me.
-Order in the court!
-Can l speak with my lawyer?
Your Honor, may counsel
approach the bench?
-What's going on?
-l don't know.
What's the discussion?
The court is not pleased
with this application.
You understand that by pleading
guilty to a lesser charge...
...the court, under law, can impose
a sentence of three years to life...
...with parole eligibility
after 12 months. Do you understand?
Absolutely.
How'd you let this happen?
We wanted some of the crack
off the streets. l wanted Nino too.
He gave up his connections,
and Powell wanted to make the deal.
Let's go.
This court is now adjourned.
What? All he gets is a year?
This ain't happening.
l should have
killed you myself, bitch!
That's the difference between
you and me.
Don't get mad, Tito. lt's the law.
Sucks, huh?
When this is over with,
you can come and work for me.
Did you turn state's evidence?
Did you sell out CMB?
-Are you pleased with the outcome?
-Absolutely.
The justice system is the greatest.
l'm proud to be an American.
-Hi, Mom.
-ldolater!
Your soul is required in hell!
Although this is a fictional story,
there are Nino Browns in every major city in America.
If we don't confront the problem realistically --
without empty slogans and promises -- then
drugs will continue to destroy our country.