1
00:00:01,950 --> 00:00:03,950
听写：草草

2
00:00:03,950 --> 00:00:05,950
翻译：灰灰是菇凉

3
00:00:05,950 --> 00:00:07,950
翻译：草草

4
00:00:07,950 --> 00:00:09,950
翻译：桑桑

5
00:00:09,950 --> 00:00:11,950
校对：草草

6
00:00:11,950 --> 00:00:13,950
时间轴：大锤萌

7
00:00:13,950 --> 00:00:15,950
时间轴：洛基全家桶

8
00:00:15,950 --> 00:00:17,950
时间轴：女神讷

9
00:00:17,950 --> 00:00:19,950
时间轴：毒舌吉

10
00:00:19,950 --> 00:00:21,950
特效：草草

11
00:00:21,950 --> 00:00:23,950
后期：抖松

12
00:03:44,900 --> 00:03:49,490
雷 神 2 ： 黑 暗 世 界

13
00:06:15,260 --> 00:06:18,350
{\pos(195,207)}华纳海姆

14
00:09:41,310 --> 00:09:45,110
{\pos(208,194)}阿斯加德

15
00:13:05,840 --> 00:13:08,860
{\pos(193,205)}伦敦

16
00:13:17,590 --> 00:13:19,050
你好啊

17
00:29:11,250 --> 00:29:16,630
{\pos(193,205)}瓦特海姆

18
00:51:59,960 --> 00:52:03,230
{\an4}{\pos(234,160)}地球
(米德加德)

19
00:51:59,960 --> 00:52:03,230
{\pos(30,190)}尼达维勒

20
00:51:59,960 --> 00:52:03,230
{\pos(330,70)}华纳海姆

21
00:51:59,960 --> 00:52:03,230
{\pos(340,217)}约顿海姆

22
01:33:43,130 --> 01:33:45,990
{\pos(263,77)}查令十字街站

23
00:01:07,930 --> 00:01:08,880
马勒基斯
Malekith.

24
00:01:09,100 --> 00:01:11,470
阿斯加德的军队攻来了
Asgard's forces are upon us.

25
00:01:37,430 --> 00:01:39,840
派出诅咒战士
Send in the Kursed!

26
00:02:55,220 --> 00:02:57,760
消灭他们  我们才能生存
Their deaths will mean our survival.

27
00:02:59,250 --> 00:03:01,130
这场战争还远没有结束
This war is far from over.

28
00:23:00,440 --> 00:23:02,910
以太粒子唤醒了我们
The Aether awakens us.

29
00:23:03,030 --> 00:23:05,620
天体汇聚又开始了
The Convergence returns.

30
00:29:28,070 --> 00:29:30,700
瞧瞧我留下了什么  阿格姆
Look upon my legacy, Algrim.

31
00:29:32,470 --> 00:29:34,850
我几乎记不清光明之前的日子了
I can barely remember a time before the light.

32
00:29:35,550 --> 00:29:38,720
我们种族的延续将是你留给后世的遗产
Our survival will be your legacy.

33
00:29:40,780 --> 00:29:44,390
我要让阿斯加德人尝尽我们吃的苦头
The Asgardians will suffer as we have suffered.

34
00:29:44,430 --> 00:29:45,730
我要拿回以太粒子
I will reclaim the Aether.

35
00:29:45,770 --> 00:29:47,060
我要恢复我们的世界
I will restore our world.

36
00:29:47,140 --> 00:29:49,380
我要终结这饱受荼毒的宇宙
And I will put an end to this poisoned universe.

37
00:33:24,210 --> 00:33:27,110
天体汇聚即将形成
The worlds are nealy aligned.

38
00:33:32,390 --> 00:33:34,250
你将是最后一个诅咒战士
You will be the last of the Kursed.

39
00:33:35,260 --> 00:33:37,250
我愿牺牲自己
Let my life be sacrificed.

40
00:33:37,720 --> 00:33:39,990
就像我们的人民
It is no less than our people did,

41
00:33:40,990 --> 00:33:42,170
和你那样
or you have done.

42
00:33:50,390 --> 00:33:52,570
你将成为黑暗
You will become darkness,

43
00:33:53,410 --> 00:33:57,510
并维持这一形态  直到它耗尽你的生命
cursed to this existence until it consumes you.

44
00:34:02,780 --> 00:34:06,450
在那之前  我们的敌人将不是你的对手
Until then, no power our enemies possess can stop you.

45
00:34:09,420 --> 00:34:12,150
我将摧毁他们的防线
I will tear down their defenses 

46
00:34:12,790 --> 00:34:16,390
让你回到一个崭新的宇宙中
and ensure your return to a universe reborn.

47
00:53:01,940 --> 00:53:05,290
恢复吧  夺回以太粒子  你需要力气
Heal. You will need your strength to reclaim the Aether.

48
00:53:06,680 --> 00:53:10,240
等你醒来  我们去把他们赶尽杀绝
And when you wake, we will kill them all.

49
01:08:16,170 --> 01:08:19,180
我们得马上出击
We must strike now.

50
01:08:20,610 --> 01:08:21,670
不
No.

51
01:08:22,530 --> 01:08:28,830
不必去阿斯加德了
Asgard is meaningless.

52
01:08:33,120 --> 01:08:34,790
以太自己送上门了
The Aether has found its way home.

53
01:15:00,500 --> 01:15:03,160
他是阿斯加德的敌人
He is an enemy of Asgard.

54
01:15:03,160 --> 01:15:05,810
他也被关在他们的地牢里
He was a prisoner in their dungeons.

55
00:00:34,290 --> 00:00:38,530
早在光出现之前  世界是一片黑暗
Long before the birth of light, there was darkness, 

56
00:00:38,940 --> 00:00:43,000
那黑暗孕育了黑暗精灵
and from that darkness came the Dark Elves.

57
00:00:44,820 --> 00:00:46,120
一千年前
Millennia ago 

58
00:00:46,340 --> 00:00:48,890
最残暴的黑暗精灵  马勒基斯
the most ruthless of their kind, Malekith,

59
00:00:48,890 --> 00:00:51,090
企图将我们的宇宙
sought to transform our universe 

60
00:00:51,090 --> 00:00:53,800
重归于无尽黑夜
back into one of eternal night. 

61
00:00:56,010 --> 00:00:58,090
要实现这邪恶的计划
Such evil was possible 

62
00:00:58,220 --> 00:01:00,190
他必须借助以太粒子的力量
through the power of the Aether,

63
00:01:00,830 --> 00:01:04,300
那是能带来无限毁灭的古老武器
an ancient force of infinite destruction.

64
00:01:19,300 --> 00:01:21,280
阿斯加德的圣军
The noble of armies of Asgard, 

65
00:01:21,280 --> 00:01:23,340
在我父亲包尔王的率领下
led by my father, King Bor,

66
00:01:23,340 --> 00:01:26,730
对这些邪恶的生灵发起了伟大的战争
waged a mighty war against these creatures.

67
00:01:56,550 --> 00:01:59,410
九大王国的汇聚渐渐形成
As the nine worlds converged above him

68
00:01:59,410 --> 00:02:03,660
马勒基斯终于可以释放以太粒子
Malekith could at last unleash the Aether.

69
00:02:22,010 --> 00:02:24,900
但阿斯加德从他手上夺走了那武器
But Asgard ripped the weapon from his grasp.

70
00:02:26,370 --> 00:02:29,530
没了武器  黑暗精灵就此战败
Without it, the Dark Elves fell.

71
00:02:43,510 --> 00:02:45,670
尽管大势已去
With the battle all but lost 

72
00:02:45,670 --> 00:02:48,450
马勒基斯仍不惜牺牲他的部下
Malekith sacrificed his own people 

73
00:02:48,760 --> 00:02:52,800
妄图与阿斯加德军队同归于尽
in a desperate attempt to lay waste to Asgard's army.

74
00:03:08,790 --> 00:03:13,900
马勒基斯被击败  以太粒子也被摧毁
Malekith was vanquished, and the Aether was no more.

75
00:03:15,530 --> 00:03:17,700
至少我们以为是这样
Or so we were led to believe...

76
00:03:18,700 --> 00:03:22,290
陛下  是否要摧毁以太粒子
Sire, the Aether, shall we destroy it?

77
00:03:22,890 --> 00:03:27,160
只可惜它的力量太过强大  我们无法摧毁
If only we could, but its power is too great.

78
00:03:27,960 --> 00:03:29,560
将它深埋
Bury it deep. 

79
00:03:30,650 --> 00:03:32,980
藏在没人能找到的地方
Somewhere no one will ever find it.

80
00:04:14,900 --> 00:04:15,730
洛基
Loki.

81
00:04:16,230 --> 00:04:17,380
你好  母亲
Hello, mother. 

82
00:04:18,290 --> 00:04:19,690
你为我骄傲吗
Have I made you proud.

83
00:04:20,080 --> 00:04:22,720
求求你  别让事情变得更糟
Please, don't make this worse.

84
00:04:22,720 --> 00:04:24,010
怎样才算更糟
Define "worse".

85
00:04:24,380 --> 00:04:25,300
够了
Enough!

86
00:04:26,200 --> 00:04:28,150
我要单独跟犯人谈谈
 I will speak to the prisoner alone.

87
00:04:42,480 --> 00:04:44,860
有何必要如此大惊小怪
I really don't see what all the fuss is about.

88
00:04:44,860 --> 00:04:48,060
你还没认识到你罪行的严重性吗
Do you not truly feel the gravity of your crimes?

89
00:04:48,730 --> 00:04:53,150
你所到之处  必是战争  毁灭与死亡
Wherever you go there is war, ruin and death.

90
00:04:53,650 --> 00:04:55,790
我是作为仁慈的神去米德加德
I went down to Midgard to rule the people of Earth 

91
00:04:55,790 --> 00:04:57,470
统治地球人民
as a benevolent god,

92
00:04:58,770 --> 00:04:59,970
就像你一样
just like you.

93
00:05:00,520 --> 00:05:02,040
我们不是神
We are not gods. 

94
00:05:02,040 --> 00:05:06,060
我们跟人类一样  出生  生活然后死去
We are born, we live, we die, just as humans do.

95
00:05:07,670 --> 00:05:09,520
但是我们能活五千年
Give or take five thousand years.

96
00:05:10,180 --> 00:05:14,190
这一切都是因为你想要王位
All this because Loki desires a throne.

97
00:05:14,190 --> 00:05:15,580
这是我与生俱来的权利
It's my birthright!

98
00:05:15,580 --> 00:05:16,840
你与生俱来的权利
Your birthright 

99
00:05:17,540 --> 00:05:18,710
是一出生
was to die...

100
00:05:19,570 --> 00:05:20,800
就死去
as a child!

101
00:05:22,060 --> 00:05:24,410
你本被丢弃在冰冷的岩石上
Cast out onto a frozen rock.

102
00:05:26,570 --> 00:05:28,300
如果不是我当时收留了你
If I had not taken you in 

103
00:05:28,960 --> 00:05:31,650
此刻你就不会站在这里憎恨我
you would not be here now to hate me.

104
00:05:31,650 --> 00:05:33,860
如果我该被处死  那发发慈悲
If I am for the axe, then for mercy's sake, 

105
00:05:33,860 --> 00:05:35,890
赶紧动手吧
just swing it.

106
00:05:36,860 --> 00:05:38,760
我并非不喜欢和你谈话
It's not that I don't love our little talks,

107
00:05:38,770 --> 00:05:39,980
只是...
it's just...

108
00:05:41,860 --> 00:05:42,980
我的确不喜欢
I don't love them.

109
00:05:43,680 --> 00:05:46,010
你还活着  完全是因为弗丽嘉不忍杀你
Frigga is the only reason you are still alive 

110
00:05:46,010 --> 00:05:47,580
你以后休想再见她了
and you will never see her again.

111
00:05:48,160 --> 00:05:51,400
你会在地牢里度过余生
You will spend the rest of your days in the dungeons.

112
00:05:55,630 --> 00:05:56,760
那托尔呢
And what of Thor? 

113
00:05:58,460 --> 00:06:02,040
我在牢里关到死  你却要封那个蠢货为王吗
You'll make that witless oaf king while I rot in chains?

114
00:06:02,040 --> 00:06:05,000
托尔必须尽力弥补你造成的损害
Thor must strive to undo the damage you have done,

115
00:06:05,790 --> 00:06:08,330
他将恢复九大王国的秩序  之后
he will bring order to the nine Realms and then,

116
00:06:08,330 --> 00:06:11,500
是的  他会成为王
yes, he will be king.

117
00:06:59,380 --> 00:07:01,570
局面完全在我掌控之中
I've got this completely under control!

118
00:07:01,570 --> 00:07:03,240
难怪四处火光连天
Is that why everything's on fire!

119
00:07:27,580 --> 00:07:28,620
不用谢
You're welcome.

120
00:07:51,040 --> 00:07:52,080
交给你了
All yours.

121
00:08:14,890 --> 00:08:15,610
你好
Hello.

122
00:08:18,880 --> 00:08:20,330
我接受你的投降
I accept your surrender.

123
00:08:33,230 --> 00:08:34,090
还有谁
Anyone else?

124
00:08:42,420 --> 00:08:45,070
也许下次我们该直接拿块头大的下手
Perhaps next time we should start with the big one.

125
00:09:04,160 --> 00:09:05,360
接下来去哪
Where do we go next?

126
00:09:06,240 --> 00:09:09,830
霍根  九大王国都已基本恢复安宁
Hogun, the peace is nearly won across the Nine Realms.

127
00:09:11,130 --> 00:09:11,790
你该留下
You should stay here 

128
00:09:11,800 --> 00:09:13,650
与你的人民在一起  这也是你心之所向
be with your people where your heart is,

129
00:09:13,940 --> 00:09:15,150
迟点回阿斯加德也无妨
Asgard can wait.

130
00:09:16,970 --> 00:09:18,280
多谢你了
You have my thanks.

131
00:09:19,730 --> 00:09:20,710
我也该谢你
As you have mine.

132
00:09:25,980 --> 00:09:27,280
海姆达尔  可以走了
Heimdall, when you're ready.

133
00:10:12,640 --> 00:10:13,960
华纳海姆安定了吗
Is Vanaheim secure?

134
00:10:14,730 --> 00:10:16,470
是的  诺恩海姆和里亚也是
As are Nornheim and Ria.

135
00:10:16,470 --> 00:10:19,020
但如果您率军亲征  战事必能更早结束
Though our work would have gone more quickly with you at the fore.

136
00:10:19,610 --> 00:10:21,830
你一定把我当成一块面包了
You must think I'm a piece of bread

137
00:10:21,840 --> 00:10:24,020
需要时常涂上甜言蜜语
that needs to be buttered so heavily.

138
00:10:24,330 --> 00:10:25,800
我不是这个意思
That was not my intent.

139
00:10:26,620 --> 00:10:28,850
彩虹桥被毁之后  这是九大王国
For the first time since Bifrost was destroyed,

140
00:10:28,850 --> 00:10:30,450
第一次重归安宁
the Nine Realms are at peace.

141
00:10:30,860 --> 00:10:33,170
他们会因此铭记我们的强大
They're well reminded of our strength

142
00:10:33,510 --> 00:10:37,540
而你也赢得了他们的敬意和我的谢意
and you have earned their respect and my gratitude.

143
00:10:38,650 --> 00:10:39,310
谢谢您
Thank you.

144
00:10:40,170 --> 00:10:44,130
一切都安定了  除了你茫然若失的心
Nothing out of order except your confused and distracted heart.

145
00:10:45,200 --> 00:10:47,570
这与简·福斯特无关  父王
This isn't about Jane Foster, father.

146
00:10:47,570 --> 00:10:49,440
人类的生命转瞬即逝  不值得挂心
Human lives are fleeting, they're nothing.

147
00:10:49,780 --> 00:10:52,070
你该好好珍惜眼前人
You'd be better served by what lies in front of you.

148
00:10:54,190 --> 00:10:56,300
我说这话  不是以众神之父的身份
I'm telling you this not as the All-father, 

149
00:10:56,470 --> 00:10:57,780
而是以父亲的身份
but as your father.

150
00:10:57,780 --> 00:11:00,730
你准备好了  该接掌王位了
You are ready, the time has come for you to take the throne.

151
00:11:00,730 --> 00:11:02,580
去享受庆祝你的胜利吧
Embrace and celebrate what you've won.

152
00:11:02,900 --> 00:11:04,200
与你的将士一起
Join your warriors, 

153
00:11:04,450 --> 00:11:07,340
美酒佳肴  举杯同庆
eat and drink, revel in their celebration.

154
00:11:08,070 --> 00:11:10,160
至少也装出点开心的样子
At least pretend to enjoy yourself.

155
00:11:55,300 --> 00:11:56,560
再来
Another.

156
00:12:12,910 --> 00:12:15,340
你以前会欢庆上好几个星期呢
There was a time when you would celebrate for weeks.

157
00:12:17,280 --> 00:12:20,010
我记得海拉根一战后  你兴致高昂
I remember you celebrated the Battle of Harokin

158
00:12:20,460 --> 00:12:23,020
差点挑起了第二次战役
so much that you nearly started the second.

159
00:12:23,450 --> 00:12:25,090
谁让第一仗那么过瘾呢
Well, the first was so much fun.

160
00:12:31,880 --> 00:12:33,060
跟我喝一杯吧
Take a drink with me. 

161
00:12:34,020 --> 00:12:36,590
众神之父今晚不会再派任务给你了吧
Surely the All-father could have no further task for you tonight.

162
00:12:36,590 --> 00:12:38,640
对  可我给自己派了任务
No, this is one I set myself.

163
00:12:40,870 --> 00:12:43,540
我注意到你每晚都会消失
It does not go unnoticed that you disappear each night.

164
00:12:44,530 --> 00:12:45,880
世间有九大王国
There are Nine Realms,

165
00:12:46,690 --> 00:12:49,530
阿斯加德未来的国王不能只盯着其中一个
the future king of Asgard must focus on more than one.

166
00:12:54,740 --> 00:12:58,560
谢谢你的英勇与谏言  尊贵的希芙小姐
I thank you for your sword and for your counsel, good Lady Sif.

167
00:13:23,890 --> 00:13:25,190
你有什么放不下的事
So what's the story with you?

168
00:13:25,720 --> 00:13:27,740
为什么非得有事  我没什么放不下的事
Why does there have to be a story, there's no story.

169
00:13:27,740 --> 00:13:29,970
我们约会的前十分钟里
You spent the first ten minutes of our date

170
00:13:30,260 --> 00:13:32,710
你都躲在一份只有三道菜的菜单后面
hiding behind a menu that has three choices on it.

171
00:13:32,710 --> 00:13:34,800
你能选的就只有鸡肉  蔬菜或鱼  简
It's either chicken, vegetarian or fish, Jane.

172
00:13:34,800 --> 00:13:36,490
我猜你有放不下的事
I think there's a story

173
00:13:36,910 --> 00:13:40,390
而那件事是有关一个男人的  对吗
and I'm thinking the story involves a guy?

174
00:13:40,900 --> 00:13:42,390
一言难尽
It's complicated.

175
00:13:42,390 --> 00:13:43,750
他还在你身边吗
Is he still around?

176
00:13:43,750 --> 00:13:45,240
不  他
No, he...

177
00:13:46,370 --> 00:13:47,360
走了
went away.

178
00:13:47,360 --> 00:13:48,390
我也经历过
I've been there. 

179
00:13:48,870 --> 00:13:51,320
心爱的人离开是很痛苦的事  不是吗
The going away. It's hard, isn't it?

180
00:13:51,320 --> 00:13:54,980
我以前交往过一个女人  她去纽约工作了
I was seeing a woman and uh...she took a job in New York,

181
00:13:55,290 --> 00:13:57,100
最终感情敌不过距离
eventually the distance killed it.

182
00:13:57,100 --> 00:13:58,800
还有就是...
And...and the fact that she uh...

183
00:13:59,060 --> 00:14:00,800
她一直跟别的男人上床
she kept sleeping with other dudes.

184
00:14:00,800 --> 00:14:02,340
-不是吧  -好多呢
- No! - Oh, so many.

185
00:14:03,730 --> 00:14:06,790
你好  能给我们上点红酒吗
Hi. Um...could we get some wine please?

186
00:14:06,790 --> 00:14:07,750
好啊  我也想来点
Sure, I'd love some.

187
00:14:07,750 --> 00:14:09,960
理查德  这是达西
Richard, this is Darcy.

188
00:14:10,440 --> 00:14:11,480
你来干什么
What are you doing here?

189
00:14:13,670 --> 00:14:15,320
你好
Oh, hello.

190
00:14:15,330 --> 00:14:19,270
我去了实验室也就是你妈家
So, I show up to work at the lab/your mom's house,

191
00:14:19,270 --> 00:14:22,880
满心以为会看到你穿着睡衣在屋里晃悠
fully expecting you to be moping around in your pajamas

192
00:14:22,880 --> 00:14:26,210
吃着冰激凌  念念不忘...那个谁
eating ice cream obsessing about... you know who...

193
00:14:26,570 --> 00:14:29,490
可你居然没有  你穿上了淑女装
But you're not! You're wearing lady clothes,

194
00:14:29,490 --> 00:14:31,300
甚至还洗了澡  对吧  香喷喷的
you even showered, didn't you? You smell good.

195
00:14:31,300 --> 00:14:32,430
有什么事
Is there a point to all this,

196
00:14:32,430 --> 00:14:34,570
你跑到这儿来找我一定有什么要紧事
because there really needs to be a point to all this.

197
00:14:34,570 --> 00:14:35,120
对
Right. 

198
00:14:36,390 --> 00:14:38,760
还记得你被你丢在一边的科学仪器吗
You know all that scientific equipment you don't look at anymore?

199
00:14:39,490 --> 00:14:41,250
你现在得开始看了
You might wanna start looking at it again.

200
00:14:41,470 --> 00:14:43,560
我们大老远跑来就是为了这个
This is the reason we came all the way out here.

201
00:14:43,560 --> 00:14:44,730
出故障了
It's malfunctioning.

202
00:14:44,730 --> 00:14:46,020
我也这么觉得
That's what I said.

203
00:14:47,360 --> 00:14:48,770
我也这么做的
That's what I did!

204
00:14:48,770 --> 00:14:50,890
还以为你做事会更科学点
I thought you'd do something a little more scientific.

205
00:14:50,900 --> 00:14:52,560
-应该没什么问题  -嗯...
- I'm sure it's nothing. - Yeah, it's...

206
00:14:52,560 --> 00:14:53,910
看起来不像没问题
It doesn't look like nothing.

207
00:14:53,910 --> 00:14:56,720
有点像艾瑞克之前念叨的那些读数
Kind of looks like the readings that Erik was rambling about.

208
00:14:56,720 --> 00:14:59,750
我们的朋友艾瑞克  他有点疯了
Our friend Erik, kind of went banana-balls.

209
00:14:59,750 --> 00:15:00,630
他没兴趣
He's not interested.

210
00:15:00,630 --> 00:15:01,930
-我有兴趣  -我也没兴趣
- I'm interested. - I'm not interested.

211
00:15:01,930 --> 00:15:02,960
你可以走了
It's time for you to go now.

212
00:15:04,850 --> 00:15:05,750
好吧
Okay.

213
00:15:09,210 --> 00:15:10,310
短暂但愉快
Short but sweet.

214
00:15:10,310 --> 00:15:11,440
她该吃药了
She needs help.

215
00:15:15,520 --> 00:15:17,320
我还是点份鲈鱼吧
I think I'm gonna have the sea bass.

216
00:15:17,320 --> 00:15:19,460
鲈鱼  嗯  鲈鱼不错
Sea bass. Yeah, sea bass is good.

217
00:15:20,400 --> 00:15:22,890
鲈鱼  鲈鱼  鲈鱼  鲈鱼
Sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass,

218
00:15:22,890 --> 00:15:27,740
鲈鱼  鲈鱼  鲈鱼  鲈鱼...
sea bass, sea bass, sea bass...sea bass. Sea bass...

219
00:15:29,110 --> 00:15:30,660
-鲈鱼  -简
- Sea bass. - Jane, 

220
00:15:31,500 --> 00:15:32,960
你还是别念叨鲈鱼了
maybe you should stop saying "sea bass"

221
00:15:32,960 --> 00:15:34,570
跟你朋友走吧
and go after your friend.

222
00:15:35,200 --> 00:15:36,300
午餐很愉快
This was so fun.

223
00:15:36,530 --> 00:15:39,260
我就自己在这儿念叨鲈鱼吧
You know, I'll just stay here and say "Sea bass" alone.

224
00:15:47,140 --> 00:15:48,370
我恨你
And I hate you.

225
00:15:48,720 --> 00:15:50,620
怎么了  我都夸他了
What?! I said he was cute.

226
00:15:50,620 --> 00:15:52,410
你还是闭嘴开车吧
Just shut up and drive.

227
00:16:02,260 --> 00:16:03,610
下个路口左转
You need to take the next left.

228
00:16:04,390 --> 00:16:05,260
他是谁
Who's he?

229
00:16:05,260 --> 00:16:06,240
他是我的实习生
He's my intern.

230
00:16:06,690 --> 00:16:07,590
你都有实习生了
You have an intern?

231
00:16:07,590 --> 00:16:08,490
没错
Oh, yeah.

232
00:16:08,760 --> 00:16:10,800
你好  福斯特博士
Hello, Dr. Foster. It's uh...

233
00:16:10,800 --> 00:16:12,820
能与你共事真是太荣幸了
It's such a great honor to be working with you.

234
00:16:12,820 --> 00:16:14,940
好吧  我得打给艾瑞克
Right. I need to call Erik.

235
00:16:15,310 --> 00:16:16,680
右转
Oh, uh...take a right.

236
00:16:19,280 --> 00:16:20,120
再左转
And a left.

237
00:16:22,020 --> 00:16:24,990
在伦敦开车我已经驾轻就熟了
I have totally mastered driving in London.

238
00:16:25,000 --> 00:16:28,580
喂  艾瑞克  还是我  你在哪
Hi, Erik, it's me again. Where are you?

239
00:16:28,580 --> 00:16:30,420
我过来是因为你说你有发现
I came here because you said you were onto something 

240
00:16:30,420 --> 00:16:31,640
结果你却消失了
and then you vanish.

241
00:16:31,640 --> 00:16:33,300
我现在在巨石阵
I'm here at Stonehenge,

242
00:16:33,300 --> 00:16:36,700
对今天发生的一则趣闻进行跟踪报道
for what has been an interesting unfolding of events today.

243
00:16:36,700 --> 00:16:38,030
警方于今天上午11点刚过时
The police were called to the scene 

244
00:16:38,030 --> 00:16:39,890
接到报警  赶到现场
shortly after 11 a.m. this morning,

245
00:16:39,890 --> 00:16:43,410
一名看似正常的男游客来到这里
after a seemingly harmless rambler approached the area

246
00:16:43,410 --> 00:16:45,370
随即开始裸奔
then, decided to strip naked

247
00:16:45,370 --> 00:16:49,110
并举着科学仪器  吓坏了游客
and effectively terrorize tourists there with scientific equipment

248
00:16:49,110 --> 00:16:51,610
嘴里喊着他是想救他们
while shouting that he was trying to save them.

249
00:16:51,610 --> 00:16:54,640
此人随后被证实为著名天文物理学家
The man later identified as noted astrophysicist 

250
00:16:54,640 --> 00:16:55,810
艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
Dr. Erik Selvig

251
00:16:55,810 --> 00:16:58,330
他目前已被警方拘留待审
has been called in for questioning by police.

252
00:17:00,840 --> 00:17:02,720
快走  多令人激动啊
Come on, this is exciting!

253
00:17:03,260 --> 00:17:05,300
看  实习生都激动了
Look, the intern is excited.

254
00:17:05,300 --> 00:17:06,090
我叫伊恩
"Ian".

255
00:17:06,110 --> 00:17:07,770
要带上相位表吗
Do you want the phase meter?

256
00:17:07,770 --> 00:17:09,480
-不要  -拿上相位表
- No. - Bring the phase meter.

257
00:17:10,260 --> 00:17:11,300
长得像面包机的那个
The toaster-looking thing.

258
00:17:11,300 --> 00:17:13,450
我知道相位表长什么样
Yeah. I know what the phase meter is.

259
00:17:21,730 --> 00:17:24,200
这手机的铃声要怎么换
How do I change the ringtone on this thing?

260
00:17:24,200 --> 00:17:26,150
有三个学位的天文物理学家
An astrophysicist with three degrees

261
00:17:26,150 --> 00:17:28,060
应该会自己换铃声
should be able to change her own ringtone.

262
00:17:28,060 --> 00:17:29,060
为什么要打电话
Why are you calling me?

263
00:17:29,070 --> 00:17:30,100
我不想大喊大叫
I didn't want to shout.

264
00:17:30,100 --> 00:17:31,340
实习生说往这边走
Intern says it's this way.

265
00:17:31,810 --> 00:17:33,420
伊恩  我叫伊恩
"Ian". My name is Ian.

266
00:17:47,580 --> 00:17:51,210
我可不想因为搞个科学被人捅死
I am not getting stabbed in the name of science.

267
00:17:51,210 --> 00:17:52,890
没事的  我们是美国人
It's okay, we're Americans!

268
00:17:52,890 --> 00:17:54,570
这样说他们就会喜欢我们了吗
Is that supposed to make them like us?

269
00:17:54,980 --> 00:17:56,410
他们能把它弄走
They'll make it go away.

270
00:17:58,480 --> 00:17:59,740
只是孩子
Oh, they're kids.

271
00:18:00,550 --> 00:18:01,930
你们是警察吗
Are you the police?

272
00:18:02,600 --> 00:18:06,080
不  我们是科学家  我是
No, we're scientists. Well, I am.

273
00:18:06,080 --> 00:18:08,010
-谢谢  -我们无意中发现的
- Thanks. - We just found it.

274
00:18:10,680 --> 00:18:11,820
能带我们去看看吗
Can you show us?

275
00:18:38,420 --> 00:18:40,010
这可不太正常
That doesn't seem right.

276
00:18:57,950 --> 00:18:58,880
去哪了
Where'd it go?

277
00:19:12,600 --> 00:19:13,490
这真是...
That's...

278
00:19:14,070 --> 00:19:15,270
太不可思议了
that's incredible.

279
00:19:28,970 --> 00:19:29,980
怎么回事
What happened?

280
00:19:30,510 --> 00:19:33,610
有时候能回来  有时候回不来
Sometimes they come back, sometimes they don't.

281
00:19:36,440 --> 00:19:39,160
我也想丢个东西  简  把你的鞋给我
I want to throw something. Jane, give me your shoe.

282
00:19:41,640 --> 00:19:43,950
我上次见到这样的读数还是在...
I haven't seen readings like this since... 

283
00:19:44,500 --> 00:19:45,500
在...
since...

284
00:19:45,500 --> 00:19:46,520
新墨西哥吗
New Mexico?

285
00:19:51,070 --> 00:19:52,400
什么都别碰
Don't touch anything!

286
00:19:55,810 --> 00:19:56,800
把你的鞋给我
Give me your shoe.

287
00:20:18,450 --> 00:20:20,570
那是车钥匙吗
Were those the car keys?

288
00:20:58,870 --> 00:20:59,980
达西
Darcy!

289
00:23:21,330 --> 00:23:22,590
你来迟了
You're late.

290
00:23:24,080 --> 00:23:27,470
有时欢庆比战斗更累人
Merriment can sometimes be a heavier burden than battle.

291
00:23:27,470 --> 00:23:29,460
那你一定有一样没做对
Then you're doing one of them incorrectly.

292
00:23:30,510 --> 00:23:31,400
也许吧
Perhaps. 

293
00:23:32,160 --> 00:23:33,920
繁星都还好吗
How fare the stars?

294
00:23:33,920 --> 00:23:35,690
一如既往地闪烁着
Still shining. 

295
00:23:35,700 --> 00:23:39,260
我在这儿能看到九个王国和亿万生灵
From here I can see nine realms and ten trillion souls.

296
00:23:43,450 --> 00:23:46,310
记得我跟你说过的天体汇聚吗
Do you recall what I told you of the Convergence?

297
00:23:46,310 --> 00:23:49,490
记得  各个王国连成一线
Yes, the alignment of the worlds. 

298
00:23:50,100 --> 00:23:51,390
快要到来了  是吗
It approaches, doesn't it?

299
00:23:51,910 --> 00:23:53,670
这宇宙奇观上一次出现
The universe hasn't seen this marvel 

300
00:23:53,670 --> 00:23:55,780
是在我守卫开始之前了
since before my watch began.

301
00:23:56,910 --> 00:23:59,860
很少有人能感觉到  能看到的更少了
Few can sense it, even fewer can see it.

302
00:24:01,910 --> 00:24:04,040
虽然它可能带来危险
But while its effects can be dangerous,

303
00:24:05,030 --> 00:24:07,300
但真是美极了
it is truly beautiful.

304
00:24:09,170 --> 00:24:10,160
我什么也看不到
I see nothing.

305
00:24:10,890 --> 00:24:14,150
也许是因为那不是你想看的美景
Or perhaps that is not the beauty you seek.

306
00:24:20,070 --> 00:24:20,850
她怎么样
How is she?

307
00:24:21,530 --> 00:24:23,410
你的凡人还挺聪明
She's quite clever, your mortal.

308
00:24:23,410 --> 00:24:24,650
她自己还不知道
She doesn't know it yet,

309
00:24:24,650 --> 00:24:26,780
但她也在研究天体汇聚
but she studies the Convergence as well. 

310
00:24:27,680 --> 00:24:28,380
甚至...
Even...

311
00:24:30,570 --> 00:24:31,330
怎么了
What?

312
00:24:35,080 --> 00:24:36,130
我看不到她了
I can't see her.

313
00:25:16,890 --> 00:25:17,700
简
Jane! 

314
00:25:19,000 --> 00:25:20,500
你去哪了啊
Where the hell were you?

315
00:25:20,500 --> 00:25:22,070
你不会报警了吧
Tell me you didn't call the police!

316
00:25:22,080 --> 00:25:23,310
不然我该怎么办
What was I supposed to do?

317
00:25:23,310 --> 00:25:24,380
别报警啊
Not call the police!

318
00:25:24,380 --> 00:25:25,180
我急疯了
I was freaking out.

319
00:25:25,180 --> 00:25:26,740
你报警  警察就会通知联调局
You call the cops, they tell the Feds, 

320
00:25:26,740 --> 00:25:28,550
紧接着神盾局就从天而降
the next thing you know we have S.H.I.E.L.D crawling all over,

321
00:25:28,550 --> 00:25:29,690
把这里变成51区
"Area 51-ing" the place.

322
00:25:29,690 --> 00:25:32,470
-简  -我们发现了一个稳定的重力异常场
- Jane! - We had a stable gratification anomaly,

323
00:25:32,470 --> 00:25:33,900
并且能自由进行研究
We had unimpeded access.

324
00:25:33,900 --> 00:25:35,770
我们唯一的竞争对手是十岁的孩子
Our only competition was ten years old!

325
00:25:35,770 --> 00:25:38,570
简  你失踪了五个小时
Jane, you were gone for five hours!

326
00:25:38,590 --> 00:25:39,290
什么
What?

327
00:25:46,650 --> 00:25:47,680
好诡异
That's weird.

328
00:26:09,870 --> 00:26:10,670
总这样
Typical.

329
00:26:12,080 --> 00:26:12,860
简
Jane.

330
00:26:15,690 --> 00:26:18,460
抱歉  我必须确认下你是真的
Sorry. I just needed to make sure you were real,

331
00:26:18,460 --> 00:26:20,040
今天真的好诡异
it's been a very strange day.

332
00:26:20,040 --> 00:26:21,470
我是真的  简
Well, I am. Jane what...

333
00:26:22,220 --> 00:26:23,590
你去哪了
Where were you?!

334
00:26:23,590 --> 00:26:24,620
你又去哪了
Where were you? 

335
00:26:25,390 --> 00:26:26,950
海姆达尔看不到你
Heimdall could not see you.

336
00:26:26,960 --> 00:26:28,880
我一直在原地等你
I was right here where you left me.

337
00:26:28,880 --> 00:26:31,100
我一直在等你  后来我哭了
I was waiting and then I was crying

338
00:26:31,100 --> 00:26:32,780
再后来我到处去找你
and then I went out looking for you.

339
00:26:32,780 --> 00:26:33,920
你说你会回来的
You said you were coming back.

340
00:26:33,920 --> 00:26:36,880
我知道  但是彩虹桥被毁了
I know, I know, but the Bifrost was destroyed.

341
00:26:36,880 --> 00:26:38,630
九大王国爆发了战乱
The Nine Realms erupted into chaos,

342
00:26:38,640 --> 00:26:41,110
战争肆虐  劫盗成群
wars were raging, marauders were pillaging.

343
00:26:41,370 --> 00:26:43,240
我必须制止杀戮
I had to put an end to the slaughter.

344
00:26:44,700 --> 00:26:48,100
这个理由倒是不坏
As excuses go, it's not terrible.

345
00:26:48,510 --> 00:26:51,730
但我在电视上看见你了  你去了纽约啊
But I saw you on TV, you were...you were in New York!

346
00:26:52,130 --> 00:26:54,770
简  我那时努力保护你不受来自我的世界的侵害
Jane, I fought to protect you from the dangers of my world, 

347
00:26:54,770 --> 00:26:57,740
但我错了  我太傻了
but I was wrong, I was a fool.

348
00:26:59,630 --> 00:27:02,820
我相信是命运让我们走到一起
But I believe that fate brought us together. 

349
00:27:05,240 --> 00:27:07,140
简  我不知道你去了哪  发生了什么事
Jane, I don't know where you were or what happened, 

350
00:27:07,150 --> 00:27:08,470
但我很清楚一件事
but I do know this.

351
00:27:09,270 --> 00:27:09,980
什么
What?

352
00:27:11,620 --> 00:27:12,490
我知道
I know...

353
00:27:13,710 --> 00:27:14,620
真的知道吗
You do?

354
00:27:16,380 --> 00:27:17,370
知道什么
Do what?

355
00:27:18,030 --> 00:27:18,880
什么
What?

356
00:27:22,380 --> 00:27:23,430
是你干的吗
Is this you?

357
00:27:28,060 --> 00:27:29,940
我们有点事要忙
Uh...we're kind of in the middle of something here.

358
00:27:29,940 --> 00:27:33,130
我确定我们要被捕了
Um...I'm pretty sure we are getting arrested.

359
00:27:33,130 --> 00:27:34,100
等一下
Hold that thought.

360
00:27:35,480 --> 00:27:36,910
看看你
Look at you!

361
00:27:36,910 --> 00:27:40,230
还是那么肌肉发达  宇宙怎么样
Still all muscly and everything. How's space?

362
00:27:40,820 --> 00:27:41,760
挺好的
Space is fine.

363
00:27:43,470 --> 00:27:44,570
打扰一下
Excuse me?

364
00:27:44,570 --> 00:27:45,860
-你是简·福斯特吗  -是的
- Are you Jane Foster? - Yes.

365
00:27:45,860 --> 00:27:47,040
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?

366
00:27:48,410 --> 00:27:49,620
他是我的实习生
He's my intern. 

367
00:27:50,480 --> 00:27:51,720
我实习生的实习生
My intern's intern.

368
00:27:51,720 --> 00:27:52,790
这里是私人领地
This is private property 

369
00:27:52,790 --> 00:27:54,330
你们全都涉嫌非法入侵
and you're trespassing, the lot of you.

370
00:27:54,330 --> 00:27:55,450
请你跟我们走一趟
You'll have to come with me.

371
00:28:01,180 --> 00:28:01,960
简
Jane! 

372
00:28:02,690 --> 00:28:03,620
简
Jane?

373
00:28:03,620 --> 00:28:04,570
托尔
Thor.

374
00:28:05,340 --> 00:28:06,230
你没事吧
You alright?

375
00:28:06,470 --> 00:28:08,150
刚刚怎么回事
What just happened?

376
00:28:08,150 --> 00:28:10,630
把手放在头上  退后
Place your hands on your heads, step back!

377
00:28:10,630 --> 00:28:11,950
这位女士不舒服
This woman is unwell.

378
00:28:11,950 --> 00:28:13,120
她很危险
She's dangerous.

379
00:28:13,710 --> 00:28:14,880
我也是
So am I.

380
00:28:16,150 --> 00:28:18,500
请求武警速到现场支援
Requesting armed response officers to the scene.

381
00:28:18,500 --> 00:28:19,490
抱紧我
Hold on to me.

382
00:28:19,490 --> 00:28:20,580
你要干什么
What are you doing?

383
00:28:28,590 --> 00:28:30,580
我去
Holy shit!

384
00:28:58,110 --> 00:28:59,600
我们得再来一次
We have to do that again.

385
00:29:04,480 --> 00:29:05,850
欢迎来到阿斯加德
Welcome to Asgard.

386
00:29:58,130 --> 00:29:59,120
这是什么
What's that?

387
00:29:59,130 --> 00:30:00,070
别动
Be still.

388
00:30:07,950 --> 00:30:09,800
这不是地球上的物质  它是什么
This is not of Earth, what is it?

389
00:30:10,920 --> 00:30:12,020
还不清楚
We do not know. 

390
00:30:13,460 --> 00:30:16,400
但她体内涌动的能量太大  她撑不住的
But she will not survive the amount of energy surging within her.

391
00:30:22,920 --> 00:30:25,170
这是量子场发生器  对吗
That's a quantum field generator, isn't it?

392
00:30:25,180 --> 00:30:26,720
这是灵魂冶炼炉
It's a Soul Forge.

393
00:30:27,210 --> 00:30:30,550
灵魂冶炼炉能迁移分子能吗
Does a Soul Forge transfer molecular energy from one place to another?

394
00:30:33,580 --> 00:30:34,460
是的
Yes.

395
00:30:34,900 --> 00:30:36,360
就是量子场发生器
Quantum field generator.

396
00:30:37,530 --> 00:30:40,400
我的话对你来说只是耳旁风吗
My words are mere noises to you that you ignore them completely?

397
00:30:40,400 --> 00:30:41,660
她病了
She's ill.

398
00:30:41,660 --> 00:30:42,830
她是凡人
She is mortal. 

399
00:30:43,690 --> 00:30:45,420
他们都会患病
Illness is their defining trait.

400
00:30:45,420 --> 00:30:47,120
我带她来是因为我们能救她
I brought her here because we can help her.

401
00:30:47,120 --> 00:30:49,360
她不属于阿斯加德
She does not belong here in Asgard

402
00:30:49,360 --> 00:30:52,670
如同山羊肉上不了宴会台面一样
anymore than a goat belongs at a banquet table.

403
00:30:53,140 --> 00:30:54,040
他刚刚是说...
Did he just...?

404
00:30:54,750 --> 00:30:56,320
你以为你是谁啊
Who do you think you are?

405
00:30:56,320 --> 00:30:58,800
我是奥丁  阿斯加德国王
I'm Odin. King of Asgard. 

406
00:30:59,160 --> 00:31:00,980
九大王国的保护者
Protector of the Nine Realms.

407
00:31:02,800 --> 00:31:03,310
我是...
Oh. Well, I'm...

408
00:31:03,320 --> 00:31:06,130
我很清楚你是谁  简·福斯特
I know very well who you are, Jane Foster.

409
00:31:07,330 --> 00:31:08,880
你跟你爸提过我
You told your dad about me?

410
00:31:09,610 --> 00:31:11,020
她体内有一些物质  父王
Something is within her, father,

411
00:31:11,020 --> 00:31:12,170
我从没见过的物质
something I have not seen before.

412
00:31:12,170 --> 00:31:14,710
她的星球有自己的治疗师  他们叫医生
Her world has its healers. They are called "doctors."

413
00:31:14,710 --> 00:31:15,680
交给他们处理吧
Let them deal with it. 

414
00:31:15,970 --> 00:31:17,810
守卫  送她回米德加德
Guards, take her back to Midgard.

415
00:31:19,340 --> 00:31:20,540
不  不要
No, I wouldn't...

416
00:31:22,680 --> 00:31:23,680
碰她
...touch her.

417
00:31:24,040 --> 00:31:25,250
简  你没事吧
Jane, are you alright?

418
00:31:30,410 --> 00:31:31,340
这不可能
It's impossible.

419
00:31:32,880 --> 00:31:35,450
她感染的东西在保护她
The infection, it's defending her.

420
00:31:36,280 --> 00:31:37,330
不
No, 

421
00:31:38,060 --> 00:31:39,680
是在保护它自己
it's defending itself.

422
00:31:40,810 --> 00:31:42,110
跟我来
Come with me.

423
00:31:42,880 --> 00:31:46,450
有些东西的历史可以追溯到宇宙成形之前
There are relics that predate the universe itself. 

424
00:31:46,880 --> 00:31:50,590
她体内的东西  似乎就是这样的古物
What lies within her appears to be one of them. 

425
00:31:51,720 --> 00:31:53,820
九大王国并非永恒的
The Nine Realms are not eternal.

426
00:31:54,470 --> 00:31:57,050
他们有诞生的黎明  也将有坍圮的黄昏
They had a dawn as they will have a dusk.

427
00:31:58,160 --> 00:32:00,490
但在那黎明之前  黑暗势力
But before that dawn the dark forces,

428
00:32:00,490 --> 00:32:04,280
黑暗精灵  独霸宇宙  
the Dark Elves, reigned absolute 

429
00:32:04,280 --> 00:32:05,990
无人匹敌
and unchallenged.

430
00:32:07,560 --> 00:32:08,650
诞自永恒之夜
"Born of eternal night,

431
00:32:08,660 --> 00:32:11,360
黑暗精灵将盗走你的光明
the Dark Elves comes to steal away your light."

432
00:32:12,340 --> 00:32:15,170
小时候母后跟我们讲过他们的故事
They were these stories mother told them to us as children.

433
00:32:15,940 --> 00:32:17,280
他们的首领  马勒基斯
Their leader, Malekith 

434
00:32:17,460 --> 00:32:19,180
用那黑暗创造了一个武器
made a weapon out of that darkness,

435
00:32:19,180 --> 00:32:20,790
叫做以太粒子
and it was called the Aether. 

436
00:32:21,010 --> 00:32:23,820
其他古物大都是固体
While the other relics often appeared as stones, 

437
00:32:23,900 --> 00:32:26,720
以太粒子却是不停变化的流体
the Aether is fluid and everchanging.

438
00:32:26,770 --> 00:32:29,170
它能将物体变成暗物质
It changes matter into dark matter,

439
00:32:29,340 --> 00:32:31,410
它寻找寄主寄生
it seeks out to host bodies,

440
00:32:31,410 --> 00:32:33,930
并汲取寄主的生命力
drawing strength from their life force.

441
00:32:34,310 --> 00:32:37,380
马勒基斯想利用以太的能量
Malekith sought to use the Aether's power

442
00:32:37,410 --> 00:32:41,130
让宇宙重归黑暗
to return the universe to one of darkness.

443
00:32:41,880 --> 00:32:44,690
但历经了漫长的血战
But after eternities of blood shed,

444
00:32:44,740 --> 00:32:47,570
我父王包尔  终于取胜
my father Bor, finally triumphed,

445
00:32:47,710 --> 00:32:52,270
从此开启了数千年的和平
ushering in the peace that lasted thousands of years.

446
00:32:52,860 --> 00:32:54,210
怎么个取胜法
What happened?

447
00:32:55,410 --> 00:32:56,950
他消灭了黑暗精灵
He killed them all.

448
00:32:57,450 --> 00:32:58,840
您确定吗
Are you certain? 

449
00:32:59,540 --> 00:33:01,680
传说以太粒子跟他们一同被摧毁
The Aether was said to have been destroyed with them 

450
00:33:01,680 --> 00:33:03,080
但如今却又出现
and yet here it is.

451
00:33:04,450 --> 00:33:06,380
黑暗精灵已经灭绝
The Dark Elves are dead.

452
00:33:07,670 --> 00:33:10,200
书上提到怎么把它从我身体里取出来吗
Does your book happen to mention how to get it out of me?

453
00:33:11,070 --> 00:33:14,490
没有
No, it does not.

454
00:34:38,450 --> 00:34:41,380
看管这些无赖真是有失我们的身份
Acting as caretakers to these scoundrels is beneath us.

455
00:34:41,560 --> 00:34:42,800
拜托
Oh, please. 

456
00:34:42,810 --> 00:34:44,860
如果他们压在了你的身下  我壮硕的朋友
If they were beneath you my rotund friend, 

457
00:34:44,860 --> 00:34:46,060
他们肯定要没命了
they'd all be dead.

458
00:35:00,610 --> 00:35:01,800
不要出队
Keep in line. 

459
00:35:02,080 --> 00:35:03,170
往前走
Move it!

460
00:35:03,910 --> 00:35:06,980
奥丁总给我送新朋友来
Odin continues to bring me new friends. 

461
00:35:08,020 --> 00:35:09,960
真周到啊
How thoughtful.

462
00:35:10,140 --> 00:35:12,690
我送来的书  你不喜欢吗
The books I sent, do they not interest you?

463
00:35:14,120 --> 00:35:17,560
我就这么打发余生吗  读书
Is that how I'm to wile away eternity, reading?

464
00:35:17,560 --> 00:35:20,800
我已经尽力让你过得舒坦些  洛基
I've done everything in my power to make you comfortable, Loki.

465
00:35:20,800 --> 00:35:21,920
是嘛
Have you? 

466
00:35:22,780 --> 00:35:24,890
奥丁也会操这份心吗
Does Odin share your concern? 

467
00:35:26,060 --> 00:35:27,480
托尔呢
Does Thor?

468
00:35:27,870 --> 00:35:31,460
他们如此日夜挂念我  一定很操劳啊
It must be so inconvenient them asking after me day and night.

469
00:35:31,470 --> 00:35:35,000
你很清楚  你落得这个下场完全是咎由自取
You know full well it was your actions that brought you here.

470
00:35:35,000 --> 00:35:36,340
咎由自取
My actions. 

471
00:35:36,600 --> 00:35:38,290
你们一直骗我说我生来就该为王
I was merely giving truth to the lie

472
00:35:38,290 --> 00:35:40,180
我不过是将这个谎言
that I've been fed my entire life, 

473
00:35:40,180 --> 00:35:41,870
变成了现实
that I was born to be a king.

474
00:35:41,880 --> 00:35:42,910
为王
A king? 

475
00:35:43,740 --> 00:35:45,930
真正的国王会承认错误
A true king admits his faults.

476
00:35:45,930 --> 00:35:47,470
你在地球大开杀戒要怎么说
What of the lives you took on Earth?

477
00:35:47,470 --> 00:35:50,740
跟奥丁杀过的人相比简直九牛一毛
A mere handful compared to the number Odin has taken himself.

478
00:35:51,120 --> 00:35:51,950
你父亲
Your father...

479
00:35:51,950 --> 00:35:53,710
他不是我父亲
He's not my father!

480
00:35:56,760 --> 00:35:58,610
那我也不是你母亲吗
Then am I not your mother?

481
00:36:04,030 --> 00:36:05,210
不是
You're not.

482
00:36:10,080 --> 00:36:14,760
你总能看透一切  却看不透自己
You're always so perceptive about everyone but yourself.

483
00:36:29,420 --> 00:36:32,500
你去找我的时候就知道我有麻烦了吗
When you came for me, you knew I was in trouble.

484
00:36:33,160 --> 00:36:36,360
海姆达尔看不到你时  你就不在地球上了
When Heimdall had lost sight of you, you were no longer on Earth.

485
00:36:36,480 --> 00:36:37,970
这怎么可能啊
Well, how's that possible?

486
00:36:37,970 --> 00:36:39,840
我认为你既在又不在
I believe you were and you weren't.

487
00:36:40,210 --> 00:36:42,550
九大王国在宇宙树中游走
The Nine Realms travel within Yggdrasil, 

488
00:36:43,120 --> 00:36:46,140
像地球环绕太阳那样环绕米德加德
orbiting Midgard in much the way your planet orbits the sun. 

489
00:36:46,740 --> 00:36:50,690
每五千年  这些王国列成一条直线
And every five thousand years the worlds align perfectly,

490
00:36:50,690 --> 00:36:52,510
我们称之为天体汇聚
and we call this the Convergence.

491
00:36:55,190 --> 00:36:58,310
在此期间  各王国间的界线会变得模糊
During this time the boarders between worlds become blurred.

492
00:36:59,600 --> 00:37:01,940
你可能就是找到了这样一个模糊点
It's possible you found one of these points.

493
00:37:04,380 --> 00:37:06,180
那个点没有关闭真是走运
We are lucky that it remained open.

494
00:37:06,810 --> 00:37:10,090
一旦各王国偏离汇聚直线
Once the worlds pass out of alignment, 

495
00:37:12,380 --> 00:37:14,270
与彼此的连接就会中断
the connection is lost.

496
00:37:27,330 --> 00:37:29,790
我喜欢你解释的方式
I liked the way you explained things.

497
00:37:31,900 --> 00:37:33,320
我会怎么样
What's gonna happen to me?

498
00:37:33,510 --> 00:37:35,020
我会想办法救你的  简
I'll find a way to save you, Jane.

499
00:37:35,020 --> 00:37:36,070
你父亲说没办法...
Your father said there was...

500
00:37:36,070 --> 00:37:38,480
我父亲也并非无所不知
My father doesn't know everything.

501
00:37:38,570 --> 00:37:40,730
可别让他听见你说这话
Don't let him hear you say that.

502
00:37:42,330 --> 00:37:44,210
简·福斯特  这位是弗丽嘉
Jane Foster, please meet Frigga, 

503
00:37:44,210 --> 00:37:46,650
阿斯加德的王后  我母亲
Queen of Asgard, my mother.

504
00:38:40,140 --> 00:38:40,820
快走
Move!

505
00:39:27,690 --> 00:39:28,620
快去地牢
To the dungeons!

506
00:39:30,200 --> 00:39:30,950
快走
Come on!

507
00:39:54,050 --> 00:39:56,660
走左边的楼梯吧
You might want to take the stairs to the left.

508
00:40:07,570 --> 00:40:08,610
是监狱
The prisons.

509
00:40:09,080 --> 00:40:09,900
洛基
Loki.

510
00:40:09,900 --> 00:40:12,280
去吧  我会照顾她
Go, I will look after her.

511
00:40:24,500 --> 00:40:26,360
他们简直像是讨厌被囚禁
It is as if they resented being imprisoned.

512
00:40:30,220 --> 00:40:32,070
有些家伙就是不知足
There's no pleasing some creatures.

513
00:40:40,520 --> 00:40:42,900
回牢房去  事后概不追究
Return to your cells, no further harm will come to you. 

514
00:40:42,910 --> 00:40:44,240
我保证
You have my word.

515
00:40:45,960 --> 00:40:48,460
好吧  我收回
Very well, you do not have my word.

516
00:40:58,290 --> 00:41:00,240
派一队人去武器库
Send a squadron to the weapons vault,

517
00:41:00,390 --> 00:41:03,320
不惜一切代价保卫那里  守住地牢
defend it at all costs. Secure the dungeon.

518
00:41:03,330 --> 00:41:04,310
奥丁
Odin.

519
00:41:04,460 --> 00:41:05,430
弗丽嘉
Frigga.

520
00:41:05,530 --> 00:41:06,600
去啊
Go!

521
00:41:07,630 --> 00:41:09,850
就是点小乱子  不用担心
It's a skirmish, nothing to fear.

522
00:41:10,100 --> 00:41:11,850
你一向不会撒谎
You've never been a very good liar.

523
00:41:12,500 --> 00:41:15,040
带她去你房里  等安全了我会去找你
Take her to you chambers, I'll come for you when it's safe.

524
00:41:15,650 --> 00:41:16,730
你小心
You take care.

525
00:41:17,110 --> 00:41:18,990
历经了多少风风雨雨
Despite all I have survived, 

526
00:41:19,120 --> 00:41:21,700
我的王后还是会担心我
my queen still worries over me.

527
00:41:22,150 --> 00:41:25,190
就是因为我担心  你才能逢凶化吉
It's only because I worry over you that you have survived.

528
00:41:27,650 --> 00:41:28,830
听好了
Listen to me now, 

529
00:41:28,930 --> 00:41:32,120
你要完全照我说的做  不许多问
I need you to do everything I ask and no questions.

530
00:41:32,350 --> 00:41:33,420
是  夫人
Yes, ma'am.

531
00:46:42,820 --> 00:46:46,150
阿斯加德的王座被毁了  去保护国王
The throne of Asgard is destroyed! To the king!

532
00:47:01,660 --> 00:47:02,840
弗丽嘉
Frigga.

533
00:47:11,580 --> 00:47:13,500
退下  怪物
Stand down, creature.

534
00:47:14,120 --> 00:47:15,900
我尚可饶你一命
And you may still survive this.

535
00:47:15,900 --> 00:47:18,110
我命大得很呢  女人
I have survive worse, woman.

536
00:47:19,370 --> 00:47:20,610
你是谁
Who are you?

537
00:47:21,300 --> 00:47:22,950
我是马勒基斯
I am Malekith.

538
00:47:23,510 --> 00:47:25,580
我要拿回我的东西
And I would have what is mine.

539
00:47:56,760 --> 00:47:59,260
你拿走了一样东西  孩子
You have taken something, child.

540
00:48:00,340 --> 00:48:01,800
还给我
Give it back.

541
00:48:15,540 --> 00:48:16,840
女巫
Witch.

542
00:48:20,290 --> 00:48:21,500
以太粒子在哪
Where is the Aether.

543
00:48:22,050 --> 00:48:23,900
我绝不会告诉你
I'll never tell you.

544
00:48:25,150 --> 00:48:26,470
这我相信
I believe you.

545
00:48:29,380 --> 00:48:31,210
不
No.

546
00:51:57,690 --> 00:52:00,570
宇宙五千年一个循环
The universe rotates on a five thousand years cycle.

547
00:52:00,900 --> 00:52:03,660
每轮循环中会有一次  各个世界排列成直线
And once a cycle, all the worlds align.

548
00:52:03,830 --> 00:52:06,520
把这个想象成我们的世界
Imagine... imagine that this is our world,

549
00:52:07,470 --> 00:52:08,260
谢谢
oh, thank you, 

550
00:52:08,260 --> 00:52:09,670
这是另一个世界
and this is another world, 

551
00:52:09,670 --> 00:52:11,390
一般来说  他们彼此分开
normally, they're seperate. 

552
00:52:11,740 --> 00:52:13,610
但世界汇聚时
But during the Alignment,

553
00:52:13,610 --> 00:52:15,190
一切都彼此相连
everything is connected,

554
00:52:15,870 --> 00:52:19,700
九大王国都在穿过彼此
all nine realms. All nine realms are passing through each other, 

555
00:52:19,700 --> 00:52:22,180
重力  光  甚至物质
and gravity, light, and even matter 

556
00:52:22,180 --> 00:52:24,520
都会从一个世界挤进另一个世界
is crushing from one world to the other.

557
00:52:27,000 --> 00:52:30,460
如果这一切现在发生  后果将是毁灭性的
But if this happens to us now, the result could be cataclysmic.

558
00:52:31,250 --> 00:52:33,370
我的重力测量仪能稳定
My gravimetric-spikes can stablize

559
00:52:33,620 --> 00:52:36,070
天体汇聚的界点
the focus point of the Convergance.

560
00:52:36,250 --> 00:52:38,610
这样  其他世界
This time, the Alignment

561
00:52:38,620 --> 00:52:41,570
和他们的纵列就会跟我们擦肩而过
and all the other worlds would just pass us by.

562
00:52:41,750 --> 00:52:43,070
太妙了
It's beautiful.

563
00:52:44,770 --> 00:52:46,010
也很简单
Simple.

564
00:52:46,010 --> 00:52:47,350
有什么问题吗
Any questions?

565
00:52:50,700 --> 00:52:53,790
有  能把我的鞋还给我吗
Yeah, can I have my shoe back?

566
00:53:46,310 --> 00:53:47,910
简·福斯特
Jane Foster?

567
00:53:48,780 --> 00:53:50,240
你得跟我们来
You need to come with us.

568
00:53:52,180 --> 00:53:55,370
我们依然无法恢复王宫的屏障
We are still unable to restore the palace shields.

569
00:53:55,370 --> 00:53:57,100
我们的大炮探测不到他们
Our artillery cannot detect them, 

570
00:53:57,100 --> 00:53:59,070
海姆达尔都看不到他们
even Heimdall cannot see them.

571
00:54:02,080 --> 00:54:03,370
陛下
My king, 

572
00:54:04,100 --> 00:54:05,880
我们完全失去了防御能力
we're all but defenseless.

573
00:54:08,520 --> 00:54:10,160
你把她囚禁起来了
She's your prisoner now?

574
00:54:12,390 --> 00:54:13,570
都退下
Leave us.

575
00:54:22,740 --> 00:54:24,610
我不想跟你争论
I do not wish to fight with you.

576
00:54:25,450 --> 00:54:27,370
我也不想跟您争论
Nor I with you.

577
00:54:27,370 --> 00:54:29,280
但我想去追击马勒基斯
But I intended to pursue Malekith.

578
00:54:29,320 --> 00:54:31,060
以太粒子在我们手上
We possess the Aether.

579
00:54:31,300 --> 00:54:32,780
马勒基斯会送上门来
Malekith will come to us.

580
00:54:32,780 --> 00:54:34,730
没错  他会摧毁我们
Yes, and he will destroy us.

581
00:54:34,730 --> 00:54:37,150
你高估了这些怪物
You overestimate the power of these creatures.

582
00:54:37,150 --> 00:54:39,470
不  我只是珍惜我们人民的生命
No, I value our people's lives.

583
00:54:39,470 --> 00:54:41,080
我带简去黑暗世界
I'll take Jane to the Dark World, 

584
00:54:41,080 --> 00:54:43,410
将敌人从阿斯加德引开
and draw the enemies away from Asgard.

585
00:54:43,590 --> 00:54:45,650
马勒基斯把以太粒子从简身体里取出时
When Malekith pulls the Aether from Jane, 

586
00:54:45,650 --> 00:54:47,980
它会暴露在外  不堪一击
it would be exposed and vulnerable.

587
00:54:47,980 --> 00:54:50,140
我到时就把他们一同消灭
And I would destroy it and him.

588
00:54:51,670 --> 00:54:53,030
你这是冒险
If you fail, 

589
00:54:53,750 --> 00:54:56,680
一旦失败  武器就会落入敌手
you risk this weapon falling into the hands of our enemie.

590
00:54:56,680 --> 00:54:59,360
如果我们坐以待毙只会更危险
The risk is far greater if we do nothing.

591
00:54:59,380 --> 00:55:01,310
他的舰队可能此刻就在我们头上盘旋
His ships could be over our heads right now,

592
00:55:01,310 --> 00:55:02,540
我们根本无从知道
we would never even know.

593
00:55:02,760 --> 00:55:04,080
等他来了
If and when he comes,

594
00:55:04,230 --> 00:55:07,820
他的手下会败在数万阿斯加德士兵的兵刃下
his men will fall on ten thousand Asgardian blades.

595
00:55:07,820 --> 00:55:09,630
那我们又要牺牲多少人呢
And how many our men should fall on theirs?

596
00:55:09,630 --> 00:55:11,680
牺牲多少都在所不惜
As many as I need it.

597
00:55:20,680 --> 00:55:21,950
我们会坚持战斗
We will fight

598
00:55:24,840 --> 00:55:26,740
坚持到最后一个阿斯加德人
till the last Asgardian breath,

599
00:55:28,120 --> 00:55:30,250
坚持到阿斯加德人鲜血流尽
till the last drop of Asgardian blood.

600
00:55:33,400 --> 00:55:36,510
那您跟马勒基斯又有何区别
Then how are you different from Malekith?

601
00:55:39,580 --> 00:55:41,880
我的儿子  区别在于  我终将胜利
The different, my son, is that I will win.

602
00:55:56,350 --> 00:55:57,830
简不回我电话
Jane isn't calling me back.

603
00:55:57,960 --> 00:55:59,450
艾瑞克不回我电话
Erik isn't calling me Back.

604
00:55:59,480 --> 00:56:01,230
神盾局也不回我电话
Stupid S.H.I.E.L.D isn't calling me back.

605
00:56:01,230 --> 00:56:02,270
神盾局是什么
What's S.H.I.E.L.D?

606
00:56:02,270 --> 00:56:03,090
是秘密
It's a secret.

607
00:56:03,270 --> 00:56:05,490
艾瑞克  又是达西
Hi, Erik, it's Darcy again.

608
00:56:05,750 --> 00:56:06,860
托尔回来了
Thor came back, 

609
00:56:06,900 --> 00:56:08,290
他把简带去了阿斯加德
he took Jane to Asgard.

610
00:56:08,290 --> 00:56:12,220
我也不知道该怎么办才好
And I'm not sure what I'm suppose to do.

611
00:56:12,270 --> 00:56:14,020
这周还有人丢了点什么
Something else went missing this week, 

612
00:56:14,020 --> 00:56:17,060
天体物理学家  艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
when astrophysicist Dr. Erik Selvig

613
00:56:17,110 --> 00:56:19,750
因卷入纽约外星人入侵事件
notable for his involvement in the alien invasion 

614
00:56:19,750 --> 00:56:20,740
而为人所知
of New York.

615
00:56:20,930 --> 00:56:24,540
-裸奔在...  -达西  你得看看这个
- Stripped nude... - Darcy, you really need to look at this.

616
00:56:25,080 --> 00:56:26,400
你的朋友艾瑞克
Your friend Erik, 

617
00:56:26,540 --> 00:56:27,990
他姓什么来着
what was his last name again?

618
00:56:29,210 --> 00:56:32,630
并对该历史景点的游客大吼大叫
...and began shouting at visitors to the historic site.

619
00:56:32,640 --> 00:56:35,210
随后他被警方拘留
He was later taken into police custody

620
00:56:35,300 --> 00:56:37,320
以待精神鉴定
for psychiatric evaluation.

621
00:56:37,720 --> 00:56:40,020
警方仍然不肯证实...
The police is still refusing to confirm...

622
00:56:50,300 --> 00:56:52,130
你没去参加奥丁的军事会议
You were not at Odin's war council.

623
00:56:52,650 --> 00:56:55,330
你父王下令关闭彩虹桥
The Bifrost is closed by your father's orders.

624
00:56:55,330 --> 00:56:57,360
任何人不得进出阿斯加德
No one was to come, or to go.

625
00:56:59,670 --> 00:57:02,370
连我都看不见敌人
We face an enemy that is invisible even to me, 

626
00:57:02,370 --> 00:57:03,690
那么
what use

627
00:57:04,430 --> 00:57:06,130
我这个守护者还有何用
is a guardian such as that.

628
00:57:07,270 --> 00:57:09,920
马勒基斯还会回来的  这你很清楚
Malekith will return. You know this.

629
00:57:13,020 --> 00:57:14,270
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.

630
00:57:14,870 --> 00:57:16,940
我不能违抗国王的命令
I cannot overrule my king's wishes.

631
00:57:17,570 --> 00:57:18,680
即便是为你
Not even for you.

632
00:57:18,680 --> 00:57:20,040
我没有这个意思
I'm not asking you to.

633
00:57:20,290 --> 00:57:22,980
九大王国需要一个坚强  服众的众神之父
The realms need their All-father strong and unchallenged,

634
00:57:22,980 --> 00:57:24,530
不论情况是否如此
whether he is or not.

635
00:57:25,480 --> 00:57:27,170
但他看不清现实  海姆达尔
But he's binded Heimdall, 

636
00:57:27,810 --> 00:57:29,310
仇恨和悲伤蒙蔽了他
by hatred and by grief.

637
00:57:29,310 --> 00:57:30,240
我们不都是吗
As are we all.

638
00:57:30,240 --> 00:57:32,020
我看得很清楚
I see clearly enough.

639
00:57:32,490 --> 00:57:34,130
风险太大了
The risks are to great.

640
00:57:34,130 --> 00:57:36,610
从现在起  我们走的每一步都有风险
Everything we do from here on is a risk.

641
00:57:36,740 --> 00:57:38,320
我们别无选择
There is no other way.

642
00:57:42,750 --> 00:57:44,290
你要我怎么做
What do you require of me.

643
00:57:45,010 --> 00:57:48,220
我要你们做的事  是最严重的叛国罪
What I'm about to ask you is treason of the highest order.

644
00:57:48,820 --> 00:57:50,650
即便成功  我们也将被流放
Success will bring us exile, 

645
00:57:50,650 --> 00:57:52,600
而失败则必死无疑
and failure shall mean our death.

646
00:57:55,650 --> 00:57:58,210
马勒基斯知道以太粒子在这儿
Malekith knew the Aether was here.

647
00:57:58,300 --> 00:57:59,820
他能感应它的能量
He can sense its power.

648
00:58:00,190 --> 00:58:02,650
如果不采取行动  他会再次攻来
If we do nothing, he'll come for it again, 

649
00:58:02,650 --> 00:58:05,940
但这次  他们将彻底摧毁阿斯加德
but this time, lay waste to all of Asgard.

650
00:58:07,860 --> 00:58:09,760
我们得带简离开这儿
We must move Jane off world.

651
00:58:10,100 --> 00:58:11,370
彩虹桥已经关闭
The Bifrost has been shut down, 

652
00:58:11,370 --> 00:58:13,480
宇宙魔方也锁在地下室里
and the Tesseract locked away in the vault.

653
00:58:13,950 --> 00:58:15,890
离开阿斯加德还有其他途径
There are other path off Asgard,

654
00:58:16,250 --> 00:58:17,890
了解这些途径的人为数不多
ways known only to a few.

655
00:58:18,020 --> 00:58:19,600
准确说只有一个
One actually.

656
00:58:22,140 --> 00:58:22,780
不会吧
No.

657
00:58:28,140 --> 00:58:29,380
托尔
Thor.

658
00:58:29,990 --> 00:58:31,490
都这么久了
After all this time,

659
00:58:31,490 --> 00:58:33,180
你现在来看我
now you come to visit me,

660
00:58:35,250 --> 00:58:36,250
来干什么
why?

661
00:58:38,030 --> 00:58:39,530
幸灾乐祸吗
Have you come to gloat?

662
00:58:40,450 --> 00:58:41,070
嘲笑我
To mock?

663
00:58:41,070 --> 00:58:42,300
洛基  够了
Loki enough.

664
00:58:43,130 --> 00:58:44,620
别再用幻象了
No more illusions.

665
00:58:52,070 --> 00:58:53,570
现在你看到我了  哥哥
Now you see me brother.

666
00:59:02,840 --> 00:59:04,040
她走得痛苦吗
Did she suffer?

667
00:59:04,300 --> 00:59:06,670
我不是来跟你一同哀悼母亲的
I did not come here to share our grief.

668
00:59:07,270 --> 00:59:10,350
我是来给你机会得到一样更好的东西
Instead I offer you the chance of a far richer sacrament.

669
00:59:11,620 --> 00:59:12,610
说
Go on.

670
00:59:13,080 --> 00:59:15,430
我知道你跟我一样想复仇
I know you seek vengeance as much as I do.

671
00:59:16,060 --> 00:59:18,710
你帮我逃出阿斯加德  我就给你机会
You help me escape Asgard and I will grant it to you.

672
00:59:19,180 --> 00:59:20,130
让你复仇
Vengeance.

673
00:59:20,760 --> 00:59:22,150
然后再回这儿来
And afterwards this cell.

674
00:59:29,860 --> 00:59:34,050
你一定是走投无路了  才会来找我帮忙
You must be truely desperate to come to me for help.

675
00:59:36,430 --> 00:59:37,900
你凭什么觉得你能信任我
What makes you think you can trust me.

676
00:59:37,900 --> 00:59:38,970
我不信任
I don't.

677
00:59:41,120 --> 00:59:42,080
母亲信任你
Mother did.

678
00:59:43,390 --> 00:59:46,010
但你要知道  过去我们交手的时候
But you should know that when we fought each other in the past, 

679
00:59:46,960 --> 00:59:48,270
我仍然抱有一丝希望
I did so with a glimpse of hope 

680
00:59:48,280 --> 00:59:50,410
相信我弟弟还没完全消失
that my brother was still in there somewhere.

681
00:59:51,780 --> 00:59:54,130
这一丝希望已经幻灭  不能再保护你了
That hope is no longer exist to protect you.

682
00:59:55,160 --> 00:59:57,150
你敢背叛我  我就杀了你
You betray me, and I will kill you.

683
01:00:04,160 --> 01:00:05,300
什么时候出发
When do we start?

684
01:00:05,860 --> 01:00:07,290
他肯定会背叛你的
He will betray you.

685
01:00:07,580 --> 01:00:08,520
让他试试看
He will try.

686
01:00:13,310 --> 01:00:15,240
这太不像你了  哥哥
This is so unlike you, brother.

687
01:00:16,060 --> 01:00:17,600
这样秘密行动
So clandestine.

688
01:00:18,350 --> 01:00:20,980
你真的不想靠蛮力打出一条血路出去吗
Are you sure you wouldn't rather just punch your way out.

689
01:00:21,200 --> 01:00:23,090
你再不闭嘴我就要动手了
If you keep speaking I just might.

690
01:00:23,370 --> 01:00:24,850
好吧  听你的
Fine, as you wish,

691
01:00:25,310 --> 01:00:26,660
我都不在这儿
I'm not even here.

692
01:00:27,760 --> 01:00:28,830
这样好点了吧
Is this better?

693
01:00:29,290 --> 01:00:31,050
比你本人强多了
It's better company at least.

694
01:00:32,170 --> 01:00:35,430
不过  我们还可以再低调点
Still, we could be less conspicuous.

695
01:00:37,360 --> 01:00:38,460
哥哥
Umm, brother,

696
01:00:38,780 --> 01:00:40,070
你可真美
you look ravishing.

697
01:00:41,970 --> 01:00:44,430
就算变成这样  我照样能让你死得很惨
It will hurt no less when I kill you in this form.

698
01:00:44,600 --> 01:00:45,650
好吧
Very well.

699
01:00:46,180 --> 01:00:48,060
或许你想要你新结交的小伙伴
Perhaps you prefer one of your new companions,

700
01:00:48,060 --> 01:00:50,340
毕竟你似乎很喜欢他们
given that you seem to like them so much.

701
01:00:50,400 --> 01:00:52,190
这样好多了呢
Oh this is much better.

702
01:00:54,110 --> 01:00:55,550
服装不太合身
The costume is bit much.

703
01:00:55,570 --> 01:00:56,790
太紧了
So tight.

704
01:00:56,900 --> 01:00:58,170
但那股自信
But the confidence,

705
01:00:58,170 --> 01:01:00,640
我能感到正义在我身体里涌动
I can feel the righteousness surging.

706
01:01:00,980 --> 01:01:03,430
想跟我畅谈一下真理吗
Hey, do you wanna have a rousing discussion about truth?

707
01:01:03,510 --> 01:01:04,290
或是荣誉
Honor?

708
01:01:04,330 --> 01:01:05,370
爱国主义
Patriotism?

709
01:01:05,370 --> 01:01:06,650
天佑美国...
God bless America...

710
01:01:08,860 --> 01:01:09,650
干什么
What?

711
01:01:14,660 --> 01:01:16,670
你至少也该给我件武器啊
You could at least furnish me with a weapon.

712
01:01:17,320 --> 01:01:18,710
我的匕首什么的
My dagger, something.

713
01:01:24,700 --> 01:01:25,650
这才对嘛
At last, 

714
01:01:26,080 --> 01:01:27,770
总算讲点理了
a little common sense.

715
01:01:33,900 --> 01:01:35,440
你不就喜欢小戏法吗
And I thought you like tricks.

716
01:01:36,480 --> 01:01:37,490
然后呢
Well, what then?

717
01:01:38,010 --> 01:01:40,930
你心爱的凡人被一整队英灵战士看守着
Your lovely mortal is been guarded by a legion of Einherjar

718
01:01:40,930 --> 01:01:42,780
他们大老远就能看到你
who will see you coming from miles away.

719
01:01:42,780 --> 01:01:44,840
去接她的不是我
I won't be the one who comes for her.

720
01:01:52,680 --> 01:01:53,660
我不饿
I'm not hungry.

721
01:01:56,110 --> 01:01:57,380
那正好  我们走
Good, let's go.

722
01:02:04,030 --> 01:02:04,780
是你...
You're...

723
01:02:04,910 --> 01:02:06,580
我是洛基  你可能听说过我
I'm Loki, you may have heard of me.

724
01:02:07,270 --> 01:02:08,620
这一掌是为了纽约
That was for New York.

725
01:02:09,680 --> 01:02:10,710
我喜欢她
I like her.

726
01:02:11,400 --> 01:02:12,830
那众神之父呢
And what of the All-Father?

727
01:02:13,600 --> 01:02:17,090
我曾立誓向他通报一切叛国罪行
It is my sworn duty to notify him of crimes against the throne.

728
01:02:17,610 --> 01:02:18,950
你要我过来
You called me here

729
01:02:19,360 --> 01:02:20,710
说是有紧急情况
on urgent matter.

730
01:02:22,090 --> 01:02:22,860
是什么事
What is it?

731
01:02:23,460 --> 01:02:24,760
有人叛国犯上  陛下
Treason, my lord.

732
01:02:24,920 --> 01:02:25,730
是谁
Whose? 

733
01:02:27,000 --> 01:02:27,820
我
Mine.

734
01:02:29,150 --> 01:02:29,970
陛下
My king, 

735
01:02:30,460 --> 01:02:31,960
那个凡人被劫走了
the mortal has been taken.

736
01:02:36,240 --> 01:02:37,370
阻止托尔
Stop Thor,

737
01:02:37,630 --> 01:02:39,250
不惜一切代价
by any means necessary.

738
01:02:41,970 --> 01:02:43,660
他们在那儿  抓住他们
There they are! Take them.

739
01:02:44,530 --> 01:02:45,630
听我命令
On my command.

740
01:02:45,630 --> 01:02:47,380
我拖住他们  带她走
I'll hold them off. Take her.

741
01:02:48,650 --> 01:02:49,430
谢谢你
Thank you.

742
01:02:52,700 --> 01:02:53,700
你敢背叛他
Betray him,

743
01:02:53,790 --> 01:02:54,810
我就杀了你
and I'll kill you.

744
01:02:56,850 --> 01:02:58,610
我也很高兴见到你  希芙
It's good to see you, too, Sif.

745
01:03:05,070 --> 01:03:09,220
就算洛基肯帮你  你也救出了那个凡人
Assuming you can get Loki's help and you can free this mortal,

746
01:03:09,920 --> 01:03:11,190
又有什么用啊
what good would it do?

747
01:03:11,290 --> 01:03:14,330
我们踏出宫殿一步  就必死无疑
We'd all be dead the minute we step one foot outside the palace.

748
01:03:14,330 --> 01:03:17,700
所以  我的朋友  我们不会步行离开
That, my friend, is why we won't be leaving by foot.

749
01:03:21,740 --> 01:03:23,660
我尽量帮你拖延时间
I will give you as much time as I can.

750
01:03:23,660 --> 01:03:24,930
谢谢你  我的朋友
Thank you, my friend.

751
01:03:29,570 --> 01:03:32,380
你胆敢打背叛他的主意
If you even think of betraying him.

752
01:03:32,390 --> 01:03:33,610
你就杀了我吗
You'll kill me?

753
01:03:34,690 --> 01:03:36,200
看来你得排队了
Evidently there will be a line.

754
01:03:51,820 --> 01:03:53,730
你不是说你会驾驶这东西吗
I thought you said you knew how to fly this thing.

755
01:03:54,160 --> 01:03:55,920
我是说这能有多难
I said "How hard could it be".

756
01:03:59,330 --> 01:04:00,620
他们在飞船上
They're on the ship.

757
01:04:01,180 --> 01:04:02,390
拦住飞船
Get to the ship.

758
01:04:06,230 --> 01:04:08,600
不管你在做什么  哥哥  你得快点了
Well, whatever you're doing brother, I suggest you do it faster.

759
01:04:08,610 --> 01:04:09,710
闭嘴  洛基
Shut up, Loki.

760
01:04:12,490 --> 01:04:13,760
你肯定漏掉什么了
You must have missed something.

761
01:04:13,850 --> 01:04:16,230
我没有  我把这上面的按钮都按遍了
No, I didn't, I'm pressing every button on this thing.

762
01:04:16,230 --> 01:04:17,950
别用力那么猛  轻轻按
No. Don't hit it, just press it gently.

763
01:04:17,950 --> 01:04:20,870
我在轻轻按了  不好使
I am pressing it gently, it's not working.

764
01:04:27,370 --> 01:04:29,350
擒住他  拿下他
Get him! Get him!

765
01:04:58,730 --> 01:04:59,790
还有根柱子没撞到呢
I think you missed a column.

766
01:04:59,800 --> 01:05:00,590
闭嘴
Shut up!

767
01:05:07,570 --> 01:05:08,870
你为什么不让我来呢
Look, why don't you let me take over,

768
01:05:08,870 --> 01:05:10,360
我的驾驶技术显然更好
I'm clearly the best pilot.

769
01:05:10,480 --> 01:05:11,380
是嘛
Is that right? 

770
01:05:11,380 --> 01:05:14,270
我们两个人中  谁才是会飞的那个
Well, out of the two of us, which one can actually fly?

771
01:05:24,570 --> 01:05:26,440
天啊  她死了吗
Oh dear, is she dead?

772
01:05:26,440 --> 01:05:27,230
简
Jane.

773
01:05:28,170 --> 01:05:29,150
我没事
I'm okay.

774
01:05:36,150 --> 01:05:37,430
别多嘴
Not a word.

775
01:05:39,540 --> 01:05:40,850
他们跟上来了
Now they're following us.

776
01:05:46,250 --> 01:05:47,190
他们开火了
Now they're firing at us.

777
01:05:47,200 --> 01:05:48,900
多谢你的解说  洛基
Yeah, thank you for the commentary Loki, 

778
01:05:48,900 --> 01:05:50,480
完全不会让人分心
it's not at all distracting.

779
01:05:54,930 --> 01:05:57,540
干得漂亮  你把你爷爷的头砍下来了
Well done, you just decapitated your grandfather.

780
01:06:08,840 --> 01:06:10,140
这真是太棒了
You know this is wonderful, 

781
01:06:10,340 --> 01:06:12,560
这主意真是了不起
this is a tremendous idea.

782
01:06:12,820 --> 01:06:16,170
我们去把宇宙中最大最显眼的飞船偷来
Let's steal the biggest, most obvious ship in the universe,

783
01:06:16,170 --> 01:06:17,430
乘着它逃跑
and escape in that.

784
01:06:17,440 --> 01:06:18,470
驾着它满城乱飞
Flying around the city, 

785
01:06:18,470 --> 01:06:21,040
看见什么撞什么  让大家都看见我们
smashing into everything in sight, so everyone can see us.

786
01:06:21,050 --> 01:06:22,240
太聪明了  托尔
It's brilliant, Thor.

787
01:06:22,240 --> 01:06:23,440
真有你的
It's truly brilliant.

788
01:06:37,380 --> 01:06:38,920
在牢里关了那么久
I see your time in the dungeons

789
01:06:38,920 --> 01:06:41,550
你还是这么优雅啊  洛基
has make you no less graceful, Loki.

790
01:06:45,990 --> 01:06:47,090
你骗我
You lied to me.

791
01:06:49,130 --> 01:06:50,310
挺厉害啊
I'm impressed.

792
01:06:50,340 --> 01:06:51,610
你满意我很高兴
I'm glad you're pleased.

793
01:06:51,640 --> 01:06:52,990
遵守你的承诺吧
Now do as you promised.

794
01:06:53,130 --> 01:06:54,990
带我们去你的秘密通道
And take us to your secret pathway.

795
01:07:18,260 --> 01:07:19,000
范达尔
Fandral.

796
01:07:19,140 --> 01:07:19,930
好的
Right.

797
01:07:23,520 --> 01:07:24,590
为了阿斯加德
For Asgard.

798
01:07:29,920 --> 01:07:31,300
别往心里去啊  伙计们
Nothing personal, boys.

799
01:07:46,890 --> 01:07:47,800
洛基
Loki.

800
01:07:48,030 --> 01:07:49,350
如果那么容易
If it were easy, 

801
01:07:49,860 --> 01:07:51,380
谁都能做到了
everyone would do it.

802
01:07:51,700 --> 01:07:52,660
你疯了吗
Are you mad?

803
01:07:52,720 --> 01:07:53,640
或许吧
Possibly.

804
01:08:09,400 --> 01:08:10,340
胜利到达
Ta-da.

805
01:08:50,570 --> 01:08:54,030
那能量要是给我  我能做多少事啊
What I could do with the power that flows through those veins.

806
01:08:54,580 --> 01:08:56,870
你会被吞噬的
It would consume you.

807
01:08:58,030 --> 01:08:59,560
她不就没事
She's holding up all right

808
01:09:00,390 --> 01:09:01,470
暂时没事
For now. 

809
01:09:01,960 --> 01:09:04,260
她拥有的力量你无法理解
She's strong in ways you'd never even know.

810
01:09:04,780 --> 01:09:05,950
道别吧
Say goodbye.

811
01:09:06,750 --> 01:09:07,710
不会是今天
Not this day.

812
01:09:07,770 --> 01:09:09,220
今天  明天
This day, the next,

813
01:09:09,330 --> 01:09:10,870
一百年  算什么
a hundred years, is nothing,

814
01:09:12,070 --> 01:09:13,350
弹指一挥间而已
it's a heartbeat.

815
01:09:14,030 --> 01:09:15,500
你永远放不开手
You'll never be ready.

816
01:09:16,430 --> 01:09:19,460
你唯一珍视的挚爱终将被岁月夺去
The only woman whose love you've prized will be snatched from you.

817
01:09:19,460 --> 01:09:21,340
那样你就满足了吗
And will that satisfy you.

818
01:09:21,340 --> 01:09:22,660
我永远不会满足
Satisfaction is not in my nature.

819
01:09:22,660 --> 01:09:24,100
我永远不会放弃
Surrender is not in mine.

820
01:09:25,930 --> 01:09:27,070
果然是奥丁之子
Son of Odin.

821
01:09:27,070 --> 01:09:29,160
我不只是奥丁的儿子
No, not just of Odin.

822
01:09:29,590 --> 01:09:31,920
你以为母亲只爱你吗
You think you alone were loved of Mother?

823
01:09:32,120 --> 01:09:34,510
她把技艺教给了你  但她信任的是我
You had her tricks but I had her trust.

824
01:09:34,510 --> 01:09:35,370
信任
Trust? 

825
01:09:36,510 --> 01:09:38,140
那是她的遗言吗
Was that her last expression?

826
01:09:38,650 --> 01:09:39,610
她信任你
Trust? 

827
01:09:39,650 --> 01:09:41,120
你却眼睁睁看她遇害
When you let her die?

828
01:09:41,120 --> 01:09:42,960
你在地牢里出手相救了吗
What help were you in your cell?

829
01:09:42,960 --> 01:09:43,920
谁把我关进去的
Who put me there?

830
01:09:44,090 --> 01:09:45,530
谁把我关进去的
Who put me there?

831
01:09:45,530 --> 01:09:48,700
你心里清楚  你心里清楚是谁
You know damn well. You know damn well who.

832
01:09:55,110 --> 01:09:57,060
她不会希望我们兄弟相争
She wouldn't want us to fight.

833
01:09:59,140 --> 01:10:01,350
她都见怪不怪了吧
Well, she wouldn't exactly be shocked.

834
01:10:06,040 --> 01:10:08,030
真希望我能相信你
I wish I can trust you.

835
01:10:23,090 --> 01:10:24,580
相信我的怒火吧
Trust my rage.

836
01:10:31,250 --> 01:10:34,720
塞尔维格先生  请签收您父亲的物品
You'll have to sign for your fathers' belongings Mr. Selvig.

837
01:10:35,300 --> 01:10:36,020
什么
What?

838
01:10:36,780 --> 01:10:37,870
啊对
Oh, yeah.

839
01:10:38,520 --> 01:10:41,160
我父亲  艾瑞克·塞尔维格博士
My father Dr. Erik Selvig.

840
01:10:42,850 --> 01:10:45,300
一个棕色男士钱包
One man's leather wallet, brown,

841
01:10:45,300 --> 01:10:47,500
一串钥匙  共三把
one keyring, three keys, 

842
01:10:48,020 --> 01:10:49,360
处方药
prescription medicine,

843
01:10:50,490 --> 01:10:51,580
若干
various.

844
01:10:54,250 --> 01:10:56,100
-还有  -艾瑞克
- And, - Erik.

845
01:10:57,840 --> 01:11:00,290
-这些  -对  这些
- These. - Yeah, those. 

846
01:11:00,860 --> 01:11:01,970
谢天谢地
Thank goodness.

847
01:11:03,930 --> 01:11:04,860
艾瑞克
Erik.

848
01:11:07,030 --> 01:11:07,710
嗯
Yes.

849
01:11:08,070 --> 01:11:09,920
我是达西
It's...Darcy.

850
01:11:10,030 --> 01:11:11,200
达西
Darcy.

851
01:11:13,270 --> 01:11:14,710
见到你真高兴
So good to see you.

852
01:11:14,880 --> 01:11:16,300
我也挺想你
I miss you too.

853
01:11:16,310 --> 01:11:17,420
你怎么找到我的
How did you find me?

854
01:11:17,420 --> 01:11:18,990
你在电视上裸奔了
You were naked on TV.

855
01:11:19,950 --> 01:11:22,190
好了  该走了  还有事要做
Okay, it's time to go, lots to do.

856
01:11:24,610 --> 01:11:25,810
越来越尴尬了
Getting weird now.

857
01:11:28,100 --> 01:11:30,840
怎么能让我管这些事
I should not be left in charge of stuff like this,

858
01:11:30,840 --> 01:11:32,010
又没人给我那么多钱
I don't get paid enough.

859
01:11:32,010 --> 01:11:33,440
是根本没人给我钱
I don't get paid period.

860
01:11:34,140 --> 01:11:37,230
那个  我叫伊恩  达西的实习生
I'm Ian, by the way, Darcy's inter. 

861
01:11:37,370 --> 01:11:38,960
也没人给我钱
Yeah, I don't get paid either.

862
01:11:40,080 --> 01:11:41,580
你没事吧
Are you alright?

863
01:11:42,030 --> 01:11:43,770
我脑子里有个神
I've had a god in my brain.

864
01:11:45,030 --> 01:11:46,640
这滋味可不好受了
I don't recommend it.

865
01:11:48,500 --> 01:11:50,750
塞尔维格博士  这设备响了
Dr. Selvig, sir, your gear is beeping.

866
01:11:50,750 --> 01:11:51,640
果然开始了
It's happening.

867
01:11:51,640 --> 01:11:53,260
比我计算得还早
It's sooner than I calculate.

868
01:11:53,280 --> 01:11:54,630
什么开始了
Wait what's happening?

869
01:11:58,410 --> 01:11:59,110
鸟吗
Birds?

870
01:11:59,950 --> 01:12:01,120
鸟儿开始了
Birds are happening?

871
01:12:01,540 --> 01:12:03,820
那是一群欧椋鸟
It's starling. It's called the murmuration.

872
01:12:01,540 --> 01:12:03,820
{\an8}专门用于一大群欧椋鸟的量词

873
01:12:03,830 --> 01:12:06,130
小时候我爸常带我去观鸟
My dad, he used to take me bird watching as a kid.

874
01:12:06,300 --> 01:12:07,070
呆子
Nerd.

875
01:12:07,340 --> 01:12:07,880
看
Look.

876
01:12:12,540 --> 01:12:13,480
他们去哪了
Where did they go?

877
01:12:27,310 --> 01:12:28,750
刚刚怎么回事
What the hell was that?

878
01:12:30,060 --> 01:12:31,370
你笑什么
Why are you smiling?

879
01:12:31,840 --> 01:12:33,840
发现这世界比我还疯狂
There's nothing more reassuring than realize 

880
01:12:33,840 --> 01:12:35,920
我倍感安心
that the world is crazier than you are.

881
01:12:37,280 --> 01:12:38,730
带我去简的实验室
Take me to Jane's lab.

882
01:12:52,290 --> 01:12:53,040
简
Jane.

883
01:13:00,470 --> 01:13:01,480
马勒基斯
Malekith.

884
01:13:24,110 --> 01:13:25,240
准备好了吗
All right, are you ready?

885
01:13:26,170 --> 01:13:27,020
我准备好了
I am.

886
01:13:40,990 --> 01:13:43,210
你这破计划得把咱俩都害死
You know this plan of yours is gonna get us killed.

887
01:13:43,210 --> 01:13:44,270
或许吧
Yeah, possibly.

888
01:13:48,740 --> 01:13:50,390
你还不相信我吗  哥哥
You still don't trust me, brother?

889
01:13:51,570 --> 01:13:52,350
你会相信你吗
Would you?

890
01:14:02,010 --> 01:14:03,550
不会
No, I wouldn't.

891
01:14:07,570 --> 01:14:08,530
托尔
Thor.

892
01:14:10,140 --> 01:14:10,920
不
No.

893
01:14:20,950 --> 01:14:23,510
你真以为我在乎弗丽嘉
You really think I cared about Frigga.

894
01:14:23,690 --> 01:14:25,170
在乎你们任何人吗
About any of you.

895
01:14:28,370 --> 01:14:29,940
我只渴望
All I ever wanted 

896
01:14:30,490 --> 01:14:31,820
看到你和奥丁
was you and Odin 

897
01:14:31,930 --> 01:14:33,340
死在我脚下
dead at my feet.

898
01:14:45,960 --> 01:14:47,080
马勒基斯
Malekith.

899
01:14:48,360 --> 01:14:50,350
我是约顿海姆的洛基
I am Loki of Jotunheim.

900
01:14:50,840 --> 01:14:52,480
给你送来了大礼
And I bring you a gift.

901
01:14:54,040 --> 01:14:55,940
我要的回报很简单
I ask only one thing in return.

902
01:14:56,700 --> 01:14:59,820
让我看着阿斯加德化为灰烬
A good seat from which to watch Asgard burned.

903
01:15:20,090 --> 01:15:21,150
看着我
Look at me.

904
01:16:19,250 --> 01:16:21,010
洛基  快
Loki, now!

905
01:19:35,450 --> 01:19:36,920
不
No!

906
01:19:46,320 --> 01:19:48,250
我们地狱见  怪物
See you in hell, monster.

907
01:20:07,040 --> 01:20:08,970
不不不不
No, no, no, no...

908
01:20:11,110 --> 01:20:14,100
-你真傻  怎么不听我的  -我知道
- You fool, you didn't listen. - I know.

909
01:20:15,450 --> 01:20:16,600
我真傻
I'm a fool. 

910
01:20:17,030 --> 01:20:19,070
-我真傻  -挺住
- I'm a fool. - Stay with me. Okay?

911
01:20:19,530 --> 01:20:20,580
对不起
I'm sorry.

912
01:20:22,180 --> 01:20:24,040
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.

913
01:20:24,210 --> 01:20:25,200
没事的
It's okay.

914
01:20:29,380 --> 01:20:30,430
没事的
It's all right. 

915
01:20:30,920 --> 01:20:33,290
你的英勇我会禀告父王
I'll tell father what you did here today.

916
01:20:37,720 --> 01:20:39,400
我不是为了他
I didn't do it for him.

917
01:20:49,260 --> 01:20:50,980
不
No!

918
01:21:45,320 --> 01:21:46,860
他要释放以太
He's going to unleash it.

919
01:21:47,590 --> 01:21:49,530
不只是在阿斯加德或是哪个星球
No just on Asgard or on a stars.

920
01:21:49,530 --> 01:21:52,900
马勒基斯要毁灭一切
Malekith is gonna destroy everything.

921
01:21:52,900 --> 01:21:53,950
怎么毁灭
How?

922
01:21:54,840 --> 01:21:56,100
简  怎么毁灭
Jane, how?

923
01:21:56,220 --> 01:21:59,560
我看到他在地球上  他去那儿干什么
I saw him on Earth. Why would he go to Earth?

924
01:22:00,070 --> 01:22:01,290
天体汇聚
The Convergence.

925
01:22:01,500 --> 01:22:02,710
天哪
Oh, God. 

926
01:22:02,710 --> 01:22:05,360
我要是没发现以太  就不会走到这一步了
None of this would have happened if I hadn't found the Aether.

927
01:22:06,130 --> 01:22:09,090
马勒基斯只会更早得到以太
Then Malekith would've only possess that much sooner.

928
01:22:09,590 --> 01:22:11,880
我是找你的时候发现了以太
I only found it because I was looking for you.

929
01:22:12,770 --> 01:22:13,820
简
Jane.

930
01:22:15,590 --> 01:22:17,250
结果困在这儿了
Now we're trapped here.

931
01:22:23,980 --> 01:22:25,270
不是我
It's not me.

932
01:22:26,270 --> 01:22:27,040
喂
Hello?

933
01:22:27,040 --> 01:22:29,150
简  是我  理查德
Hi, Jane, it's Richard.

934
01:22:29,150 --> 01:22:30,920
理查德  你在哪
Richard? Where are you?

935
01:22:30,920 --> 01:22:34,180
还在办公室里  今天忙疯了
I'm still at the office, it's...it's been a crazy day here today.

936
01:22:34,180 --> 01:22:35,490
天哪  太神奇了
Oh, my God, this is amazing.

937
01:22:35,490 --> 01:22:37,650
是吗  跟你共进午餐很开心
Is it? I quite enjoy our lunch. 

938
01:22:37,650 --> 01:22:39,860
虽然什么都没点
Despite never actually ordering anything.

939
01:22:39,870 --> 01:22:41,570
这地方怎么有信号
How am I getting service here?

940
01:22:41,570 --> 01:22:43,540
现在不方便吗  要不我过会儿再打
Is it a bad time? Do you want me to try later?

941
01:22:43,540 --> 01:22:45,600
不不  无论如何
No, no, no... please, whatever you do, 

942
01:22:45,600 --> 01:22:47,070
千万别挂电话
do not hang up the phone.

943
01:22:47,940 --> 01:22:48,940
好吧
Okay then. 

944
01:22:48,940 --> 01:22:51,160
我就是想问你想不想再约一次
I was just wondering if you want to try again.

945
01:22:51,160 --> 01:22:52,760
一起共进晚餐吧
Uh, maybe dinner next time. 

946
01:22:52,770 --> 01:22:54,250
好啊
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah.

947
01:22:54,250 --> 01:22:55,870
别挂电话  好吗
Just... stay on the phone, okay? 

948
01:22:55,870 --> 01:22:57,200
好呀
Yeah, I will.

949
01:22:57,200 --> 01:22:58,390
天哪
Oh, my God.

950
01:23:02,830 --> 01:23:04,040
你在忙吗
Am I interrupting something?

951
01:23:04,040 --> 01:23:05,740
没  没有
No, no... nothing at all.

952
01:23:06,300 --> 01:23:08,210
-走吧  -我听不清  你在隧道里吗
- Come on. - I'm losing you there, are you in tunnel?

953
01:23:08,220 --> 01:23:09,560
怎么  这是去哪
What? Where are we going?

954
01:23:10,040 --> 01:23:10,910
喂
Hello? 

955
01:23:10,910 --> 01:23:12,630
这里怎么这么多鞋
Why are there so many shoes in here?

956
01:23:14,330 --> 01:23:15,690
还是发短信吧
I'll just text her.

957
01:23:28,330 --> 01:23:29,770
理查德是谁
So who's Richard?

958
01:23:29,770 --> 01:23:30,880
你不是吧
Really?

959
01:23:39,610 --> 01:23:40,620
简
Jane.

960
01:23:41,120 --> 01:23:44,520
你怎么说走就走  全世界都疯了
You can't just leave like that. The whole world is going crazy.

961
01:23:44,520 --> 01:23:46,550
我们之前看到的异象到处都是了
All the stuff we saw is spreading.

962
01:23:47,580 --> 01:23:48,740
你去参加派对了吗
Did you go to a party?

963
01:23:48,740 --> 01:23:49,910
艾瑞克
Erik?

964
01:23:50,200 --> 01:23:51,240
简
Jane.

965
01:23:51,630 --> 01:23:52,840
太好了
How wonderful.

966
01:23:55,610 --> 01:23:56,590
你去阿斯加德了
You've been to Asgard. 

967
01:23:56,590 --> 01:23:57,420
你的裤子呢
Where are your pants?

968
01:23:57,430 --> 01:23:59,270
他说光着有助于思考
Oh, he says it helps him think.

969
01:23:59,270 --> 01:24:01,160
你的研究成果都给我
Okay, well, I'm gonna need everything you got on this,

970
01:24:01,160 --> 01:24:03,510
所有针对重力异常的研究
all the work you've been doing on gravimetric anomalies, 

971
01:24:03,510 --> 01:24:04,710
-都给我  -好吧
- everything. - Okay.

972
01:24:04,870 --> 01:24:06,530
你还好吧  艾瑞克
Are you well, Erik?

973
01:24:07,820 --> 01:24:09,680
你弟弟不来吧
Your brother's not coming, is he?

974
01:24:10,290 --> 01:24:11,710
洛基死了
Loki is dead.

975
01:24:11,710 --> 01:24:13,070
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.

976
01:24:14,070 --> 01:24:16,530
那个  请节哀
I.. meant, I'm so sorry.

977
01:24:16,530 --> 01:24:17,580
谢谢
Thank you.

978
01:24:41,590 --> 01:24:43,050
打扰了  陛下
Forgive me, my liege.

979
01:24:44,290 --> 01:24:46,610
我从黑暗世界带来了消息
I've returned from the Dark World with news.

980
01:24:49,420 --> 01:24:50,480
托尔吗
Thor?

981
01:24:50,930 --> 01:24:52,630
没见到他
There was no sign of Thor.

982
01:24:53,260 --> 01:24:54,760
也不见那个武器  但是
Or the weapon, but...

983
01:24:57,230 --> 01:24:58,270
怎么了
What?

984
01:25:01,380 --> 01:25:02,640
发现了具尸体
We found a body.

985
01:25:07,720 --> 01:25:08,800
洛基
Loki.

986
01:25:12,850 --> 01:25:14,440
马勒基斯要在
Malekith is going to fire the Aether 

987
01:25:14,440 --> 01:25:16,970
九大王国汇聚相连的地方发射以太
at the spot where all the nine worlds are connecting.

988
01:25:16,970 --> 01:25:19,190
以增加以太的威力
Amplifying the weapon's impact.

989
01:25:19,610 --> 01:25:23,350
威力随连通的王国数的增加呈指数增长
For each additional world, the power will increase exponentially.

990
01:25:23,350 --> 01:25:25,870
足以波及整个宇宙
The effect would be universal.

991
01:25:26,300 --> 01:25:27,990
但汇聚只会维持很短的时间
Yes, but the Alignment is only temperory, 

992
01:25:27,990 --> 01:25:30,890
他必须分秒不差地赶到正确地点
he must be in exactly the right place at the right time.

993
01:25:30,890 --> 01:25:32,580
那正确地点是哪
Well, how do we know where that is?

994
01:25:33,970 --> 01:25:35,650
沿着路标走
We follow the directions.

995
01:25:36,680 --> 01:25:39,210
几千年前汇聚也曾发生过
This has happened before, thousands of years ago.

996
01:25:39,210 --> 01:25:41,100
古人曾亲眼目睹
And the Ancients were there to see it.

997
01:25:42,010 --> 01:25:43,910
那些了不起的古建筑工程
All the great constructions,

998
01:25:44,230 --> 01:25:47,300
玛雅人  中国人  古埃及人
the Mayans, the Chinese, the Egyptians.

999
01:25:47,300 --> 01:25:50,810
都曾利用汇聚对重力的影响
They made use of the gravitational affects of the Convergence.

1000
01:25:50,810 --> 01:25:52,210
这就是我们的地图
And they left us a map.

1001
01:25:52,850 --> 01:25:54,000
巨石阵
Stonehenge.

1002
01:25:55,710 --> 01:25:57,890
斯诺登山  大奥姆岬
Snowdon. Great Orme.

1003
01:25:57,890 --> 01:26:00,190
以他们为坐标  就能找到
These are all coordinates. Taking us...

1004
01:26:01,730 --> 01:26:02,760
这里
here.

1005
01:26:04,980 --> 01:26:06,110
格林威治
Greenwich.

1006
01:26:06,310 --> 01:26:09,130
九大王国之间的界限将几乎消失
The walls between worlds will almost non-existing, 

1007
01:26:09,130 --> 01:26:10,630
物理学定律完全乱套
physics is gonna go ballistic.

1008
01:26:10,630 --> 01:26:12,470
重力忽增忽减
Increases and decreases of gravity, 

1009
01:26:12,470 --> 01:26:13,920
空间挤压
spacial extrusions, 

1010
01:26:13,920 --> 01:26:16,740
现实的世界在那里支离破碎
the very fabric of reality is gonna be torn apart.

1011
01:26:19,890 --> 01:26:21,230
我还是穿上裤子吧
I better get my pants.

1012
01:26:23,700 --> 01:26:25,300
集中精神  这可重要了
Focus, this is important.

1013
01:26:25,300 --> 01:26:26,930
我们得先把仪器钉在周围
We had to hammer them in all around the site, 

1014
01:26:26,930 --> 01:26:29,240
然后简和艾瑞克会在塔上启动
and then Jane and Erik will activate them from the tower.

1015
01:26:29,240 --> 01:26:30,670
都绑在一起了
They're taped together.

1016
01:26:31,060 --> 01:26:33,320
你知道这仪器是干什么的吗
Do you even know what these things do?

1017
01:26:34,370 --> 01:26:35,390
不知道
No.

1018
01:26:36,020 --> 01:26:37,180
我也不知道
Neither do I.

1019
01:26:45,500 --> 01:26:47,620
-快点  快点  -好吧
- Come on, come on, come on. - Right.

1020
01:27:00,420 --> 01:27:01,630
我...
Holy 

1021
01:27:02,000 --> 01:27:02,920
去
shit.

1022
01:28:20,800 --> 01:28:23,360
何必跑这么远  阿斯加德人
You needn't have come so far Asgardian.

1023
01:28:23,360 --> 01:28:25,910
死亡很快就要找上门了
Death would've come to you soon enough.

1024
01:28:25,910 --> 01:28:27,330
那也不是死在你手上
Not by your hand.

1025
01:28:27,330 --> 01:28:30,480
你们的宇宙就不该存在
Your universe was never meant to be.

1026
01:28:30,480 --> 01:28:35,230
你的王国  你的家人将被彻底消灭
Your world, and your family will be extinguished.

1027
01:28:37,790 --> 01:28:39,180
没时间了
We're running out of time.

1028
01:28:39,190 --> 01:28:40,280
快了
Almost there. 

1029
01:28:40,280 --> 01:28:41,930
这真的能行吗
You sure this is gonna work.

1030
01:28:41,930 --> 01:28:44,950
这仪器是用来检测异常的  而不是引发异常
These devices were made to detect anomalies, not causing them.

1031
01:28:45,440 --> 01:28:46,540
快点
Come on.

1032
01:28:51,770 --> 01:28:52,880
快点  达西
Come on, Darcy.

1033
01:29:03,550 --> 01:29:05,270
你有那么强的力量
You know, with all that power,

1034
01:29:06,230 --> 01:29:07,760
出手怎么这么轻
I thought you'd hit harder.

1035
01:29:32,850 --> 01:29:33,830
好了
Done.

1036
01:29:41,260 --> 01:29:43,630
天体汇聚将于7分钟后达到最佳状态
The Convergences will be in full effect in 7 minutes.

1037
01:29:43,630 --> 01:29:46,200
那我们得拖住马勒基斯8分钟
That just means we have to keep Malekith busy for 8.

1038
01:29:52,480 --> 01:29:55,010
好了  你最好扶稳了
Okay, you might want to hold on to something.

1039
01:30:00,490 --> 01:30:03,160
太厉害了  你怎么办到的
That is awesome. How did you do that?

1040
01:30:03,160 --> 01:30:06,930
重力场与各王国之间的薄弱点相互作用
Well, gravitational fields interact with the weak spot between worlds...

1041
01:30:06,930 --> 01:30:08,970
-产生了  -干掉拿剑的那个
- creating... - Get the guy with the sword.

1042
01:30:12,860 --> 01:30:13,840
走吧
Let's go.

1043
01:30:15,610 --> 01:30:17,400
这是怎么回事
What the hell just happened?

1044
01:30:18,560 --> 01:30:19,620
快跑
Move!

1045
01:30:37,120 --> 01:30:38,420
你们干什么呢
What are you all doing?

1046
01:30:38,420 --> 01:30:40,400
赶快出去啊
You need to get out of here. Now.

1047
01:30:40,400 --> 01:30:41,560
你开玩笑呢
You're joking, right? 

1048
01:30:41,560 --> 01:30:42,750
那可是雷神
That's Thor out there, 

1049
01:30:42,750 --> 01:30:45,160
还拿着锤子挥来挥去
he's waving his hammer around and everything.

1050
01:32:03,600 --> 01:32:05,020
请确认是否为敌方飞船
Confirming ship is hostile.

1051
01:32:05,250 --> 01:32:06,950
确认为敌方飞船
Confirmed, ship is hostile.

1052
01:32:07,110 --> 01:32:08,730
可以开火
You have permission to engage.

1053
01:32:08,730 --> 01:32:10,950
收到  导弹锁定
Roger, missiles locked.

1054
01:32:11,560 --> 01:32:12,740
导弹已发射
Missiles away.

1055
01:32:14,870 --> 01:32:17,920
导弹偏离目标  重复  偏离目标
Missiles off target. I repeat, target missed.

1056
01:32:17,920 --> 01:32:19,900
我失去控制了  求救  求救
I'm losing control. Mayday. Mayday. 

1057
01:32:19,900 --> 01:32:21,660
我失去控制了
Lost positive control.

1058
01:32:23,790 --> 01:32:24,860
你干什么
What're you doing?

1059
01:32:24,860 --> 01:32:26,470
信号连不上了
The signal's not connecting.

1060
01:32:29,130 --> 01:32:30,100
简
Jane.

1061
01:32:30,310 --> 01:32:31,280
快跑
Come on.

1062
01:33:13,250 --> 01:33:14,220
你还好吧
Are you all right?

1063
01:33:14,860 --> 01:33:16,280
你救了我
You save my life.

1064
01:33:19,580 --> 01:33:21,730
是啊  没错
Yeah. I guess I did.

1065
01:33:31,040 --> 01:33:32,940
-达西  -简
- Darcy? - Jane.

1066
01:33:33,520 --> 01:33:34,480
伊恩
Ian.

1067
01:33:34,760 --> 01:33:35,890
塞尔维格
Selvig.

1068
01:33:36,210 --> 01:33:37,250
飞锤
Mew mew!

1069
01:33:40,920 --> 01:33:42,760
注意站台间隙
Mind the gap.

1070
01:33:45,030 --> 01:33:46,470
怎么去格林威治
How do I get to Greenwich?

1071
01:33:47,190 --> 01:33:49,010
上车  坐三站
Take this train, three stops.

1072
01:33:51,050 --> 01:33:52,940
注意站台间隙
Mind the gap.

1073
01:33:55,700 --> 01:33:57,730
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry. Sorry.

1074
01:34:35,200 --> 01:34:36,290
没时间了
We're out of time.

1075
01:34:36,510 --> 01:34:37,480
简
Jane.

1076
01:34:37,990 --> 01:34:38,960
简
Jane.

1077
01:35:05,120 --> 01:35:06,070
托尔
Thor.

1078
01:35:07,500 --> 01:35:08,590
太晚了
We're too late.

1079
01:35:09,890 --> 01:35:11,600
天体汇聚已达最佳状态
The Convergence is at its peak.

1080
01:35:12,880 --> 01:35:14,380
这东西能阻止他吗
Can those things stop him?

1081
01:35:14,600 --> 01:35:15,370
在这儿不行
Not from here.

1082
01:35:15,380 --> 01:35:16,930
我们没法接近他
We can't get close enough.

1083
01:35:19,240 --> 01:35:20,250
我能
I can.

1084
01:35:45,810 --> 01:35:46,920
马勒基斯
Malekith.

1085
01:35:54,240 --> 01:35:56,860
黑暗回来了  阿斯加德人
Darkness returns, Asgardian.

1086
01:35:57,550 --> 01:36:00,530
你是来看宇宙湮灭的吗
Have you come to witness the end of the universe?

1087
01:36:00,870 --> 01:36:03,060
我是来受降的
I've come to accept your surrender.

1088
01:36:22,570 --> 01:36:25,020
你觉得你能阻止吗
You think you can stop this?

1089
01:36:25,350 --> 01:36:27,920
以太是不可摧毁的
The Aether cannot be destroyed.

1090
01:36:28,220 --> 01:36:29,350
但你不是
But you can.

1091
01:37:15,780 --> 01:37:16,780
托尔
Thor!

1092
01:37:17,280 --> 01:37:17,870
不要
No.

1093
01:37:28,250 --> 01:37:29,210
简
Jane.

1094
01:37:59,550 --> 01:38:00,870
大家还好吧
Everybody okay?

1095
01:38:45,710 --> 01:38:47,020
他会回来的
He's gonna come back.

1096
01:38:49,910 --> 01:38:51,280
就是...
Except, you know...

1097
01:38:51,960 --> 01:38:54,430
上次他一走就是两年
last time he was gone for like two years.

1098
01:38:54,700 --> 01:38:56,850
他才走了两天
Well, it's only been two days, so...

1099
01:38:57,740 --> 01:38:59,840
他走之前说什么了吗
Did he say anything before he left?

1100
01:38:59,970 --> 01:39:02,420
说了  他得跟他父王做些解释
Yeah, he had to figure some stuff out with his father, 

1101
01:39:02,430 --> 01:39:04,340
我们逃出来的时候
he kinda committed treason 

1102
01:39:04,920 --> 01:39:06,210
他犯了叛国罪
on our way out.

1103
01:39:15,060 --> 01:39:19,580
你曾说  不会有比我更贤明的君主
You once said, there would never be a wiser king than me.

1104
01:39:19,900 --> 01:39:21,040
你错了
You were wrong.

1105
01:39:21,440 --> 01:39:24,950
九大王国汇聚在一起
The Alignment has broght all the realms together, 

1106
01:39:25,500 --> 01:39:28,670
他们都看到你用生命拯救了他们
every one of them saw you offer your life to save them.

1107
01:39:29,170 --> 01:39:33,360
阿斯加德要如何回报它新的国王呢
What can Asgard offer its new king in return?

1108
01:39:34,800 --> 01:39:35,980
我的生活
My life.

1109
01:39:37,890 --> 01:39:40,210
父王  我不能做国王
Father I cannot be king of Asgard.

1110
01:39:40,700 --> 01:39:45,420
我会用一生竭力保卫九大王国
I will protect Asgard and all the realms with my last and every breath, 

1111
01:39:45,420 --> 01:39:47,430
但坐在王位上可办不到
but I cannot do so from that chair.

1112
01:39:47,980 --> 01:39:49,700
洛基虽有不是
Loki, for all his grave imbalance

1113
01:39:49,710 --> 01:39:52,330
却懂得一些我永远学不会的道理
understood rule as I know I never will.

1114
01:39:53,000 --> 01:39:55,190
王位所带来的残忍和牺牲
The brutality, the sacrifice.

1115
01:39:55,720 --> 01:39:57,070
会改变一个人
It changes you.

1116
01:39:57,660 --> 01:40:00,440
我宁可做好人  也不愿做明主
I'd rather be a good man, than a great king.

1117
01:40:01,460 --> 01:40:05,970
这是我儿子的意愿  还是他爱的女人的意思
Is this my son I hear, or the woman he loves.

1118
01:40:06,190 --> 01:40:08,530
我从没觉得是母亲在左右您的决定
When you speak, do I never hear mother's voice.

1119
01:40:10,830 --> 01:40:13,200
我不是为了简  父王
This is not for Jane, father.

1120
01:40:13,470 --> 01:40:15,660
她不知道我要说什么
She does not know what I came here to say.

1121
01:40:16,240 --> 01:40:17,660
禁止我见她
Now, forbid me to see her, 

1122
01:40:17,660 --> 01:40:20,610
或是同意她与我共同治国  都无济于事
or say she can rule by my side, it changes nothing.

1123
01:40:21,360 --> 01:40:24,170
一个儿子太过渴求王位
One son who wanted the throne too much, 

1124
01:40:25,550 --> 01:40:27,590
另一个却弃之而去
another who will not take it.

1125
01:40:28,210 --> 01:40:30,180
这就是我留给后世的吗
Is this my legacy?

1126
01:40:30,180 --> 01:40:31,890
洛基光荣牺牲
Loki died with honor.

1127
01:40:32,630 --> 01:40:35,600
我也要尽力而为  这还不够吗
I shall try to live the same, is that not legacy enough?

1128
01:40:46,580 --> 01:40:48,200
只要你配得上它
It belongs to you

1129
01:40:49,640 --> 01:40:51,480
它就是你的
if you're worthy of it.

1130
01:40:51,690 --> 01:40:52,970
我会尽力的
I shall try to.

1131
01:40:55,550 --> 01:40:57,480
我不能祝福你
I cannot give you my blessing, 

1132
01:40:58,330 --> 01:41:00,330
也不能祝你好运
nor can I wish you good fortune.

1133
01:41:01,130 --> 01:41:02,140
我知道
I know.

1134
01:41:05,730 --> 01:41:08,890
即使我为我儿子如今的为人而骄傲
If I were proud of the man my son had become, 

1135
01:41:09,500 --> 01:41:11,560
我也不能说出来
even that, I could not say.

1136
01:41:14,650 --> 01:41:17,380
但我会在心里赞许你
It would speak only from my heart.

1137
01:41:19,310 --> 01:41:20,360
去吧
Go.

1138
01:41:21,810 --> 01:41:22,920
我的儿子
My son.

1139
01:41:25,410 --> 01:41:26,620
谢谢  父王
Thank you, father.

1140
01:41:42,340 --> 01:41:43,320
不
No. 

1141
01:41:44,630 --> 01:41:45,790
该谢谢你
Thank you.

1142
01:44:04,710 --> 01:44:06,680
向二位介绍
I present to you

1143
01:44:07,400 --> 01:44:10,820
收集者坦利亚·蒂万
Taneleer Tivan, the Collector.

1144
01:44:16,890 --> 01:44:20,540
阿斯加德人  真是荣幸
Asgardians. It's an honor.

1145
01:44:25,000 --> 01:44:26,650
你知道我们为何而来
You know why we're here.

1146
01:44:30,770 --> 01:44:32,370
是的
Of course.

1147
01:44:33,570 --> 01:44:35,490
但容我问一句
But if I may ask.

1148
01:44:35,890 --> 01:44:39,940
为什么不保管在你们那儿呢
Why not keep it secure in your own vault?

1149
01:44:39,950 --> 01:44:42,400
宇宙魔方已经在阿斯加德了
The Tesseract is already on Asgard.

1150
01:44:43,230 --> 01:44:46,660
不该把两颗无限宝石放得太近
It's not wise to keep two Infinity Stone so close together.

1151
01:44:47,160 --> 01:44:49,290
很明智
That's very wise.

1152
01:44:59,510 --> 01:45:01,320
我保证
I can assure you

1153
01:45:02,140 --> 01:45:07,810
在我手里
it will be absolutely safe here

1154
01:45:09,570 --> 01:45:11,290
一定万无一失
in my collection.

1155
01:45:13,350 --> 01:45:14,850
务必保管好
See that it is.

1156
01:45:34,170 --> 01:45:35,930
一个拿到
One down, 

1157
01:45:38,180 --> 01:45:39,790
还剩五个
five to go.

1158
01:45:41,130 --> 01:45:51,130
{\an8}六颗无限宝石分别代表空间  时间  灵魂  现实  力量  意志
原由包括收集者在内的宇宙元老们保管
集齐宝石者可拥有支配宇宙的无限神力
而灭霸将六颗宝石制作成了"无限手套"
可以说是终极神器

