Dear sister and brother-in-law,
thank you
From here on in, it's your show
Isn’t it our turn for photos?
Where are the kids?
Grandma...
look
It was on the tree
Anything wrong?
You know that strange woman?
Can I help you, Miss?
- Looking for someone
- May I ask who?
Mind your own business!
Yun-Yun!
Ting-Ting...
you look so pretty today!
Where's your grandma?
I'm so sorry!
It should have been me
marrying your son today!
I let you down, I'm so sorry
It breaks my heart,
I'm not worthy of you!
Don't push me around!
It's not that bad!
Where is she?
Where is that pregnant bitch?
Dad...
Grandma wants to go home
Go home?
She doesn't feel well
And tonight?
Where's Xiao Yan?
Show your face, Xiao Yan!
Give A-Di back to me!
You'll face retribution
for this!
YI YI
Sorry about the mess
We're the Jiangs... I'm Lili
I'm Ting-Ting
This is my grandma
We're the Jians
See you later, bye!
Ting-Ting!
Take out the garbage before we go
I'm doing it
It's starting to smell
There's some on the balcony
I know
What was I getting?
How did you find me?
Followed the removal men
Mother will be livid!
I miss you!
Don't I call you?
Can't see you on the phone
Come
Sorry, I'm in the middle
of moving house
It's a huge mess!
Call me on this mobile number
I'll have a phone-line in tomorrow
No problem
Ready, Ting-Ting?
What's on your mind?
I feel sorry for Yun-Yun
If it's not Uncle's fault,
it must be Xiao Yan's
Don't say that, we hardly know her
I think Grandma's right,
we can't accept her
Did Grandma say that?
No...
but she's been unhappy all day
Did she say anything else?
No, but she said
she feels really old
What does she mean by that?
The groom is right behind me!
Put your hands together!
Your wife's brother is some guy!
Not many weddings
with the bride so very pregnant!
That's the way he is!
He put off the wedding
for months...
because this is the luckiest day
of the year in the almanac
Take his shoe!
Don't mess with girls!
Pregnant brides aren't
unusual these days
We had "bus rides without tickets"
in our day too, you know
Sorry, Yang-Yang,
this is your seat
Girls teased him again
Never mind, have some food
So, did you and NJ?
Guess
No thanks!
You women always trap men
that way!
It still works!
It worked on your brother!
NJ would be a pushover!
So?
Here's the bus-rider!
What? I drove myself here
Drink! It's on my brother-in-law!
Why aren't you eating?
Those girls teased him again
Try this new toy!
Just let him be
Is it really you?
You're still in Taipei?
I live... in the US now
Your son?
So cute
This is my number
Call me
Why didn't you come that day?
I waited and waited...
I've never got over it, you know
Sherry!
How many years has it been?
Almost 30!
Not that long!
It hasn't been that long
since we graduated!
Didn't know you two
were still in touch!
We just ran into each other
by chance
Good to see you still get along!
My name card
My husband does business in China,
so I'll be in town quite a bit!
- Stay in touch, okay?
- I sure will
Sorry, I've run out of name cards.
I keep forgetting to...
Sorry, I must go...
- Remember, stay in touch!
- Promise!
It really is a lucky day!
I've forgotten my own first love
Why do I remember yours?
What did I come down for?
Some tea?
No, thanks
- Something wrong?
- Nothing
Dad, your cigar burst it!
See what happens when you smoke
those disgusting things?
It wasn't...
Then who was it?
Er... Whatever
Quiet! Shut it!
Now the elders are involved
Fair enough, they must both drink!
One each!
What the fuck is this?
It's called a "depth charge"
You'll both have pot bellies
after this!
Beer!
Plus fruit juice!
Chewed betel nuts!
Eggs and salt!
Drink up!
Applause!
Is it raining?
Can you manage
the stuff in the trunk?
If not, ask Dad to bring it in
when he's parked
Don't forget the big bag
Mrs Jian! Why are you so late?
Get to the hospital!
Your mother's been rushed there!
My mother?
Wait!
I'll go in to see her first, NJ
Wait here for A-Di,
he'll be here soon
Tell Ting-Ting
to put Yang-Yang to bed
I did. You go ahead!
What does the doctor say?
She's had a stroke...
they need to operate
I saw her lying in the driveway
by the dustbins...
Did she fall over?
Was she hit by a car?
Why was she downstairs?
You drove here drunk!?
The cops drink too!
Don't worry, NJ
Sister called
and told me what happened
Mother will be fine,
it's the luckiest day of the year!
- She'll wake up in no time.
- A-Di, it's not that simple...
Maybe you don't trust me
Things are different now!
I was unlucky,
so I borrowed from you and sister
Now my luck has turned!
I'll be repaying you soon!
- There's no rush
- Trust me!
You saw my partner Piggy tonight
He'll pay me back tomorrow,
and I'll pay you back next day!
Ting-Ting took out the garbage
in the afternoon
What was Mother doing
down by the dustbins?
We don't know if she fell
or was knocked over by a car
My brother says
she'll recover quickly
It was the luckiest day
of the year
He put off his wedding
for this lucky day
Nothing unlucky can happen
Otherwise Mother
would be dead by now
That's one way to see it
How else?
Don't complicate things!
How's this, Min-Min?
Didn't I say it goes to City Hall?
How does your Master see it?
You should ask him yourself,
I think
I spent two weeks
at the temple with you!
But I didn't understand
his teachings
I don't think the Master
would take me as his disciple
Two weeks may not be enough
Look how busy I am
How can I find the time?
Maybe you need a bit more humility
Are you saying...
there's something wrong with me?
Look at Yang-Yang!
My auntie was like this
at her wedding
So fat?
No, guess why
What's under your shirt?
A balloon!
One inside another!
She's coming!
Concubine! Concubine!
Is she the Concubine?
Shut up!
Stay there!
Get on with your work!
What's that in your hand?
Nothing
Better watch yourself!
Yang-Yang, she likes you!
Her old man will be jealous!
Who's her old man?
Today...
one of you has brought
something bad to class. Who is it?
Who has brought a condom?
Stand up!
If he won't admit it,
I'll name him!
Jian Yang-Yang, it's you!
Stand up!
Hand over your condom!
What's a condom?
Playing dumb?
Don't laugh! You're shameless!
You can't hide it!
I know everything!
Who's telling lies about me?
Never you mind!
You just heard something,
you didn't see it
So I'm wrong, am I?
You think
I need to see it to know?
I even know which pocket it's in
Your left pocket... come on!
What's this?
A balloon
Quiet!
I'll let it go this time...
but you'd better watch out!
Finish your milk!
We both will be late!
You'll never grow tall!
Good morning, Mrs Jiang
First Girls' High... great school!
You are good!
So is Lili!
I hear her playing every day,
so beautiful!
I hope it's not too loud.
Do you play an instrument?
Yes, but I'm not very good
Better to be good at books, anyway
What's the point?
Last year's profits are gone
Everyone does computers now
Remember how
the garment business crashed?
The more orders you fill,
the more money you lose!
Instead of cashing in...
you blew it all
on lavish expansion plans
So, what can I do?
You screwed up real bad,
what can I do?
We do have a strategy,
one step at a time
There's always ups and downs
at a time of transition
I warn you...
one more negative review...
and we'll pull out
So what's this strategy?
Moving into software?
Or into... content?
Damn right!
It's still hush-hush...
Heard of a Japanese named Ota?
Computer games?
- That surprised you, right?
- Promising...
Go on!
We're always cutting-edge!
Sure you are! But you're
down the tube if we pull out
Why "cash in" when we were ahead?
"No prisoners!" was our policy.
Remember?
He better shut up!
Why should he?
You were too honest
and told him everything!
I'm not like you...
We don't even know this "Ota"
And we're going bust!
He doesn't come cheap
He's a brand name!
We buy his name...
to attract investors!
Brand name? What if
it costs too much to recoup?
It's our neck, I'm against it!
Taiwan has the best copycats.
Are they ripping off Ota's stuff?
I'll check
What will you guys do
if we go bust?
I know, you'll retire,
stay home and smoke your pipe
Da-Da, you'll move
to San Francisco?
And you, NJ?
All your money's in the company,
isn't it?
He didn't hear me
He doesn't want to answer
He has other things on his mind
I'm going, Uncle is here
Ting-Ting! You're leaving?
Yes, you two enjoy yourselves
I didn't know she was meeting you
She and I are still very close
Hey, everything's fine now
I even urged Ting-Ting
to be kind to your new wife
We didn't marry,
but we're still friends
All these years!
Yes, many years
You're so calm, I'm surprised
Let's get to work
Everyone was stunned by what
you did at the wedding banquet
Don't get me going again, okay?
Here, look
I've transferred part
of our savings to your account
We cleared 20 million
on Yahoo and AOL
Part of it is in a mutual fund
The documents here
need your authorization
And find me a boyfriend
I'm alone now, you know that
Figures give me a headache
Lili!
I heard your grandma
is in hospital
Yes
Is it serious?
She's in a coma... She fell
I love your grandma,
she's so elegant
She was a teacher
It's your boyfriend...
Right
Why don't you go over?
I'll see you later
You should move her
every hour or so
Like this
A different position every time
First one side, like this...
then the other, like that
And put a pillow under her back
That's the way
And pat her back often
Do it yourself
if the nurse isn't here
- That's for her circulation?
- Exactly
I think that's all...
Doctor...
how long before Mother
regains consciousness?
It's hard to say
Treat her normally...
open her window in the daytime
Take her out in the wheelchair,
turn off the lights at night
Most important, talk to her,
it stimulates her senses
But I'm not optimistic
You should prepare for the worst
Sorry, brother-in-law,
I haven't repaid you yet
Never mind
If I forget again, remind me
I'm thinking about the company
Bad mood?
More financial problems?
You're not going bust, are you?
I'm thinking about the meeting
with the Japanese tomorrow
Fuck! Are you in debt to Japan?
No! What are you saying?
Of course not!
Yang-Yang...
it's your turn
From now on, we'll take turns
to talk to Grandma
It will make her wake up sooner
Ting-Ting hasn't done it
She played the piano, didn't she?
I could show her my drawings,
but she can't see
But she'll hear you!
Didn't the doctor say so?
There's lots to tell her
Like what happened at school...
or some little secret you have
You can tell Grandma anything
What's the matter?
Why that grumpy look?
Don't want to talk to her?
What's the point?
She can't see what I tell her
What?
Are you trying to get out of it?
That's not nice!
How can you let Grandma down?
You're making me cross!
Don't they teach you anything
at school?
Grandma loves you so much
You can't just ignore her,
can you?
You just can't!
You take a break...
I'll talk to her first
It's my turn
Ma, I'm good at talking
Luck's on my side now,
don't worry!
I'm rich now
People come to me for loans!
Not like the old days
when my borrowing made you worry
I've made lots of rich friends
And...
Don't you worry about Xiao Yan
She's a nice girl
Really...
And... what else...
The other stuff...
I guess you know
If you have questions,
you can't ask...
Today...
let's call it...
You must be tired...
I'll try and tomorrow...
That's for... today...
Grandma
Did I forget
to take out the garbage?
I can't remember
If you forgive me, wake up!
Please?
Because,
I can't sleep if you don't
Survival instincts
are all the same
Overfeeding may not improve growth
It may diminish
evolutionary impulses
So, the drive to reproduce
declines
Some of you
can't bring them into bloom
You're overdoing the care
Like, say... Jian Ting-Ting
Jian Ting-Ting!
She stays up all night
nurturing her plant
The others must be slacking...
See how they bloom?
It begins to acquire
signs of human life...
It begins to think,
then matures
into a living entity...
and becomes
our most devoted companion
That's the limitless future
for computer games
We haven't yet surpassed...
fighting and killing games
Not because we haven't fully
understood computers
But because we haven't fully
understood ourselves: human beings
Our future collaboration
can be based on these objectives
This is the way forward
These are uncharted waters,
so I understand your hesitations
But this cutting-edge approach
puts us well ahead
of any future competition
So there are ample grounds
for optimism
That concludes my presentation,
thank you
Wonderful!
We learned a lot today!
Really good...
No-one's dared try it before,
but we have to pay for it?
I thought we were just buying
a brand name, pure and simple
I liked what he said
It's a risk worth taking
Shit, you were against it before!
He's too expensive, not worth it
I found a local copycat of Ota
Calls itself "Ato", close enough?
Forget the names!
What about performance?
Small return on small risks,
big deal!
It beats big losses on big risks
Let's not sign with him yet!
Find an excuse
to send him back to Tokyo
That's not nice!
Who has to tell him?
NJ...
take Mr. Ota to dinner tonight.
Tell him we're keen to sign
But play hard to get,
let's buy some time
Why me?
You look honest!
So? Am I pretending?
What's wrong with a little acting?
So honesty is an act?
And friendship? Business?
Is anything real left?
Don't mind what I said
about acting
We've been a team since schooldays
Sure, why else do I stick around?
By the way, Sherry's husband,
Rodney Breitner...
He's from Chicago,
big in insurance
Good reputation
I had a long talk with her
on the phone
She asked me to say "Hi"
Give her a call sometime
Just as a classmate,
not an ex-lover
It's not locked
You're home early
I was next door
Hello? Dad!
Yang-Yang hid the phone,
I couldn't find it
It was under the seat cushion
We're cooking a health-food dinner
and you'll miss it!
Okay, next time
Yes, I'll tell Ma
That was my dad
He's going to miss my masterpiece
Well, that's his loss
So what's next?
Check that page
We're out of carrots
We have some
Next time
I'll show you my pad in Shanghai
My daughter's in
My daughter Lili
Call him Uncle
Call me Allen
You're cooking?
Nice place you have here
Hi, Mrs Jiang
Ting-Ting, you're cooking too?
Big job, isn't it?
It's fun!
Join us for a health-food feast!
We're going to the movies
That's nice... Hold on
Allen, make yourself at home
I'm fine
We're going to the movies?
It's on me.
Treat Ting-Ting to a good show
Your daughter is a musician!
She certainly is,
she's won prizes!
Lots of comedies,
which one do you fancy?
We can do something else...
if you'd prefer...
Welcome
Can I help you?
Our friend is...
They're my friends
Hi, Fatty
I thought you were cooking
What're you doing?
Checking these
I don't come here every day
Wait for me
at the usual place, okay?
"Fatty"? He's so thin!
Maybe he used to be fat
You shouldn't mind waiting...
he's often waited for you
It's not that...
He'll be here soon
Want to be alone?
I can go home...
Okay
Don't worry, he'll be here soon
Keep it down!
This isn't your own place!
Hey, you seem
to be disturbing her!
Cool it!
It's not our fault that
your boyfriend stood you up!
Leave her alone
Been in the army too long,
I'm not used to this!
Don't worry
I may look rough
but I have a heart of gold
Let it be, okay?
This must be fish...
Where's he from? He's good
Japan. I just met him
He plays well for a computer guy
Bring more friends like him
Great for atmosphere
Times are hard
We're in trouble
Come more often...
Sherry? It's me, NJ
I'm glad it's the machine.
Otherwise I'd be tongue-tied
Da-Da said he spoke to you
He says you're doing well,
I'm so glad
Before,
I'd heard your life was tough
I felt it might be my fault
You asked why I vanished
without a word 30 years ago
There were many reasons
Now they all sound stupid
I'm glad that you have a good life
I'm really happy for you
All my best wishes
I have nothing to say to Mother
I tell her the same things
every day
What I did in the morning
In the afternoon
In the evening
It only takes a minute
I can't bear it
I have so little
How can it be so little?
I live a blank!
Every day... Every day...
I'm like a fool!
What am I doing every day?
If I ended up like her one day...
I'll ask the nurse
to read the newspaper to her
She'll have something new
to listen to, okay?
I was busy!
So was I! Why should I wait all day
for you to call?
- Where were you last night?
- Why should I tell you?
You think I'm some dumb bitch?
Why should I wait for you?
Give me back the cell-phone!
What are you doing?
You asking me?
Get the hell out!
Fuck you, you nosey bitch!
You're a fucking joke!
Yang-Yang, the lift's here
Don't stare at people like that.
It's rude
People will be cross
I wanted to know why she's unhappy.
I can't see from behind
How do you know she's unhappy?
She had a big fight last night
I could hear from my room
Really?
Daddy, I can't see what you see
and you can't see what I see
How can I know what you see?
Good question.
I never thought of that
That's why we need a camera
Do you want to play with one?
Daddy, can we only know
half of the truth?
What? I don't get it
I can only see what's in front,
not what's behind
So I can only know
half of the truth, right?
You have a lot of questions today!
Let me ask you one...
Where shall we take Mummy
this weekend to cheer her up?
You can decide
Min-Min!
Still here?
Nancy...
Where can I go...
What are you doing?
What are you snapping?
I want to show Mummy
the mosquitoes
Mosquitoes? Can you snap them?
Daddy said so,
or people won't believe me
That's not our place!
I know
Your Mum and I
both think they are strange
Is Mummy home?
I haven't seen her lately
My boss is here, bye!
Your partners are in a meeting
with Ato Company
They want you to join them
Ato?
Isn’t it Ota? I wasn't told
No, Ato is Ota's copycat
Confusing, isn't it?
General Manager's office
The President's in a meeting
May I say who called?
No? Thank you
General Manager's office
My boss is here,
I'll call you later
General Manager's office
Hold on
NJ, long-distance from the US
I knew it was you
You take care of the company
I'm staying home
Call me when you need me
Seems I'm the only one left
to keep you company
When Min-Min was home,
I thought...
she'd solve
all the problems around here
But now...
there's no-one to do it
And I really don't know
when she'll be back
It's hard for me
to mumble like this
I hope you won't be offended
if I say...
it's like praying
I'm not sure
if the other party can hear me...
and I'm not sure
if I'm sincere enough
Frankly...
there's very little
I'm sure about these days
I wake up feeling unsure
about almost everything
And I wonder
why I wake up at all...
just to face the same
uncertainties again and again
Would you want to wake up,
if you were me?
Maybe Yang-Yang's right
You've lived so many more years
Other than these questions
we can't answer...
what is there to tell you?
Anyhow, I guess
you don't blame Yang-Yang...
for not talking to you
In many ways he takes after me
Really
Which brand do you want?
The same one
Which was that?
This one
Right, hold on...
Shida Road Art Portraits,
can I help you?
And the surname is...?
Okay, I'll check
What the...?
What the hell are all these?
Oh, I get it
This is what they call
avant-garde art!
Amazing!
Class,
time for some art appreciation!
What's it for?
It's art! Expensive art!
Why is art expensive?
Why take so many?
Look at him! Our newfound maestro!
A rare genius in our school!
Didn't you love to talk back?
Take after your father, right?
Tell him you are caught in the act
Call him
and ask for help!
Scared?
Stand there until he comes!
Don't pull that face at me!
Turn around against the wall!
I dare you do that again!
How was it the other night?
Isn’t Lili home yet?
Could you give this to her?
Uh... nothing
This...
is for you
- It's...
- I know
"Wen-Ηo Lee,
originally from Tainan...
"was found to be
in breach of Security Codes...
"and dismissed from his post
at Los Alamos Research Lab
"To date,
the Federal authorities...
"do not have enough evidence
to prosecute him
"as a spy"
"Taipei City
Rapid Transit Commission...
"has lost its lawsuit...
"against the French company
Matra..."
Let's eat
You don't like my cooking?
Been to McDonald's again?
Why so moody?
He got picked on...
Girls, right?
Master wants to see you
Please come in, Master
Ting-Ting, Nancy is here!
Will you make some tea?
Have you eaten?
We just did
First, Min-Min
is doing well in the temple
Master wanted to visit you...
so as to know
Min-Min's family better
Mr Jian, most people
neglect spiritual disciplines
So you missed Min-Min's signals
Yang-Yang, don't run around naked!
You should join us on the mountain
A purified soul
helps the gods to answer prayers
Nothing would help your wife more
Like everyone, my wife and I
need help from others
But maybe I'd anger the gods
by making too many requests
If I turn to them only for
the big things I can't handle...
my sincerity may impress them more
But...
I haven't yet had troubles
I couldn't handle myself
These thoughts seem interesting...
They do this work voluntarily
Your encouragement
means so much...
I see
Do you take cheques?
Of course
Thanks, NJ
Your wife is in good hands
Thanks for all the help
It's our pleasure
Lend me $300,
I have nothing on me
A cab driver's waiting,
I owe him $300
You'd die without me!
Aren't you lucky?
The clothes you left
are still here
Do they still fit?
How did you get into this mess?
She went crazy and threw me out
I went to NJ's place...
He threw you out too?
I still owe him money
I was ashamed to borrow...
from him again
Didn't I give you 9 million
to clear your debt with NJ?
I let Piggy invest that
He says it's tripled in value
Piggy?
I hear he's on the run in China
Bullshit!
I won big on mahjong
at his place last week
Cash?
I see
Let's visit him tomorrow to check
Okay?
Thank you so much,
it'll only take a minute
No problem, just shut the door
when you leave
Don't tell anyone I let you in!
Trust me
Fatso, learn from your wife!
See how easy she handles me?
Thanks a lot
They're no slouches,
cleaned the place out
How much money have I got left?
Barely!
Didn't we just make ten million?
Values can go down too
Shit, what are these?
You mean...
I'm broke again
Why did you trust
a guy like Piggy?
Come here
Remember this: trust no-one!
It's just junk
Fucking useless!
Are you skipping
audio/visual class?
Buzz off!
Here she comes!
Quick!
Good morning, Dean
Lovely new outfit!
You little fuckers! Don't run
I'll get you! You fuckers!
"Warm, damp air rises
as the earth heats up
"At high altitude,
it condenses into small droplets
Get in, quick!
"This creates
these beautiful clouds
"To the quiet rhythms of nature...
"they dance silently
above our heads
"Often we overlook their beauty
"As they dance higher...
"they silently turn into hail...
"and return to earth
through the clouds
"During their plunge...
"they shed their positive charge
and form a negative-charged front
Close the door!
Don't just stand there!
Find a seat, quick!
"The two opposing forces...
"are attracted towards each other
"It grows irresistible
"In one flashing moment,
the two violently reunite
"That makes: thunder
"It's believed that thunder
created all life on earth
"400 million years ago,
"a bolt of lightning
created the first amino acid,
"the origin of life
"That was the beginning
of everything"
I can't help you!
You two can't fight like this!
Everyone envied you!
You can't do this!
I'm very disappointed!
What sense does it make?
I haven't seen her in ages
Of course not! You mistreated her!
Lili is so lovely! How could you?
Is she seeing other guys?
I didn't say that...
You should know better
Tough lady!
How can this be?
Open the door!
Why is it suddenly locked?
Not ashamed, are you?
How can this be?
Lili, it's not how it looks
What is it then?
Listen to me
You're my teacher!
You're my mother!
You should be teaching me English!
Teachers are human too!
I'll tell the principal!
Listen to me!
Listen to what?
Excuse me
It's not what you think, Lili!
Look this way!
Let Daddy videotape you
Still crying...
Look this way...
The eyes...
What? You're moved?
Suddenly it all seems...
so cruel
What's wrong?
Is his horoscope really so bad?
Didn't you say...
we can counter it
by giving him a lucky name?
It's all right!
A-Di!
Congratulations!
You're the first!
Let's see the baby
Like you, but more handsome!
So they say! I can't tell
To wish you luck...
How's his horoscope?
What's his name?
The name is crucial,
I'm still working on it
Right, it's for life!
Have some tea
Congratulations! Good job, A-Di!
Migo!
I hear you've set
the world to rights!
Made peace between
your wife and Yun-Yun!
Let's drink to that!
Here, some expensive red wine!
All your old classmates
are relieved!
Lovely little baby!
Looks more like the mother
than the father
You sure?
Go fetch the baby pictures
What pictures?
Behind the screen!
Had a good eye, didn't I?
I hired Xiao Yan
fresh out of school
See what happens?
You should thank me, Xiao Yan
Right, you should
Get Migo in here!
Why is that bitch here?
Did you invite her?
Of course not!
What the hell is going on?
Why did you bring Yun-Yun?
She said you invited her,
and we brought the wine!
You didn't invite her!
You think I'm nuts?
What a let-down!
We all thought you two made up
We were so glad to hear it
That's what she told you all?
Weren't you so friendly
to each other just now?
Forget the past,
make a fresh start
Let's be happy
Fuck, it's a set-up!
What?
It's a fucking set-up!
Look! Throw her out, right now!
Come now...
Harmony is a precious thing!
Think of our classmates' feelings!
It's for everyone's good
Bullshit!
For everyone's good?
What about me?
Where does that leave me?
Your behavior isn't helping
Yun-Yun is our old friend!
Your wife
is out of line here
What the fuck?
What the fuck are you playing at,
Yun-Yun?
She doesn't mean that!
Trying to wreck the party?
You're wrecking it, not her!
Xiao Yan, don't get me wrong
I'm sincerely happy
for both of you, believe me
So I'm the villain?
What did I do to deserve this?
Xiao Yan! Take some advice!
You should repent! Our friendship
doesn't deserve this!
Don't leave! Stay here!
Long time no see, don't go!
Classmates, calm her down
or Yun-Yun will leave!
This is not right!
Xiao Yan invited us!
We are her guests!
See? I'm the host!
You're full of shit!
This is not fair!
Who asked your opinion?
You lowlife!
This is all your fault!
Xiao Yan and the baby
are coming with me
You'll never see them again!
I'll cut off your dick
and feed it to the pigs!
Let's get Xiao Yan and the baby
out of here!
Named your baby yet?
His horoscope's bad?
Why was Yun-Yun there?
It was a set-up
You've been seeing her?
Not exactly...
Xiao Yan's been pregnant
Yun-Yun and I go back a long way
I've helped her out a little,
out of courtesy
Paging NJ Jian,
you have a visitor!
How courteous
You're one lucky guy
A nice home and a colorful life!
I'll take a shower,
help yourself to a drink
Give me a break,
I have to drive home
Sleep it off,
start afresh tomorrow
I wish!
Go to bed
A bad day's over
It's all over
Fuck!
Look at this mess!
Thanks
All these empty bottles, damn it
A-Di!
Can't you answer
while you're running your bath?
Still mad at me, you bastard?
What are you doing in there?
I smell gas!
What happened?
Open the door!
Telephone!
Where's the damn phone?
Open the door, A-Di!
What were you doing?
Why did you close the window?
Why didn't you open the window?
Why was the window closed?
Why didn't you open it?
I won't fight with you again
What happened?
You seemed fine last night
Don't scare me
I'm fine
What did I do?
I just took a bath!
Go ask the gas company
Check my pager for me
What a time to page me!
2773-7557
That's my office!
Why are they paging you?
I tried all your numbers!
Lucky we had his pager number
What's the rush?
We have serious interest
from this guy
But he gives us only one hour
What guy? Interested in what?
Get in
You need an 'honest-looking' guy
again, right?
Why come to me?
You've sewn it up!
Get on board
Mind if I don't have a ticket?
Boss Huang knows all about Ota
You've signed with him, and Boss
Ηuang wants in at whatever price
Today, we'll finalize the details
NJ is Ota-san's very old friend!
Right, NJ?
Boss Huang was drinking
with the President all night
He's resting now.
Time is tight
Wait here a moment
Fly to Tokyo and sign
with Ota right away!
Get on the next flight
Huang used to run game arcades
He knows Ota's stuff well
As a legislator,
he now supports women's rights...
and quotas!
Is this gonna make money?
This is a long weekend in Japan
The noon flight is full,
you're wait-listed
Shall I book a later flight?
You'd get in quite late
Why not? Go ahead
International call on Line 2.
This person has called before
I was away...
running around on business
I'll be in Tokyo tomorrow
Are you sure?
Hang on, I'll check
Which hotel am I in?
I won't be your go-between!
Why come to me again?
What did I say last time?
This is for you, Ting-Ting
I have to go to Tokyo tomorrow
The nurse
will come in every day, but...
You'll be on your own, okay?
You got here so quickly!
So many flights everyday
from Chicago to Tokyo
Shall we visit
your father's school?
We'll change
from the green line to...
the blue
That's the exit
But the map says this way
No, that's the way out
The blue line is this way,
that's the Chuo line
This reminds me of our first date
I was so nervous I had hiccups,
remember?
I've had hiccups since I was a kid
whenever I'm nervous...
I was too nervous to ask why!
You were too nervous to breathe!
I sweat when I'm nervous,
my palms,
even my feet!
Excuse me
Rodney and I
don't have children...
but he loves kids
He's on business a lot
We're thinking of adopting
so I'll have company
- And you?
- Two
A girl in high school
and a boy of 8
I love my daughter
She's growing into a woman.
I get jealous...
knowing eventually
she'll be with someone else
My son? I want to be his friend...
The relationship I always wanted
with my father
What time is it?
Nine
It's almost 10...
that's 8 am in Chicago
9 pm in Taipei
Let's find a place for the night
Look, this is like
the crossing near our school
That's gone now
The first time I held your hand...
We were at a railroad crossing,
going to the movies
I reached for you,
ashamed of my sweaty palm...
Now, I'm holding your hand again
Only it's a different place...
A different time...
A different age...
But the same sweaty palm
Did you like the movie?
A bit too serious
You prefer comedies?
Not really,
but it didn't have to be so sad
Life is a mixture
of sad and happy things
Movies are so lifelike,
that's why we love them
Then who needs movies?
Just stay home and live life!
My uncle says...
"we live three times as long
since man invented movies"
How can that be?
It means movies give us twice
what we get from daily life
For example, murder
We never killed anyone,
but we all know...
what it's like to kill.
That's what we get from the movies
What good is it to me?
If life's so horrible,
why live at all?
If we're nice to people,
they'll be nice back
Who needs to kill anybody?
It's only one example
There are other things
Like he also said...
"There's no cloud...
"no tree...
"that isn't beautiful
"So we should be too"
I found that very touching
It changed me in many ways
You make it sound tragic!
Shouldn't it sound cheerful?
Later I married and had a child,
didn't you hear?
But I divorced within a year
I went to study in Seattle,
married a Chinese-American
I had to run away
That day...
I waited and waited
You never showed up
I waited because I knew...
I'd be ruined if I didn't see you
I wouldn't know how to live on!
I'd fall apart!
Waiting was my only chance
I waited for one day
Then for another day
I asked friends to find you.
There was no response
You just vanished
I left without a word
Aside from silly excuses,
I had nothing to say
I was so angry!
You pushed me
to become an engineer
Did you ever ask what I wanted?
You and my parents were so happy
the day I graduated
But me? I was so sad
You can't run someone else's life,
dictate how he spends his days...
That's sad, you know?
And the one doing it
was the one I loved most!
So...
Do you know how that hurt inside?
Do you?
How funny...
I'm doing exactly
what you wanted me to do
And you have a better life
than I could ever give you
You were so naive...
I thought we'd end up penniless
What? You were always after me!
Nonsense!
You were just standing there
looking at me!
I couldn't stand it any longer!
Remember what I said?
"If you want to talk to me,
get a move on!"
Why did you...
suddenly fall for me
in high school?
It was much earlier
In primary school
That's when it all started
Strange, I just wanted
to see you every day
If I missed seeing you,
I'd feel bad all day
That's why you gawped...
We all wore uniforms
but yours looked different
In what way?
A very special way...
Yang-Yang...
You've been in there a long time
What are you doing?
Say something!
Why don't you answer?
Hurry up! Come out!
What are you doing?
What are you playing with?
Did you fall into the toilet?
What are you doing in there?
May I use your mother's bathroom?
Of course
That'll be from the hospital
I'll get it
Tell me the truth
What?
Are you seeing Fatty?
No...
We're just friends
Don't be like this, Ting-Ting
Of course she spoke to me too
You have known her a long time.
That's how she is
You should know by now
What is she to you now?
Nothing
In my heart...
there's only you!
Is that true?
You don't believe me?
It's...
not right
One of my aunts got married here
Which one?
It was that summer
They still dance the twist
around here!
"Good morning"
Good morning? It's almost bedtime!
It's the only Japanese word
I know!
The clerk gave you a strange look
when he handed you two keys
Who sleeps
in separate rooms these days?
To sleep with someone
means nothing now
You're off again
But it's true!
You dragged me to a hotel first,
remember?
I was scared, I ran off!
I used to think you'd vanish
if I just looked away
If you gave yourself to me...
you could always hold me
to account for it later, right?
Not at all
But when you left the room...
I knew you didn't love me
any more
You still feel that way now?
You know how I felt...
when you turned away just now?
It felt as if
I'd never see you again!
I don't want to go on like this
I have everything.
What am I afraid of?
If I divorced Rodney, I'd be
well off for the rest of my life
We could start over,
how about it?
I was too insecure,
it was my fault
Now I have nothing to fear
Let's start a new life, shall we?
You're tired, Sherry
Don't change the subject!
You're scared, right?
You never loved me!
Admit it!
Sherry!
Why do I behave like this
whenever I'm with you?
Why do I always do that?
I'm sorry
Why do I always
make the same mistakes?
When I know I'll regret them
for the rest of my life?
Don't feel sorry
Who understands you
better than I do?
I think of you...
every day of my life, you know?
Think?
Think...
We all need time to think
Carefully think
Come on
This is my business trip!
You've handed me a huge workload!
It'll take several trips
to deal with!
Give me a break,
this is a big job
I'm so tired
I have to crash
I'll pick you up for breakfast
Have a good meeting tonight
Sherry...
I never loved anyone else
Can you bring me a pack of cards?
Yes, but Morita-san
prohibits gambling here, sir
I won't gamble.
Morita-san knows
Then why do you need them?
Two warm pots of sake
Yes, sir
You're not gambling, are you?
Who won?
I tried to reach you
all day yesterday
Relax, I talked to Mr. Ota...
Listen, we've signed with Ato
That's what I wanted
to tell you yesterday
Ato? Why? I thought Boss Huang...
He's into quota-representation
for women, I told you...
And Ato is a woman?
A 34E-cup!
Make an excuse
and come back home
What do you say, NJ?
Nothing! I get it!
NJ, what's wrong?
Don't get emotional,
this solves our problems
We should celebrate!
We didn't promise Ota anything
You...
You know that hurts!
What hurts?
Mr. Ota is a good man!
Where's our dignity?
What's that got to do
with business?
I'll ride pillion!
I just got back
Where's my cup? Can't find it.
Fatty, don't feel this way
because of me
It's okay. We can still
be friends, I'm still...
Still what?
Still cheerful, right?
It's all crap!
Life's not like your dreams!
If it was, you wouldn't need those
love stories to kid yourself!
Get lost!
Never bug me again!
Stay away from me!
Believe it, these things happen!
When the stars are in alignment,
the gods smile on us!
How old is hi-tech? 20 years?
Horoscopes are
thousands of years old!
Ting-Ting must be back
Here's the bank draft
That clears my debt
That bastard Piggy
is on the run in China!
So I rushed to his place
It was crawling with cops!
The place was empty
and sealed off!
So I found this one cop
Talked him into letting me in
Shit, the creditors
had cleared the place out!
Only junk left lying around
Still, I found
this funny piece of rock
Nobody had seen what it was!
How did you get so wet?
Is it raining so hard?
Get out of those wet clothes
I had it valued,
and the guy's eyes lit up
It was antique jade!
An 8000-year-old
national treasure!
I kept my cool
I asked for what Piggy owed me
The guy wrote out a cheque
on the spot!
It must have been worth a lot more
We shouldn't be too greedy!
Get out of bed!
Just lying there
will make you sick!
I'll pick you up at 7 tomorrow
Stick with me, your horoscope
will improve no end!
What's this? For me?
This is me!
The back of my head!
What's this for?
You can't see it yourself,
so I help you
So that's why!
That's why what?
I've done nothing bad
Why is it so unfair?
Unless... you haven't forgiven me
Why don't you wake up?
Please wake up, will you?
Nobody's home.
His daughter must be at school
- Which school?
- First Girls' High
I'll send a policewoman there
Mr Jian is usually home these days
"This front passed us
yesterday afternoon
"We should now have clear weather
until Thursday
"Next up, City News
"There was a murder this morning
"It happened
in the Da-An district of Taipei
"The suspect is a teenager
"We cross to the murder site
for a report
"This is the suspect.
Nicknamed Fatty, he's a pupil
"at a posh school
"The victim was an English teacher
named Chen Lihua
"We are reliably informed
"the suspect's girlfriend
"had a sexual relationship
"with the victim
"The police confirm the victim...
"was also involved
with the girl's mother
"It complicates the case
"The mother works
"for a well-known American bank
"She had no comment today
"The security guard
recalls the suspect...
"was seen loitering
near the building yesterday
"As the victim left the building
early this morning...
"the suspect took a knife
from his satchel and stabbed him
"It was reportedly a grisly scene"
I thought it was the nurse
It's 2.30, she's still not here!
I was at the police station
I can't face going back to school
I haven't slept for so long
I'm so tired, Grandma
Now...
you've forgiven me...
I can sleep
Grandma...
Why is the world so different
from what we thought it was?
Now that you're awake...
and see it again...
has it changed at all?
Now...
I close my eyes...
the world I see...
is so beautiful
Migo, this isn't a joke
Why would I kid you?
Yes, Migo
I'm not kidding
Migo...
calm down!
I feel it's my fault
If I'd come earlier,
this might not have happened
It's all my fault
Don't be so upset
It's my mother's funeral!
Money is not a problem!
Unfortunately
I was out all day today
It must have been a peaceful end
Even if someone were home,
they wouldn't have noticed
Listen, stay in your room, okay?
Good boy
It was about 3 hours ago,
around 2.30 pm
Nothing's changed here
The kids are both fine
How was it up the mountain?
It was fine
Actually, it was much the same...
Just like...
talking to Mother
But with the roles reversed
I was like Mother,
they were like me
They took turns to talk to me,
the same things every time
Several times a day
I've come to realise...
things aren't really
so complicated
Why did they ever seem so?
Right
How can I say this?
While you were away,
I had a chance to relive
part of my youth
My first thought...
was that I could...
make things turn out differently
But...
they turned out the same,
or not much different
I suddenly realized that...
even if I was given
a second chance...
I wouldn't need it
I really wouldn't
Why did you have to leave us?
How could you leave us?
A-Di and I
can't go on without you!
Come back to us!
You were right again
It was a waste of time
Ato's copies were terrible
Buyers are too smart now
No one buys cheap imitations
Boss Huang is no slouch
Ato is now his mistress,
surprise, surprise!
She just sits
by the pool half-naked...
and the cash comes rolling in
One smart lady!
Come back, NJ
Rejoin the team.
We go back so far
Staying home all day
is no solution!
I've worked my butt off
all these years!
I didn't do it for fun!
You know, NJ, I'm never happy
When you don't love what you do...
how could you be?
Can I speak to Grandma?
Of course, go ahead
I'm sorry, Grandma
It wasn't that
I didn't want to talk to you
I think all the stuff
I could tell you...
you must already know
Otherwise, you wouldn't always
tell me to "Listen!"
They all say you've gone away
But you didn't tell me
where you went
I guess it's someplace
you think I should know
But, Grandma, I know so little
Do you know what I want to do...
when I grow up?
I want to tell people
things they don't know
Show them stuff they haven't seen
It'll be so much fun
Perhaps one day...
I'll find out where you've gone
If I do, can I tell everyone...
and bring them to visit you?
Grandma...
I miss you
Especially when I see...
my newborn cousin
who still doesn't have a name
He reminds me that you always said
you felt old
I want to tell him
that I feel
I am old too
Subtitles
by Tony Rayns and Edward Yang