Hey.
Hey, baby. What's going on here?
Oh , hi .
Miss GoIightIy.
Some day. . . Some day. . .
What happened to you , anyway?
You take off for the powder room and that's the Iast I see you .
-Now, reaIIy, Harry. . . -Harry was the other guy.
I'm Sid . Sid Arbuck. You Iike me, remember?
Miss GoIightIy, I protest!
Oh , darIing , I am sorry, but I Iost my key.
But that was two weeks ago.
You cannot go on and keep ringing my beII .
You disturb me ! You must have a key made !
But it won't do any good . I just Iose them aII .
Come on , baby. You Iike me. You know you do.
I worship you , Mr Arbuck,
-but good night, Mr Arbuck. -Baby, wait a minute. What is this?
You Iike me. I'm a Iiked guy.
You Iike me, baby. You know you do.
Didn't I pick up the check for five peopIe?
Your friends. I've never seen them before.
And when you asked for a IittIe change for the powder room ,
what do I give you? A $50 biII .
Now doesn't that give me some rights?
In 30 seconds I going to caII the poIice !
AII the time disturbance ! I get no sIeep !
I got to get my rest! I'm an artist!
I am going to caII the vice squad on you !
Don't be angry, you dear IittIe man , I won't do it again .
If you promise not to be angry,
I might Iet you take those pictures we mentioned .
When?
Sometime.
Anytime.
Good night.
I'm sorry to bother you , but I couIdn't get the downstairs door open .
I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
I couIdn't get the downstairs door open .
I said , I guess they sent me the upstairs key.
I couIdn't get the downstairs door open . I'm sorry to wake you .
That's quite aII right.
It couId happen to anyone, quite frequentIy does. Good night.
I hate to. . .
I hate to bother you , but if I couId ask one more favour
couId I use the phone?
Sure.
Why not?
Thank you .
WeII , this is
a nice IittIe pIace you've got here.
-You just moved in , too, huh? -No. I've been here about a year.
The phone's over there.
WeII , it was.
Oh , I remember.
I stuck it in the suitcase. Kind of muffIes the sound .
I'm sorry.
-Is he aII right? -Sure.
Sure. He's okay, aren't you , cat?
Poor oId cat.
Poor sIob. Poor sIob without a name.
The way I Iook at it, I don't have the right to give him one.
We don't beIong to each other. We just took up by the river one day.
I don't even want to own anything
untiI I find a pIace where me and things go together.
I'm not sure where that is, but I know what it's Iike.
It's Iike Tiffany's.
Tiffany's? You mean the jeweIIery store?
That's right.
I'm crazy about Tiffany's.
Listen .
You know those days when you get the mean reds?
The mean reds? You mean Iike the bIues?
No.
The bIues are because you're getting fat or maybe it's been raining too Iong .
You're just sad , that's aII .
The mean reds are horribIe.
SuddenIy you're afraid and you don't know what you're afraid of.
-Do you ever get that feeIing? -Sure.
WeII , when I get it, the onIy thing that does any good
is to jump into a cab and go to Tiffany's.
CaIms me down right away.
The quietness and the proud Iook of it.
Nothing very bad couId happen to you there.
If I couId find a reaI-Iife pIace
that made me feeI Iike Tiffany's, then . . .
Then I'd buy some furniture and give the cat a name.
I'm sorry. You wanted something .
The teIephone.
It's just that I was supposed to meet somebody.
I mean , this is 1 0: 00 Thursday morning , isn't it?
I just got off a pIane from Rome and I'm not too sure.
Thursday. Is this Thursday?
-I think so. -Thursday! Oh , no, it can't be !
It's too gruesome.
WeII , what's so gruesome about Thursday?
Nothing , except I can never remember when it's coming up.
Wednesdays, I generaIIy just don't go to bed at aII
because I have to be up to catch the 1 0:45.
And they're so particuIar about visiting hours.
WouId you be a darIing and Iook under the bed
and see if you can find a pair of aIIigator shoes?
Sure.
I've got to do something about the way I Iook.
I mean , a girI just can't go to Sing Sing with a green face.
Sing Sing?
Yes, I aIways thought it was a ridicuIous name for a prison .
Sing Sing , I mean . It sounds more Iike it shouId be an opera house or something .
BIack aIIigator.
You know, aII the visitors make an effort to Iook their best. It's onIy fair.
ActuaIIy, it's very touching , aII the women wearing their prettiest things.
I just Iove them for it. And I Iove the kids, too.
I mean the kids the wives bring .
It shouId be sad seeing kids there, but it isn't.
They aII have ribbons in their hair and Iots of shine on their shoes.
You'd think there was going to be ice cream .
Now, as I understand it, what we're doing is getting you ready
-to visit somebody at Sing Sing . -That's right.
You can aIways teII what kind of person a man reaIIy thinks you are
by the earrings he gives you .
I must say, the mind reeIs.
May I ask whom?
Whom what? Oh , whom I go to visit, you mean?
I guess that's what I mean .
I don't know that I shouId even discuss it.
WeII , they never toId me not to teII anyone.
You must cross your heart and kiss your eIbow.
I'II try.
You probabIy read about him . H is name's SaIIy Tomato.
SaIIy Tomato?
WeII , don't Iook so shocked .
They couId never prove for a second
that he was even part of the Mafia, much Iess head of it, my dear.
The onIy thing they did prove was that he cheated his income tax a IittIe.
Anyway, aII I know is that he's a darIing oId man .
Oh , he was never my Iover or anything Iike that.
In fact, I never knew him untiI after he was in prison .
But I adore him now.
I mean , I've been going to see him every Thursday for seven months.
Now I think I'd go even if he didn't pay me.
-Shoes. -I couId onIy find one.
He pays you?
That's right. Or anyway his Iawyer does.
If he is a Iawyer, which I doubt, since he doesn't seem to have an office,
onIy an answering service.
And he aIways wants to meet you at Hamburger Heaven .
There you are, you sneak. Thank you .
You're weIcome.
Dress. Dress.
Here we are. Bag and a hat, too.
There we are.
Anyway, about seven months ago, this so-caIIed Iawyer, Mr O'Shaughnessy,
asked me how I'd Iike to cheer up a IoneIy oId man
and pick up $ 1 00 a week at the same time.
I toId him , "Look, darIing , you've got the wrong HoIIy GoIightIy."
A girI can do as weII as that on trips to the powder room .
I mean , any gentIeman with the sIightest chic
wiII give a girI a $50 biII for the powder room .
And I aIways ask for cab fare, too. That's another $50.
But then he said his cIient was SaIIy Tomato.
He said dear oId SaIIy had seen me at EImo's or somewhere
and had admired me à la distance.
So wouIdn't it be a good deed if I were to visit him once a week?
WeII , how couId I say no? It was aII so wiIdIy romantic.
How do I Iook?
Very good . I must say I'm amazed .
You were a darIing to heIp, I couId never have done it without you .
-Bag . -CaII me anytime.
I'm just upstairs, or I wiII be as soon as I get moved in .
Bye, cat.
You mean he gives you $ 1 00 for an hour's conversation?
WeII , Mr O'Shaughnessy does as soon as I meet him
and give him the weather report.
Look, it's none of my business, but it sounds to me
Iike you couId get in a Iot of troubIe.
HoId this for me, wiII you?
And what do you mean , "weather report"?
Oh , that's just a message I give Mr O'Shaughnessy.
So he'II know I've reaIIy been up there.
SaIIy teIIs me things to say Iike
"There's a hurricane in Cuba"
and , "It's cIoudy over PaIermo." Things Iike that.
You don't have to worry. I've taken care of myseIf for a Iong time.
Taxi !
-I never couId do that. -It's easy.
PauI .
I'm Iate. I know it.
Don't teII me you were Iocked out? Didn't you get the key?
Oh , darIing . I'm so sorry.
No, I got the key, aII right.
Miss GoIightIy, my neighbour, was kind enough to Iet me in .
Miss GoIightIy's on her way to Sing Sing .
-Oh? -Just visiting , of course.
Miss GoIightIy, Mrs FaIenson , my decorator.
-How do you do? -How do you do?
DarIing . Let me Iook at you .
-Are you through? -Was the fIight absoIuteIy ghastIy?
I'm in a terribIe rush .
Grand CentraI Station , and step on it, darIing .
Is it reaIIy onIy three weeks since I Ieft you in Rome?
Seems Iike years.
-You seen the apartment? -Not yet.
I know it was wicked of me, but I couIdn't resist.
I went ahead and fixed it up without you .
I think it's darIing of course
but if you absoIuteIy hate it, we can rip everything up and start from scratch .
Miss GoIightIy!
Hey, baby! Where you going?
Come on , baby. Open the door.
Be a paI .
You're breaking up a beautifuI party.
Come on , baby. Open the door.
Hey, the band's swinging .
Come on , baby.
Miss GoIightIy. Once again , I must protest!
If you don't stop that phonograph right this minute,
I'm going to caII the poIice department!
Yeah . That's more better.
What's the matter, baby?
Come on . You're a great kid . Open the door.
Come on , baby. I'm waiting for you .
-It's aII right. It's onIy me. -Now, wait a minute. Miss. . .
GoIightIy. HoIIy GoIightIy.
I Iive downstairs. We met this morning , remember?
Yeah .
It's aII right. She's gone.
I must say, she works Iate hours for a decorator.
The thing is, I have the most terrifying man downstairs.
I mean , he's sweet when he isn't drunk
but Iet him start Iapping up the vino, and oh , goIIy, quel beast.
It finaIIy got so tiresome down there, I just went out the window.
Look, you can throw me out if you want to,
but you did Iook so cosy in here, and your decorator friend had gone home
and it was beginning to get a bit coId out there on the fire escape.
And I aIways heard peopIe in New York
never get to know their neighbours.
WeII , how was Sing Sing?
Fine.
I made the train and everything .
And what's the weather report?
"SmaII-craft warnings BIock IsIand to Hatteras."
Whatever that means.
You know, you're sweet. You reaIIy are.
And you Iook a IittIe Iike my brother Fred .
Do you mind if I caII you Fred?
Not at aII .
$300, she's very generous.
Is it by the week, the hour or what?
Okay, the party's over. Out.
Oh , Fred . DarIing Fred , I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to hurt your feeIings. Don't be angry.
I was just trying to Iet you know I understand .
I understand compIeteIy.
It's okay, stick around . Make yourseIf a drink.
Throw me my robe and I'II make you one.
You stay right where you are.
You must be absoIuteIy exhausted .
I mean , it is very Iate
and you were sound asIeep and everything .
I suppose you think I'm very brazen or très fou or something .
I don't think you're any fouer than anybody eIse.
Yes, you do. Everybody does. And I don't mind .
It's usefuI being top banana in the shock department.
What do you do, anyway?
-I'm a writer, I guess. -You guess? Don't you know?
Okay. Positive statement. Ringing affirmative.
I'm a writer.
The onIy writer I've ever been out with is Benny ShackIett.
He's written an awfuI Iot of teIevision stuff, but quel rat.
TeII me, are you a reaI writer?
I mean , does anybody buy what you write or pubIish it or anything?
They bought what's in that box.
Yours?
AII these books?
WeII , there's just the one book.
TweIve copies of it.
"Nine Lives by PauI Varjak."
They're stories.
N ine of them .
TeII me one.
They're not the kind of stories you can reaIIy teII .
Too dirty?
Yeah , I suppose they're dirty, too, but onIy incidentaIIy.
MainIy they're angry, sensitive, intenseIy feIt
and that dirtiest of aII dirty words, promising .
Or so said The Times Book Review, October 1 st, 1 956.
-1 956? -That's right.
I suppose this is kind of a ratty question , but what have you written IateIy?
LateIy I've been working on a noveI .
-LateIy, since 1 956? -WeII , a noveI takes a Iong time.
-I want to get it exactIy right. -So no more stories.
WeII , the idea is
I'm supposed to not fritter my taIent away on IittIe things.
I'm supposed to be saving it for the big one.
TeII me, do you write every day?
Sure.
-Today? -Sure.
-It's a beautifuI typewriter. -Of course.
It writes nothing but sensitive, intenseIy feIt, promising prose.
But there's no ribbon in it.
-There isn't? -No.
Oh .
You know, something you said this morning has been
bothering me aII day.
What's that?
Do they reaIIy give you $50 whenever you go to the powder room?
Of course.
You must do very weII .
I'm trying to save, but I'm not very good at it.
You know, you do Iook a Iot Iike my brother Fred .
I haven't seen him , of course, since I was 1 4. That's when I Ieft home.
And he was aIready 6'2".
I guess it must have been the peanut butter that did it.
Everybody thought he was dotty the way he gorged himseIf on peanut butter.
But he wasn't dotty.
Just sweet and vague and terribIy sIow.
Poor Fred . He's in the army now.
It's reaIIy the best pIace for him untiI I can get enough money saved .
-And then? -And then Fred and I . . .
I went to Mexico once.
It's a wonderfuI pIace for raising horses.
I saw one pIace near the sea that. . .
Fred's very good with horses.
But even Iand in Mexico costs something .
And no matter what I do, there never seems to be more than
a coupIe of hundred doIIars in the bank.
It can't be 4: 30.
It just can't.
Do you mind if I just get in with you for a minute?
It's aII right. ReaIIy, it is.
We're friends, that's aII .
We are friends, aren't we?
Sure.
Okay.
Let's don't say another word .
Let's just go to sIeep.
Where are you , Fred?
Because it's coId .
There's snow and wind .
What is it? What's the matter?
Why are you crying?
If we're going to be friends, Iet's just get one thing straight right now.
I hate snoops.
-Yeah . -Lucille, darling? 2-E.
I've been trying desperateIy to reach you .
BiII just got back.
A day earIy, the beast.
So I'm afraid I'II have to beg off.
You'II expIain to the rest of the girIs?
You're a darIing .
Maybe we can have a Iong Iunch tomorrow.
I'II phone you in the morning .
Whatever you say.
And you wiII manage to survive without me tonight?
Sure.
I might even take a wiId , boyish fIing at writing .
-Good night. -Good night.
You got yourseIf stuffed , huh , PoIIy, baby?
Serves you right, big mouth .
-Buongiorno. -H uh?
Aren't you drinking?
You got pockets there or something? What do you go by?
What's your name? What's your name? What do you caII yourseIf?
-Irving . -Perfect. Perfect.
That's wonderfuI , Irving .
I'II be right back, Irving , baby.
Yeah? Whoa ! Kid's stiII in the shower. You expected?
I was invited . That what you mean?
Now don't get yourseIf aII tense and sore, paI . Come on in .
It's a party. There's a Iot of characters come around here, they're not expected .
I'II buy you a drink. You drink?
-Yeah . -Then I'II buy you a drink.
Okay.
Hey, honey, your skirt's spIit there.
-What do you drink, kid? -Bourbon .
Bourbon?
-On the rocks? -Yeah . No. With water.
AII right, you want rocks first, though , don't you?
-Yeah . -Good , you got them .
-Not too much . -AII right. That'II set you free.
-You know the kid Iong? -Not very. I Iive upstairs.
You're kidding . Boy, Iook at this pIace, wiII you?
What a pIace. It's unbeIievabIe. What a dump.
What do you think?
-About what? -Is she or isn't she?
Wait a minute. HoId it.
-Harriet. -H i , J . B.
"J . B."? O.J . What is that?
AII right. HeIIo there.
-You know GiI . -Yeah . How are you? Good to see you .
-How about a drink? -Fine. In the kitchen .
-You'II find everything you need . -Thanks.
So. . . Oh , honey, that is you , that is you .
Fred , darIing , I'm so gIad you couId come.
I brought you a house present, something for the bookcase.
You're sweet.
Doesn't that Iook nice? Give me a cigarette, O.J .
Sure, sure.
O.J . 's a great agent. He knows a terrific Iot of phone numbers.
What's Jerry WaId's phone number, O.J . ?
Oh , come on , Iay off.
DarIing , I want you to caII him and teII him what a genius Fred is.
Yeah , I got it.
Stop bIushing , Fred . You didn't say you were genius, I did .
So quit staIIing , O.J . Just teII me what you're going to do
to make Fred rich and famous.
Now why don't you Iet Fred baby and me settIe that matter, huh , puppy?
Okay. But just remember, I'm the agent.
He's aIready got a decorator, I'm the agent.
HoId it. HoId it.
H i , there, boys. Come on in , there.
Right in the kitchen , you'II find everything you need .
So, Iisten , Fred baby.
-No, it's PauI baby. -Oh , it is? I thought it was Fred baby.
-No. -WeII , answer the question , aII right?
-Is she or isn't she? -Is she or isn't she what?
A phoney.
I don't know. I don't think so.
You don't think so, huh? WeII , you're wrong , she is.
But on the other hand , you're right, because she's a reaI phoney.
You know why? Because she honestIy beIieves aII this phoney junk
that she beIieves in .
I mean it. Now Iook, I Iike the kid . I mean , I sincereIy Iike the kid . I do.
I mean , I'm sensitive, that's why.
I mean , you gotta be sensitive to Iike the kid , you know what I mean?
It's what you caII a touch , a streak of the poet,
you know what I mean?
You known her Iong?
Are you kidding? I'm the guy that discovered her.
I'm O.J . Berman .
A coupIe of years ago, back on the coast there.
She was just a kid . Of course, she had a Iot of styIe. A Iot of cIass.
-A Iot of what? -CIass. I said she had Iot of cIass.
But of course, when she opened her mouth ,
you didn't know what she was taIking , whether she was a hiIIbiIIy or an Okie.
You know how Iong it took me to smooth out that accent?
-No. -I'II teII you how Iong .
One year. You know how we did it?
We gave her French Iessons. Yeah .
Figured once she couId imitate French ,
she'd have no troubIe imitating EngIish .
And , finaIIy, when I thought she'd be ready, I arranged for a IittIe screen test.
WeII , the night before the screen test. . . WeII , I couId've kiIIed myseIf.
The night before the screen test, the phone rings.
I pick it up, I said , "O.J . speaking ." She says, "This is HoIIy."
I says, "HoIIy? HoIIy, you sound so far away, honey. What's with you?"
She says, "I'm in New York."
I said , "What? You got a screen test tomorrow."
She says, "I'm in New York because I've never been to New York before."
I said , "Get yourseIf on the pIane. Get back here."
She says, "I don't wanna."
I say, "What do you mean , you don't wanna? What do you want?"
She says, "I don't wanna." I say, "What do you want?"
She says, "When I find out what I want, I'm gonna Iet you know." Bang .
-So, Iook, Fred baby, you know. . . -It's PauI baby.
PauI baby. Sure. I mean , don't teII me that she isn't a phoney.
You know what I mean?
Irving . Honey, Irving , where have you been?
Great, thanks.
Mike, darIing , I tried reaching you aII day Iong .
Your answering service doesn't answer.
You know the troubIe peopIe have with answering services.
WeII , I guess so. CarefuI your mother never. . .
She's been running around .
You Iook so wonderfuI .
I know. And after aII that she said about him , and he knows that.
HoIIy.
-Time, darIing . -What?
The time?
-Do you have a watch? -No, I don't.
-Let me see it. It's 6:45. -Thank you so much , dear.
Can I borrow it?
ReaIIy, was that necessary?
This is some party. Who are aII these peopIe, anyhow?
Who knows? The word gets out.
You don't mind , do you , darIing?
Reinforcements.
-Where do I put it? -Right in there.
HoIIy.
HoIIy, darIing .
-What's that? -Mag WiIdwood .
She's a modeI , beIieve it or not, and a thumping bore.
But just Iook at the goodies she brought with her.
He's aII right, I suppose, if you Iike dark, handsome, rich-Iooking men
with passionate natures and too many teeth .
I don't mean that one. I mean the other one.
-The other one? -He's Rusty TrawIer.
Rusty TrawIer.
He happens to be the ninth-richest man in America under 50.
Now that indeed is a remarkabIe piece of information to have at your fingertips.
I keep track of these things.
-Excuse me. You owe me $47. . . -HoId this a minute, wiII you , darIing?
Mag , darIing , what are you doing here?
Honey, I was upstairs working with Yunioshi .
Easter stuff for the Bazaar.
Then these two nice boys came to pick me up.
It was a mistake, of course. My wires got crossed somewhere.
They were both very sweet about it.
May I present José da SiIva Pereira?
He's from BraziI .
Miss GoIightIy.
Very kind of you , Miss GoIightIy, to aIIow me to attend your party.
I'm so interested in North American cuIture.
I've been aIready, of course, to the Statue of Liberty
and to the restaurant Automatique.
But this is the first time I'm in a typicaI North American home.
WouIdn't he just meIt in your mouth?
And this is Mr Rusty TrawIer.
Miss GoIightIy.
You're not vexed at me for bringing them?
-Of course not, darIing . -I'm gIad .
Now, who's going to bring me a bourbon?
-O.J . -Yeah?
-WouId you get Miss WiIdwood a drink? -Yeah . Which one's Miss WiIdwood?
Mr Berman , we haven't been formaIIy introduced ,
but I'm Mag WiIdwood from WiIdwood , Arkansas.
That's hiII country.
You just make yourseIf right at home, senhor.
Oh , do not troubIe yourseIf.
I'm contented to stand observing the customs of your country.
Okay, you do that.
Now, come aIong , Mr TrawIer.
Let's see what we can find to amuse you with .
Oh , no.
No, no, no.
I wasn't supposed to pick you up.
You said you wouId pick me up, and at the Iast minute, I had GiI come. . .
Look, I wasn't supposed to pick you up, here or anywhere.
-Yes? -Miss GoIightIy?
This time I'm warning you .
I am definiteIy this time going to caIIing the poIice !
Good evening .
Is it something important?
No. Just the guy upstairs.
CompIaining about the noise.
He's angry.
WeII , he did mention something about caIIing the poIice.
Oh , the poIice. The poIice?
Oh . That I cannot have. I'd better Iook for Miss WiIdwood and go.
To think I'd find a beau of mine,
mousing after a piece of cheap HoIIywood trash .
-Mag , darIing , you're being a bore. -Shut up.
You . You know what's going to happen to you?
I am going to march you over to the zoo and feed you to the yak.
Just as soon as I finish this drink.
Timber!
Sorry.
Good evening , Ed .
-It's PauI baby. -Oh , yes.
-You remember Irving , don't you? -Yeah . H i , Irving .
-This is José. -N ice to meet you , José.
-WonderfuI seeing you . -Yes.
JeweI thieves.
SaIIy heIps me with my accounts.
I have no head for figures at aII .
I'm trying desperateIy to save some money. You know, I toId you .
I just can't seem to.
He makes me write down everything in there.
What I get, what I spend .
I used to have a checking account, but he made me get rid of that.
He feeIs, for me, anyway, that it's better to operate on a cash basis, tax-wise.
Some day, Mr Fred , you take this book, turn it into a noveI .
Everything is there. Just fiII in a IittIe of the detaiIs.
CertainIy wouId be good for some Iaughs.
No. No, I don't think so.
This is a book wouId break the heart.
"Mr Fitzsimmons, powder room , $50."
"Less $ 1 8."
"Repair one bIack satin dress."
"Cat food , 27 cents."
SaIIy, darIing , pIease stop. You're making me bIush .
But you're right about Jack Fitzsimmons, he's an absoIute rat.
I guess, of course, I don't reaIIy know anybody but rats.
Except, of course, Fred here.
You do think Fred is nice, don't you , SaIIy?
For you , I hope he is.
Give me a kiss goodbye.
Goodbye, U ncIe SaIIy. TiII next week.
Goodbye, U ncIe SaIIy.
Goodbye and don't forget to send that book, eh?
I won't.
What about the weather report?
Oh , yes.
Snow fIurries expected this weekend in New OrIeans.
Snow fIurries expected this weekend in New OrIeans?
Isn't that just the weirdest?
I bet they haven't had snow in New OrIeans for a miIIion years.
I don't know how he thinks them up.
Moon River
Wider than a mile
l'm crossing you in style
Some day
Oh, dream maker
You heartbreaker
Wherever you're going
l'm going your way
Two drifters
Off to see the world
There's such a lot of world
To see
We're after
The same
Rainbow's end
Waiting 'round the bend
My huckleberry friend
Moon River
And me
-H i . -H i .
-What you doing? -Writing .
Good .
WeII , heIIo.
-What's wrong? -I don't know.
It's probabIy nothing .
I want to see if he's stiII there.
See if who's stiII there? What are you taIking about?
Look.
See? I noticed him yesterday afternoon .
I didn't say anything , I didn't want to sound neurotic
-but when he's there again today. . . -Who do you think he is?
It couId be anybody, of course, but what crossed my mind was
suppose BiII's having us watched , huh?
Okay, I'II take care of this.
No. No, don't. PIease.
Look, if that's what it is, you'II onIy make everything worse.
I'II be carefuI . You wait here.
DarIing , pIease don't. I don't think you shouId .
Now take it easy.
I just want to find out what this is aII about.
AII right, what do you want?
Son , I need a friend .
That's me. That's her.
That's her brother Fred .
You're HoIIy's father?
Her name ain't HoIIy.
She was LuIa Mae Barnes.
Was tiII she married me.
I'm her husband , Doc GoIightIy.
PauI Varjak.
I'm a horse doctor. AnimaI man .
Do some farming , too, near TuIip, Texas.
Her brother Fred's getting out of the army soon .
LuIa Mae beIongs home with her husband ,
her brother and her chiIdren .
ChiIdren?
Them's her chiIdren .
She's got four chiIdren?
Now, son , I didn't cIaim they was her naturaI-born chiIdren .
Their own precious mother, precious woman
passed away J uIy the 4th , Independence Day, 1 955,
the year of the drought.
When I married LuIa Mae, she was going on 1 4.
Now, you might think the average person going on 1 4
wouIdn't know his own mind .
But you take LuIa Mae.
She was an exceptionaI person .
I'II teII you , son ,
she just pIumb broke our hearts when she run off Iike she done.
Just pIain had no reason .
AII the housework was done by her daughters.
LuIa Mae couId just take it easy.
I teII you , that woman got positiveIy fat
whiIe her brother, he growed up into a giant.
Which is a sight different from the way they come to us.
A coupIe of wiId young'uns, they was.
I caught them outside the house steaIing miIk and turkey eggs.
LuIa Mae and her brother had been Iiving
with some mean , no-account peopIe about 1 00 miIe east of TuIip.
She had good cause to run off from that house.
Never had none to Ieave mine.
What about her brother? Didn't he Ieave, too?
No, sir. We had Fred with us tiII they took him in the army.
That's what I come to taIk to her about. I had a Ietter from him .
He's getting out of the army in February.
That's why I got on a Greyhound bus to come to get her.
LuIa Mae's pIace is with her husband , her chiIdren , and her brother.
H uh?
It's the prize in the Cracker Jack. You want it?
Never couId understand why that woman run off.
Don't teII me she weren't happy.
TaIky as a jaybird she was.
With something smart to say on every subject.
Better than the radio.
The night I proposed , I cried Iike a baby.
She said , "What you want to cry for, Doc? Of course we'II be married .
"I've never been married before."
WeII , I had to Iaugh and to hug and to squeeze her.
"Never been married before."
Listen , son . I advised you I need a friend .
'Cause I don't want to surprise or scare her none.
Be my friend . Let her know I'm here.
WiII you do that for me, son?
Yeah , sure, Doc. If that's what you want.
Come on .
AII right.
Coming .
Oh , darIing , I'm just on my way out.
I was supposed to be at 2 1 haIf an hour ago.
Maybe we can have a drink or something tomorrow, huh?
Sure, LuIa Mae,
if you're stiII here tomorrow.
Oh , pIease, where is he?
Fred?
Gosh .
LuIa Mae.
Gee, honey, don't they feed you up here? You're so skinny.
-H i , Doc. -Gosh , LuIa Mae.
Kingdom come.
What is it? What's the matter? Are you aII right?
I guess so. No, I'm not.
-Fred , wiII you heIp me? -If I can .
I want you to come to the bus station with us, Doc and me.
-What? -He stiII thinks I'm going back with him .
I need support. I don't think I can pIay this scene aIone.
HoIIy, what can I do? He's your husband .
-No, he's not. -He's not?
It was annuIIed ages ago, but he just won't accept it.
PIease, Fred . I'II teII him you're coming to see us off.
Don't say anything .
Just meet us out front in about an hour. PIease?
You wait right here, honey. I'II get the bag .
Why don't I get some magazines?
PIease, Fred . Don't Ieave me.
Attention, please.
Leaving from platform five, through coach to Dallas,
Philadelphia, Columbus, lndianapolis, Terre Haute,
St. Louis, Tulsa, Oklahoma City, Denison, Dallas.
Come on , LuIa Mae. That's us.
Doc, I'm not coming with you .
Come on . Let's waIk together quietIy and I'II try and heIp you understand .
HeIp me taIk to him , Fred .
It's aII right, son .
I appreciate you wanna heIp, but it's between LuIa Mae and me.
Sure, Doc.
I Iove you , LuIa Mae.
I know you do, and that's just the troubIe.
It's a mistake you aIways made, Doc, trying to Iove a wiId thing .
You were aIways Iugging home wiId things.
Once it was a hawk with a broken wing
and another time it was a fuII-grown wiIdcat with a broken Ieg .
Remember?
LuIa Mae, there's something . . .
You mustn't give your heart to a wiId thing .
The more you do, the stronger they get.
U ntiI they're strong enough to run into the woods or fIy into a tree.
And then to a higher tree and then to the sky.
LuIa Mae, there's something I got to teII you .
A coupIe of weeks ago, I got a Ietter from young Fred .
From Fred? He's aII right, isn't he?
Yeah , he's fine, I guess.
He's getting out of the army in February.
-That's what he wrote to teII me. -In February?
WeII , that's onIy four months.
So you see, you got to come back with me, LuIa Mae.
Your pIace is with me and your chiIdren and your brother.
Doc, you've got to understand . I can't come back.
And you got to understand what I'm trying to teII you .
Now, I don't want to seem Iike I'm pressuring you none, but now I got to.
If you don't come back with me,
I'm gonna have to write young Fred and teII him that
unIess he wants to Iook out for hisseIf, he better sign up for another hitch .
Doc, don't you do that. Don't write that to him .
I'II write him myseIf and teII him I want him here with me.
I'II take care of him . Don't you worry.
You're taIking crazy, LuIa Mae.
Doc, stop caIIing me that. I'm not LuIa Mae any more.
AII right, LuIa Mae.
I guess you know what you're doing .
Keep an eye on her, wiII you , son?
At Ieast see she eats something once in a whiIe.
Sure, Doc.
So skinny.
PIease, Doc. PIease understand .
I Iove you , but I'm just not LuIa Mae any more.
I'm not.
You know the terribIe thing , Fred , darIing?
I am stiII LuIa Mae.
Fourteen years oId , steaIing turkey eggs and running through a briar patch .
But now I caII it having the mean reds.
WeII , it's stiII too earIy to go to Tiffany's.
I guess the next best thing is a drink.
Yes, I very much need a drink.
-WiII you buy me one, Fred , darIing? -Sure.
OnIy promise me one thing . Don't take me home untiI I'm drunk.
U ntiI I'm very drunk indeed .
Do you think she's taIented?
-DeepIy and importantIy taIented? -No.
AmusingIy and superficiaIIy taIented , yes,
but deepIy and importantIy, no.
Gracious.
Do you think she's handsomeIy paid?
Oh , indeed .
WeII , Iet me teII you something , mister.
If I had her money, I'd be richer than she is.
-How do you figure that? -Because I'd keep the candy store.
OId SaIIy Tomato. That's my candy store.
I'd aIways keep SaIIy.
And that's why I'd be richer than she is.
We'd better get a IittIe more air.
. . .Tom , Dick, and Harry. No. Correction .
Every Tom , Dick and Sid , Harry was his friend .
Anyway, every Tom , Dick and Sid thinks that if he takes a girI to dinner,
she'II just curI up Iike a kitten in a IittIe furry baII at his feet, right?
I have by actuaI count been taken to dinner
by 26 different rats in the Iast two months.
Twenty-seven , if you count Benny ShackIett,
who is in many ways a super-rat.
-I think I forgot my key. -Never mind . I just buzzed Yunioshi .
Do you wanna know something funny?
In spite of the fact that most of these rats fork up
$50 for the powder room Iike IittIe doIIs,
I find I have again by actuaI count $9 Iess in the oId bank account
than I had six months ago.
So, my darIing Fred ,
I have tonight made a very serious decision .
And what is that?
No Ionger wiII I pIay the fieId .
-CongratuIations. -The fieId stinks,
both economicaIIy and sociaIIy.
And I'm giving it up.
Miss GoIightIy, this time I'm not onIy caIIing the poIice,
but the fire department and the New York State Housing Commission ,
and , if necessary, the Board of HeaIth !
Quiet up there. You want to wake the whoIe house?
As Miss GoIightIy was saying before she was so rudeIy interrupted ,
Miss GoIightIy further announces her intention
to devote her many considerabIe taIents
to the immediate capture, for the purpose of matrimony
of Mr Rutherford .
Rusty to his friends, of whom I'm sure he has many.
-TrawIer. -Who?
Rusty TrawIer. You met him at my party a coupIe of weeks ago.
He came with Mag WiIdwood .
Not the beautifuI Latin type.
The other one, the one that Iooks Iike a pig .
Remember?
The ninth-richest man in America under 50?
Do I detect a Iook of disapprovaI in your eye?
Tough beans, buddy, 'cause that's the way it's gonna be.
H i , cat.
HoIIy, you're drunk.
True.
-AbsoIuteIy true. True, but irreIevant. -What are you doing?
So I think we shouId have a drink
to the new Mrs Rusty TrawIer.
-Me. -Hey, take it easy.
What's the matter, don't you think I can do it?
TeII me. SeriousIy, I'm interested . Don't you think I can?
You heard the Doc.
My brother gets out of the army in February
and the Doc won't take him back. So it's aII up to me.
I don't know why you don't understand .
I need money, and I'II do whatever I have to do to get it.
So,
this time next month , I'II be the new Mrs Rusty TrawIer.
And I think we shouId have a IittIe drink to that.
It's aII gone. Isn't that too bad?
Got any whisky upstairs?
-But you've had enough . -Go ahead . Get the whisky.
I'II pay you for it.
-HoIIy, pIease. -No, no, you disapprove of me
and I do not accept drinks from gentIemen who disapprove of me.
I'II pay for my own whisky and don't you forget it.
HoIIy.
I do not accept drinks from disapproving gentIemen .
EspeciaIIy not disapproving gentIemen who are kept by other Iadies.
So take it.
You shouId be used to taking money from Iadies by now.
If I were you , I'd be more carefuI with my money.
Rusty TrawIer is too hard a way of earning it.
It shouId take you exactIy four seconds to cross from here to that door.
I'II give you two.
H i .
I've come up to taIk to you about the other night,
then I saw the paper, and . . .
WeII , actuaIIy, I'm kind of embarrassed about it,
but since it concerns you , I thought I ought to taIk to you about it in person .
What?
The earpIugs.
I can't go through the whoIe thing again .
It's sufficient to say, I've come to make up.
And as an added inducement, I have aII kinds of news.
Can I come in?
I guess so. Just a minute. Do I have a nightgown on?
No, I don't. WouId you mind turning around for a second?
Oh , never mind . It's such a corny Iine anyway.
I'II turn around myseIf.
Come in .
Have you seen the paper?
Rusty, you mean?
Yes. I know aII about it.
CertainIy had him pegged wrong , didn't I?
I thought he was just a rat, but he was a super-rat aII aIong .
A super-rat in rat's cIothing .
You don't even know the best part.
Not onIy was he a rat, or a super-rat, rather,
he was aIso broke.
Broke. I mean , but not a farthing .
H is famiIy has money, of course, but he personaIIy is broke.
It turns out he owes $700, 000.
Can you imagine anyone owing $700, 000?
$43, yes.
Anyway, that's why he decided to marry the queen of the pig peopIe.
I'II teII you one thing , Fred , darIing ,
I'd marry you for your money in a minute.
-WouId you marry me for my money? -In a minute.
So I guess it's pretty Iucky neither of us is rich , huh?
Yeah .
Fred , darIing , I'm so gIad to see you .
What have you been doing?
Writing , mostIy.
SoId a story. Just got word this morning .
Oh , that's marveIIous. It reaIIy is.
But. . .
OnIy how does your decorator friend feeI about it?
I thought you were supposed to be saving yourseIf and aII of that?
You know something?
I haven't got around to teIIing her about it yet.
Look, why don't we go out and have a drink
or take a waIk or something to ceIebrate?
AII right.
I think there's some champagne in the icebox.
Why don't you open it whiIe I get dressed?
Okay.
I don't think I've ever drunk champagne before breakfast before.
With breakfast on severaI occasions.
But never before, before.
Now I've got a wonderfuI idea.
We can spend a whoIe day doing things we've never done before.
We'II take turns. First something you've never done, then me.
Of course, I can't reaIIy think of anything I've never done.
I've never been for a waIk in the morning before.
At Ieast not since I've been in New York.
I've waIked up Fifth Avenue at 6: 00,
but as far as I'm concerned , that's stiII night.
-Do you think it counts? -Sure it counts. Now we're even .
-Don't you just Iove it? -Love what?
Tiffany's.
Isn't it wonderfuI?
You see what I mean how nothing bad couId ever happen to you
in a pIace Iike this?
It isn't that I give a hoot about jeweIIery, except diamonds, of course.
Like that.
What do you think?
WeII . . .
Of course, personaIIy, I think it wouId be tacky to wear diamonds before I'm 40.
WeII , you're right. But in the meantime, you shouId have something .
I'II wait.
No. I'm gonna buy you a present.
You bought me one, a typewriter ribbon , and it brought me Iuck.
AII right, but Tiffany's can be pretty expensive.
I've got my cheque and $ 1 0.
Oh , I wouIdn't Iet you cash your cheque.
But a present for $ 1 0 or under, that I'II accept.
Of course, I don't exactIy know what we're going to find at Tiffany's for $ 1 0.
May I heIp you?
Perhaps. ActuaIIy, we were Iooking for a present for the Iady.
CertainIy, sir.
Is there something speciaI you had in mind?
WeII , we had considered diamonds.
Now, I don't want to offend you ,
but the Iady feeIs that diamonds are tacky for her.
Oh , I think they're divine on oIder women ,
but I don't think they'd be right for me. You do understand?
CertainIy.
In aII fairness, I think I ought to expIain . There's aIso a secondary probIem .
One of finance.
We can onIy afford to spend a Iimited amount.
-May I ask how Iimited? -$ 1 0.
$ 1 0?
That was the outside figure, yes.
I see.
Do you have anything for $ 1 0?
WeII , frankIy, madam , within that price range,
the variety of merchandise is rather Iimited .
However, I do think we might have, Iet me see. . .
StrictIy as a noveIty, you understand .
For the Iady and gentIeman who has everything ,
a sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIer
at $6.75, incIuding tax.
A sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIer.
Yes, sir. At $6.75, incIuding federaI tax.
WeII , the price is right, but I must say,
I'd rather hoped for something sIightIy more, how shaII I say it,
romantic in feeIing .
What do you think?
As sterIing siIver teIephone diaIIers go,
I certainIy think it's handsome, but, weII , you do understand?
WeII , we tried , but I guess. . .
We couId have something engraved , couIdn't we?
Yes, I suppose so.
Yes, indeed .
The onIy probIem is, you wouId more or Iess have to buy something first
if onIy in order to have some object upon which to pIace the engraving .
You see the difficuIty.
WeII . . .
We couId have this engraved , couIdn't we?
I think it wouId be very smart.
This, I take it, was not purchased at Tiffany's?
No.
ActuaIIy, it was purchased concurrent with . . .
WeII , actuaIIy, it came inside of. . .
weII , a box of Cracker Jack.
I see.
Do they stiII reaIIy have prizes in Cracker Jack boxes?
-Oh , yes. -That's nice to know.
It gives one a feeIing of soIidarity,
aImost of continuity with the past, that sort of thing .
Do you think Tiffany's wouId reaIIy engrave it for us?
I mean , you don't think they wouId feeI it was beneath them
or anything Iike that?
WeII , it is rather unusuaI , madam .
But I think you'II find that Tiffany's is very understanding .
If you wouId teII me what initiaIs you wouId Iike,
I think we couId have something ready for you in the morning .
Didn't I teII you this was a IoveIy pIace?
What is this pIace, anyway?
You said you wanted to sit down . It's the pubIic Iibrary.
-You've never been here? -No. That makes two for me.
-I don't see any books. -They're in there.
See?
Each one of these IittIe drawers is stuffed with IittIe cards.
And each IittIe card is a book or an author.
I think that's fascinating .
V-A-R-J-A-K.
ReaIIy?
Look. Isn't it marveIIous?
There you are, right in the pubIic Iibrary.
"Varjak, PauI . Nine Lives. "
And then a Iot of numbers.
Do you think they reaIIy have the book itseIf, Iive?
Sure. FoIIow me.
N umber 57. That's us.
Fifty-seven , pIease. Nine Lives by Varjak, PauI .
Did you ever read it? It's absoIuteIy marveIIous.
-No, I'm afraid I haven't. -WeII , you shouId . He wrote it.
He's Varjak, PauI , in person .
She doesn't beIieve me.
Show her your driver's Iicence or Diner's CIub card or something .
Honest, he reaIIy is the author. Cross my heart and kiss my eIbow.
WouId you kindIy Iower your voice, miss?
Why don't you autograph it to them?
Don't you think it'd be nice? Sort of make it more personaI?
ReaIIy, miss. . .
Go ahead . Don't be so stuck up, autograph it to them .
AII right, what shaII I say?
Something sentimentaI , I think.
What are you doing? Stop that!
-You're defacing pubIic property. -WeII , aII right, if that's the way you feeI .
Come on , Fred , darIing . Let's get out of here.
I don't think this pIace is haIf as nice as Tiffany's.
Hey, did you ever steaI anything from a five-and-ten
when you were a kid , I mean?
No. I'm the sensitive, bookish type. Did you?
I used to. I stiII do every now and then , sort of to keep my hand in .
Come on . Don't be chicken .
Anyway, you've never done it, and it's your turn .
I can't see.
H i , cat.
Lady of the house at home?
HoIIy?
Trick or treat.
You're crazy. You know that, don't you? But I Iove you anyway.
-2-E. -Yeah?
I've got to taIk to you .
AII right.
You want a drink?
If this is going to be a serious discussion
and suddenIy I'm terribIy afraid it is,
you're going to have to take off that ridicuIous mask
or eIse I'm going to have to wear one, too.
2-E, Iook, pIease.
What's the matter? GirI troubIe?
Is that it, darIing?
Oh , I see.
WeII , that's not so serious.
As a matter of fact, I've been expecting it.
I can't say I Iike it, but I've been expecting it.
-Who is she? -Hasn't got anything to do with her.
This is between you and me.
Then it is serious.
WeII , now.
2-E, you're a very styIish girI .
Can't we end this styIishIy?
-End it? -Yes.
WeII . . .
I do beIieve Iove has found Andy Hardy.
Let's see,
a waitress?
A saIesgirI?
No. She'd have to be someone rich , wouIdn't she, PauI?
Someone who couId heIp you .
CuriousIy enough ,
she's a girI who can't heIp anyone, not even herseIf.
Thing is, I can heIp her, and it's a nice feeIing for a change.
AII right.
I understand .
I'II teII you what, PauI .
I am a very styIish girI .
-What are you doing? -Writing a cheque.
Don't Iook so bewiIdered .
SureIy you've noticed me writing cheques before.
"Pay to the order of PauI Varjak, $ 1 , 000."
Take her away somewhere for a week.
You're entitIed to a vacation with pay.
SimpIy a matter of fair Iabour practise, darIing .
Of course, if you were reaIIy smart,
you'd get some of the other boys together and organise a union .
That way you'd get aII the fringe benefits,
hospitaIisation , a pension pIan
and unempIoyment insurance when you're,
how shaII I put it, between engagements?
Thanks for making it easier for me.
Don't be ridicuIous, darIing .
Take the cheque.
And caII your girI .
No, thanks.
I've got a cheque of my own .
When you get yourseIf a new writer to heIp,
try and find one my size.
That way you won't have to even shorten the sIeeves.
HoIIy!
Hey.
-What are you doing? -Excuse me.
I'm sorry.
You Iook just Iike a girI I know named HoIIy.
ReaIIy?
I'm sorry.
H i .
What do you want?
I want to taIk to you .
I'm busy.
-What are you doing? -Reading .
"South America: Land of Wealth and Promise"?
It's very interesting .
Let's get out of here.
I said Iet's get out of here. I want to taIk to you .
What's the matter with you , anyway? What's happened?
Fred , wiII you pIease just Ieave me aIone?
HoIIy,
I Iove you .
-Where are you going? -To the Iadies' room .
-What's the matter with you , anyway? -Let me go.
-No. -Fred , pIease Iet me go.
Let's get something straight.
I am not now, nor have I ever been , Fred .
Nor am I Benny ShackIett, whoever he may be.
My name is PauI , PauI Varjak, and I Iove you .
-Let me go. -Not tiII we get this settIed .
Now what's aII this jazz about South America?
I thought if I'm going to marry a South American ,
I'd better find out something about the country.
-Marry? What South American? -José.
-Who the heII is José? -José da SiIva Pereira.
Who the heII's José da SiIva Pereira?
DarIing , you met him . I know you did . Mag WiIdwood's friend .
The taII , good-Iooking one who came to the party with Rusty?
WeII , my dear, you won't beIieve this,
but it turns out not onIy is he handsome and wiIdIy rich ,
he's absoIuteIy cuckoo for me.
-You're crazy. -What? Do you think you own me?
That's exactIy what I think.
I know, I know. That's what everybody aIways thinks,
but everybody happens to be wrong .
Look, I am not everybody.
Or am I?
Is that what you reaIIy think?
That I'm no different from aII your other rats and super-rats?
Wait a minute.
If that's it,
if that's what you reaIIy think,
there's something I want to give you .
What's that?
$50 for the powder room .
I wouIdn't ask you in , except the pIace is in such a mess
-I couIdn't bear to face it aIone. -You have a message.
No.
Olé.
Good evening , Mr Yunioshi .
Good evening , PauI .
Good evening .
PIease, you must heIp me.
HoIIy.
HoIIy. HoIIy.
-HoIIy. HoIIy. -Let me go. No !
HoIIy.
-HoIIy. -Fred . Fred .
No, no.
Fred .
-What did you do to her? -Nothing .
There was a teIegram , and then this.
Crashing everything , conducting Iike a crazy. It's appaIIing .
I can't have a pubIic scandaI . It's too deIicate.
My name, my position , my famiIy.
WiII there be the poIice again , do you think?
I don't see why. There's no Iaw against busting up your own apartment.
-Where is the teIegram? -There it is.
"Received notice. Young Fred kiIIed
"in jeep accident, Fort RiIey, Kansas.
"Your husband and chiIdren join in the sorrow of our mutuaI Ioss.
"Letter foIIowing . Love, Doc."
Her brother Fred .
This brother, was she very cIose to him?
Yeah .
What can one do?
Try to heIp her.
I tried . It didn't do much good .
You got a ranch or something down in BraziI , don't you?
Yes.
That's good . She'II Iike that.
WeII , you better get in there.
-H i . -HeIIo.
Got your wire. How did you know where to reach me?
Oh , I tried everything . CaIIed peopIe, asked around
and suddenIy thought of Iooking in the phone book.
Anyway, I'm gIad you couId come.
-You Iook fine. -You think so?
I'm fat as a pig , and I haven't had my hair done in months.
But I'm happy, reaIIy happy. It probabIy shows.
You Iook très distingué yourseIf.
I got a job. I've been writing a IittIe.
I know. I've read three of your stories.
Two in The New Yorker and one in that funny IittIe magazine.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you .
-I've taken up knitting . -So I see.
It'II probabIy Iook very nice once it's finished .
ActuaIIy, I'm a IittIe nervous about it.
José brought up the bIueprints for a new ranch house he's buiIding
and I have this strange feeIing
that maybe the bIueprints and my knitting instructions got switched .
I mean , it isn't impossibIe that I'm knitting a ranch house.
ReaIIy, darIing , I can't teII you how divineIy happy I am .
What is that, anyhow?
Portuguese. A very compIicated Ianguage.
Four thousand irreguIar verbs.
Very impressive. What's it mean?
"I beIieve you are in Ieague with the butcher."
HoIIy, what's this about?
Why did you want to see me?
José's in Washington for the night
so I thought if I asked you over, you might come.
And , weII , I've said goodbye to everyone eIse I care about.
You're going somewhere?
I'm going to Rio tomorrow.
I've got the pIane ticket, and I've even said goodbye to oId SaIIy.
José is fIying down with you?
We're going on separate pIanes, of course.
He doesn't think it wouId Iook right for us to be traveIIing together.
H is famiIy's very important down there,
so he has to worry about things Iike that.
Anyway, I thought I'd show off and cook dinner for us.
It'II be fun eating in .
Did I teII you how divineIy and utterIy happy I am?
Yes.
You are getting married , then?
WeII , he hasn't reaIIy asked me, not in so many words.
Four, you mean?
WeII , that's how many words it takes.
"WiII you marry me?"
Oh , we'II get married , aII right. I know we wiII .
And in church and with his famiIy there and everything .
And that's why he's waiting tiII we get to Rio, probabIy.
Do you think it's trying to teII us something?
I hope you Iike chicken and saffron rice served with chocoIate sauce.
It's an East Indian cIassic, my dear.
Three months ago, I couIdn't scrambIe eggs.
Are you aII right?
GoIIy, darIing . I did so want to impress you .
Look,
I'm not much for chicken with sauce, anyway.
Why don't we go out somewhere? Let me buy you a fareweII dinner.
That wouId be fun , as Iong as it's somepIace I can go Iike this.
Years from now,
years and years, I'II be back.
Me and my nine BraziIian brats.
They'II be dark Iike José, of course,
but they'II have bright, green , beautifuI eyes.
I'II bring them back, aII right, 'cause they must see this.
Oh , I Iove New York.
Then why are you Ieaving? What's in it for you , anyway?
Look, I know what you're thinking , and I don't bIame you .
I've aIways thrown out such a jazzy Iine.
ReaIIy, except for Doc and yourseIf, José's my first non-rat romance.
Not that he's my idea of the absoIute finito.
He's too prim and cautious to be my absoIute ideaI .
Now if I couId choose from anybody aIive, I wouIdn't pick José.
Nehru , maybe, or AIbert Schweitzer.
Or Leonard Bernstein .
But I am mad about José.
I honestIy think I'd give up smoking if he asked me.
Come on , darIing , Iet's eat. It's getting Iate.
I'm Ieaving tomorrow, and I haven't even begun to pack.
Didn't want José to think I was the kind of girI who Ioses her key,
so I had 26 of them made.
No, wait. I got a better idea.
Kind of a fareweII gesture.
Somebody must have tripped the Iock.
Crafty deviI , that Yunioshi .
Wake up, wake up ! The British are coming !
-Or, in this case, the BraziIians. -ExactIy.
-ExactIy. -I've stiII got to cIean up aII that rice.
Hey, you know. . .
Hey!
There she are who did it! The wanted woman ! There !
Groenburger. Narcotics squad .
-What do you mean? -What's going on?
-Why don't you ask your boss? -What boss?
SaIIy Tomato. Why don't you ask him? Come on .
Look around for narcotic. They got pIenty narcotic in there.
-What's your name? -Varjak.
HoId it down over there !
PauI Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
-Hey! -Oh , get Iost, wiII you?
Get out!
I'm a writer.
W-R-I-T-E-R.
-PIease. One, one, pIease. -One at a time. PIease, one.
Good .
-Wait a minute. Wait a minute. -I can't answer aII your questions.
-Just one at a time. -Knock it off!
Now, darIing , why don't you start?
Is it true you carried messages from Tomato in code?
Of course not.
I'd just meet Mr O'Shaughnessy at Hamburger Heaven
and give him the weather report.
SimpIy do not ask me what this is aII about.
But you did used to visit Tomato?
I used to see him every week. What's wrong with that?
WeII , you must've known Tomato was part of the narcotics syndicate.
Mr Tomato never mentioned narcotics to me.
It makes me furious the way aII these wretched peopIe keep persecuting him .
He's a deepIy sensitive person .
-A darIing oId man . -Then you're innocent.
-Of course I'm innocent. -What are you going to do about it?
-What do you mean? -WeII , who's your Iawyer?
I don't know.
Mr O'Shaughnessy, I guess.
Mr O'Shaughnessy!
Hey! Get out of here !
-AII right, come on . -Okay, move.
-Come on , then . -Mr O'Shaughnessy?
-Shut up ! -Get in there.
-Yeah . -Mr Paul Varjak?
-Yeah . -Ready with Mr Berman in Hollywood.
Kindly deposit $3 for the first 3 minutes, please.
Hello?
O.J . Berman here. Who's caIIing?
-Mr Berman , this is PauI Varjak. -N ice to taIk to you , kid .
Varjak. V-A-R-J-A-K.
I'm a friend of HoIIy's. I met you at a party in New York.
-Who? -Paul. Paul Varjak.
V-A-R. . .
Mr Berman , this is Fred .
Oh , Fred baby, huh?
So you're calling about the kid, huh?
Everything's under controI . Just reIax.
I spoke to my Iawyer in New York.
I toId him to take care of everything , send me the biII
but to keep my name anonymous.
-What? -Unknown. l don't want any part of it.
-You hear me? -You sound Iike you're in a tunneI .
It's this executive phone I have.
-what? -Executive phone !
Fred baby, they onIy got her on $ 1 0, 000 baiI .
My Iawyer can get her out at 1 0: 00 this morning . I'II teII you what you do.
You bust into that dump she Iives in ,
coIIect aII her junk.
Go down to the jaiI . Get her out.
Take her straight over to a hoteI under a phoney name, right?
You wanna keep away from the reporters as much as possibIe.
Do you know what I mean? WiII you do that?
Sure, Mr Berman .
-I can't teII you how much I appreciate. . . -Forget it.
I owe her something .
Not that I owe her anything , I mean , if you reaIIy get right down to it,
but she's a crazy.
She's a phoney.
But she's a reaI phoney.
-Know what I mean , kid? -Yeah , I know what you mean .
-Thanks, Mr Berman . Thanks a Iot. -Right!
Why don't you behave?
Quel night.
I did a IittIe housebreaking whiIe you were away.
CIayton HoteI , driver. 84th and Madison .
O.J . thinks it'd be a good idea if you stayed out of sight for a whiIe.
I got most of your stuff here, incIuding cat. Hope he's aII right.
Yeah .
HeIIo, cat.
Poor no-name sIob.
Listen , darIing . Did you find that pIane ticket?
-Right here. We can cash it in . -Cash it in? Are you kidding?
What time is it?
-A IittIe after 1 0: 00. -Good .
IdIewiId Airport, pIease, driver.
-Never mind . You can't do that. -Why not?
You don't understand . You're under indictment.
If they catch you jumping baiI , they'II Iock you up and throw away the key.
Don't be ridicuIous, darIing .
By the day after tomorrow,
I'II be married to the future president of BraziI .
And that'II give me dipIomatic immunity or something .
I wouIdn't bet on it.
What is it, darIing?
Message for you .
Oh , yes, I see.
Did he bring it in person , or was it,
just there, shoved under the door?
A cousin .
Hand me my purse, wiII you , darIing?
A girI can't read that sort of thing without her Iipstick.
You read it to me, wiII you , darIing?
I don't think I can quite bear. . .
Sure you want me to?
Okay.
"My dearest IittIe girI ,
"I have Ioved you knowing you were not as others.
"But conceive of my despair
"upon discovering in such a brutaI and pubIic styIe
"how very different you are from the manner of woman
"a man of my position couId hope to make his wife.
"I grieve for the disgrace of your present circumstances.
"And I do not find it in my heart
"to add my condemn
"to the condemn that surrounds you .
"So I hope you wiII find it in your heart not to condemn me.
"I have my famiIy to protect and my name
"and I am a coward where these institutions enter.
"Forget me, beautifuI chiId . And may God be with you .
"José."
WeII?
WeII , at Ieast he's honest.
-It's kind of touching . -Touching?
That square-baII jazz.
He says he's a coward .
AII right. So he's not a reguIar rat or even a super-rat.
He's just a scared IittIe mouse, that's aII .
But, oh , goIIy.
Gee, damn .
WeII , so much for South America.
I didn't reaIIy think you were cut out to be queen of the Pampas, anyway.
-CIayton HoteI . -IdIewiId .
What?
The pIane Ieaves at 1 2: 00. And on it I pIan to be.
HoIIy, you can't.
I'm not hotfooting it after José, if that's what you think. Oh , no.
As far as I'm concerned , he's the future president of nowhere.
OnIy why shouId I waste a perfectIy good pIane ticket?
Besides, I've never been to BraziI .
PIease, darIing , don't sit there Iooking at me Iike that.
I'm going and that's aII there is to it.
Now aII they want from me
are my services as the state's witness against SaIIy.
Nobody has any intention of prosecuting me.
To begin with , they don't have a ghost of a chance.
Even so, this town's finished for me.
At Ieast for a whiIe.
There are certain shades of IimeIight that can wreck a girI's compIexion .
They'II have the rope up at every saIoon in town .
I'II teII you what you do for me, darIing .
When you get back to town ,
I want you to caII up the New York Times or whoever you caII .
I want you to maiI me a Iist of the 50 richest men in BraziI .
The 50 richest.
-HoIIy, I'm not going to Iet you do this. -You're not going to Iet me?
HoIIy, I'm in Iove with you .
-So what? -So what?
So pIenty.
-I Iove you . You beIong to me. -No.
-PeopIe don't beIong to peopIe. -Of course they do.
I'm not gonna Iet anyone put me in a cage.
I don't want to put you in a cage. I want to Iove you .
-It's the same thing . -No, it's not.
-HoIIy. . . -I'm not HoIIy.
I'm not LuIa Mae, either. I don't know who I am .
I'm Iike cat, here.
We're a coupIe of no-name sIobs. We beIong to nobody.
And nobody beIongs to us. We don't even beIong to each other.
Stop the cab.
What do you think?
This ought to be the right kind of pIace for a tough guy Iike you .
Garbage cans, rats gaIore.
Scram !
I said take off! Beat it!
Let's go.
Driver
puII over here.
You know what's wrong with you , Miss Whoever-you-are?
You're chicken . You've got no guts.
You're afraid to stick out your chin and say, "Okay, Iife's a fact."
PeopIe do faII in Iove.
PeopIe do beIong to each other
because that's the onIy chance anybody's got for reaI happiness.
You caII yourseIf a free spirit, a wiId thing .
And you're terrified somebody's going to stick you in a cage.
WeII , baby, you're aIready in that cage. You buiIt it yourseIf.
And it's not bounded in the west by TuIip, Texas
or in the east by SomaIiIand .
It's wherever you go.
Because no matter where you run , you just end up running into yourseIf.
Here. I've been carrying this thing around for months.
I don't want it any more.
Here, cat!
Cat!
Where's the cat?
I don't know.
Cat!
Cat.