Mathematicians won the war.
Mathematicians broke
the Japanese codes
and buiIt the A-bomb.
Mathematicians, like you.
The stated goal of the Soviets
is global Communism.
In medicine or economics,
in technology or space
battle lines
are being drawn.
To triumph,
we need resuIts,
publishable,
applicable resuIts.
Now who among you
will be the next Morse?
The next Einstein?
Who among you
will be the vanguard
of democracy,
freedom, and discovery?
Today,
we bequeath America's future
into your able hands.
Welcome to Princeton,
gentlemen.
NEILSON: It's not enough
Hansen won the
Carnegie Scholarship.
BENDER: No, he has to
have it all for himself.
It's the first time the
Carnegie Prize has been split.
Hansen's all bent.
NElLSON: He's got his
sights set on Wheeler Lab,
the new military
think-tank at MlT.
BENDER: They're only
taking one this year.
Hansen's used to
being picked first.
Yeah,
he's wasted on math.
He should be running
for president.
There could be
a mathematical explanation
for how bad your tie is.
(LAUGHlNG)
Thank you.
Neilson,
symbol cryptography.
Neils here broke a Jap code.
Helped rid the world
of Fascism.
At least that's what
he tells the girls,
eh, Neils?
The name's Bender.
Atomic physics.
And you are?
Am l late?
Yes, Mr. Sol.
Good. Hi.
Sol. Richard Sol.
HANSEN: Ah,
the burden of genius.
SOL: There he is.
So many supplicants,
and so little time.
Mr. Sol.
How are you, sir?
Bender.
Nice to see you.
NElLSON: Congratulations,
Mr. Hansen.
HANSEN: Thank you.
I'll take another.
Excuse me?
A thousand pardons.
l simply assumed
you were the waiter.
Play nice, Hansen.
Nice is not
Hansen's strong suit.
HANSEN: An honest mistake.
Well, Martin Hansen.
It is Martin, isn't it?
Why, yes, John, it is.
l imagine you're getting
quite used to miscalculation.
I've read your preprints,
both of them.
The one on Nazi ciphers
and the other one on
nonlinear equations.
And I am supremely confident
that there is not
a single seminal
or innovative idea
in either one of them.
Enjoy your punch.
(ALL CHUCKLE)
Gentlemen, meet John Nash,
the mysterious
West Virginia genius.
The other winner
of the distinguished
Carnegie Scholarship.
BENDER: Oh, okay.
SOL: Oh, yeah?
BENDER: Of course.
(CORAL MUSlC PLAYlNG)
CHARLES: (COUGHS)
Oh, Christ.
The prodigal roommate arrives.
Roommate?
Oh, God, no.
(MUSlC STOPS)
Did you know that
having a hangover
is not having enough
water in your body
to run your Krebs cycle?
Which is exactly
what happens to you
when you're dying of thirst.
So, dying of thirst
would probably feel
pretty much like
the hangover that
finally bloody kills you.
John Nash?
Hello.
Charles Herman.
Pleased to meet you.
MAN: All right! Well done!
CHARLES: Well, it's official.
I'm almost human again.
Officer,
I saw the driver who hit me.
His name was Johnnie Walker.
(MlMlCS DRUM ROLL)
Well, I got in
last night in time
for English
department cocktails.
Cock was mine,
the tail belonged to
a particularly lovely
young thing with a passion
for D. H. Lawrence.
You're not easily
distracted, are you?
I'm here to work.
Are you? Right.
I see. Crikey!
ls my roommate a dick?
Hmm?
Listen. lf we can't
break the ice,
how about we drown it?
So what's your story?
You the poor kid
that never got to go
to Exeter or Andover?
Despite my privileged
upbringing, I'm actually
quite well-balanced.
I have a chip on
both shoulders.
(CHUCKLES)
Maybe you're just better
with the old integers
than you are with people.
My first grade teacher,
she told me
that I was born with
two helpings of brain
but only half
a helping of heart.
(CHUCKLES)
Wow!
She sounds lovely!
The truth is that
I don't like people much.
And they don't
much like me.
But why, with all your
obvious wit and charm?
(LAUGHS)
Seriously, John.
Mathematics.
Mathematics is
never going to lead you
to a higher truth.
And you know why?
Because it's boring.
It's really boring.
You know,
half these schoolboys
are already published?
I cannot waste time
with these classes
and these books.
(COUGHS)
Memorizing
the weak assumptions of
lesser mortals!
(STUDENTS CHUCKLlNG)
l need to look through
to the governing dynamics.
Find a truly original idea.
That's the only way
I'll ever distinguish myself.
It's the only way
that I'll ever. . .
Matter.
Yes.
HANSEN: All right,
who's next?
I've played enough Go
for one day.
Come on.
l hate this game.
Cowards, all of you !
None of you rise to
meet my challenge?
Come on, Bender.
Whoever wins, Sol does
his laundry all semester.
Does that seem unfair
to anyone else?
Not at all.
SOL: Look at him.
Nash !
Taking a reverse
constitutional?
I'm hoping to
extract an algorithm
to define their movement.
Oh.
Psycho.
Nash, I thought
you dropped out.
You ever going to
go to class or. . .
Classes will
dull your mind.
Destroy the potential
for authentic creativity.
Oh, l didn't know that.
Nash is going to stun
us all with his genius.
Which is another way of
saying he doesn't have
the nerve to compete.
You scared?
Terrified.
Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied by you.
No starch.
Pressed and folded.
Let me ask you
something, John.
Be my guest, Martin.
Bender and Sol here
correctly completed
Allen's proof of
Perron's conjecture.
Adequate work
without innovation.
Oh, I'm flattered.
You flattered?
Flattered.
And I've got
two weapons briefs
under security review
by the DoD.
Derivative drivel.
But Nash achievements,
zero.
I'm a patient man, Martin.
ls there an actual
question coming?
What if you never come up
with your original idea, huh?
How will it feel when
I'm chosen for Wheeler
and you're not?
(CHUCKLES)
What if you lose?
You should not have won.
I had the first move,
my play was perfect.
The hubris of the defeated.
The game is flawed.
SOL: Oh !
Gentlemen,
the great John Nash.
CHARLES: You've been
in here for two days.
You know Hansen
has just published
another paper?
I can't even find
a topic for my doctorate.
Well, on the bright side,
you've invented window art.
This is a group
playing touch football.
This is a cluster of pigeons
fighting over breadcrumbs.
And this here is a woman
who is chasing a man
who stole her purse.
John, you watched a mugging.
That's weird.
In competitive behavior,
someone always loses.
Well,
my niece knows that, John,
and she's about this high.
See, if l could
derive an equilibrium
where prevalence is
a non-singular event,
where nobody loses.
Can you imagine the effect
that that would have
on conflict scenarios. . .
When did you last eat?
Currency exchange?
You know, food.
You have no respect
for cognitive reverie,
you know that?
Yes. But pizza. . .
(CHUCKLES)
Now, pizza I have
enormous respect for.
And, of course, beer.
I have respect for beer.
I have respect for beer!
(PEOPLE LAUGHlNG)
BENDER: Good evening,
Neils. Ladies.
HANSEN: Hey, Nash.
Who's winning? You or you?
BENDER: Good evening, Nash.
SOL: Hey, guys. Hey, Nash.
WOMAN: He's looking
at you for sure.
(MOUTHS) Me?
(MOUTHS) Nash.
Hey, Nash.
Neils is trying to
get your attention.
BENDER: You're joking.
SOL: (CHUCKLES) Oh, no.
Go with God.
Come back a man.
Fortune favors the brave.
Bombs away.
Gentlemen,
might I remind you
that my odds of success
dramatically improve
with each attempt?
This is going
to be classic.
Maybe you want to
buy me a drink.
I don't exactly know
what I'm required to say
in order for you to
have intercourse with me,
but could we assume
that I've said all that?
Essentially,
we're talking about
fluid exchange, right?
So, could we just go
straight to the sex?
That was sweet.
Have a nice night, asshole!
NElLSON: Ladies, wait!
(MAN LAUGHlNG)
l especially liked the bit
about fluid exchange.
It was really charming.
HELlNGER: Walk with me, John.
I've been meaning
to talk with you.
The facuIty is completing
mid-year reviews.
We're deciding which
placement applications
to support.
Wheeler, sir.
That would be
my first choice.
And, actually,
I don't really have
a second choice, sir.
John, your fellows
have attended classes.
They've written papers.
They've published.
Oh, I'm still searching,
sir, for my. . .
Your original idea.
Governing dynamics, sir.
It's very clever,
John, but I'm afraid
it's just not
nearly good enough.
May l?
Thank you.
I've been working on
manifold embedding.
My bargaining stratagems
are starting to
show some promise.
lf you could just
arrange another meeting,
if you would be kind enough,
with Professor Einstein.
I've repeatedly
asked you for that, sir.
Now, John. . .
l'd be able to show him
my revisions on his. . .
John.
Do you see what
they're doing in there?
Congratulations, Professor.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
It's the pens.
Reserved for a member of
the department that makes
the achievement of a lifetime.
Now what do you see, John?
Recognition.
Well done, Professor.
Well done.
Well,
try seeing accomplishment.
ls there a difference?
John, you haven't focused.
I'm sorry,
but up to this point,
your record doesn't warrant
any placement at all.
Good day.
And my compliments
to you, sir.
Thank you so much.
I can't see it.
(EXCLAlMS lN PAlN)
Jesus Christ, John.
I can't fail.
This is all I am.
Come on, let's go out.
I have to get
something done.
I can't keep
staring into space.
John, that's enough !
Got to face the wall,
follow their rules,
read their books,
do their classes.
You wanna do some damage,
that's fine,
but don't mess around.
Come on !
Go on, bust your head !
Kill yourself.
John, do it.
Don't mess around.
Bust your head !
Go on, bust that
worthless head wide open.
Goddamn it, Charles!
What the hell is
your problem?
It's not my problem.
And it's not your problem.
It's their problem.
Your answer isn't,
"Face the wall."
It's out there,
where you've been working.
(JOHN GASPS)
(PANTlNG) That was heavy.
That lsaac Newton
fellow was right.
He was onto something.
(LAUGHlNG)
Clever boy.
Don't worry, that's mine.
I'll come and get it
in a minute.
(BOTH LAUGHlNG)
Oh, God !
NElLSON: Incoming, gentlemen.
(SOL EXCLAlMlNG)
Deep breaths.
SOL: Nash, you might want
to stop shuffling your
papers for five seconds.
I will not buy
you gentlemen beer.
HANSEN: We're not here
for beer, my friend.
JOHN: Oh.
Does anyone else feel
she should be moving
in slow motion?
Will she want
a large wedding,
you think?
Shall we say swords?
Pistols at dawn?
Have you remembered nothing?
Recall
the lessons of Adam Smith,
the father of
modern economics.
ALL: "In competition,
individuaI ambition
serves the common good."
Exactly!
Every man for himself,
gentlemen.
BENDER: Those who strike out
are stuck with her friends.
HANSEN: I'm not
going to strike out.
SOL: You can lead
a blonde to water,
but you can't make her drink.
All right, nobody move.
She's looking over here.
She's looking at Nash.
HANSEN: Oh, God.
All right, he may have
the upper hand now,
but wait until he
opens his mouth.
(ALL LAUGHlNG)
Remember the last time?
BENDER: Oh, yes.
That was one
for the history books.
Adam Smith needs revision.
What are you
talking about?
lf we all go
for the blonde,
we block each other.
Not a single one of us
is going to get her.
So then we go
for her friends,
but they will all
give us the cold shoulder
because nobody likes
to be second choice.
Well, what if no one
goes for the blonde?
We don't get in
each other's way
and we don't insuIt
the other girls.
That's the only way we win.
That's the only way
we all get laid.
(CHUCKLES)
Adam Smith said,
"The best resuIt comes
"from everyone in the group
doing what's best
for himself."
Right? That's what
he said. That's right.
Incomplete. Incomplete, okay?
Because the best resuIt
will come from everyone
in the group
doing what's best for
himself and the group.
Nash, if this is
some way for you to get
the blonde on your own,
you can go to hell.
Governing dynamics, gentlemen.
Governing dynamics.
Adam Smith was wrong.
Here we go.
Careful, careful.
Thank you.
"C" of "S" equals "C" of "T."
(MUTTERlNG)
(CONTlNUES MUTTERlNG)
You do realize
this flies in the face
of 1 50 years of
economic theory?
Yes, I do, sir.
That's rather presumptuous,
don't you think?
It is, sir.
Well, Mr. Nash,
with a breakthrough
of this magnitude,
I'm confident you will get
any placement you like.
Wheeler Labs,
they'll ask you to
recommend two team members.
Stills and Frank
are excellent choices.
Sol and Bender, sir.
Sol and Bender are
extraordinary mathematicians.
Has it occurred to you,
Mr. Nash,
that Sol and Bender might
have plans of their own?
(BENDER AND SOL LAUGHlNG)
We made it!
Wheeler, we made it!
Cheers, cheers, cheers!
Oh ! Oh !
Okay,
awkward moment, gentlemen.
Governing dynamics.
Congratulations, John.
NElLSON: Toast!
To Wheeler Labs!
To Wheeler!
MAN: General, the analyst
from Wheeler Lab is here.
Dr. Nash, your coat?
Thank you, sir.
ROGERS: Doctor.
General, this is
Wheeler team leader,
Dr. John Nash.
Glad you could come, Doctor.
Hello.
Right this way.
We've been intercepting
radio transmissions
from Moscow.
GENERAL: The computer can't
detect a pattern,
but I'm sure it's code.
Why is that, General?
Ever just know
something, Dr. Nash?
Constantly.
GENERAL: We've developed
several ciphers.
lf you'd like to review
our preliminary data?
Doctor?
JOHN: 6-7-3-7. 0-3-6...
8-4-9-4.
9-1-4-0-3-4.
(CONTlNUES
MENTAL CALCULATlONS)
0-3-4.
l need a map.
46-1 3-08, 67-46-90.
Starkey Corners, Maine.
48-03-01 . 91 -26-35.
Prairie Portage, Minnesota.
These are latitudes
and longitudes.
There are at least
10 others.
They appear to be
routing orders across
the border into the US.
Extraordinary.
Gentlemen,
we need to move on this.
Who's Big Brother?
You've done your country
a great service, son.
Captain !
Yes, sir.
Accompany Dr. Nash.
What are the Russians
moving, General?
Captain Rogers
will escort you to the
unrestricted area, Doctor.
Thank you.
ROGERS: Dr. Nash,
follow me, please.
MAN ON RADlO: None of
those who have said
they don't like the method
have told us any other
method they could use
that would be effective.
DRlVER: It's Dr. Nash.
GUARD: All right.
MAN: Thank you, sir.
Home run at
the Pentagon, huh?
Have they actually taken
the word "classified"
out of the dictionary?
Hi. The air conditioning
broke again.
How am l supposed to be
in here saving the world
if I'm meIting?
Our hearts go
out to you, John.
You know,
two trips to the Pentagon
in four years.
That's two more
than we've had.
It gets better, John.
Just got our latest
scintillating assignment.
You know, the Russians
have the H-bomb,
the Nazis are
repatriating South America,
the Chinese have
a standing army
of 2.8 million,
and I am doing
stress tests on a dam.
Look, you made the cover
of Fortune again.
Please note the use of
the word "you," not "we."
That was supposed
to be just me.
(CHUCKLES)
Not only do they rob me
of the Fields Medal,
now they put me on the cover
of Fortune magazine
with these hacks,
these scholars of trivia.
John, exactly what
is the difference
between genius
and most genius?
Quite a lot.
He's your son.
Anyway,
you've got 1 0 minutes.
I've always got 1 0 minutes.
BENDER: Before your new class?
Can l not get a note
from a doctor or something?
You are a doctor, John,
and no.
Come on. You know the drill,
we get these
beautiful facilities. . .
MlT gets America's
great minds of today
teaching America's
great minds of tomorrow.
Poor bastards.
Now, have a nice day
at school.
The bell is ringing.
The eager young minds
of tomorrow.
(LOUD JACKHAMMERlNG)
Can we leave
one open, Professor?
It's really hot, sir.
Your comfort comes
second to my ability
to hear my own voice.
Personally,
I think this class will be
a waste of your,
and what is
infinitely worse,
my time.
However, here we are.
So, you may attend or not.
You may complete
your assignments
at your whim.
We have begun.
Miss.
Excuse me!
Hey, hey!
Hi !
We have a little problem.
It's extremely hot in here
with the windows closed
and extremely noisy
with them open.
So I was wondering
if there was
any way you could,
I don't know,
maybe work someplace else
for about 45 minutes?
FOREMAN: Not a problem.
Thank you so much !
FOREMAN: Break!
WORKER: Got it!
FOREMAN: Let's go.
Clean it up a little bit.
As you will find in
muItivariable calculus,
there is often
a number of solutions
for any given problem.
As I was saying,
this problem here
will take some of you
many months to solve.
For others among you,
it will take you the term
of your natural lives.
PARCHER: Professor Nash.
William Parcher.
Big Brother,
at your service.
What can I do for the
Department of Defense?
Are you here to
give me a raise?
Let's take a walk.
lmpressive work
at the Pentagon.
Yes, it was.
Oppenheimer used to say,
"Genius sees the answer
before the question."
You knew Oppenheimer?
His project was
under my supervision.
Which project?
That project.
It's not that simple,
you know?
Well, you ended the war.
We incinerated 1 50,000
people in a heartbeat.
Great deeds come at
great cost, Mr. Parcher.
Conviction, it turns out,
is a luxury of those
on the sidelines, Mr. Nash.
I'll try and
keep that in mind.
So, John, no family,
no close friends.
Why is that?
l like to think it's
because I'm a lone wolf.
But mainly it's because
people don't like me.
Well, there are
certain endeavors
where your lack of
personal connection
would be considered
an advantage.
This is a secure area.
PARCHER: They know me.
Have you ever been here?
We were told during
our initial briefing
that these warehouses
were abandoned.
That's not
precisely accurate.
(LOUD RADlO CHATTER)
(MAN SPEAKlNG RUSSlAN
ON RADlO)
PARCHER: By telling you what
I'm about to tell you,
I am increasing
your security clearance
to top secret.
Disclosure of
secure information can
resuIt in imprisonment.
Get it?
What operation?
Those are a good idea.
This factory is in Berlin.
We seized it at
the end of the war.
Nazi engineers were
attempting to build
a portable atomic bomb.
The Soviets
reached this facility
before we did,
and we lost the damn thing.
The routing orders
at the Pentagon.
They were about this,
weren't they?
The Soviets aren't as
unified as people believe.
A faction of the Red Army
calling itself Novaya Svoboda,
the "New Freedom,"
has control of the bomb
and intends to
detonate it on U.S. soil.
Their plan is to incur
maximum civilian casuaIties.
Man is capable of
as much atrocity
as he has imagination.
New Freedom
has sleeper agents
here in the U.S.
McCarthy is an idiot,
but, unfortunately,
that doesn't make him wrong.
New Freedom
communicates to its agents
through codes imbedded in
newspapers and magazines,
and that's where
you come in.
You see, John,
what distinguishes you
is that you are,
quite simply,
the best natural code-breaker
I have ever seen.
What exactly is it
that you would like me to do?
Commit this list of
periodicals to memory.
Scan each new issue,
find any hidden codes,
decipher them.
DOCTOR: Place your chin
on the chin rest.
Stare into the light.
TECHNlClAN: Pulse 88, regular.
Okay, this may be
a little uncomfortable.
(GROANS)
PARCHER: It's got a little zap
to it, doesn't it?
He just implanted
a radium diode.
Don't worry, it's safe.
The isotope
decays predictably.
As a resuIt,
these numbers change
over time.
They're the access codes
to your drop spot.
So what am l now, a spy?
(KNOCKlNG ON DOOR)
Come.
Boy, you must be
really important.
It's all right, Mike.
What are you working on?
Classified.
Everyone waited
half an hour.
For?
Class.
You missed class today.
Well, I suspect that
nobody missed me.
The problem that you
left on the board. . .
I solved it.
No, you didn't.
You didn't even look.
I never said that
the vector fields
were rational functions.
Your solution is elegant.
Though on this
particular occasion
uItimately incorrect.
You're still here.
I'm still here.
Why?
I'm wondering,
Professor Nash,
if I can ask you
to dinner.
You do eat, don't you?
On occasion, yeah.
Table for one.
Prometheus alone,
chained to the rock
with the bird
circling overhead,
you know how it is.
(CHUCKLES)
No, l expect that
you wouldn't know.
Leave your address
with my office.
I'll pick you up Friday
at 8:00 and we'll eat.
One more thing.
Do you have a name,
or should I just
keep calling you "miss"?
Governor,
may l present. . .
Miss Alicia Larde.
Professor, please.
You and the governor.
Wait, one second.
I'm sorry.
I want a copy of this.
First big date
and all, you know.
So, you boys
need to look good,
which is not a state
you find yourselves in
aItogether naturally.
There. Better.
I'm surprising him.
You just keep on
surprising him. Professor.
God must be a painter.
Why else would we
have so many colors?
So you're a painter?
That's not actually
what I said,
but, yes, I am.
Here.
Me. Your date.
Practice human interaction
and social comportment.
(LAUGHlNG)
That's a plan.
Champagne would be lovely.
I'll be outside.
I will get the champagne.
ALlClA: Oh, thank you.
Thank you for that.
No, keep it.
I believe in deciding
things will be good luck.
Do you?
No.
I don't believe in luck.
(SNlFFS)
But I do believe in
assigning value to things.
Oh.
l once tried to
count them all.
l actually made it
to 4,348.
You are exceptionally odd.
l bet you're very
popular with the girls.
A pair of odd ducks, then.
Mmm.
Pick a shape.
What?
Pick a shape,
an animal, anything.
Okay.
An umbrella.
Do it again.
All right.
What would you like?
Do an octopus.
(DOG BARKS)
(CHUCKLES)
You don't talk much,
do you?
I can't talk to you
about my work, Alicia.
I don't mean work.
l find that
polishing my interactions
in order to make them sociable
requires a tremendous effort.
I have a tendency to
expedite information flow
by being direct.
l often don't get
a pleasant resuIt.
Try me.
All right.
l find you attractive.
Your aggressive
moves towards me
indicate that you
feel the same way.
But still,
ritual requires that
we continue with a number
of platonic activities
before we have sex.
I am proceeding
with those activities,
but in point of
actual fact,
all I really want to do is
have intercourse with you
as soon as possible.
Are you going to
slap me now?
How was that resuIt?
MARCEE: What are you doing?
I'm attempting to isolate
patterned reoccurrences
within periodicals
over time. And you?
You talk funny, Mr. Nash.
Do l know you?
My uncle says
you're very smart
but not very nice,
so l shouldn't pay no mind
if you're mean to me.
And who might
your uncle be?
CHARLES: The prodigal roommate
returns.
Come here!
Charles, Charles.
My sister got herself
killed in a car crash.
Not too far now, Marcee!
Her cowboy husband
was too drunk
to know that he was
too drunk to drive.
So, l took her in.
She's so small.
Well, she's young, John.
That's how they come.
I'm at Harvard
doing the great
author's workshop.
D. H. bloody Lawrence.
I really do think
you should buy
yourself a new book.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, I've been reading
a lot about you.
How are you, John?
At first, all my work
here was trivial,
but a new assignment
came up and. . .
I can't really
tell you any details.
Top secret?
Black bag? Black ops?
Something like that.
And. . .
Yes?
Well, l met a girl.
No! A human girl?
Homo sapien.
A biped?
Yep. And contrary
to all probabilities,
she finds me attractive
on a number of
different levels.
God, that's wonderful.
Well, there's no
accounting for taste,
is there?
Should l marry her?
God. Right.
I mean,
everything's going well.
The job is fine.
I have enough money.
It alI seems to add up.
But how do you know
for sure?
Nothing's ever
for sure, John.
That's the only
sure thing I do know.
WAlTER: Good evening.
Alicia, please don't be angry.
I just lost track
of time at work,
again.
Mmm-hmm.
I'm sorry.
l didn't have time
to wrap it.
Happy birthday.
The refractive faces
of the glass, you see,
they create a full
wavelength dispersal,
so if you look inside it,
you can see. . .
ALlClA: Every
possible color.
Every possible color.
Yeah.
Remember you said that time,
"God must be a painter
because of all the colors"?
At the governor's house,
you said that.
l didn't think
you were listening.
I was listening.
It's beautiful.
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
Alicia, does our
relationship warrant
long-term commitment?
Because l need
some kind of proof,
some kind of verifiable,
empirical data.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
I'm sorry,
just give me a moment
to redefine my
girlish notions of romance.
A proof?
Verifiable data.
Okay.
Well, how big
is the universe?
Infinite.
How do you know?
l know because
all the data indicates
it's infinite.
But it hasn't
been proven yet?
No.
You haven't seen it.
How do you know for sure?
I don't,
I just believe it.
Mmm.
It's the same with love,
I guess.
Now, the part that
you don't know
is if I want to
marry you.
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(PEOPLE APPLAUDlNG)
Smile for the camera!
Well done!
Congratulations.
You look beautiful.
Hi,
how are you?
WOMAN 1 : Bye-bye.
MAN: Bye, now.
WOMAN 2: Bye!
WOMAN 3: Bye!
WOMAN 4: Be safe!
Get in. Hurry.
They're following us.
Who is. . .
Who is following us?
The drop has been
compromised.
Get down !
Stay down.
(HORNS HONKlNG)
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)
(GUNFlRE)
Here, take this.
I ain't shooting anybody.
Take the goddamn gun !
No!
(SCREAMS)
PARCHER: You stay back.
Don't move.
(SCREAMS)
(GROANS)
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)
ALlClA: John?
Hi.
Where were you?
Sol. . .
Yeah, l talked to Sol.
He said you left
the office hours ago.
Why didn't you call me?
Are you all right?
Honey?
(BOLT LOCKS)
John.
Please, talk to me.
Tell me what happened.
John, open the door.
(POUNDlNG ON DOOR)
Come on, open the door!
Let me in !
Talk to me!
John !
Open this door!
(PANTlNG)
WOMAN: Watch for cars, kids.
(DOOR SLAMS)
What was that?
PARCHER: John.
William.
This is not what
I signed up for.
Every time a car backfires
or a door slams. . .
l understand
better than you could
possibly imagine.
You need to
calm down, John.
Now listen to me.
We're closing in
on the bomb,
in large part
due to your work.
Now don't you think
your fear is a small price
to pay?
William,
my circumstance has changed.
Alicia's pregnant.
I told you
attachments were dangerous.
You chose to
marry the girl.
l did nothing
to prevent it.
The best way to
ensure everybody's safety
is for you to
continue your work.
Well, I'lI just quit.
You won't.
Why would l not?
Because l keep
the Russians from knowing
you work for us.
You quit working for me,
l quit working for you.
Parcher! Parcher!
John, you all right?
John?
Turn it off!
Turn off the light!
Why would you do that?
Why would you
turn the light on?
What is wrong with you?
You have to go
to your sister's.
l left the car
at the back.
Now you can
take CommonweaIth,
no side streets.
John. . .
Stay where it's crowded.
John,
I'm not going anywhere!
When you get to
your sister's, you wait
for me to call.
No, I'm not going.
Just get your things.
I'm not leaving !
Stop! Stop it.
Please, Alicia.
I'll explain when I can.
MARCEE: Uncle John !
Uncle John !
(ROARS)
Hey, baby girl !
(GlGGLlNG)
Wow,
someone needed a hug.
I saw you on the slate,
and I thought to myself,
"How can l miss seeing
a guest lecture by the
inimitable John Nash?"
What's wrong?
I got myself into something.
I think l might need
some help.
Well, now you tell me,
what is it?
WOMAN: Professor Nash !
Welcome!
After?
So, we see that the zeroes
of the Riemann zeta function
correspond to singularities
in space-time.
Singularities in
space-time then. . .
And conventional
number theory. . .
It breaks down
in the face of
relativistic exploration.
Sometimes our expectations
are betrayed by the numbers.
Variables are impossible
to assign any rational value.
(ALL MURMURlNG)
Professor Nash !
Hold it!
Professor Nash?
Professor Nash,
let's avoid a scene,
shall we?
What do you want?
My name is Rosen.
Dr. Rosen.
I'm a psychiatrist.
Forgive me if l
don't seem persuaded.
l'd like you to
come with me, John.
Just for a chat.
It appears
I have no choice.
(GROANS)
Help me! Somebody!
(SCREAMS)
Somebody! Help me!
Get off me!
l know who you are!
No, no, no, don't!
JOHN: Charles!
Charles, they're Russians!
Call somebody!
Call somebody, Charles!
They're Russians!
Steady the leg.
Get away from me.
Stay away from me!
ROSEN: There, now.
All better.
Everything's all right here.
Watch your head.
ROSEN: (FAlNTLY)
John? John?
Can you hear me?
(RADlATOR CLANGlNG)
Go easy now.
Thorazine takes
a little while to wear off.
Sorry about the restraints.
But you've got one
hell of a right hook.
(WEAKLY) Where am l?
(CLEARlNG THROAT)
MacArthur
Psychiatric Hospital.
l find that
highly unlikely.
You made a mistake.
My work is non-military
in application.
Which work is that,
John?
I don't know anything.
There's no good
in keeping secrets,
you know.
(GROANS)
(BUZZER SOUNDlNG)
Charles?
l didn't mean to get
you involved in this.
I'm. . . I'm sorry.
Charles?
The prodigal
roommate revealed.
"Saw my name on
the lecture slate"?
You lying son of a bitch !
Who are you talking to?
Tell me who you see.
How do you say
"Charles Herman"
in Russian?
How do you say it
ROSEN: There's
no one there, John.
There's no one there.
He's right there.
Stop! I don't know anything !
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held
against my will.
Somebody call the
Department of Defense.
My name is John Nash.
I'm being held
against my will !
ALlClA: What's wrong
with him?
John has schizophrenia.
People with this disorder
are often paranoid.
But. . . But his work.
He deals with conspiracy.
So. . .
Yes. Yes, l know.
In John's world,
these behaviors are
accepted, encouraged.
As such,
his ilIness may
have gone untreated
far longer than is typical.
What do you mean?
How long?
Possibly since
graduate school.
At least that's
when his hallucinations
seem to have begun.
What are you talking about?
What hallucinations?
One, so far,
that I am aware of.
An imaginary roommate
named Charles Herman.
Charles isn't imaginary.
He and John have
been best friends
since Princeton.
Have you ever met Charles?
Has he ever come to dinner?
He's always in town
for so little time,
lecturing.
Was he at your wedding?
He had to teach.
Have you seen
a picture of him,
or talked to him
on the telephone?
This is ridiculous.
l phoned Princeton.
According to
their housing records,
John lived alone.
Now, which is more likely?
That your husband,
a mathematician with
no military training,
is a government spy
fleeing the Russians. . .
You're making him
sound crazy.
Or, that he has lost
his grip on reality?
Now, the only way
I can help him is to
show him the difference
between what is real
and what is in his mind.
Come on.
What's he been
working on?
His work is classified.
He mentioned
a supervisor by the name
of William Parcher.
Maybe Mr. Parcher can
clarify things for us.
But I can't get to
him without clearances.
You want me to help
you get the details
of my husband's work?
John thinks I'm a Russian spy.
ls that what you think?
What did the doctor say?
ls he sick?
I don't know.
I want to see what
John's been working on.
Alicia, you know,
you can't go in his office.
You know, it's classified,
Alicia. Stop.
Oh, my God.
Why didn't you
say something?
Alicia, I mean,
John has always
been a little weird.
He said he was
doing code-breaking.
That it was eyes-only.
Top-secret, part of
the military effort.
Was he?
Well,
it was possible,
you know?
I mean, directives
come down all the time
that some of us
aren't cleared for.
It was possible.
Possible, but not likely.
Lately, he'd become
so much more agitated,
and then when you called. . .
So, is this all he's
been doing every day?
Cutting up magazines?
Well, not all.
(SOBS) I'm so sorry.
It's okay.
l missed you.
I have to talk to you.
Okay.
Alicia, I've been
thinking about it,
and I do realize
that my behavior
and my inability to discuss
the situation with you
must have appeared insane.
l left you with
no other choice.
l do understand,
and I'm truly sorry.
That's okay.
Everything is
gonna be all right.
(WHlSPERS) We just have to
talk quietly.
They may be listening.
There may be microphones.
I'm gonna tell
you everything now.
It's breaking with protocol,
but you need to know
because you have to
help me get out of here.
Alicia, I've been
doing top-secret work
for the government.
There's a threat that exists
of catastrophic proportions.
I think the Russians feel
my profile is too high.
That's why they simply
just don't do away with me.
They're keeping me here
to try to stop me
from doing my work.
You have to get to Wheeler.
Stop.
You have to find
William Parcher.
Stop.
He could help us.
Stop. Stop.
He could help us. . .
Stop!
l went to Wheeler.
Good, good.
There is no William Parcher.
Of course there is.
I've been working for him.
Doing what?
Breaking codes?
Dropping packages
in a secret mailbox for the
government to pick up?
How could you know that?
Sol followed you.
He thought
it was harmless.
Sol followed me?
They've never been opened.
It isn't real.
There is no conspiracy, John.
There is no William Parcher.
It's in your mind.
Do you understand, baby?
You're sick.
You're sick, John.
John?
Code red.
Dr. Rosen, code red.
Observation Room 2.
John?
The implant is gone.
I can't find it.
It's gone.
ROSEN: You see,
the nightmare of schizophrenia
is not knowing what's true.
lmagine if you had
suddenly learned that
the people and the places
and the moments
most important to you
were not gone, not dead,
but worse, had never been.
What kind of hell
would that be?
FEMALE NURSE:
Administering insulin.
MALE NURSE: 8:42 a.m.
How often?
Five times a week
for 1 0 weeks.
ALlClA: John always
spoke so fondly of
being here at Princeton.
And Hansen is running
the department now.
So he keeps reminding us,
and reminding us. (CHUCKLES)
Yeah.
John won't come near
the campus, though.
I think he's ashamed.
(BABY CRlES)
Hey, hey.
Want this?
So, Alicia,
how are you holding up?
Well,
delusions have passed.
They're saying
with the medication and
low stress environment. . .
No. . .
I mean, how are you?
I think often what l feel
is obligation.
Or guiIt over
wanting to leave.
Rage against John,
against God, and. . .
But. . .
Then l look at him,
and l force myself to see
the man that l married.
And he becomes that man.
He's transformed into
someone that l love.
And I'm transformed into
someone who loves him.
It's not
all the time, but
it's enough.
I think John is
a very lucky man, Alicia.
So unlucky.
ALlClA: This is us.
This is it?
It's nice.
It's near
where l work.
John? You have a visitor.
(CLASSlCAL MUSlC PLAYlNG
ON RADlO)
Hi.
l hope it's okay.
(JOHN TURNS OFF RADlO)
Hey, chief.
Cigarette?
No, thanks.
l quit, actually.
Hello.
Hey, John.
Have you met Harvey?
(STAMMERS lN EMBARRASSMENT)
John, there's no. . .
Relax, it's okay.
There's no point in
being nuts if you can't
have a little fun.
(LAUGHS NERVOUSLY)
Jesus Christ, John.
You know, l should have known.
Here you go.
I can take those later.
You're supposed
to take them now.
Can l bring you something?
I'm okay.
Okay.
So, yeah, I was in
town giving a workshop.
l go back tonight.
You know, Bender,
he really wanted to stop by
and, you know, see you.
You know, say hi.
Squeamish?
Yeah.
l suppose I would be, too.
But, alas,
I'm stuck with me.
I'm trying to solve
the Riemann hypothesis.
Uh-huh.
Yeah?
I figured if I dazzle them
they wilI have
to reinstate me.
But it's difficuIt
with the medication
because it's hard to
see the solution.
You know, John,
you should go easy.
There are other things
besides work.
What are they?
(BABY CRYlNG)
(SHUSHlNG)
(DOOR CLOSES)
What are you thinking about?
What do people do?
It's life, John.
Activities available.
Just add meaning.
You could try
leaving the house.
You know,
maybe talk to people.
You could try
taking out the garbage.
(JOHN CHATTERlNG lNDlSTlNCTLY)
And there's some more. . .
There's some more in. . .
Who. . .
Who were you talking to?
Garbage man.
Garbage men
don't come at night.
I guess around here
they do.
(MAN WHlSTLES)
(TRUCK APPROACHlNG)
(CHUCKLES)
Sorry.
(SlGHS)
ALlClA: ls it the medication?
(DOOR CLOSES)
(SCREAMlNG)
(SOBBlNG)
I don't know what to do.
(SOBBlNG CONTlNUES)
My mother's going
to keep the baby
a little longer tonight.
I can get three
hours of overtime.
(SlGHS)
(CLASSlCAL MUSlC PLAYlNG
ON RADlO)
I'm going to bed.
Good night.
(CLATTERlNG)
(GASPS)
(TWlG SNAPPlNG)
(GUNS COCKlNG)
PARCHER: It's good to
see you, John.
It's been a while.
Parcher?
Yes, sir.
You're not real !
Of course I am.
Don't be ridiculous.
(GUNS COCKlNG)
I don't think that
I would go that way, John.
It's time for you
to get back to work.
The bomb is in
its final position
here in the U.S.
Knowing your
situation requires
you keep a low profile,
Mohammed,
we've brought
the mountain to you.
(GENERATOR WHlRRlNG)
(FAlNT RADlO FEEDBACK)
We've narrowed
the bomb's location
to somewhere on
the eastern seaboard,
but we haven't been able to
pinpoint its exact position.
(MAN SPEAKlNG RUSSlAN
ON RADlO)
Their codes have grown
increasingly complex.
(BEEPlNG)
Look at this, John.
What? What?
Dr. Rosen said. . .
Rosen ! That quack!
"Schizophrenic break
from reality," right?
Psychological bullshit!
Look at me, John.
John, look at me.
Do l look like
I'm imagined?
Wheeler has
no record of you.
Do you think we
list our personnel?
(SCOFFS)
John, I'm sorry you had
to go through all this.
I've gone to
a great deal of trouble
to get you back.
I can restore your
status at Wheeler.
I can let the world
know what you did.
But l need you now,
soldier.
I was so scared
you weren't real.
There's a storm coming.
I'm just going to
grab the laundry. Okay?
I'll draw his bath.
It's okay.
Okay.
(FAlNT RADlO FEEDBACK)
(lNDlSTlNCT VOlCES
CHATTERlNG ON RADlO)
(lNDlSTlNCT CHATTERlNG
CONTlNUES)
(RADlO FEEDBACK CONTlNUES)
(WHlMPERlNG)
(GASPS)
(CRYlNG)
ALlClA: John !
I've almost got it!
Charles, you just
watch the baby.
No!
Oh, God.
(BABY CRYlNG)
Charles was watching him.
He was okay.
There is no one here.
Oh, my God !
Charles was watching him.
There is no one here!
He's been injected
with a cloaking serum.
I can see him
because of a chemical
that was released
into my bloodstream
when my implant dissolved.
I couldn't tell you,
it was for your
own protection !
Alicia!
No!
Hello, l need
Dr. Rosen's office, please.
PARCHER: You've got to
stop her, John.
You leave her out of it.
Who are you talking to?
It's not her fauIt.
John.
She'll compromise us again.
No, she won't.
You'll go back
to the hospital.
John, answer me!
Countless people will die.
Alicia, please put
the phone down.
I can't let that happen.
Yes, hello?
Hi, l need Dr. Rosen.
ls he in?
I'm sorry, John.
No!
(EXCLAlMS)
(BABY CRYlNG)
Alicia.
PARCHER: You know what you
have to do, Nash.
Get away from me.
She's too great a risk.
Get away!
l didn't mean
to hurt you !
Finish her.
She knows too much now.
MARCEE: Uncle John?
You take care of her,
you pathetic piece of shit,
or I'll take care of you.
John. Christ,
John, please do
what he says.
Move, soldier.
Now.
MARCEE: Uncle John?
CHARLES: John, please!
Now!
JOHN: Alicia and Charles
never coexist in the
same interactive field.
(VOlCES ECHOlNG)
Parcher and Charles...
Charles and Marcee
cannot coexist with Alicia.
With Alicia.
l understand.
(TlRES SCREECHlNG)
No!
She never gets old.
Marcee can't be real.
You see them now?
Yes.
Why did you
stop your meds?
Because I couldn't
do my work.
I couldn't help with
the baby. I couldn't. . .
I couldn't
respond to my wife.
You think that's better
than being crazy?
We'll need to start
you on a higher run
of insulin shocks
and a new medication.
No.
There has to be
another way.
ROSEN: Schizophrenia
is degenerative.
Some days may be
symptom-free, but over time,
you are getting worse.
It's a problem.
That's all it is.
It's a problem
with no solution.
And that's what I do,
l solve problems.
That's what I do best.
This isn't math.
You can't come up
with a formula to
change the way
you experience the world.
All I have to do
is apply my mind.
ROSEN: There's no theorem,
no proof.
You can't reason
your way out of this.
Why not? Why can't l?
Because your mind
is where the problem
is in the first place.
I can do this.
I can work it out.
All l need is time.
(BABY GlGGLlNG)
ls that the baby?
The baby is at
my mother's, John.
(MARCEE HUMMlNG)
Without treatment, John,
the fantasies may
take over entirely.
ALlClA: You almost ready?
Rosen's waiting outside.
I can't go back
to that hospital.
l won't come home.
He said that if you said that
he has commitment papers
for me to sign.
Well, maybe you
won't sign them.
Maybe you'lI just
give me some time.
I will try to
figure this out.
Whatever you do,
Rosen is right
about one thing.
You shouldn't be here.
I'm not safe anymore.
Would you have
hurt me, John?
I don't know.
Maybe you should
let Dr. Rosen drive you
to your mother's.
(SNlFFS)
ALlClA: He told me to leave.
(ROSEN CHATTERlNG
lNDlSTlNCTLY)
ALlClA: l understand.
(CAR DOORS CLOSlNG)
(ENGlNE STARTlNG)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG)
Rosen said to call if
you try and kill me,
or anything.
You want to know
what's real?
This.
This is real.
Maybe the part
that knows the waking
from the dream,
maybe it isn't here.
Maybe it's here.
l need to believe
that something
extraordinary is possible.
(CHATTERlNG)
HANSEN: Come.
Hello, Martin.
Jesus Christ.
No, l. . .
I don't have that one.
My savior complex takes on
a completely different form.
(JOHN CHUCKLES)
l heard what happened
and I wanted to write,
and I tried you
at MacArthur's,
but you'd left,
and I just. . .
This is
Helinger's old office.
Yeah.
Yeah, l stole it from him.
Seems that you won
after all, Martin.
They were wrong, John.
No one wins.
Please, please,
have a seat.
God, it's so good
to see you.
What brings you
back to Princeton?
John? John, I'm sorry,
but you have to tell him.
Tell him you're a genius.
You're a genius, John !
Tell him your work is
critical. John, please!
ls there any chance
that you could ignore
what I just did?
Of course.
What are old friends for?
ls that what
we are, Martin? Friends?
John, of course.
Of course.
We always have been.
Alicia and I think that
fitting in, being part of
a community,
might do me some good.
That a certain
level of attachment,
familiar places,
familiar people,
might help me elbow out
these certain delusions
that I have.
It's a lot to ask,
and now that I'm here,
I'm quite certain that
you wilI just say no.
But I was wondering
if l could hang around.
(SlGHS)
Huh.
Will you be
needing an office?
No.
No, l could just
work out of the library.
Well, this guy tries to
wander into the library,
but he doesn't have lD.
Why can't people
read their memos, huh?
Then, he goes
totally nuts.
You're not real !
You're not real.
There's no mission.
Shit. Shit.
You're not real !
You are not real !
ls this what
you are, soldier?
Some useless ghoul?
The local madman?
I'm not a soldier.
You're gonna
end up in a cell !
Old, worthless, discarded.
There's no mission.
And while you rock and drool,
the world will burn to ashes!
You are not real !
You're still
talking to me, soldier.
There's no mission !
I'm not a soldier!
John ! John !
Hey, hey, hey.
John, John. It's okay.
I just heard
what happened,
I'm sorry. John.
I'm not a soldier.
John. Hey, Nash.
Nash, hey,
you're all right.
Nash.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the great John Nash !
John?
JOHN: You should've
seen their faces.
Everybody was
just staring at me.
John, you know
that stress triggers
the delusions.
l know.
But then, on the way home,
Charles was there.
Sometimes, I really
miss talking to him.
Maybe Rosen's right.
Maybe I have to
think about going back
into the hospital again.
No. Come here.
Maybe try again tomorrow.
John, now you can't
ignore me forever.
Charles, you've been
a very good friend to me.
The best.
But l won't
talk to you again.
I just can't.
Same goes for you,
baby girl.
(SNlFFLES)
Good-bye.
I was wondering if
l might audit your course.
It's an honor,
Professor Nash.
ls something wrong?
This will be
my first class.
Good morning,
eager young minds.
(MUTTERlNG)
It's never
going to work, John.
You're just
humiliating yourself.
It's pathetic!
You are being pathetic.
I'm ashamed of you !
(STUDENTS LAUGHlNG)
Man !
Are you coming?
You're going to be late.
Dad, you've got my book.
What?
You've got my book.
Right.
Thanks.
Good-bye.
Bye.
ALlClA: See you tonight.
Bye, honey.
Did you just solve Riemann?
Well, what do you think?
Huh.
That's an analog
to Frobenius for
non-commutative extensions.
Yes, it is.
But it only appears
to work sporadically,
so, no.
But I believe
I'm making progress.
You're John Nash, right?
Toby Kelly.
Hello.
I've been studying
your equilibrium,
the one you wrote
here at Princeton.
To come up with something
totally original, the way you did.
You know, I was young.
(CHUCKLES)
I've been developing
a theory.
I believe I can prove
that Galois extensions
are covering spaces.
That everything,
everything is connected.
That it's all part
of the same subject.
When was the last time
you ate?
Excuse me?
You know, food.
Oh. . . Uh. . .
My wife,
she loves mayonnaise.
Thank you.
Go on.
The function is in
the two categories.
Mmm-hmm.
HANSEN: Alicia!
Alicia!
JOHN: . . .and meet together
at a maximum speed
of, let us say,
1 0 miles per hour.
So you have a fly on
the tire of bicycle "B,"
and the fly,
who can travel at
20 miles an hour,
leaves the tire of bicycle "B"
and flies to the tire
of bicycle "A,"
and backwards and forwards,
and so on and so forth,
until the two bikes collide
and the poor
little fly is squashed.
This is the important thing
about actually focusing in
and comprehending
the area that
you're dealing with.
Mathematics is very specific,
and it is an art form,
no matter what these people
around here will tell you,
especially the people
from Biology.
Don't listen to
any of those people.
(ALL CHUCKLlNG)
Let me go back to
what you were doing before
because I think l
might want to steal this
and write a book
and get famous.
(STUDENTS CHUCKLlNG)
I was thinking
that l might teach.
A classroom with 50 students
can be daunting for anyone.
John, besides,
you're a terrible teacher.
I'm an acquired
taste, Martin.
I was hoping there
still might be something
l could contribute.
What about the. . .
Well, you know.
Are they gone?
No, they're not gone.
And maybe
they never will be.
But I've gotten
used to ignoring them,
and I think, as a resuIt,
they've given up on me.
You think that's
what it's like with
all our dreams and
our nightmares, Martin?
You've got to
keep feeding them
for them to stay alive?
John,
they haunt you though.
They're my past, Martin.
Everybody is haunted
by their past.
Well, good-bye.
John, I'll talk
to the department.
Maybe in the spring.
Hey, Nash.
You scared?
Terrified.
Mortified. Petrified.
Stupefied by you.
Now you ought
best ring Alicia,
or you're gonna get me. . .
I'll ring her.
. . .in an awful
lot of trouble.
Thanks, Professor.
Good-bye.
Have a nice day.
Papers in hand, Mr. Beyer.
Monday, sir.
KlNG: Professor Nash?
Can you see him?
Yeah.
You sure?
Positive? He's within
your vision? Good.
(CHUCKLlNG)
Forgive me,
I'm just always
suspicious of new people.
See you next week,
Professor.
See you next week.
So now that l know
that you're real,
who are you,
and what can I do for you?
Professor,
my name is Thomas King.
Thomas King?
Mmm-hmm.
And I'm here to tell you that
you're being considered
for the Nobel Prize.
Forgive me, but I'm
just a little stunned.
Over the past few years,
your equilibrium
has become a cornerstone
of modern economics.
Suddenly,
everybody likes that one.
What about my work on
other some such projects,
like manifold embedding?
The application of
your bargaining problem
to FCC bandwidth auctions
or to antitrust cases. . .
Antitrust cases?
Yes.
I never would
have considered that.
Have I just reached
some level of honesty
that borders on stupidity?
(LAUGHlNG)
No, you haven't.
Because I wouldn't
have thought of that.
Shall we have tea?
I don't go in there.
l usually just take my
sandwich in the library.
Come on, John.
Let's have some tea.
It's a big day.
Most commercially
available brands of tea
are not suitable to
my palate, you see.
I'm not. . .
There are some
Northern Indian teas
which are dense enough.
l enjoy the flavor
that they have.
I have not been in this room
for quite some many years.
l wonder what tea
they serve.
Why, thank you,
young lady.
Things have certainly
changed around here.
I have a son that age.
Harvard.
(CHUCKLES)
(SNlFFlNG)
Hmm.
I would have thought
the nominations for
the Nobel Prize
would've been secret.
I would have thought
you'd only find out
if you won or lost.
That is generally
the case, yes,
but these are
special circumstances.
The awards are substantial.
They require private funding.
As such,
the image of the Nobel is. . .
Oh, I see. So, you came here
to find out if I was crazy?
Find out if I would
screw everything up
if l actually won?
Dance around the podium,
strip naked and
squawk like a chicken,
things of this nature?
(CHUCKLlNG)
Something like that, yes.
Would l embarrass you?
Yes, it is possible.
You see, I am crazy.
l take the
newer medications,
but l stilI see things
that are not here.
I just choose not
to acknowledge them.
Like a diet of the mind,
l choose not to indulge
certain appetites.
Like my appetite
for patterns.
Perhaps my appetite
to imagine and to dream.
MAN: Professor Nash.
It's good to
have you here, John.
Thank you.
It's an honor, sir.
Thank you very much.
A privilege, Professor.
Professor.
Nicely done, John.
Thank you, Tom.
Thank you.
Thank you, Ed.
That was certainly
most unexpected.
JOHN: Thank you.
I've aIways
believed in numbers,
in the equations and Iogics
that lead to reason.
But after
a Iifetime of such pursuits,
I ask, what truIy is Iogic?
Who decides reason?
My quest has taken me
through the physicaI,
the metaphysicaI,
the delusional and back.
And I have made
the most important
discovery of my career.
The most important
discovery of my Iife.
It is onIy in the mysterious
equations of Iove
that any IogicaI
reasons can be found.
I'm onIy here tonight
because of you.
You are the reason I am.
You are aII my reasons.
Thank you.
JOHN: So nice to
have met you.
I'll call for the car, Dad.
Bye-bye.
WOMAN: Bye-bye.
Are you ready to go now?
Yes, I am.
Yes, indeed,
and yes, please.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
What is it?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Come with me,
young lady.
I have a car outside.
Are you interested in a ride?
Where's it going to?