m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
YYeTs.com
I've never seen him this happy before.
That's because you've never seen him
on "Restock the Medicine Cabinet Day."
Look!
A new topical antihistamine with lidocaine.
I can't wait until I get a rash.
Oh, Gas-X has a new ultra strength.
I guess they really do read their mail.
Hey, isn't that Professor Proton?
Oh, yeah.
Look at him, just standing in line
like he wasn't moderately famous 30 years ago.
Let's go say hello.
Oh, maybe we shouldn't bother him.
I'm not going to bother him, I'm going to talk to him.
He thinks there's a difference.
Arthur?
Arthur, it's me--
Sheldon Cooper.
You may not remember because of your advanced age.
Trust me, I... I remember.
This is my girlfriend, Amy.
Amy, this is television legend Arthur Jeffries.
His science show inspired millions of children.
Ho-hold on.
You... You have a girlfriend?
Yes, and I've heard so much about you.
Hey look-- we're wearing the same orthopedic shoes.
I can't believe I dress like a celebrity.
O-Okay, I get it now.
Dr. Jeffries, hello again. Leonard Hofstadter.
Oh, oh, right, I remember your-your girlfriend.
Is-Is she... is she here?
No, she's not.
So, what prescription are you getting filled?
- Sheldon. - Wait, I want to guess.
Don't tell me.
I wasn't going to tell you.
Sheldon, come on.
No, no, no. I'm really good at this.
All right, give me a hint.
Does it involve difficulty initiating a stream of anything?
Well, given my age, that's more than just a lucky guess.
Hey, Sheldon, let's go mock the people
buying homeopathic medicine-- you love that.
But I'm hanging out with my friend,
and we're having fun.
Look how happy he is.
Bernie's having a girls' night on Friday at our place.
You want to do something?
- Actually, I'm busy. - Doing what?
There's a new sports bar over on Colorado Ave...
- You're going to girls' night. - Yeah.
You know they're making jewelry, right?
You think they came up with that?
They were going to drink beer and play darts.
What's up?
Not his testosterone levels.
Excuse me.
I happen to be very comfortable with my masculinity.
How is that possible?
Hey, I got an email from Professor Proton.
Goody! What's it say?
He's working on a paper about nano vacuum tubes,
and wants to know if I'd take a look at it.
That's strange.
That he would come to you for that and not me.
Oh, I got two emails from him.
"Do you have Leonard's email address?"
And...
"Never mind, I found it."
I can't believe he picked you over me.
You don't want to read a paper by some old has-been
who hasn't done any real science in decades.
Yeah, it's nothing to cry about.
Sheldon Cooper does not cry.
It's true, you'd rust.
And to think I idolized that man.
And why?
At the end of the day he's just another Hollywood phony.
Is it really worth getting upset about?
They say don't meet your heroes.
Don't peek behind that curtain of fame and celebrity,
because if you do, you'll see them as they really are--
degenerate carnival folk.
Come on, he's a retired kids show host.
That's even worse.
Using the sweet candy of science
to trick children into loving him.
Pervert.
Have you ever thought about
why Arthur didn't want you to read his paper?
Yes, I have.
And my only conclusion
is the prescription he was picking up the other day
was for cuckoo pills.
Maybe he found you, um, a bit much.
That's kind of a stretch.
Look, when it comes to social skills,
I've mastered the big three.
There's the coy smile.
There's the friendly chuckle.
There's the vocalization of sympathy.
That last one's tricky, I'm still working on it.
From what I saw the other day,
I could understand why he and...
some people might find you...
What?
Doesn't matter.
No, go ahead, say it.
I know what it is.
I've heard it my whole life.
The word's "annoying".
Go ahead, say it.
Say it. Say I'm annoying.
Sheldon...
Oh, it won't hurt my feelings.
Go ahead, Amy, say I'm annoying.
I'm annoying. I'm annoying.
I'm annoying. Yeah, now, uh...
Now where are you going?
Look, you know you want to say it-- say it.
Say I'm annoying. Go ahead, say it.
Say it. Say it. Amy, say it.
Well, she can't stand it when I'm right.
This is fun.
I'm going to feel like such a vixen wearing jewelry
that doesn't have a list of medications I'm allergic to.
Penny, how's it going over there?
Good-- I'm just having little trouble with the glue.
How do you not know how to use glue?
Did you ditch pre-school?
Yeah, but only because I was dating a second grader.
Hello, everyone.
Okay, let me have it.
Let's hear all the "Raj is a girl" jokes.
Nope.
Bernadette told me it isn't nice and I'm not allowed.
Thank you.
So I won't be making fun of you,
or the things you like,
or the fact that you just want to have fun.
Howie, stop.
Come on, look at what I'm making.
Oh, that's actually pretty nice.
I'm making a bracelet.
Yeah, I'm just making a mess.
You know, instead of beads and glue,
you guys can use my soldering iron.
You'd be able to make much cooler stuff.
Oh, I think we're doing just fine, thank you.
- Actually, I'd kind of like to try that. - Me, too.
Be right back.
When did I have pistachios?
Arthur.
Door knocker.
That's TV money.
Sheldon, what are you doing here?
I'm sorry, did I wake you?
Of course you woke me, it's 7:30.
Well, I would have been here sooner,
but for some reason your home
isn't on this map of Hollywood stars.
What do you want, Sheldon?
It's been pointed out by my girlfriend
that I may have been annoying to you.
She sounds like a keeper.
Anyway, I wanted to apologize.
I am truly sorry.
All right, apology accepted. Have a nice night.
No, no, now that... we've cleared the air,
I wanted to discuss another matter with you.
Sheldon, in a couple hours, I have to get up,
pee and then wander around the house.
Well, then, I'll make this quick.
Um, I want to talk about the paper you sent Leonard.
Now, I know he said it's promising
and he's going to collaborate on it,
but now that you and I are friends again,
I am at your disposal.
Frankly, lending my name and reputation to it will help,
because a lot of people think that you're a washed-up has-been.
Or dead.
I should be so lucky.
So, uh, what do you say?
You know, if it's all the same with you,
I think I'll stick with Leonard.
It's because I'm annoying, right?
I know it is. Say it.
Say it. Say I'm annoying.
- Good night. - Say it.
Arthur, say it. Say I'm annoying.
Say it. Say it.
I'm annoying. Say it.
You're annoying!
Wow, that really hurt.
If you would have told me when I was a kid
that someday I would be doing science
next to Professor Proton,
I would not have believed you.
If someone had told me
that people would still call me Professor Proton
when I was 83 years old,
I never would have quit smoking.
I'm sorry, Dr. Jeffries, I'm just excited.
This nano vacuum tube idea of yours is really interesting.
Hello, Leonard.
Oh, hello, Arthur.
What an odd coincidence that you're both here.
Why is it odd?
Because as it just so happens, I'm also spending the day
with a beloved children's television science personality.
Isn't that right, new friend and colleague,
Bill Nye the Science Guy.
Sorry, I replaced you with a newer model.
Wow, Arthur Jeffries.
It's an honor to meet you.
My show never would have happened without yours.
That's what I told my lawyers.
Mr. Nye, hello.
I'm sorry he got you involved in this nonsense.
He said I'd be speaking to a class.
No, I said you were teaching someone a lesson.
Now let's go.
What are you guys working on?
Oh, uh, we're making nano vacuum tubes.
That's interesting.
Haven't you stolen enough from me?
Back off, bow tie!
Hey, guys...
What do you think?
Wow, Penny, good job.
Thanks. Target, $4.99.
I'm getting a drink.
What are you working on?
Oh, I'm making a necklace for my mom.
That's sweet.
Yeah, she and my dad are going through
a bit of a rough patch, so
I wanted to do something to let her know
I was thinking about her.
What's going on with them?
They're just having a little trouble communicating.
My dad says it's because the sound of my mom's voice
makes him want to tear his ears off
and sew them over his eyes
so he never has to look at her again.
Hi.
- Hey, guys. - Hello.
Look who's here to put
the "Jew" In "Jewelry Night"!
Oh, sure, so it's fine when you say it.
Sorry we're late.
I wanted to swing by the lab
and pick up some even cooler tools for us to use.
I didn't know you were coming again.
Well, last week was a blast.
Plus, I thought you might like having a guy here.
It was not funny.
So, what tools did you bring?
Everything we need to make jewelry molds.
Here's some silver, a crucible
and an acetylene torch to melt it down.
Ooh, that looks like fun.
Maybe you should master glue
before you move on to fire.
Okay, who's up first?
Rajesh, do you want to make a bracelet for your mom
to go with the necklace?
No, thanks.
I was gonna make a necklace for my mom,
but unfortunately, she doesn't have a neck.
She's just chins and fat and feet.
Okay, we're almost ready to go.
Once we bond the wires, we can test the tubes.
This is so exciting, I-I feel...
like I'm 75 again.
Oh, God.
What... what is it?
Sheldon just sent me a picture
of him and Bill Nye getting smoothies.
Can-can I ask you a question?
Yeah, sure.
W-Why do you put up with Sheldon?
Oh, uh, you know, because we're friends.
Why?
- Wow, you ask really hard questions. - Yeah.
Look, I-I know he can be aggravating,
but what you have to remember is that
he's not doing it on purpose.
It's just how he is.
But he's also loyal and trustworthy
and we have fun together...
You... you know you're describing a dog.
He did bite me once.
But in his defense,
I came up behind him while he was eating, so...
Yeah, they-they hate that.
You know what, Sheldon is the smartest person I have ever met.
And he's a little broken and he needs me.
I guess I need him, too.
Why-why is that?
Boy, you will not let this go, will you?
Oh, geez.
Another photo from Sheldon?
No, I have to go pick him up.
Bill Nye ditched him at the smoothie place.
He probably stole his wallet, too.
You know, if you guys are interested,
there's a technique where I can take a lock of your hair,
refine it into carbon dust,
and use the hydraulic press at work
to turn it into a tiny little diamond
with your DNA in it.
Oh, that's amazing!
Yeah. See Bernie's engagement ring?
That came right off my mom's back.
He's kidding.
If that were true, it'd be so much bigger.
"My name is Howard.
I can make your hair into diamonds.
My mom is morbidly obese.
Everybody love me."
Whoa, where is that coming from?
I'll tell you where it's coming from.
All you do is make fun of me for coming to girls' night
and now you're here ruining it for everyone.
Raj, cool it...
he's gonna make us hair diamonds.
How am I ruining anything?
I'm just trying to help you make better jewelry.
But this isn't about the jewelry.
This is about me having a place
where I can open up about my feelings.
Since when can't you open up with me?
There are just some things
that I feel more comfortable sharing with the girls,
because they won't make fun of me
or and call me names, or ask me if my
"Koothrapanties are in a bunch."
Buddy, I was just joking around.
Yeah, well, sometimes your jokes hurt.
Well, you're right.
I didn't realize I was making you feel that way.
It was very brave of you to tell me.
Thank you.
It wasn't easy.
They're gonna have sex before Sheldon and I do,
I know it.
Arthur.
Hi, Sheldon.
I'm surprised to see you here.
Yeah, me, too.
Somewhere around the third floor,
I began to see a white light.
I'll get Leonard.
No, no, no, I'm...
I'm here... I'm here to see you.
If you're hoping to get in touch with Bill Nye,
I can't help you.
I've been informed that he's now
Bill Nye the Restraining Order Guy.
No, I'm...
I-I was thinking, if it isn't too much trouble,
I'd like to get your opinion about my-my paper.
Thank you.
It would be an honor.
Oh. Uh, great.
Well, actually, I don't need that.
I hacked into your e-mail account and read it.
And... what did you think?
Well, first, I think the fact that
you use your birthday as a password
is embarrassing.
Thank you.
Second, um...
I thought your paper was inspired.
Oh, well, that... that means a lot to me.
Can I invite you in for tea?
Uh, no, no. I-I really...
I have... I have to run.
Hey, Arthur. How are you?
Well, I guess one cup wouldn't hurt.
Oh, hey, buddy, what's up?
Well, I was feeling bad about how I acted the other night
so I made you a little something.
You didn't have to do that.
Well, it was fun.
I used some of the jewelry techniques you taught us.
It's a lightsaber belt buckle.
Wow, this is so cool, thanks.
Oh gets better.
And that's not even the best part. See?
I have one, too.
Check it out.
You can wear yours and we can have little sword fights
whenever we want.
Yeah, and my eighth favorite episode of Professor Proton
was "Alka-Seltzer Rocket."
You said, "Plop, plop, fizz, fizz,
oh, what a blast-off it is."
Remember? Remember that?
Remember?
He can't help it. He can't.
He really can't.
You wait here.
I'll get some Alka-Seltzer,
we can build that rocket,
and we can shoot it at Bill Nye's house.
As long as I'm not within 500 feet of it.
So, you, uh...
you have... you have any...
single grandmothers?
- Sorry, they're both married. - Good.
H-Happily?