There you are, Tod.
I found one.
No way.
Look at the size of that thing.
Sure is ugly.
It's a monster.
I can smell its evil breath from here.
No, that's me.
I had socks for lunch.
How about you take this one.
Come on. We're a team, right?
Wanna shake on it?
Shake on it.
Ready, set...
- Go.
Come on, Copper!
Get him!
Come on, keep up.
Wait for me.
We leap into the river deep
Who can make the biggest splash?
Or the widest grin as we jump on in
Who can let out the loudest laugh?
For I do not care who hears
And I don 't care who sees
Yes I want the world to know
Everything you mean to me
Cross my heart and hope to die
I will never tell a lie
I will not run away
I'll go ahead and say
We 're not just two of a kind
We 're friends for life
Friends for life
W e chasi n' crickets,
or are we just hang i n' out?
I messed up agai n.
I can't do nothin' right.
Hey. Well, that's not true.
You're... You're...
You're housetrained, ain't ya?
Oh, Copper.
Race ya.
Wow, the trucks for the fair.
I've never seen
so much stuff in my life.
Oh, boy. I can't wait.
- You goin'?
- I'm a-goin'.
Chief says you can win a ribbon.
- For what?
- Just for being a good dog.
Whoa. That's a pretty good pumpkin.
That one's even bigger.
And noisier.
Hey, Tod, you hear that?
You OK?
Tripped over my own ears.
See, I told ya.
I'm just a bad dog.
Don't be like that.
Copper.
Time for my huntin' lesson.
Hey, maybe I'll be good at huntin'.
Yeah. I'm gonna be
the huntingest puppy ever.
Now you're talkin'.
Let's see now.
Copper.
Oh, where could that pup
have gotten off to?
Hi, Chief. Ready for my lesson.
Oh, durn my hide.
Playin' nursemaid to a pup when I
should be a-practicin' for the contest.
Oh, you don't need to practice.
You're the best huntin' dog
in the whole county.
Well, I reckon it's true. I mean,
they don't give those
fourth place prizes to just anybody.
There you are, Copper.
We'll make a huntin' dog out of you yet.
Here, snuff this up.
Now, when this rabbit takes off,
you follow his scent.
Then, when you have him,
Iet loose with a big ol' hound dog howl.
I must be goin' deaf. I said howl.
You're gonna lose your head
one of these days, Amos Slade.
It's my head, woman.
Good boy.
OK, Chief.
Get goin'.
What are you waitin' for? Go get him.
Go, Copper.
Attaboy, Copper.
Pup's as useful as a
milk bucket under a bull.
Tod?
Oh, I'm gettin' all turned around.
I don't know what I'm doin'.
It's easy. You just sniff him out.
When you smell him,
lift up your head and howl.
Like this?
No, not me.
Gotta go.
Oh, ding-dang it.
I've got you now.
Come back here, you little varmint.
Excuse me, comin' through.
- My milk.
- Oh, no.
Abigail, wait.
Amos Slade!
Amos Slade, I told you to
keep your beasts away from my Tod.
That mangy hound of yours
just cost me a bucket of milk.
Your fox was after my chickens, Tweed.
What do I care about your milk?
Well, as long as you're wasting my milk,
you may as well have some pie
to go along with it.
What the dickens are you...
Bad dog, Copper.
You are a very bad dog.
Well, you can just forget
about the fair, Copper.
Oh, dagnabit.
You couldn't find a rabbit
at a petting zoo on Easter Sunday.
There. That ought to
keep you out of trouble.
Let's go, Chief. Fair's a-waitin'.
You'll get it one day, boy.
You just gotta grow up a little is all.
He got you over a barrel, huh?
Well, say somethin'.
There's nothin' to say.
That's just what I'm good for...
Nothin'.
You're real good
at gettin' into trouble.
'Course you're good
at something, Copper.
We just gotta figure out what.
You know what you need? A little fun.
I wonder if there's
a county fair around here.
Come to think of it, there is!
In case you haven't noticed,
I'm a little tied up right now.
Nothin' a fox can't fix.
- What do you wanna do first?
- Everything.
Mom, fireworks! Fireworks!
Balloons!
Ice cream!
Fireworks.
- Oh, yeah.
- We gotta see 'em.
Smack at sundown.
Shake on it.
There's that sound again.
Sounds pretty good.
Sounds like somebody
got their tail stuck in a door.
We're in harmony
Voice like a angel.
- With looks to match.
- Oh, please.
We're in harmo...
Oh, my poor...
Darn this one horse,
two-bit, three-timin' fair.
Dixie, it ain't like
it smacked your singin'.
Can we get back to rehearsin'?
I refuse to work under these conditions.
Here we go.
I'll tell you what, Dixie.
You rehearse,
and afterwards I'll give that piece
of wood a good ol' talkin' to.
- I got two bones on Dixie.
- I'll cover that.
It just so happens I am a professional,
and my standards...
Oh, now, Dixie, darlin',
you put on that
same ol' record every day.
Ain't it about wore out by now?
Some nerve talkin' to me that way.
If your ear were any more tin,
they'd can beans with it.
You listen to me, Miss fancy-tail.
In a couple of days we'll be
in front of that talent scout
from the Grand Ole Opry.
I get possibly maimed for life,
and all you can talk about
is the Grand Ole Opry?
- Oh, now, Dixie...
- I'll be in my trailer.
Darlin', we got a show to do.
You can't just walk...
...away.
Sometimes I dislike that woman.
If they dislike each other any more,
they'd have to get hitched.
Holy Pete, where are...
Sorry, fellas.
Oh, I can tell right now, this is
gonna be the worst show of all time.
It's gonna be the worst.
OK, let's have fun out there.
- Who's gonna sing Dixie's part?
- Just give me a second to...
- I do a good Dixie.
- Waylon, somehow I don't picture...
- D's been lead as long as I remember.
- I been practicin' my falsetto.
Sit!
OK, here's the good news.
Granny Rose,
you are singin' Dixie's part.
Me?!
Oh, she's gonna love this one.
We have a real treat for you now.
Lyle Snodgrass and The Singin' Strays.
You can almost swear
them dogs are really singin'.
Like the sun and blue skies
Like summer nights and fireflies
- Like an itch
- And a scratch
We're the perfect match
'Cause we're in harmony
Like a tick and a flea
A bird and a bee
A nose and a tail
A horse and a trail
A pond and a frog
A bump and a log
We 're hand in glove
An example of
Come on, kid. Si ng with us.
Purebred, down-home, true sweet...
Harmony
Any crowd we face
Any squirrel we chase
Any time any place
We 're in harmony
Thick melodies
What?
Sweet honey for me
Listen up you 'll see
We 're in harmony
We were meant to be
Together you and me
We 're in harmony
Y eah.
- Oh, yeah.
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
Hot dog, listen to 'em, Cash.
They love that number.
Yeah, and if a cow had wheels,
it'd be a milk truck.
That song is hokey.
They're clappin' for this little puppy.
Well, the kid's cute, all right.
Kid, I'll tell you what. You can sing!
- You got pipes of gold.
- You sure do.
- Hey, kid, what's your name?
- Copper.
Copper, thanks for gettin' us
out of a tight spot.
It was fun.
You got a future in show business.
You come back and see us
in a couple of years.
Yep, in a couple of years.
'Cause bein' in a band takes maturity.
What?
What just happened?
I'll tell you what happened.
You're good at somethin'.
And I mean good.
- What do you think you're doin'?
- Little audience participation.
That kid wowed them.
- Kid? What kid?
- Bye, Mr. Cash.
- That kid.
- Little critter was heaven sent.
That sang my lead?
Oh, no, he didn't just sing it.
He sang it!
You don't mean to tell me
that wet behind the ears puppy
- could ever take my place in the band?
- I didn't say that.
Although, he does have that refreshin'
bloom of youth about him.
- Just what exactly are you sayin'?
- What do you think I'm sayin'?
- Better not be sayin' what I think.
- You know what I'm sayin'.
You better know
what you're sayin' isn't what I think.
- Why do you always have to...
- 'Cause you never...
- What if I said...
- I'd say...
You know, this is just like
the time when you j...
You better not bring that up.
Well, I think we've both
been perfectly clear.
Oh, perfectly.
- I quit!
- Huh?
Cash, what are we gonna do?
- Gone with the wind.
- She's gone.
Sit!
I'll take care of this.
I better. That talent scout'll
be here any minute.
Hi there.
Now, who are you?
Olivia Farmer, designated chaperone
to Winchell P. Bickerstaff,
talent scout from the Grand Ole Opry.
- That's you.
- Chaperone, huh?
I'm working to get my
community service merit badge.
Well, that's quite admirable,
little lady.
Then, I'll have more than
Sally Ann Marybob.
Thinks she's so great.
Well, lead on Miss Farmer.
I'm a-lookin' for some talent.
Oh, Dixie, you ain't mad
over a little joshin', are ya?
I was only teasin' ya.
You know how I feel about ya.
Yeah, you have a
lousy way of showin' it.
I am tryin' to kiss and make up here.
Now, won't you please accept my apology?
Blow it out your ear.
All right, you diva dog,
but I'm in charge of this band
and ain't no one's indispensable.
You're in charge?
Which one of us is in the driver's seat?
Now, listen you...
Now, you got me riled.
All right.
Yee-haw! Ride 'em cowboy, away.
Yee-haw! All right.
- This is the most fun ever.
- Second most fun ever.
Mr. Cash.
I saw how blissful
you looked singin'.
That had to be
the best time you ever had.
Oh, for sure.
Well, now, we can't let nothin'
get in the way of that.
Like I was sayin',
how'd you like to join the band?
- Really?
- Huh?
Yes sir, a genuine Singin' Stray.
What do you say?
Yeah!
Copper, we were gonna
have some more fun.
Well, Tod can be
in the band too, right?
- Well, uh...
- He's my best friend.
Can you sing, kid?
Course he can sing. Show him, Tod.
We're in har...
Here's the good news.
You're gonna be part of the entourage.
- What's that?
- That's French.
Means you hang out
with our new star. Keep him happy.
He does that already.
And you know, fetch water,
clean dog bowls, fun stuff like that.
- That's fun?
- Does Granny have fleas?
Come on, Tod. It's gonna be great.
Well, OK.
All right, then. Let's get movin'.
Wasn't he amazing,
the way he ate fire, Mr. Bickerstaff?
Maybe you shouldn't have stood so close.
Now you tell me.
- OK.
- Hey, Dixie.
You've come crawlin' back.
Oh, by the way, you can't quit.
You're fired.
What?! You can't fire me.
I already quit.
Cash, you get back...
Now, you've got me riled.
Don't get your collar in a bunch, Dixie.
Pitch a furball.
The nerve of that Cash.
Where does he get off firin' me?
Oh, I thought you quit.
I'm that band's heart and soul.
It's plain as a pig on a sofa.
Bet Cash can talk a dog
off a meat truck.
He talked me into gettin' sweet on him
and now he tosses me away
like yesterday's cornbread.
Honey, I don't blame you
for feeling hurt.
Hurt? What do you mean by that?
You think Cash could hurt me?
Mangy mutt.
Oh, y'all howled
real good today, fellers.
Oh, well.
There's more than one way to skin a cat.
No offence.
Soup's on!
Yeah, that's a good boy, right there.
All right, fellas. All right.
Bon appetit.
You know, if I could just play the banjo
better, y'all would be eatin' steaks.
Hey, I guess I'd better go practice.
Welcome to the band, kid.
Let me do some introductions.
That there is Waylon and Floyd.
They're the brains of the outfit.
Why I put up with this low class
crew of mutts is beyond me.
And that delicate flower is Granny Rose.
Textbook version
of growin' old gracefully.
Oh, I got me an itch.
Yep, you'll never harmonize with a finer
group of singin' strays than...
You are a stray, right boy?
Course he's a stray.
You don't see a collar on him, do ya?
- True enough.
- I don't see one.
No collar, no home.
Good. Only strays allowed
in this dog's band.
Tod, I'm not a stray.
It'll be our secret.
Chief, just wait till Copper sees this.
Another fourth place ribbon.
Next year, we're goin'
for the three-peat.
- Oh. Oh, my...
- What the...?
- Widow Tweed?
- Huh?
Do you make a career
out of gettin' in my way?
Step aside woman,
I got a prize winner comin' through.
- Well, so do I.
- What?
This here's a huntin' dog.
What could you do with a pie?
Woman's got spunk. I'll give her that.
OK, fellers, ten minutes to curtain.
Let's round 'em up and move 'em out.
- Move 'em round.
- I'm movin'.
- That means you, Copper.
- Huh?
- Good luck, Copper.
- Thanks, entourage.
Say, Tod, while we're on, why don't you
spiff up those bowls a bit?
The bowls?
OK, Cash.
Don't forget. Fireworks,
smack at sundown.
It's a promise.
Little darlin'.
Come on in. Dixie wants to talk to ya.
But, I'm supposed to sing now.
Oh, I know. I just wanna pass along
my secret of success.
Really? Thanks Miss Dixie.
Before every show,
take a big ol' helpin' of that.
Peanut butter?
All right.
Let's get to growlin' and howlin'.
Now... Granny Rose,
go fetch Copper, will you?
Hang on. Oh, that's good.
Me, me, me, me, me
Woof, woof, woof, woof
Oh-oh. Bad news in a rhinestone collar.
Cash, you look nervous as a long-tailed
cat in a room full of rockin' chairs.
'Cause I'm busy as a farmer
with one hoe and two rattlesnakes.
Oh, yeah? Well I'm as...
- Oh, I got nothin'.
- What is it, Dixie?
I just thought
you could use a lead singer.
Peanut butter?
But Copper, you have to sing.
Hold on, Copper. I'll be right back.
The winner of the milkin' contest is...
...the widow Tweed
and her fine cow, Abigail.
What?
Copper, come on out.
Perfect, just like that.
All right.
- You know darn well Copper is our...
- Copper? You mean that little pup?
Why, he ran off
with that fox friend of his
Iike a bank robber on roller skates.
You're kiddin'.
Hey, if I'm lyin',
may my fur lose its natural lustre.
That did it. I can sing.
Great. Now when you get out there,
don't forget to...
OK, see you at the fireworks, right?
Get used to it, entourage.
This is how it's gonna be from now on.
What do you mean?
While he's off havin' fun
and gettin' the glory,
he'll stick you back here
with the chores.
No, Copper isn't like that.
Yeah.
Well, we'll see, won't we?
Here I am.
Ran off, huh?
Sorry, Dix.
Peanut butter? Oh, Dixie.
You are through.
Well, gettin' rid of me
ain't gonna be so easy, Cash.
That looked easy.
Remind me to give
that piece of wood a bonus.
Look, Miss Farmer. This ain't
the kind of talent I'm a-lookin' for.
Yeah, you're right. That flea circus
was totally amateur hour.
Waylon, give me a back beat.
We are headed for the big time.
And I got a big time song
to take us there.
Follow my lead, kid.
You were headed for the pound dog
No one wanted you around dog
Now you're gonna be a found dog
You'll be a hound dude
A hound dude
Yeah, watch out
The whole world is gonna know you
They'll be fallin ' at your paws soon
So bark it up all you want to
You 'll be a hound dude
We 're all hound dudes
We 're the big dogs now
Once we were lowly pups
With nothin ' but our dreams
Now we can strut our stuff
While the fans all howl and scream
He's just so darn cute.
Oh, Cash.
I 'm supposed to meet T od soon for the...
Whoa, whoa.
We can't let nobody hold us back.
We're hound dudes, remember?
No more small town dog
Here to make lie down dog
No more bein'just a hound dog
You're a hound dude
Goodbye leash, I'm a hound dude
No collar for me
We're all hound dudes
Happy as a flea
We 're all hound dudes
On top of the world can 't you see
Hound dudes
Wow. Awesome.
I 've never been so high up in my life.
I think I was higher than the fireworks.
Yeah, and how about those free hot dogs?
You looked happier than a hog
at Sunday pot luck.
All right. Meet you backstage, kid.
- We got a lot of work to do.
- You got it, Cash.
- Oh, sorry, Tod.
- Hey, Copper.
- How was the Ferris wheel?
- The fireworks.
Oh, gosh. I forgot.
Cash and I were busier
than two mice in a cheese shop.
- Too busy for your best friend?
- It's not like that, Tod.
Cash said I had to let everyone see me.
Cash said it's good for the band.
Cash said...
Cash said! Cash said!
Who cares about Cash?
Tod, what's wrong?
Are you jealous?
- Course not, you dumb dog.
- Then what's eatin' you?
I don't know.
It's like you're not around anymore.
Well, I'm around now.
Let's do somethin'.
I mean, if you wanna.
Now?
Shake on it?
- Shake on it.
- Kid, I swear,
you're slow as an iron toad.
Come on.
You're holdin' us up. Let's go.
Waylon, would you get up.
We got more ground...
- Oh, Cash.
- Let's get to work now.
I guess I gotta go.
But... But Copper...
I'll see you later, OK.
Yeah? Well maybe you will,
and maybe you won't.
Why eat 'em, Dix?
Might as well just slap 'em
right on your hips.
Come on, Zelda. I need a drink.
Give me one, straight.
Give me that.
Oh, darlin', you look like somethin'
the cat dragged in.
Oh, no offence.
- What do you care?
- Oh, come on, Tod.
We're both in the same
ol' briar patch now.
Cast off by the one
we care about the most.
Guess you know how that feels now.
- Copper's forgotten all about me.
- Yeah, I heard that.
- Hurts worse than anything.
- Yeah.
I remember this one Tomcat named Leroy.
I'm talkin' to the fox.
You see, Tod, relationships and
show business, they just don't mix.
Oh, it starts out nice and friendly.
Then they get that first taste of fame
and it's, "Look out for number one."
First they tell you that
you're gonna be the next big thing
They put roses in your dressin' room
every time you sing
Till you ask for a little consideration
Then they call you a diva
Pink slip, termination
They grab the next yapper
Just walkin ' down the street
They got him singin ' your songs
Markin ' your tree
It's lonely at the top
When the lights go down
And the cheerin ' stops
You got no real friends
No place to call home
It's all, good doggie
No bone
Al I rig ht, let's get to crooni n'.
And the next thing you know
He ain 't bringin ' you roses
It's all cold stares, cold shoulders
Cold noses
He doesn 't write, doesn 't call
Doesn 't howl your name
All that he can think about
is fortune and fame
There ain 't nothin ' I can do
To turn his head and excite him
Sometimes I swear I just wanna bite him
It's lonely at the top
When the lights go down
and the cheerin ' stops
You got no real friends
No place to call home
It's all, good doggie
Good doggie
No bone
Oh, no, no, no
Good doggie
No bone
Good doggie, no bone
Good doggie
No bone
Good doggie, no bone
Not even a little bitty bone
Good doggie
No bone
Now that's a good little doggie.
And, you know what?
He wouldn't even be in that
dumb ol' band if I hadn't lied for him.
Come again.
I got Cash to think he was a stray.
Copper's no stray.
He lives just down the road a piece.
Little darlin',
all our troubles are over.
How'd you like
to get your best friend back?
But how?
Just listen close to ol' Dixie here.
Now we can strut our stuff
While the fans all howl and scream
Whoa, no. That last note
was flatter than a duck's footprint.
Take it from the top, please.
Oh, but Cash,
we've been at it all night.
And we'll be at it all day
if that's what it takes.
This ain't just another show.
The scout from the Grand Ole Opry
is gonna be watchin'.
Take it from the top.
- Copper, just what are you doin'?
- Well, it's a cricket.
- Me and Tod used to...
- What is the matter with you, kid?
- Don't you wanna be a star?
- Well, sure.
- Well, then, why don't you act...
- Cash, he's just a pup.
Copper's just havin' a little fun.
You do remember fun, don't you?
OK, all right.
Just take five, everyone.
Sweetie pie, don't take it to heart.
Cash's bark is worse than his bite.
And if he growls at us again,
I'm gonna muzzle him, myself.
Tod?
You in there?
Cash, have you seen Tod?
Nope. Dixie ain't around, neither.
You were looking for her?
No.
Well...
I remember when I first met her.
I was just a little ol' stray like you,
all paws and ears and...
Felt like a real good-for-nothin'.
- You?
- Yeah.
And then one night,
we went a-howlin' at the moon
and I found out we could sing.
And I said, "Dixie,
this is our ticket to success.
We are gonna be stars."
I guess I'd be stretchin' if I said
I didn't want her around sometimes.
But we're a couple
of hound dudes now, remember?
We can't let old friends
get in the way of that, right?
I guess not.
Oh, come on.
You're havin' fun, ain't you?
Are you kiddin'?
Well, you just wait till we're on top.
We are so close I can smell it.
The Grand Ole Opry.
All we gotta do is ace that audition.
- Right?
- Right.
- Come on, let's go rehearse some more.
- Attaboy.
Copper.
Copper!
Oh, where could that pup
have gotten off to?
Copper!
Tod? Oh, Tod?
Widow, what are you doin' up
this time of night?
Oh, I can't find my Tod anywhere.
That pup of yours
probably chased him off.
I wouldn't know. I can't find him.
Well...
If I see a sign of your puppy,
I'll give you a holler.
I'm obliged.
If I see hide or hair
of that fox of yours...
Well...
Thank you, Amos.
Tod.
- Oh, Tod.
- Copper.
Tod.
Oh, my...
Oh, my hair.
Broke a nail.
That's where Copper lives.
Nice spread.
Could use a woman's touch.
You sure this is a good idea?
It's the only way.
When Clem Clodkicker over there
gets to the fair and sees Copper,
he'll bring him home for sure.
You two get to be friends again.
And I'll reclaim my rightful place
in the spotlight.
We just gotta figure out
how to get them to follow us.
That's the easy part.
See, ol' Chief there hates me.
But he couldn't catch a cold in winter.
And wherever Chief goes,
Slade follows.
Let's see your stuff, there, cowboy.
Chief.
That tickles.
Snuggly-wuggly
little pookie-poo, yeah.
Chief, what the devil is...
Tod.
It's that darn critter of yours.
My critter? It's your huntin'...
Oh, my...
Oh, when I get my hands on you.
Hang on, Tod. I'm comin'.
I've got you in my sights.
You can't get away from me.
I'm a fourth place winner
two times over.
Why, you... You come back here.
Oh, Chief, come back.
Testin'. Testin'.
Why, Cash, look at you.
You're nervous as a flea on dip day.
I haven't seen you like this
in a long time.
You ain't never
seen me like this, Granny.
I just hope that talent scout
fella's in a good mood.
You know, that snake charmer
could use a little more practice.
Don't ya think?
Me, me, me, me
Oh, hey.
Get the lead out of them boots,
Mr. Bickerstaff.
The talent show's just about to start.
I know. I'm excited too.
Blueberry.
Here we are, Mr. Bickerstaff.
Just in time.
Ladies and gentlemen,
The Singin' Strays.
Comin' through.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Tod?
- Copper?
- Chief.
- Tod.
- Copper.
That's my dog.
You ain't a stray?
What in tarnation?
Dixie, what have you done?
Where they goin'?
We can't let them leave.
We got a show to do.
Wait.
That's it! I can't take any more.
I don't book no circuses!
Why, thank you, little lady.
- You've been so kind.
- Drive careful.
Bye, Mr. Bickerstaff.
See you next year.
What are we gonna do now, Cash?
You're gonna go home.
- But, the band.
- Don't you get it?
You're fired.
You know what? You used to be
a lot more fun to be around.
Oh, now, come on. Where you goin'?
Hey...
Oh, yeah? Fine.
We don't need you, either. Right boys?
Sorry, Cash.
It just ain't no fun anymore.
Why does it always rain
when things go wrong?
I don't know, Floyd.
Happy now?
Copper, I'm sorry.
- I just wanted to...
- You ruined everything.
Copper.
Attaboy.
Let's get out of here.
Oh, Tod. There, there, now.
When we were together
I knew that forever I'd always
My days follow you
Into the blue beyond
Never wanna be anywhere I cannot see
The love light you shine
Only wanna be wherever you are
Runnin '
With my friend
You never will be lonely
You need only look right behind you
To find who will follow you
Into
I'd follow you into
I'd follow you
Into
The blue beyond
Copper.
Dixie?
What are you doin' here?
I just thought you should know
that blowin' your cover was my idea.
Not Tod's.
I guess I just lost sight
of what's really important.
And darlin', I'm awful sorry.
He never wanted to hurt you.
He just wanted you
to be his friend again.
Well...
That's what I came to say.
Copper?
- Hi.
We still friends?
I don't know. Aren't you all mad?
Well, I've been thinkin'.
I've been kind of a cabbage head.
If that ain't right,
then grits ain't groceries.
Well, anyway.
I sure am sorry.
Yeah, I'm sorry too.
Hey, I just got a great idea. Hang on.
- I got somethin' for ya.
- Thanks, but I didn't get you anything.
No, it belongs to the talent scout.
I figured you can use it to find him.
You know,
if you still want that audition.
How?
You're a real huntin' dog, aren't ya?
And this here hat is his address.
Yeah, that's it. Get a good whiff.
OK, you get the scout
and I'll go get the band.
Lyle, you fool. There's your problem.
The do-hickey is comin'
out of the watchamacallit
and leakin' all over the hoozanozzle.
Cash. Cash.
- Dixie's in trouble.
- What's happened?
- Trouble?
- What's wrong?
- We gotta go.
- Where?
Sit!
- Where is she?
- Follow me.
All right. That'll do her.
All right, fellers. We are off to...
Fellers?
Waylon?
Cash?
Anybody?
Well, where is she?
That a way.
- Come on, everyone. Follow me.
- This better be her.
I mean it.
Copper, where's Dixie?
She'll be along.
Cash.
Way to go, Copper.
Cash, are you all right?
No, are you all right?
- I'm fine.
What in tarnation?
I thought you were in trouble.
Just exactly why
did you get us all together?
'Cause...
'Cause that's how it ought to be.
Like the words in the song.
Like the sun and blue skies.
Like summer nights and fireflies.
- Like an itch.
- And a scratch.
Well, ain't somebody gonna sing?
We're the perfect match
'Cause we're in harmony
Like a rhyme and a song we all belong
Like a bird in a tree
We were meant to be
Like a nose and a tail
And a horse and a trail
Like a bass and a fiddle
Like a laugh and a riddle
Like a pond and a frog
Like a bump and a log
We 're a hand and a glove
An example of
Gosh, I missed you.
Purebred, down-home
Good sweet harmony
Any crowd we face
Every squirrel we chase
Any time any place
We 're in harmony
Every time we howl
Every line we growl
- Every note
- Every vowel
We 're in harmony
'Cause we 're in harmony
W el l, fry my bacon.
I 've fi nal ly found my act.
You al I gonna be stars.
Wahoo, doggie.
There you fellers are.
Are these here talented canines yours?
Yes. Yes, they are.
We've got to talk.
Come over here, son.
Well, there you go, Cash.
You just got what you always wanted.
Well, maybe I had it all along.
- What are you sayin'?
- What do you think I'm sayin'?
You better be sayin'
what I think you're sayin'.
I think you know what I'm sayin'
is what you think I'm sayin'.
Well...
I thought you'd never ask.
Now, there's the good news.
Somebody smack me,
I must be dreamin'!
We got a little ol' barn called,
The Grand Ole Opry I'd like to show ya.
Yes, sir. That sounds great.
That would be fantastic.
Tod!
Copper?
But, the band.
Aren't you goin' with them?
Can't. You and me,
we got crickets to chase.
And if I ever forget that again,
you just kick me in my walkin' away end.
- Shake on it?
- Shake on it.
We go together
like beggin' and suppertime
Drivin' down the county line
Ears flappin' overtime
We go together like a fiddle and a bow
Diggin ' and a hole
A biscuit and a bone
I don 't care if the cold wind blows
I don 't care if the stars don 't show
You can say it now
You can say it never
But as long as we 're goin ' somewhere
We go together together
Together together
Hey.
We go together like wet dog and smelly
Peanut butter, jelly
Fleas on my belly
We go together like fireflies and jars
Chasin ' after cars
Barkin ' at a shootin ' star
I don 't care if the cold wind blows
I don 't care if the stars don 't show
You can say it now
And you can say it never
But as long as we 're goin ' somewhere
We go together together
Together together
Come on!
W ait for me!
We go together like a song in the air
Like a once in a lifetime
Memory you share
We go together like dreams and prayers
Like a little bit of heaven
And we 're already there
You can say it now
Or say it forever
But as long as we 're goin ' somewhere
We go together together
Together together
Come on!