There is no place on earth quite like it...
Here the astonishing is commonplace.
Fish leap from the water
to catch their prey...
and cats swim.
It is a realm both beautiful...and brutal.
Where adaptation is the key to sumival.
This is the Wild Amazon.
The Amazon Basin.
One of the worlds
greatest natural habitats.
Home to one tenth of all the plant
and animal species on earth.
The world's largest rainforest
is watered by the world¡¦s mightiest river.
The Amazon,
6,000 kilometres long.
This mysterious region
is finally giving up its secrets...
In the past 10 years
a new species has been discovered
on average every three days.
But the Amazon is changing fast...
threatening the animals and plants
that have evolved here
for millions of years.
The race is onto learn more
about this remarkable place
before its too late.
One of the Amazons
most elusive and mysterious creatures
is also the biggest cat in the Americas.
A male jaguar like this one
can grow up to 2 metres long
and weigh 160 kilos.
His name, from an Indian word,
means he who kills with one leap
Md he lives up to that name:
A jaguar usually kills with a single bite
to the back of the head.
His powerful jaws
and 3 centimetre long canines
can easily pierce the skull 0f his prey.
Unlike many cats, who avoid water,
the jaguar is well sdapted to swimming.
He travels along the Amazon¡¦s
intricate maze of waterways
to reach his favourite hunting sites.
But even the jaguar has to be cautious
in these muddy waters.
There are giant snakes,
like anacondas, lurking here...
and they¡¦ve been known to kill jaguars.
Back on dry land, he shifts instantly
into hunting mode.
He¡¦s equipped with keen eyesight
and an acute sense of hearing,
but stealth is another important weapon.
For the animals sharing his habitat,
he¡¦s a creature to fear.
But even a jaguar doesn¡¦t always get
what he¡¦s after.
He may be a top predator,
but that doesnt make his life easy.
Each jaguar¡¦s markings are unique
ideal camouflage in the dense jungle.
But theyve made these big cats a target
for the fur trade.
In the 1960s more than 15,111 jaguars
were killed for their pelts every year.
The trade is now banned,
but the jaguar is still threatened.
These forests are a last refuge.
The Amazon River basin dominates
the northern half of South America.
mm area over half the size Australia.
it¡¦s the green heart of a massive continent.
Md its forests are truly the lungs
0f the planet.
But now,
after millions of years of adaptation,
the Amazons wildlife is threatened,
as the forest around them changes.
Ps the biggest lend predator here,
a jaguar needs as much as
300 square kilometres of forest to thrive.
Scientists are eager to get
a better estimate of the jaguar population
to learn how theyre faring.
If they can determine what¡¦s happening
to this top predator,
they¡¦ll have a better understanding
0f the forest¡¦s interdependent web of life.
If the jaguars are thriving,
there must be plenty 0f prey,
which would be a sign
that that the habitat is healthy too.
But first the scientists must catch one.
They think there are still some in this part
of the jungle
but in four years have only caught three.
Either the cats are simply too wary
to be caught,
or the population here is dangerously low.
With traps set,
the scientists can only wait and hope.
Even ins tropical rainforest
there¡¦s a change of seasons.
In December storm clouds tether,
heralding the start of the hea rains.
For one group of birds
it¡¦s their last chance
to catch a female¡¦s eye
before rain stops play...
The brilliant feathers of male
band¡Xtailed manakin act like a beacon,
signalling to any passing female
to stop by and check him out.
Its up to the female to decide
who has the most dazzling feathers
and the smoothest moves.
Only the best and the brightest
will win a chance to breed.
For this young white¡Xthroated manakin,
colour is less important than dance.
Md hes careful to keep his arena
in perfect order.
Even a single stray leaf
can cost him points.
Its quickly disposed of and with style.
But try as he might,
he doesnt manage to impress this female.
Md he may not get another chance
this season
There isnt much time.
By the end 0f December
the rains have arrived with full force.
In some areas an incredible three meters
will fall in just a few months.
The creatures that live here
must adapt or drown.
Snowmelt from the Andes
and rain from the cloud forests
send over 2tt billion metric tons of water
thundering down the valleys.
Even the Amazon River, the largest
freshwater reservoir on the planet
cant contain that much water.
Every year it overflows its banks,
growing in width by 5 times or more.
Md flooding an area
about the size of the United Kingdom.
Dawn breaks over a world transformed.
Trees here have evolved to deal
with this annual inundation.
They can survive,
even standing in t metres of water.
The forest will stay flooded for op
to seven months.
For animals of the forest floor
it can spell disaster,
unless they can get away.
The long nosed armadillo lives on dry land
and usually travels only at night.
Forced from her flooded burrow
this female desperately swims for safety.
Shes in trove danger.
Predators like the black caiman cruise
the waterways...
and she could sink under the weight
0f her heays shell.
She can hold her breath for a few minutes,
and even walk on the river bottom
if she has to.
To make it across this wide channel,
she swallows air and inflates her stomach
creating a temporary life jacket.
But swimming this far is exhausting.
Md hungry predators are on patrol.
The floods have driven the armadillo out
of her burrow
and into the swollen river
to swim for her life.
This time shes lucky.
Below the surface the flooded forest
is a surreal landscape.
A shadow fgure swims among the branches
where birds once few.
Its a manatee, seeking food and shelter.
The Amazonian manatee
is the smallest of its species...
and the only one in the world
that lives exclusively in fresh water.
M incredibly slow metabolic rate
allows it to stay undemwter
for up to 20 minutes
before it has to surtace for air.
This female has migrated
from the river into the flooded forest.
Floating grasses and water hyacinth flourish
at this time...
and she gorges
on the newly available vegetation.
She can eat up to 15 percent
0f her body weight per day.
Plenty 0f plant matter helps her
produce plenty of milk for her baby.
It will take almost a year for the calf
to be fully weaned.
Md the young manatee may stay with its
mother for another year beyond that,
sheltering in her shadow
and learning how to survioe.
Even in this lush environment,
competition for food can be fierce.
Survivors have evolved ways
to find food where their rivals fail.
One fish has come up
with an extraordinary solution.
Its the silver arowana,
local people call it the water monkey.
It hunts out of the water
as well as below it.
Loitering in shallow pools close to trees,
it stays near the surface...
and keeps an eye out for any movement above.
Once it spots a target,
the arowana launches itself out of the water
and into the air.
It can leap more than two metres
above the surface.
Gaining a crucial edge in the race for food.
These waters are teeming with fish...
which attract plenty of fish hunters.
The Amazon is the last stronghold
for the endangered giant otters
which can grow to almost 2 metres.
They live snd hunt in large social groups.
This group of ten is an extended family,
headed up by mum&dad.
The pack is a welcome sight
to the native Kayapo Indians
who live down river.
Like the fish they eat, giant otters
can only thrive in clean and healthy rivers.
As the planet¡¦s greatest waterway
becomes more polluted,
their sumival is threatened.
People and otters
share this stretch of river
with a small fish with a bad reputation...
the red piranha.
Piranha have a mouth
full of razor sharp teeth.
Md when they¡¦re whipped
into a feeding frenzy
they can rip their prey apart in seconds.
M injured fish discarded
by the otters becomes a convenient victim.
Sound and movement
attract their attention...
but blood is the reel lure.
The Kayapo know it¡¦s safe
for them to swim here.
Despite the rumors,
pirsnhs have little interest in humans.
Living deep in the heart
of the Amazon jungle
the Kayapo were once a powerful nation.
Today, these villagers
are some of the few thousand that remain,
living in scattered settlements
along the riverbank.
They see themselves as part of the forest,
like the creatures with whom they share it.
They depend on the generosity
0f the river and forest,
but theyre careful to take no more
than they need.
At this season, the flooded rivers
offer the only route into the dense jungle.
Today two village elders
are hunting a creature they prize...
and theyve found it...
the long¡Xnosed armadillo.
They believe that the forests plants
and animals share a universal energy,
which must be kept in balance.
They understand that they should respect
all 0f the forests inhabitants...
and be grateful for its gifts.
So, as the elders head home
with their prize,
they sing to the armadillos spirit,
giving thanks for helping the tribe
to survive at least one more day.
The beauty and bounty
0f the Amazon often mask hidden dangers...
Md dark secrets.
Plants are armed with spikes
and laced with poisons...
and snare many animals.
These forests are no garden of Eden,
but a battlefield of survival
and the inhabitants
have had to adapt to its dangers.
The bright markings of the Uakari dart frog
mean only one thing...
keep away...
Chemicals in its skin make it bitter
and unpleasant to eat.
That might explain why the female
can risk laying only a few eggs...
and on a very exposed leaf.
Over time the eggs develop
into tadpoles and start to move.
Md that makes these young ones
even more vulnerable.
Movement can alert predators.
So their father stands guard
during his offsprings first weeks of life.
Predators have learned that the frogs
markings mean an unpleasant supper.
Its tadpoles may taste bad too...
But they dont...not yet.
Their survival now depends
on his protection...
and on one last task
that will help secure their future.
Hell take them on a bold
and dangerous journey
to a higher and safer place.
First the babies have to climb
onto his back.
A thin tim of mucus
will hold them in place.
As they take the ride of their lives.
Pools 0f rainwater captured
by bromeliad plants
provide a secure hiding place
for the developing tadpoles.
This will be the father¡¦s last gift
to his young.
It¡¦s only now
that he will finally leave them.
The pools provide a safe haven
and the nutrient rich water
will sustain the young tadpole
for the neut three months.
Then the small frog will acquire
its own personal tooic defence
and the cycle will begin again.
This hothouse of biodiversity
is slowly giving up its secrets.
Scientists have discovered
more than 1,200 new animals and plants
over the course of a decade.
Md they¡¦re learning how they depend
on one another to survive.
Its a fragile web
0f interlocking relationships.
During the hea rains
many rainforest trees burst into flower.
Their rich nectar attracts bees
and other insects.
Md it also captures the attention
of an extraordinary group of birds.
Hummingbirds are found only in the Americas.
Their beaks and tongues
are specially adapted
to penetrate flower heads
and extract sugary nectar.
The plants have evolved
flower shapes to match,
allowing the hummingbirds
to pollinate them as well as feed.
These tiny birds
may weigh less than two grams
about as much as a couple 0f paper clips.
But they can flap their wings
up to 80 times per second,
and their ability to hover
while feeding on a blossom
is a skill unmatched by any other birds.
To fuel their high¡Xspeed lifestyle,
some can visit up
to twenty flowers s minute.
They¡¦re drawn to red, orange,
and yellow lowers
because those provide the sweetest nectar,
packed with the most energy.
It is during the rainy season that
many species breed and raise their young.
The female long¡Xtailed hermit hummingbird
builds a fragile nest from plant fibres,
spider web and her own saliva.
To keep her hungry chick fed,
she must shuttle constantly
between nest and lowers,
returning with a life sustaining mixture
of nectar&insects.
Shell do the same for the second chick,
once it hatches.
Her intensive feeding regimen
will take up to 2t days,
until the chicks are strong enough
to leave the nest.
For animals that live so fast,
they dont necessarily die young.
This mother may go on producing chicks
for another four years.
It is April.
After nearly five months
the hea rains have subsided.
Md sunny days are more frequent now.
The stage is set
for an extraordinary event...
One of the most unusual partnerships
in the Amazon.
Flooded lagoons on the fringes
of the rainforest offer an ideal home,
for a floating giant...
The Amazon ian giant water lily
is truly a colossus.
It has the second largest
single leaf of any plant in the world.
It grows amazingly fast
up to 25 centimetres every day...
and its strong enough to support
as much as 60 kilos.
This 2 metre long caiman
uses it to lounge in the sun...
and the leaves form a perfect
fshing platform for a green heron.
But its not just its size
that makes this plant remarkable...
Its how it reproduces.
The different coloured flowers
are the clue.
Ps night falls the white flowers
internal temperature rises
up to it degrees warmer
than the surrounding air.
That prompts the flower to open.
The white flower is female
and cant produce pollen.
But it does produce a strong
sweet pineapple¡Xlike scent.
That aroma attracts a tiny scarab beetle,
just 2 centimetres long.
Its one of the lilys main pollinators.
It climbs into the heart
0f the female tower...
carrying a dusting of pollen
picked up from male lily flowers.
As dawn approaches,
the flower cools and closes.
My beetles still inside are now trapped.
But that¡¦s no problem.
They¡¦re safe from heat and danger.
Md even better: they get to spend
all day feasting on starchy nectar.
As the beetle eats,
its load of pollen drops off,
falling onto the flowers
reproductive parts.
There it triggers
a magical transformation.
The white flower blushes pink...
and turns from female to male...
so that it can now produce its own pollen.
When night falls again, the lower opens,
and the beetle
now carrying the newly male flowers pollen
escapes to search for another
sweetly scented white female lily.
Pollination complete, the pink male flower
will die back to a seed
and sink to the bottom of the pool.
Its fertilized seed
will germinate and mature...
to repeat the water lilys
magical transformation next year.
The Amazon is a living laboratory,
where nature has been experimenting
for millions of years.
But habitat destruction
is undoing natures handiwork,
putting many species here at risk.
Knowing the condition of top predators
is a good way to gauge
the health of the forest.
That¡¦s why scientists
have been trying to track
and study jaguars here for your years,
but so far they have only managed
to catch three.
That is not enough for their research.
So they¡¦ve come up with a creative solution.
They¡¦re using some unlikely technology...
M MP3 player and speakers broadcast
a jaguar call into the jungle.
Hopefully an inquisitive cat
will investigate.
Its a long shot but the scientists
are running out of options,
and the jaguars are running out of time.
Many creatures flourish here.
There are over a thousand
species of frogs...
and more than 1500 kinds of birds.
The most successful of all are the insects.
A single square kilometre
may contain 30,000 species.
None are more prolific than the ants.
They¡¦ve changed little
since the time 0f the dinosaurs...
and today they make up over 30 percent
0f the total weight of animals
in the Amazon.
They exploit all parts 0f the forest.
Under the forest floor, up in the treetops,
and everhere in between.
Mts consume more vegetation
in the Amazon than any other creature...
and the cecropia tree
is vulnerable to attack...
Unlike many trees in the Amazon
its leaves arent poisonous
but neither is it defenceless.
The cecropia has evolved
a survival strategy that welcomes an ant,
though the relationship
doesnt seem to start well.
The queen Azteca ant bores a hole
in a soft area of the tree¡¦s branch.
She quickly gets to work colonising
hollow chambers ioside the stems,
perfect for raising an entire army of ants.
The workers tend to the queen
as she lays her precious eggs.
The eggs are placed together,
where they¡¦ll develop
into the nest generation.
There¡¦s also a third party
in this relationship.
They¡¦re called scale insects.
They feed off sugars found
in the inner part of the tree¡¦s bark.
When the ants manipulate the scale insects,
some of this oozes out through their bodies
and is eaten by the ants.
So why does the tree
tolerate these alien invaders?
That becomes clear when a hungry beetle
makes its way to the trees leaves.
Movement on the stems alerts the snts.
The workers mobilize...
and immediately respond...
They track down their target... and attack.
The ants have a ferocious bite
and grab the soft parts of the beetle.
The beetle is soon covered with ants...
fighting for its life...against an army
thats defending its home tort.
For the beetle,
a hasty retreat is the only option.
The ants are free
to enjoy the trees hospitality
while taking only what they need...
and the tree has its own defence force.
Its a perfect partnership for survival.
The rain forest¡¦s upper canopy can reach up
to 50 metres above the forest floor.
So inaccessible that many of its creatures
remain a mystery.
When scientists get the chance
to eoplore it they often find something new.
Just in the last decade,
nine new primates have been discovered.
The canopy¡¦s wide range of habitats,
can accommodate a wide variety of primates.
Tiny tamarins, the size of a coconut,
live alongside t kilo howler monkeys.
One of the most bizarre looking...
is the Red Uakari that shares
its name with the poison frog.
Local people call it the English monkey
because its red face looks like
a pale skinned foreigner
whos been in the sun for too long.
In fact that red face serves
an important purpose.
The brighter the colour,
the healthier the animal.
That¡¦s a vital sign to look
for in selecting a mate.
When trees are in fruit uakaris spend most
0f their time foraging in the upper canopy.
They use their amazingly strong lower jaws
to open the tough skins
of unripe fruits and nuts
which other primates have to abandon.
Their small tails are unique
among Amazon monkeys.
But that shortcoming doesn¡¦t stop them
travelling through the trees with ease.
Family members groom each other
to strengthen bonds
and to establish a pecking order.
Their social hierarchy is crucial
for keeping the troop together.
Juvenile males forge their own relationships
throogh play and mock ights
Sometimes its hard to tell which is which.
Their antics seme another purpose:
helping young monkeys develop the skills
theyll need to survive in the csnopy.
The dry season is approaching
and the troop must take advantage
of the last remaining fruits of the flood.
A careless fumble provides a treat
to the tambaqui fish
lurking in the shallows below.
The lush green world of the canopy
is not withoot dangers.
A squirrel monkey spots
a harpy eagle and sounds the alarm,
alerting everything in earshot.
The giant Harpy eagle is well¡Xadapted
to life in the thick canopy.
Md it¡¦s fully capable
of plucking a monkey right off a branch.
A determined male with a chick
to feed poses a special threat.
Ranging far and wide to find food,
its nest is over 3 kilometres away
at the top of a giant tree.
The cumaru tree can grow up
to a height of 5t metres.
Local people prize its bsrk
and seeds as medicine,
using it to treat everything
from snake bite to earache.
The female harpy eagle
and her chick nest safely in its crown.
She is truly a giant,
the largest raptor in the Americas,
with ewing span of up to two meters.
Her talons are as large as a grizzly bears.
capable of grabbing prey
that weighs half as much as she does.
In spite of her size end strength,
her chick is at risk from many enemies,
including disease¡Xcarrying flies.
Like the native tribes,
it seems the mother understsnds something
about the health benefits of plants.
She frequently brings fresh green twigs
and branches to freshen the nest.
Her efforts seem to keep parasites
and insects away from her precious chick.
But there are other threats
for which she has no defence.
The valuable hardwood
0f the cumaru tree is sought out by loggers.
Man may not be king of this jungle,
but with a chainsaw in his hand,
he can rule supreme.
Nearly 20 percent 0f the Amazon rainforest
has already been cleared,
threatening not only the harpy eagle,
but all life on earth.
The forest is a vast storehouse of carbon.
Md its destruction releases massive amounts
of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.
That contributes to global climate change.
As the trees disappear,
the worldwide threat grows...
and wildlife in the Amazon is in peril.
Forest loss presents a special danger
for the threatened harpy eagle,
This is the mothers third attempt
at nest¡Xbuilding.
Md the third tree she has selected.
The previous two have been cut down.
It takes harpy eagles a year
to raise a single chick.
Will this one grow to adolthood?
The foresters are only a kilometre away.
Ps the season shifts from wet to dry,
water levels are dropping.
The receding floodwaters will allow jaguars
to expand their hunting grounds.
Md that could give the scientists
a better chance of locating
and capturing their quarry.
They are eater to learn more
about the big cats behaviour...
and to assess the overall health
0f this part 0f the Mnazon.
The speakers are already
broadcasting jaguar calls.
Maybe this simple technology
will make the difference.
They dont have long to wait.
They¡¦ve captured
a young female in her prime.
She¡¦ll soon be ready to breed...
and her success will be a real test
0f the health of the environment.
They need to sedate her quickly and safely.
This is the most dangerous part
of the project,
for both the scientists and the animal.
The drugs work fast.
Now they can the gather information
they need.
A radio collar and GPS tracking tag
will allow the scientists to follow
the jaguars movements through the forest.
This research will provide clues
to her behaviour
during the dry season to come.
Md that will help the scientists
understand more clearly
how she survives in her secret domain.
The insights they gain could help secure
the future 0f the forest itself.
The Amazon is I lied
with questions waiting to be answered...
Mysteries to be solved.
Ceaseless change is at its heart.
With the end of the floods,
the forest re¡Xemerges.
Birds return to brsnches
that sheltered fish.
Mnazing stories of adaptation
have been the key to survival here
for millions of years.
But as the world changes,
can the Amazon endure?