Title:
Original Script:
Synch Point:0
ScriptType:v4.00+
Collisions:Normal
PlayResX:864
PlayResY:480
Timer:100.0000

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,simhei,30,&H00FFFFFF,&H00000000,&H14121212,&H320D0D0D,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0.00,1,2,1,2,30,30,10,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Actor, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.98,0:00:06.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(432,450)\fad(0,700)\fscx80}
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.98,0:00:06.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(435,465)\fad(0,700)\fsp3\fnarial\fs24\fscy55}
Dialogue: 0,0:00:03.82,0:00:06.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(0,700)}秒速五厘米
Dialogue: 0,0:00:12.00,0:00:14.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呐 听说是秒速五厘米哦
Dialogue: 0,0:00:14.97,0:00:16.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯？你说什么？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:16.63,0:00:20.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,樱花花瓣飘落的速度 每秒五厘米
Dialogue: 0,0:00:22.80,0:00:25.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里很清楚这种事情嘛
Dialogue: 0,0:00:25.38,0:00:26.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哼哼
Dialogue: 0,0:00:27.82,0:00:31.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呐 我说 这些 不觉得就像是是飘落的雪花吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:00:31.97,0:00:32.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,会吗?
Dialogue: 0,0:00:37.53,0:00:38.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,欸 等等啊
Dialogue: 0,0:00:45.34,0:00:46.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里！
Dialogue: 0,0:00:46.29,0:00:47.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,贵树君
Dialogue: 0,0:00:49.90,0:00:53.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明年，也能一起看樱花就好了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:01:07.26,0:01:10.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“致远野贵树 久疏问候还望多多包涵”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:16.32,0:01:18.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我这里的夏天虽然也很热”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:18.98,0:01:21.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“但和东京相比还是要凉快不少”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:22.46,0:01:24.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“不过现在回想起来”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:24.45,0:01:27.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我也很喜欢东京那闷热的夏日”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:28.21,0:01:30.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“无论是烫得像要熔化般的柏油路”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:30.86,0:01:32.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“还是被热气笼罩的高楼”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:32.96,0:01:36.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“抑或是商场和地铁里让人发寒的冷气”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:37.13,0:01:41.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我们最后一次见面是在小学的毕业典礼上”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:41.50,0:01:43.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“分别后已过了半年”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:43.53,0:01:45.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}岛田 别慢吞吞地走 给我跑起来
Dialogue: 0,0:01:44.38,0:01:46.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我说 贵树君…”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:46.94,0:01:50.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“…还记得我吗？”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:53.98,0:01:56.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“前略 致贵树君”
Dialogue: 0,0:01:56.73,0:01:59.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“谢谢你的回信 我很高兴”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:00.49,0:02:02.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“现在已经完全入秋了呢”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:02.45,0:02:04.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“这里的红叶很漂亮”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:05.17,0:02:08.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“今年的第一件毛衣,我在前天织好了”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:10.29,0:02:11.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野同学
Dialogue: 0,0:02:11.23,0:02:12.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,学姐
Dialogue: 0,0:02:12.57,0:02:13.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,什么东西 情书？
Dialogue: 0,0:02:14.34,0:02:15.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不是啦
Dialogue: 0,0:02:15.38,0:02:17.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思 活都丢给你一个人了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:17.10,0:02:18.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会 很快就能做完了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:18.45,0:02:19.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:19.27,0:02:21.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对了 你真的要转学？
Dialogue: 0,0:02:21.15,0:02:23.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 是的 第三学期结束后吧
Dialogue: 0,0:02:23.35,0:02:24.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要去哪里？
Dialogue: 0,0:02:24.47,0:02:26.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鹿儿岛 因为父母的关系
Dialogue: 0,0:02:26.79,0:02:28.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来如此 想必会很寂寞呢
Dialogue: 0,0:02:28.80,0:02:31.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“最近因为社团活动的关系要早起”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:31.41,0:02:33.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“现在,在电车上写的这封信”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:34.48,0:02:36.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“前段时间去剪了头发”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:36.92,0:02:39.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“因为都短到能露出耳朵的程度了”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:39.54,0:02:43.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“就算见面了，也有可能认不出我来吧”
Dialogue: 0,0:02:43.50,0:02:44.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我回来了
Dialogue: 0,0:02:44.46,0:02:45.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回来啦
Dialogue: 0,0:02:54.37,0:02:58.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“贵树君一定也在慢慢地改变吧”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:13.74,0:03:18.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“敬启 这段时间天很冷 你身体还好吗”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:23.27,0:03:25.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我这里已经下过好几场雪了”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:26.06,0:03:29.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“每到那时我都是裹得严严实实才去上学”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:30.99,0:03:33.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“东京应该还没下雪吧”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:33.97,0:03:36.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“虽然我已经搬家了 但老习惯难改”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:36.28,0:03:39.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“看天气预报时总会连东京地区的也一起看”
Dialogue: 0,0:03:43.89,0:03:45.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好想来场雨啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:45.63,0:03:47.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过室内训练也不轻松啊
Dialogue: 0,0:03:48.59,0:03:51.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你们去过栃木吗
Dialogue: 0,0:03:51.16,0:03:52.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你说哪儿？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:52.41,0:03:53.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,栃木
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.22,0:03:53.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:03:54.43,0:03:55.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要怎么去呢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:56.08,0:03:58.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不清楚 坐新干线吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:59.22,0:04:00.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真远啊
Dialogue: 0,0:04:02.94,0:04:03.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一年级的！
Dialogue: 0,0:04:03.46,0:04:04.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在！
Dialogue: 0,0:04:05.35,0:04:06.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后三圈！
Dialogue: 0,0:04:08.51,0:04:12.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“听说贵树君你要转学 让我吃了一惊”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.92,0:04:16.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“虽说我们两人早已习惯了转学”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:17.42,0:04:19.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“但竟然是鹿儿岛”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:19.85,0:04:21.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“这次,稍微有点远了呢”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:23.25,0:04:28.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“一想到这已不再是想见面 就可以乘电车相见的距离”


Dialogue: 0,0:04:28.90,0:04:29.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“果然是…”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:29.82,0:04:33.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“有点…稍微有点寂寞了”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:34.40,0:04:37.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“还请保佑贵树君能一直有精神”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.78,0:04:54.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“前略 致贵树君”
Dialogue: 0,0:04:56.24,0:04:59.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“三月四号的约定 让我非常高兴”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:00.00,0:05:02.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我们有一年没见面了吧”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:02.81,0:05:04.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“总觉得有点紧张”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.43,0:05:15.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我家附近有棵很大的樱花树”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.71,0:05:17.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“到了春天，那儿大概也会有…”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.21,0:05:20.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“以每秒五厘米的速度落到地上的花瓣”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.33,0:05:28.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我想，春天和贵树君一起，快点到来就好了”
Dialogue: 0,0:05:46.68,0:05:48.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(放学后去哪里转转吧)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:48.24,0:05:49.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(不过在下雨啊)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.89,0:05:51.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(天气预报说傍晚会下雪呢)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:52.17,0:05:53.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(不会吧 怪不得那么冷)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:54.26,0:05:55.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(都已经三月了啊)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:55.91,0:05:57.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(这样挺容易感冒的呢)
Dialogue: 0,0:05:57.74,0:06:00.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(那我们在下北站下去喝点热饮暖暖身吧)
Dialogue: 0,0:06:00.76,0:06:01.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(好啊)
Dialogue: 0,0:06:02.53,0:06:05.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野 去参加社团活动吧
Dialogue: 0,0:06:07.99,0:06:10.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个…我今天有点事 不去社团了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:10.81,0:06:11.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,做搬家的准备？
Dialogue: 0,0:06:12.12,0:06:13.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,差不多吧 抱歉了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:14.40,0:06:18.19,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“能到我附近的车站来实在是太好了”
Dialogue: 0,0:06:18.54,0:06:21.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“但是路途遥远 还望多加小心”
Dialogue: 0,0:06:22.57,0:06:26.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我会在约定的晚上七点在车站候车室等你”
Dialogue: 0,0:06:45.76,0:06:47.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和明里约好的那一天
Dialogue: 0,0:06:48.30,0:06:50.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一过中午就下起了雪
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.41,0:06:55.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你看 贵树君
Dialogue: 0,0:06:55.39,0:06:57.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,猫咪 是巧比呢
Dialogue: 0,0:06:57.82,0:06:59.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这只猫总是呆在这附近呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.02,0:07:01.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过它今天好像挺孤单的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:02.21,0:07:05.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咪咪到哪去了？你一个人很孤单吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:02.21,0:07:07.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24\fsp-1}巧比 咪咪 这两只的猫的名字出自新海诚旧作《她与她的猫》
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.99,0:07:17.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那本书怎么样
Dialogue: 0,0:07:18.04,0:07:21.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很不错呢 昨天一晚上看完了四十亿年的章节
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.99,0:07:21.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}这里的书指川崎悟司所著《古世界の住人》
Dialogue: 0,0:07:21.68,0:07:22.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看到哪里了？
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.62,0:07:24.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看到奇虾（Anomalocaris）出现的那里
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.57,0:07:24.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8\fs44}アノマロカリス：奇虾，古生代寒武纪时生活在海中的一种生物
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.63,0:07:25.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,寒武纪！
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.21,0:07:30.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我比较喜欢怪诞虫（Hallucigenia）呢 看 这样子的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.17,0:07:30.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8\fs44}ハルキゲニア：怪诞虫，也是古寒武纪时生活在海中的一种生物
Dialogue: 0,0:07:30.97,0:07:32.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也许很像呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:32.30,0:07:33.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,贵树君你喜欢什么呢
Dialogue: 0,0:07:33.87,0:07:35.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,欧巴宾海蝎（Opabinia）吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:33.99,0:07:34.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\an8\fs44}オパビニア：欧巴宾海蝎，同样是古寒武纪时生活在海中的一种生物
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.07,0:07:37.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 有五只眼睛的那东西吧
Dialogue: 0,0:07:37.65,0:07:41.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我总觉得 我和明里在精神层面上很有些相似之处
Dialogue: 0,0:07:43.55,0:07:45.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我转学到东京一年后
Dialogue: 0,0:07:46.46,0:07:48.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里也转到了同一个班级
Dialogue: 0,0:07:50.66,0:07:53.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当时的我们体弱多病
Dialogue: 0,0:07:53.85,0:07:55.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不大去操场运动 更喜欢逛图书馆
Dialogue: 0,0:07:56.63,0:07:59.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}《地海传说》第一部《地海巫师》\n《空中花园》《纳尼亚传奇》第四部《凯斯宾王子》
Dialogue: 0,0:07:56.56,0:07:59.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以我们很自然地亲密起来
Dialogue: 0,0:07:59.33,0:08:03.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也因此常被同学们捉弄
Dialogue: 0,0:08:03.03,0:08:03.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过…
Dialogue: 0,0:08:05.73,0:08:06.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只要我们在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.89,0:08:10.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,（结婚恭喜       贵树|明里       太般配了）
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.89,0:08:10.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就会很不可思议地觉得 这些事也没什么好怕的
Dialogue: 0,0:08:15.99,0:08:18.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们俩将来会上同一所中学
Dialogue: 0,0:08:18.83,0:08:21.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,以后也会永远在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:08:21.22,0:08:24.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当时的我 不知为何 一直这样坚信着
Dialogue: 0,0:08:28.47,0:08:32.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(新宿到了 新宿到了 这里是终点站 请下车的乘客们…)
Dialogue: 0,0:08:34.76,0:08:37.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(可以换乘JR线  京王线及地铁)
Dialogue: 0,0:08:41.88,0:08:44.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是我第一次一个人来到新宿站
Dialogue: 0,0:08:45.22,0:08:48.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,接下来要搭乘的线路也都从来没坐过
Dialogue: 0,0:08:56.00,0:08:57.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我非常地紧张
Dialogue: 0,0:09:01.19,0:09:04.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为 我马上就要见到明里了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.79,0:09:12.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(之前那个男孩怎么样？)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:12.67,0:09:13.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(谁啊)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.83,0:09:14.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(就是那个西商的)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:14.92,0:09:18.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(啊？你的品味还真差呢)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.27,0:09:19.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(前方到站武藏浦和 武藏浦和)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:20.25,0:09:24.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因为将在武藏浦和等待快速列车)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:25.04,0:09:27.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本次列车将停留四分钟左右)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:27.92,0:09:31.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(赶往与野本町和大宫方向的乘客请到对面…)
Dialogue: 0,0:09:53.55,0:09:56.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个…我姓筱原
Dialogue: 0,0:09:56.71,0:09:59.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请问…贵树同学在不在
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.47,0:10:01.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里打来的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:03.19,0:10:04.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 转学？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:06.39,0:10:09.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那西中呢 你好不容易考上的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.89,0:10:13.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,爸妈说会帮我在栃木的公立中学办好手续的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:14.58,0:10:15.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:10:16.66,0:10:19.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不…这不是明里的错
Dialogue: 0,0:10:19.67,0:10:23.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也说过我可以住在葛饰的姑姑家里
Dialogue: 0,0:10:23.57,0:10:26.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是他们说我年纪还太小 不肯答应
Dialogue: 0,0:10:28.64,0:10:30.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了 算了
Dialogue: 0,0:10:31.42,0:10:32.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,够了…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:35.87,0:10:36.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起…
Dialogue: 0,0:10:38.57,0:10:41.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,透过那按得耳朵发痛的话筒
Dialogue: 0,0:10:42.19,0:10:45.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我能清楚地感受到明里受了多大的伤害
Dialogue: 0,0:10:45.74,0:10:48.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 我却无能为力
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.02,0:10:56.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(那家店味道不错呢)
Dialogue: 0,0:10:56.31,0:10:57.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(嗯 那下次见)
Dialogue: 0,0:10:57.22,0:11:01.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,换车的终点站里准备回家的人们摩肩接踵
Dialogue: 0,0:11:01.79,0:11:04.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,每个人的鞋子上都浸透着融化的雪水
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.37,0:11:09.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,空气很冷 透着下雪天里都市独有的味道
Dialogue: 0,0:11:10.51,0:11:12.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(各位乘客请注意)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:12.65,0:11:15.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(宇都宫线 小山·宇都宫方向的列车)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:16.01,0:11:19.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因下雪的缘故 将晚点八分钟左右到达)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:19.48,0:11:26.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解  还请乘客们耐心等待)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:22.48,0:11:27.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在此瞬间之前 我甚至从未考虑过电车晚点的可能性
Dialogue: 0,0:11:28.72,0:11:31.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不安的感觉突然强烈起来
Dialogue: 0,0:11:36.29,0:11:40.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因下雪的缘故 本次列车将晚点十分钟左右)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:41.18,0:11:44.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解)
Dialogue: 0,0:11:47.69,0:11:49.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,列车刚过大宫站不久
Dialogue: 0,0:11:50.60,0:11:53.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,窗外的风景中已难得一见建筑物的踪影
Dialogue: 0,0:12:06.17,0:12:08.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(下一站是久喜 久喜)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:10.36,0:12:13.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(我们为到站的大幅延迟深表歉意)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:14.59,0:12:18.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(要转乘东武伊势崎线的乘客 请走五号出口)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:20.87,0:12:22.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因后续列车晚点)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:22.87,0:12:25.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本车将在这个车站停留十分钟左右)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:26.81,0:12:31.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解 还请乘客们耐心等待)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.63,0:12:35.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:12:35.69,0:12:37.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因为后续列车晚点)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:37.45,0:12:40.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本次列车将在该站停留十分钟左右)
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.17,0:12:45.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解 还请乘客们耐心等待)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:06.92,0:13:08.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(野木 野木到了)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:09.60,0:13:12.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(非常抱歉地通知各位乘客)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:12.38,0:13:13.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(因后续列车的延迟)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:13.82,0:13:16.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本次列车将在该车站滞留片刻)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:16.87,0:13:22.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解 还请乘客们耐心等待)
Dialogue: 0,0:13:17.96,0:13:21.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,站与站之间的距离 长得令人难以置信
Dialogue: 0,0:13:22.46,0:13:26.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,电车在站台停留的时间 也久得那样脱离现实
Dialogue: 0,0:13:48.28,0:13:51.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管是窗外那未曾见过的原野雪景
Dialogue: 0,0:13:52.64,0:13:54.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是那缓缓流逝的时间
Dialogue: 0,0:13:54.97,0:13:56.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抑或是那饿得发痛的肚子
Dialogue: 0,0:13:57.10,0:13:59.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都让我越发地不安起来
Dialogue: 0,0:14:02.12,0:14:08.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,已经过了约好的时间 现在明里肯定也开始担心了
Dialogue: 0,0:14:13.06,0:14:16.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那天…她打来电话的那天
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.84,0:14:20.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对应该抱有比我更多不安感的明里
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.70,0:14:23.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却没有说出一句安慰话的我
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.38,0:14:26.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,感到…非常的害臊
Dialogue: 0,0:14:27.69,0:14:41.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(青青校树 萋萋庭草 欣霑化雨如膏)
Dialogue: 0,0:14:34.03,0:14:38.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我走了 今天就要说再见了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:14:40.55,0:14:44.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,收到明里的第一封信是在那之后半年
Dialogue: 0,0:14:44.92,0:14:46.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我上初一的那个夏天
Dialogue: 0,0:14:47.47,0:14:50.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我至今还记得她在信上都写了些什么
Dialogue: 0,0:14:51.71,0:14:54.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,直到约定好的今天为止 我花了两周时间
Dialogue: 0,0:14:54.83,0:14:57.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,写好了要当面交给她的信
Dialogue: 0,0:14:58.21,0:15:00.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想传达给她的心意
Dialogue: 0,0:15:00.48,0:15:01.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,想让她倾听的告白
Dialogue: 0,0:15:02.12,0:15:04.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,早在我心底压抑了许久
Dialogue: 0,0:15:05.00,0:15:09.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(各位乘客久等了 本次列车即将开往宇都宫)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.51,0:15:27.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(小山 小山到了 要换乘东北新干线的乘客请在本站下车)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:28.77,0:15:32.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(换乘东北新干线下行前往盛冈的乘客请到一号站台)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:33.21,0:15:37.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(上行前往东京方向的乘客请到五号站台换乘)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:37.58,0:15:40.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(换乘水户线的乘客…)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:38.67,0:15:40.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(各位乘客请注意)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:41.02,0:15:46.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(两毛线的列车由于下雪的缘故 将会大幅晚点)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:46.81,0:15:53.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解 还请乘客们耐心等待)
Dialogue: 0,0:15:55.75,0:16:01.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,此刻我能做的 只有尽快赶到明里在等待着的那个车站
Dialogue: 0,0:16:55.64,0:17:00.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(八号站台 足利·前桥方向 开往高崎的上行列车即将进站)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:00.90,0:17:02.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(请退至白线内侧…)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:34.70,0:17:36.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(各位乘客请注意)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:36.89,0:17:39.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(由于降雪导致列车时刻表混乱)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:39.89,0:17:41.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本次列车将停车片刻)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:41.96,0:17:43.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:44.17,0:17:46.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(目前还没有复原的明确时间)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:47.61,0:17:48.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(重复)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:49.16,0:17:51.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(由于降雪导致列车时刻表混乱)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.83,0:17:53.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(本次列车将停车片刻)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:53.92,0:17:55.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(给各位造成了诸多不便 敬请谅解)
Dialogue: 0,0:17:56.09,0:17:58.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(目前还没有复原的明确时间)
Dialogue: 0,0:18:03.21,0:18:05.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“贵树君 你身体还好吗”
Dialogue: 0,0:18:06.44,0:18:08.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“最近因为社团活动出门很早”
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.30,0:18:10.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“现在这封信是在电车上写的”
Dialogue: 0,0:18:10.82,0:18:15.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不知为何 我从信中所想象到的明里 总是孤零零一个人
Dialogue: 0,0:18:19.89,0:18:21.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最终,电车
Dialogue: 0,0:18:22.46,0:18:25.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就在空无一物的荒野上停开了两个小时
Dialogue: 0,0:18:26.86,0:18:29.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时间满怀着恶意从我头上缓缓流过
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.32,0:18:35.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让我觉得每一分钟都是如此地漫长
Dialogue: 0,0:18:37.12,0:18:39.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而我只能拼命咬紧牙关
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.79,0:18:44.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,忍耐着让自己不至于放声哭泣
Dialogue: 0,0:18:46.23,0:18:47.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里…
Dialogue: 0,0:18:48.65,0:18:56.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你要是已经回去就好了…
Dialogue: 0,0:19:11.28,0:19:15.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(三号站台 足利·前桥方向 开往高崎的列车已经到站)
Dialogue: 0,0:19:18.43,0:19:21.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(由于积雪 本次列车将在该站停留片刻)
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.61,0:19:59.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里
Dialogue: 0,0:20:29.66,0:20:30.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真好喝
Dialogue: 0,0:20:31.66,0:20:34.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗 这只是普通的焙茶而已
Dialogue: 0,0:20:34.27,0:20:37.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,焙茶？我还是第一次喝呢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:37.33,0:20:39.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,骗人 你以前肯定喝过
Dialogue: 0,0:20:39.76,0:20:40.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:20:40.62,0:20:41.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:20:42.54,0:20:43.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有这个
Dialogue: 0,0:20:44.64,0:20:47.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然是我自己做的 味道没法保证…
Dialogue: 0,0:20:48.43,0:20:50.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不嫌弃的话就吃吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:50.38,0:20:51.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:20:52.94,0:20:54.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肚子早就已经很饿了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:58.81,0:20:59.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么样？
Dialogue: 0,0:21:04.03,0:21:06.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我从没吃过这么好吃的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:21:07.34,0:21:08.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,太夸张了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:08.62,0:21:09.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是说真的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:09.82,0:21:11.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定是肚子饿的关系
Dialogue: 0,0:21:11.42,0:21:12.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:21:12.65,0:21:13.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:21:13.85,0:21:15.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也吃吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.43,0:21:22.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你就快搬家了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:21:22.76,0:21:24.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 下星期
Dialogue: 0,0:21:24.30,0:21:25.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,鹿儿岛啊…
Dialogue: 0,0:21:25.97,0:21:26.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很远的
Dialogue: 0,0:21:26.88,0:21:27.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:21:28.81,0:21:30.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过栃木也够远呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:31.03,0:21:32.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远得都回不去了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:21:36.19,0:21:39.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就快关门了 已经没有电车了
Dialogue: 0,0:21:39.14,0:21:39.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 好
Dialogue: 0,0:21:40.47,0:21:42.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,雪下得很大 路上要小心
Dialogue: 0,0:21:42.62,0:21:43.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:22:07.49,0:22:09.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,看到了吗？那棵树
Dialogue: 0,0:22:09.75,0:22:10.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,信上写的那棵树？
Dialogue: 0,0:22:11.13,0:22:13.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 樱花树
Dialogue: 0,0:22:20.42,0:22:21.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呐
Dialogue: 0,0:22:22.53,0:22:24.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你不觉得 这很像是飘落的雪花？
Dialogue: 0,0:22:32.87,0:22:33.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:22:44.24,0:22:45.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那一瞬间
Dialogue: 0,0:22:46.66,0:22:51.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我似乎明白了“永远”“心灵”和“灵魂”之所在
Dialogue: 0,0:22:52.86,0:22:57.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,感到两人十三年中经历过的一切在此刻交融
Dialogue: 0,0:22:57.15,0:22:59.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后在下一个瞬间
Dialogue: 0,0:23:00.34,0:23:03.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却又悲伤得无法抑制
Dialogue: 0,0:23:05.07,0:23:12.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为 我不知道该如何珍藏明里的这份温暖
Dialogue: 0,0:23:12.67,0:23:14.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也不知道该将她的灵魂带往何处
Dialogue: 0,0:23:18.19,0:23:23.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我清楚地知道 我们无法保证将来能永远在一起
Dialogue: 0,0:23:24.67,0:23:29.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,横亘在我们面前的是那沉重的人生与漫长的时间
Dialogue: 0,0:23:29.92,0:23:32.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,让人望而却步
Dialogue: 0,0:23:35.40,0:23:41.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 这束缚着我的不安 最终还是慢慢地消失
Dialogue: 0,0:23:41.66,0:23:46.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,剩下的 只有明里那柔软的双唇传来的触感
Dialogue: 0,0:24:04.20,0:24:09.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我们在田边一个小仓库里过了一夜
Dialogue: 0,0:24:11.47,0:24:14.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,裹着老旧的毯子 聊了很久很久
Dialogue: 0,0:24:15.46,0:24:17.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,最后不知不觉地睡着了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.03,0:24:24.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,清晨 乘上第一班列车 我与明里分别了
Dialogue: 0,0:24:27.96,0:24:30.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那个…贵树君
Dialogue: 0,0:24:32.41,0:24:38.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,贵树君你以后的生活 我想一定会很顺利的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:38.87,0:24:39.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢
Dialogue: 0,0:24:41.58,0:24:43.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,明里你也要保重
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.56,0:24:44.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我会写信的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:44.70,0:24:45.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还会打电话
Dialogue: 0,0:24:58.71,0:25:03.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我没有告诉明里 要交给她的信被我弄丢了
Dialogue: 0,0:25:05.94,0:25:12.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为我觉得 自那个吻之后 这个世界的一切都已改变
Dialogue: 0,0:25:20.87,0:25:25.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我越来越感觉到自己需要能保护她的力量
Dialogue: 0,0:25:26.10,0:25:33.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(0,900)}我一边久久地眺望着窗外的景色 一边如此想到
Dialogue: 0,0:27:01.81,0:27:03.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,花苗 放学后也要去吗
Dialogue: 0,0:27:04.06,0:27:05.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 姐姐你方便吗
Dialogue: 0,0:27:05.91,0:27:08.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我是有空 不过你也要好好学习啊
Dialogue: 0,0:27:08.40,0:27:09.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:27:55.19,0:27:55.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,早上好
Dialogue: 0,0:27:56.76,0:27:58.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,早上好 远野同学
Dialogue: 0,0:27:58.60,0:27:59.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天又来这么早啊
Dialogue: 0,0:27:59.89,0:28:02.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田你也很早啊 去过海边了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:03.67,0:28:04.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你挺努力的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:28:06.41,0:28:07.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,也没有啦…
Dialogue: 0,0:28:09.09,0:28:10.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,回头见 远野同学
Dialogue: 0,0:28:10.76,0:28:11.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:28:14.05,0:28:16.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听好了 你们也到了该决定出路的时候了
Dialogue: 0,0:28:16.98,0:28:18.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下星期一前交上来
Dialogue: 0,0:28:19.19,0:28:21.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好好和家里人商量一下
Dialogue: 0,0:28:23.69,0:28:26.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,佐佐木好像要去东京的大学呢
Dialogue: 0,0:28:26.57,0:28:29.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真强啊 我大概只能上熊本的短期大学了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:30.34,0:28:31.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,花苗呢
Dialogue: 0,0:28:33.66,0:28:34.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要找工作吗
Dialogue: 0,0:28:36.44,0:28:38.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你真的什么都没考虑啊
Dialogue: 0,0:28:39.05,0:28:40.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,脑子里只有远野同学
Dialogue: 0,0:28:40.73,0:28:42.92,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他在东京肯定有女朋友的啦
Dialogue: 0,0:28:43.04,0:28:44.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,才不会呢
Dialogue: 0,0:29:12.03,0:29:13.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是不行吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:29:14.54,0:29:15.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,到底是怎么搞的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:29:16.85,0:29:18.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你最好不要太过烦恼
Dialogue: 0,0:29:19.14,0:29:20.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定能成功的
Dialogue: 0,0:29:20.82,0:29:22.95,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,姐姐你还真是乐观
Dialogue: 0,0:29:23.19,0:29:24.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那你又着什么急呢
Dialogue: 0,0:29:26.87,0:29:29.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这样下去 搞不好到毕业都说不出口
Dialogue: 0,0:29:49.33,0:29:50.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你了 姐姐
Dialogue: 0,0:29:50.92,0:29:52.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我送你回去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:29:52.29,0:29:53.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不用了 我骑摩托车回去
Dialogue: 0,0:30:21.86,0:30:23.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田 现在才回去吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:30:23.75,0:30:25.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 远野同学你也是？
Dialogue: 0,0:30:25.95,0:30:26.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:30:27.21,0:30:28.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一起走吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:30:29.55,0:30:31.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果我和狗一样长着尾巴
Dialogue: 0,0:30:32.65,0:30:36.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定掩饰不住满心欢喜 乱摇个不停了
Dialogue: 0,0:30:37.49,0:30:41.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一边为自己不是狗而感到庆幸
Dialogue: 0,0:30:42.56,0:30:46.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一边又忍不住责怪自己的愚蠢
Dialogue: 0,0:30:46.23,0:30:50.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,即使如此 和远野一起回家的时光却是那样的幸福
Dialogue: 0,0:30:53.81,0:30:59.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,第一次见到远野时 就觉得他似乎和其他男生有些不同
Dialogue: 0,0:31:00.59,0:31:01.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我叫远野贵树
Dialogue: 0,0:31:01.99,0:31:04.09,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然因为父母工作的原因已经习惯了转学
Dialogue: 0,0:31:04.72,0:31:06.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但还没习惯这个岛上的生活
Dialogue: 0,0:31:06.95,0:31:08.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还请大家多多关照
Dialogue: 0,0:31:08.31,0:31:10.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在初二的那天就喜欢上了他
Dialogue: 0,0:31:10.75,0:31:12.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为想和他上同一所高中
Dialogue: 0,0:31:13.30,0:31:16.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拼了命地用功 好不容易才考上
Dialogue: 0,0:31:16.69,0:31:21.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但即使如此 每次看到他的时候都更加地喜欢他
Dialogue: 0,0:31:22.06,0:31:24.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对这样的自己感到害怕 每天都很苦恼
Dialogue: 0,0:31:25.13,0:31:29.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然而每次见面又会感到很幸福 无法控制自己
Dialogue: 0,0:31:32.17,0:31:33.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野同学你还是买那个啊
Dialogue: 0,0:31:34.44,0:31:35.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这个很好喝的
Dialogue: 0,0:31:36.32,0:31:39.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,总觉得澄田你做什么都这么认真呢
Dialogue: 0,0:31:39.71,0:31:40.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:31:42.95,0:31:43.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我先走了
Dialogue: 0,0:31:44.68,0:31:45.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,0:31:46.12,0:31:47.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给我这个
Dialogue: 0,0:31:47.60,0:31:48.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,九十日元
Dialogue: 0,0:31:49.13,0:31:49.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,给
Dialogue: 0,0:31:49.92,0:31:51.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,多谢惠顾
Dialogue: 0,0:32:02.16,0:32:04.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,来啦？买了什么？
Dialogue: 0,0:32:04.15,0:32:06.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(432,470)\fad(0,700)}嗯 虽然有点不好决定…
Dialogue: 0,0:32:05.77,0:32:08.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\pos(432,470)}时常能看到远野在给人发邮件
Dialogue: 0,0:32:09.21,0:32:18.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而我总会情不自禁地想 如果是发给我的 那该有多好
Dialogue: 0,0:32:28.01,0:32:29.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,卡伯 我回来啦
Dialogue: 0,0:32:29.62,0:32:32.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,卡伯卡伯 我回来了哦
Dialogue: 0,0:32:58.52,0:33:00.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,三年一班的澄田花苗同学
Dialogue: 0,0:33:01.42,0:33:05.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,伊藤老师有事找你 请到学生指导室来
Dialogue: 0,0:33:04.00,0:33:05.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这不是远野的女朋友吗
Dialogue: 0,0:33:06.05,0:33:07.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,她不是我女朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:32:53.10,0:32:54.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}下面播报町公所的通知
Dialogue: 0,0:32:55.16,0:32:58.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}下个休息日的值勤油站是坂井的农协加油…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:11.28,0:33:13.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,全年级就剩澄田你还没交了
Dialogue: 0,0:33:13.94,0:33:14.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对不起
Dialogue: 0,0:33:15.61,0:33:17.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然这样说可能有些不负责任
Dialogue: 0,0:33:18.07,0:33:20.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过其实没必要那么烦恼的
Dialogue: 0,0:33:20.88,0:33:22.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田老师怎么说
Dialogue: 0,0:33:23.01,0:33:23.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没说什么…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:26.90,0:33:30.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,实在决定不了的话 县内的短期大学如何
Dialogue: 0,0:33:30.84,0:33:31.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:33.64,0:33:35.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和姐姐又没什么关系…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:53.91,0:33:54.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:56.51,0:33:58.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我缠着姐姐教的冲浪
Dialogue: 0,0:33:59.83,0:34:02.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还有最重要的那个人的事
Dialogue: 0,0:34:02.91,0:34:06.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我都没有做好
Dialogue: 0,0:34:31.35,0:34:32.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,谢谢你经常光顾
Dialogue: 0,0:34:33.17,0:34:35.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哪里 下次见
Dialogue: 0,0:35:04.13,0:35:10.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一接近远野 心底就会隐隐作痛
Dialogue: 0,0:35:11.20,0:35:12.10,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野同学
Dialogue: 0,0:35:12.33,0:35:14.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田？怎么了？亏你能找到这里来呢
Dialogue: 0,0:35:16.39,0:35:20.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为看到远野同学的车才来看看的 不介意吧
Dialogue: 0,0:35:20.23,0:35:22.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会 这样啊 我很高兴
Dialogue: 0,0:35:23.01,0:35:25.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天没在停车场那里遇到你呢
Dialogue: 0,0:35:25.76,0:35:26.58,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也是
Dialogue: 0,0:35:27.09,0:35:28.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,他很温柔
Dialogue: 0,0:35:29.15,0:35:32.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但正因如此 有时会让我忍不住想要哭泣
Dialogue: 0,0:35:35.53,0:35:37.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呐 远野同学要升学吗
Dialogue: 0,0:35:37.78,0:35:39.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 去考东京的大学
Dialogue: 0,0:35:40.67,0:35:44.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,东京…是吗 我就猜到会是这样
Dialogue: 0,0:35:45.93,0:35:46.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,为什么
Dialogue: 0,0:35:47.10,0:35:49.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,因为总感觉有一天你会去远方
Dialogue: 0,0:35:50.81,0:35:51.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田你呢
Dialogue: 0,0:35:52.04,0:35:56.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我啊 还没做好将来的打算
Dialogue: 0,0:35:56.78,0:35:58.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我想大家都是这样的吧
Dialogue: 0,0:35:58.70,0:36:00.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧 远野同学你也是？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:00.68,0:36:01.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,当然了
Dialogue: 0,0:36:02.44,0:36:04.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,完全看不出来你会为什么而迷惘呢
Dialogue: 0,0:36:05.39,0:36:08.37,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么会 我总是很迷惘啊
Dialogue: 0,0:36:08.71,0:36:10.79,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是尽全力地去做自己能做的事而已
Dialogue: 0,0:36:11.15,0:36:12.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,根本没空去想将来会如何
Dialogue: 0,0:36:12.83,0:36:13.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:36:15.09,0:36:16.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来是这样啊
Dialogue: 0,0:36:23.85,0:36:24.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,飞机？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:25.02,0:36:25.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:37:16.34,0:37:17.33,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,好厉害
Dialogue: 0,0:37:18.95,0:37:20.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说是时速五公里呢
Dialogue: 0,0:37:20.57,0:37:21.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦？
Dialogue: 0,0:37:22.42,0:37:24.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,用这速度一直开到南种子的发射场
Dialogue: 0,0:37:25.95,0:37:28.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,隔了好久 今年终于要发射了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:29.70,0:37:31.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,听说会飞离太阳系 飞向宇宙的深处
Dialogue: 0,0:37:32.49,0:37:33.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管花费多少时光
Dialogue: 0,0:37:53.55,0:37:57.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,你可得好好和花苗谈谈她的出路问题啊
Dialogue: 0,0:37:57.42,0:37:58.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那孩子总是迷迷糊糊的
Dialogue: 0,0:37:59.10,0:38:02.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事的啦 她已经不是小孩子了
Dialogue: 0,0:38:06.45,0:38:08.36,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我以前也和她一样呢
Dialogue: 0,0:38:10.45,0:38:13.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,呐 卡伯 远野说他也会迷惘呢
Dialogue: 0,0:38:14.63,0:38:16.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,原来远野他也和我一样呢
Dialogue: 0,0:38:18.32,0:38:24.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那真是让人无法想像的孤独旅程
Dialogue: 0,0:38:25.62,0:38:28.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那幽深的黑暗之中 朝着一个方向不断前进
Dialogue: 0,0:38:28.84,0:38:32.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哪怕是一个氢原子都难得一遇
Dialogue: 0,0:38:33.15,0:38:38.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是一心探求那存在于无尽深渊中的宇宙真理
Dialogue: 0,0:38:44.12,0:38:47.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而我们又将去向何方
Dialogue: 0,0:38:48.53,0:38:50.55,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又能到达何处呢
Dialogue: 0,0:39:01.21,0:39:05.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a5\fs24}收件人：未输入
Dialogue: 0,0:39:01.21,0:39:05.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a5\fs24}标  题：今天的梦
Dialogue: 0,0:39:01.21,0:39:05.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a5\fs24}正  文：在异星的草原和经常见到的那位少女一起散步。\n依然看不清她的面容。而空气中有着一股让人怀念的…
Dialogue: 0,0:39:05.50,0:39:07.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a5\fs24}想要保存吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:39:05.50,0:39:07.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a5\fs24}是 / 否
Dialogue: 0,0:39:10.16,0:39:13.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,写没有收件人的邮件这个习惯
Dialogue: 0,0:39:13.51,0:39:14.84,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我究竟是何时养成的呢
Dialogue: 0,0:39:51.89,0:39:54.26,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,花苗 你决定好出路了没
Dialogue: 0,0:39:54.34,0:39:56.87,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有 我还是不大清楚
Dialogue: 0,0:39:57.12,0:39:59.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不过没关系 我已经决定了
Dialogue: 0,0:39:59.61,0:40:02.54,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,先做好自己力所能及的事再说 我走了
Dialogue: 0,0:40:20.44,0:40:24.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那天以来 有好几场台风过境
Dialogue: 0,0:40:24.70,0:40:27.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而岛上也渐渐地凉快起来
Dialogue: 0,0:40:30.26,0:40:33.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,摇动甘蔗的风中带着微弱的寒气
Dialogue: 0,0:40:33.63,0:40:35.68,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,天空变得更加高远
Dialogue: 0,0:40:36.00,0:40:37.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,云的轮廓也柔和起来
Dialogue: 0,0:40:38.51,0:40:42.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而骑摩托车的同学们 也开始披上了薄外套
Dialogue: 0,0:40:58.52,0:41:01.32,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,时隔半年 我再次乘上了浪尖
Dialogue: 0,0:41:01.68,0:41:05.99,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而时间已然是十月已过半的残夏时分
Dialogue: 0,0:41:17.27,0:41:22.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\a6\fs24}天气预报称 今天傍晚起天将放晴 最大风速为8米每秒
Dialogue: 0,0:41:22.03,0:41:24.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,山田好像向佐佐木告白了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:41:25.37,0:41:26.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,真大胆呢
Dialogue: 0,0:41:27.22,0:41:29.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 花苗 今天好像很高兴呢
Dialogue: 0,0:41:29.75,0:41:31.23,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,和远野发生什么事了吗
Dialogue: 0,0:41:33.07,0:41:33.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不会吧
Dialogue: 0,0:41:35.61,0:41:39.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也要在今天向远野告白
Dialogue: 0,0:41:44.90,0:41:46.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果在乘上浪尖的今天还不告白
Dialogue: 0,0:41:47.03,0:41:50.07,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那我以后肯定也一直开不了口
Dialogue: 0,0:42:00.62,0:42:01.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田
Dialogue: 0,0:42:01.78,0:42:02.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远…
Dialogue: 0,0:42:03.89,0:42:04.82,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野同学…
Dialogue: 0,0:42:05.54,0:42:06.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,现在回去吗
Dialogue: 0,0:42:06.18,0:42:06.91,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:42:07.52,0:42:08.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是吗
Dialogue: 0,0:42:08.63,0:42:10.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,那就一起走吧
Dialogue: 0,0:42:33.26,0:42:35.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦 澄田 今天这么快就选好了？
Dialogue: 0,0:42:35.60,0:42:36.52,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:42:47.90,0:42:48.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了
Dialogue: 0,0:42:56.15,0:42:57.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,别对我这么…
Dialogue: 0,0:42:57.49,0:42:58.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,咦？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:00.25,0:43:01.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没有
Dialogue: 0,0:43:01.62,0:43:03.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 没什么事
Dialogue: 0,0:43:11.63,0:43:12.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,出毛病了？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:13.02,0:43:14.98,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 真奇怪
Dialogue: 0,0:43:16.37,0:43:17.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,弄不好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:43:17.22,0:43:20.14,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯…可能是火花塞寿命到了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:43:20.79,0:43:21.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这是你家人用过的旧车？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:21.91,0:43:23.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 姐姐以前用的
Dialogue: 0,0:43:23.26,0:43:24.89,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,加速的时候曾经熄火过吗？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:25.02,0:43:26.15,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,可能有吧
Dialogue: 0,0:43:27.67,0:43:29.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天就先把它停在这里好了
Dialogue: 0,0:43:29.76,0:43:31.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,过会儿让家里人来拿
Dialogue: 0,0:43:32.27,0:43:33.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,今天走着回去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:43:33.69,0:43:35.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,哎?我一个人先走好了
Dialogue: 0,0:43:35.99,0:43:37.48,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野君先回去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:43:38.02,0:43:39.69,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,都到这里了 也很近了
Dialogue: 0,0:43:40.11,0:43:42.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而且…想稍微散散步
Dialogue: 0,0:44:18.26,0:44:19.29,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野君…
Dialogue: 0,0:44:19.67,0:44:20.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拜托你…
Dialogue: 0,0:44:31.89,0:44:32.67,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,怎么了?
Dialogue: 0,0:44:32.89,0:44:36.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉 没什么
Dialogue: 0,0:44:36.57,0:44:37.53,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉…
Dialogue: 0,0:44:39.92,0:44:40.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田
Dialogue: 0,0:44:43.07,0:44:45.06,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,请…不要…
Dialogue: 0,0:44:45.70,0:44:46.30,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,再对我…
Dialogue: 0,0:44:47.51,0:44:49.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,这么好了…！
Dialogue: 0,0:46:24.02,0:46:27.77,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,拼命地，想把双手伸向暗云的天空中
Dialogue: 0,0:46:28.20,0:46:30.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,…发射那样巨大的物体升空
Dialogue: 0,0:46:30.91,0:46:34.38,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,…为了寻找那远不可及的彼岸的某些东西
Dialogue: 0,0:46:39.84,0:46:45.24,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我似乎有点明白 为何远野显得那样与众不同
Dialogue: 0,0:46:45.99,0:46:47.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,与此同时
Dialogue: 0,0:46:48.11,0:46:50.81,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,远野君根本没有把我放到心上这件事
Dialogue: 0,0:46:51.55,0:46:53.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我也清楚的认识到了
Dialogue: 0,0:46:58.22,0:46:59.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,所以那天 
Dialogue: 0,0:46:59.82,0:47:02.57,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我什么都没有对远野君说
Dialogue: 0,0:47:16.59,0:47:18.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然远野君很温柔
Dialogue: 0,0:47:18.97,0:47:20.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,虽然非常地温柔
Dialogue: 0,0:47:22.18,0:47:24.43,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但是 远野君一直注视的 
Dialogue: 0,0:47:24.84,0:47:27.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,却是我身后更远的…
Dialogue: 0,0:47:27.66,0:47:30.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,更遥远的某样东西
Dialogue: 0,0:47:40.53,0:47:42.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我在远野君身上所期望的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:47:43.00,0:47:44.45,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,肯定无法实现
Dialogue: 0,0:47:44.89,0:47:45.78,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但即使如此…
Dialogue: 0,0:47:46.56,0:47:49.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,即使如此 我对远野君他
Dialogue: 0,0:47:49.68,0:47:51.86,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,不管在明天 后天 抑或是更远的日子里
Dialogue: 0,0:47:51.93,0:47:54.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,仍然无可救药地喜欢着
Dialogue: 0,0:47:57.34,0:47:59.60,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我一边想着远野君的事情
Dialogue: 0,0:48:00.50,0:48:03.85,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一边哭着、睡了过去
Dialogue: 0,0:49:29.57,0:49:32.47,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我强烈地感觉到 现在回头的话 
Dialogue: 0,0:49:32.87,0:49:35.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,对方也一定会转过身来
Dialogue: 0,0:49:49.52,0:49:53.35,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,（中央·总武末班车，开往东京，已经进站）
Dialogue: 0,0:51:09.64,0:51:11.76,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,如果能待到正月就好了
Dialogue: 0,0:51:11.95,0:51:14.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯 不过有很多事情要准备啊
Dialogue: 0,0:51:14.98,0:51:18.34,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是啊 也要多给他做点好吃的东西哦
Dialogue: 0,0:51:18.66,0:51:19.21,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:51:19.44,0:51:22.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,有什么事情要打电话哦 明里
Dialogue: 0,0:51:22.34,0:51:23.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,没事的啦
Dialogue: 0,0:51:23.90,0:51:27.56,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,下个月在婚礼上就能见面了 不用那么担心
Dialogue: 0,0:51:27.86,0:51:29.51,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很冷的 你们回家吧
Dialogue: 0,0:51:50.54,0:51:53.03,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨晚 梦到了以前的事
Dialogue: 0,0:51:54.61,0:51:58.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我和他 那时都还只是孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:51:58.61,0:52:02.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,一定是因为昨天找到了那封信的缘故吧
Dialogue: 0,0:52:43.88,0:52:50.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0330,,你好 远野君 好久没有联络了呢 你还好吗
Dialogue: 0,0:52:43.89,0:52:50.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0300,,虽然犹豫了很久 但果然还是有必须转达给远野君的事
Dialogue: 0,0:52:54.30,0:52:55.50,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,(信息已发送)
Dialogue: 0,0:52:55.62,0:52:56.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,澄田
Dialogue: 0,0:52:56.39,0:52:57.31,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,啊 是
Dialogue: 0,0:52:57.64,0:52:58.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,要开会了
Dialogue: 0,0:52:58.78,0:52:59.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,是
Dialogue: 0,0:53:08.38,0:53:13.22,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只是,这样生活而已 身边的悲哀却在不断地累积着
Dialogue: 0,0:53:14.69,0:53:16.12,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,无论是刚晒干的床单上
Dialogue: 0,0:53:16.53,0:53:18.18,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,还是洗脸台上的牙刷里
Dialogue: 0,0:53:18.59,0:53:20.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,又或者是手机的记录里
Dialogue: 0,0:53:43.14,0:53:45.13,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“我现在依然喜欢着你”
Dialogue: 0,0:53:46.08,0:53:49.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,交往了三年的女性发给我的短信里这样写道,
Dialogue: 0,0:53:51.11,0:53:57.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“但是,我们即使发了一千次短信…”
Dialogue: 0,0:53:57.20,0:54:00.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,“也肯定只能将心与心之间的距离拉近一厘米而已”
Dialogue: 0,0:54:08.74,0:54:11.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在这几年里 我光顾着低头前行
Dialogue: 0,0:54:12.34,0:54:14.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只想着得到那遥不可及的东西
Dialogue: 0,0:54:14.68,0:54:16.94,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,但又不知道那究竟是什么
Dialogue: 0,0:54:17.27,0:54:22.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,而这个不知从何而来的念头逐渐成为一种压迫
Dialogue: 0,0:54:22.22,0:54:23.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我只得靠埋头工作以求解脱
Dialogue: 0,0:54:24.57,0:54:28.96,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,等我惊觉之时 日渐僵硬的心只能感觉到痛苦
Dialogue: 0,0:54:31.08,0:54:32.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,然后在一天早上
Dialogue: 0,0:54:32.87,0:54:38.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,我发现曾经的那种严肃而又切实的念头 已然完全失却
Dialogue: 0,0:54:39.28,0:54:42.97,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,觉察已经到了极限的时候  辞去了工作
Dialogue: 0,0:55:09.35,0:55:11.42,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,昨天 我做了一个梦
Dialogue: 0,0:55:11.90,0:55:13.65,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,很久以前的梦
Dialogue: 0,0:55:14.38,0:55:17.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在那个梦中 我们还只有十三岁
Dialogue: 0,0:55:18.50,0:55:22.28,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,梦里是那被皑皑白雪覆盖的田园
Dialogue: 0,0:55:22.78,0:55:26.72,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,只能隐约看到远处人家的灯火
Dialogue: 0,0:55:27.20,0:55:32.08,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,在积起的新雪之上 只有我们走过留下的足迹
Dialogue: 0,0:55:32.47,0:55:33.59,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,就这样…
Dialogue: 0,0:55:33.72,0:55:37.25,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0200,,“将来 能再一次一起赏樱花”
Dialogue: 0,0:55:37.32,0:55:40.75,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0200,,我也好 他也好 没有一丝迷惘…
Dialogue: 0,0:55:40.90,0:55:42.74,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0200,,就这样深信不疑
Dialogue: 0,0:00:00.00,0:00:00.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,————————————————————————————
Dialogue: 0,0:55:42.86,0:55:50.05,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我一直在寻觅 寻觅着你的身影
Dialogue: 0,0:55:50.14,0:55:53.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}对面的房间 巷中的窗口
Dialogue: 0,0:55:53.92,0:55:57.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}虽然明知你不在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:55:57.78,0:56:04.80,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}若愿望能够实现 我要立刻到你身边 
Dialogue: 0,0:56:04.83,0:56:08.39,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}那样我定会无所畏惧
Dialogue: 0,0:56:08.64,0:56:15.01,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}不顾一切将你紧紧拥抱
Dialogue: 0,0:56:23.77,0:56:31.02,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}若只是排解寂寞 谁都可以取代
Dialogue: 0,0:56:31.30,0:56:38.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}但在这繁星欲坠之夜 我无法再欺骗自己 
Dialogue: 0,0:56:38.25,0:56:45.63,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}One more time 四季啊 不要如此匆匆
Dialogue: 0,0:56:46.08,0:56:53.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}One more time 回到那与你嬉戏的时光
Dialogue: 0,0:56:53.42,0:57:00.46,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我一直在寻觅 寻觅着你的身影
Dialogue: 0,0:57:00.54,0:57:04.17,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}熙攘的街头 彷徨的梦中
Dialogue: 0,0:57:04.29,0:57:07.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}虽然明知你不在那里 
Dialogue: 0,0:57:08.06,0:57:15.20,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}若奇迹能够发生 我要立刻与你相见
Dialogue: 0,0:57:15.25,0:57:18.64,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}在一个崭新早晨 抛弃所有过去
Dialogue: 0,0:57:18.88,0:57:25.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}说出那句酝酿已久的「喜欢你」
Dialogue: 0,0:57:34.23,0:57:41.73,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}夏天的回忆萦绕在心头
Dialogue: 0,0:57:42.07,0:57:48.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}想起无意间消逝的心动
Dialogue: 0,0:57:48.99,0:57:56.61,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我一直在寻觅 寻觅着你的身影
Dialogue: 0,0:57:56.66,0:58:00.27,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}黎明的街道 落樱的小镇
Dialogue: 0,0:58:00.31,0:58:04.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}虽然明知你不在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:58:04.24,0:58:07.70,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}若愿望能够实现  
Dialogue: 0,0:58:08.04,0:58:11.40,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我要立刻到你身边
Dialogue: 0,0:58:11.46,0:58:14.88,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}已经不再害怕什么 即使付出一切
Dialogue: 0,0:58:14.91,0:58:18.71,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}即使付出一切 也要将你紧紧拥抱
Dialogue: 0,0:58:18.97,0:58:25.93,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我一直在寻觅 寻觅着你的音讯 
Dialogue: 0,0:58:25.99,0:58:29.49,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}启程的旅店 报纸的角落
Dialogue: 0,0:58:29.59,0:58:33.16,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}虽然明知你不在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:58:33.41,0:58:40.44,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}若奇迹能够发生 我要立刻与你相见
Dialogue: 0,0:58:40.50,0:58:44.11,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}在一个崭新早晨 抛弃所有过去
Dialogue: 0,0:58:44.13,0:58:48.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}说出那句酝酿已久的「喜欢你」 
Dialogue: 0,0:58:48.01,0:58:55.04,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}我一直在寻觅 寻觅着你的笑容
Dialogue: 0,0:58:55.30,0:58:58.83,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}疾驰的列车 铁道的两旁
Dialogue: 0,0:58:58.86,0:59:02.41,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}虽然明知你不在那里
Dialogue: 0,0:59:02.46,0:59:09.90,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}如果还有来生 我无论如何都要来到你身边
Dialogue: 0,0:59:09.95,0:59:13.62,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}已经没有什么 能够令我留恋
Dialogue: 0,0:59:13.67,0:59:20.66,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}你才是我最重要的唯一
Dialogue: 0,0:59:25.00,0:59:35.00,*Default,NTP,0000,0000,0000,,{\fad(200,200)}

End...

