I know I should know this, darling,
but are you mad at me?
Baby. Holly!
I did something, right?
I did something bad, right?
Should I know what it is?
Or is it something maybe
you just think I did?
No, no. Idid it. Idid it.
It was a bad, bad thing I did,
and I¡¯m so sorry, Ion.
Holly, come on, will you? Holly, wait.
Baby, you have to let me in on it.
Or are you waiting until were
in the apartment before you talk to me?
ke you gonna make me sleep
in the bathtub again?
Oh, no, I don¡¯t know what I said.
You said it. You know you said it.
No, I don¡¯t know what I said,
but I didn¡¯t mean it.
Yes, you did. You mean everything you say.
Oh, sometimes I mean nothing
when I say something.
Something is never nothing.
It¡¯s always something.
Well, most 0f what I say is nothing.
It¡¯s just something to say.
No, men say it¡¯s just something to say
in order to get away with saying something,
but they know they¡¯re saying something
every time they say it.
Say what? What did I say?
You said, at my mothers tonight,
you would have a baby,
but that I¡¯m not ready.
To my mother!
You might as well have said Em a lesbian.
Well, lam the only man you ever had.
Oh, I dated Timmy Harrison for your months
before I met you.
Isnt he a woman now?
You told my mother I didnt want children!
¡ª I did not. I didnt say that.
¡ª Yes, you did. Yes, you did.
¡ª You said exactly that.
¡ªIdid not.
I didnt say that you werent ready to
have a baby. I said that you wanted to wait.
Which means I dont want one right now.
¡ª Right.
¡ª Thank you.
Wait a minute. Tm confused.
Can I get a ruling on this? Anybody?
No, you¡¯re not confused. You¡¯re just wrong.
¡®Holly doesn¡¯t wanna have a baby.¡±
We had a plan, Gerry.
To wait to have children
until we could buy an apartment,
put 25 percent of each paycheck
into a separate joint account
with a six and a quarter interest
for foe years.
Why didnt you tell my mother that?
Each paycheck? Darling, you only
just started getting regular paychecks.
You¡¯ve quit five jobs
in two years, remember?
Well, I can¡¯t work for idiots.
¡ª They can¡¯t all be idiots.
¡ª Yes, they can.
They can all be idiots.
Md why didnt you tell my mother
about the business loan
you and John took out without asking me?
You see, you finally said it.
¡ª I knew that¡¯s why you¡¯re angry.
¡ª That¡¯s not the reason I¡¯m angry.
¡ª No, it is not the reason that I¡¯m angry.
¡ª Oh, yes it is the reason you¡¯re angry.
I just think that we should have waited.
Why couldnt have you waited?
Waited for what? What are you talking about?
Waiting for what?
I¡¯ve been driving limos
for four years, Holly.
So John and me, we wanna start a business.
We buy a few cars, we get a few clients.
That¡¯s a career right there.
What is your problem?
Md what if it doesn¡¯t work out?
What if we always have to live here?
Md what about what I want, huh?
You think I wanna be a real estate agent
showing other people apartments to buy
that I can never live in?
There may be things I wanna do with my life.
¡ª Okay. Like what?
¡ª I dont know. Other things.
Then quit, all right?
I mean, the job makes
you cranky at home every bloody day anyway.
You wanna have a baby? Lets do it.
¡ª See? I hate when you do that.
¡ª Do what?
¡®Lets have a baby.¡¯ La Ia Ia.
In a five¡ªfloor walk up, we can barely move
and I¡¯d have to change diapers
on the windowsill.
You have to have a plan.
You cant act like everything
just gonna work out by itself, Gerry.
Why do I haoe to be the responsible grown¡ªup
who worries?
Why can¡¯t I be the cute, carefree Irish guy
who sings all the time?
Because you can¡¯t sing
without making dogs bark.
Look, Holly, people have babies
with no money all the time.
Md if you¡¯re so worried about it,
why don¡¯t you stop buying designer clothes?
I buy evething on eBay.
It doesn¡¯t count when you¡¯re wearing
Marc Jacobs from Minneapolis.
Do you want to have a baby?
-Do you?
-Yes, I do.
-See?
¡ªSee what?
I know what you¡¯re really saying
even when you don¡¯t say it, Gerry.
Oh, yeah.
You mean the two conversations thing.
The one we¡¯re having
and the one you think we¡¯re having.
You said that to my mother because you¡¯re
mad at me for not wanting children yet
and because Tm no fun anymore
and because we dont have enough
hot, nasty sex
because I¡¯m always bitching about bills.
That¡¯s what you¡¯re really saying, isn¡¯t it?
Why dont you just be honest and say it?
Say what you mean.
WI right.
I wish we had more hot, nasty sex.
Or the other kind is fine.
What you¡¯re really saying is
this isn¡¯t the life you wanted, is it?
Well, that¡¯s not what I¡¯m saying.
Is that what you¡¯re saying?
Md what if this is it, Gerry?
What if this is all there is to our life?
¡ª What do you mean?
¡ª It means this is it.
Were a married couple
who own a limo company,
who may or may not have children,
end of story.
¡ª Well, what other story do you want?
¡ªIdont know.
What do you want, Hol? What?
Because Tm tired
of trying to figure it out.
You went a bigger apartment?
III take a second job.
You want a child,
you don¡¯t want a child. What?
I know what I want
because I have it in my hands right now.
Do you? Do you know what you want?
Because you better tell me now
if Em not it.
Or whet? You gonna leave?
Why, you want me to leave?
I want you to leave if you wanna leave.
Don¡¯t use me as an excuse.
Ill leave if you want me to leave.
Then leave if you wanna go. Go ahead, leave!
Don¡¯t push me, Holly!
¡ª You wanna leave, just say goodbye.
¡ª Oh, that¡¯s me bollocks!
¡ª Stop acting bilingual.
¡ª Oh, kiss me arse.
Kiss mine in English.
ke we finished now, luv? Can I come beck?
Yeah.
Tm sorry.
¡ª Tm sorry, luv.
¡ª It¡¯s all right.
I¡¯m sorry.
I said the wrong thing to your mother.
God, I still get nervous around her.
I still think after nine years,
she doesn¡¯t like me.
I know I¡¯m being stupid.
No, you¡¯re not being stupid, baby.
She doesn¡¯t like you.
Really? And I thought deep down,
she really loved me.
No, she doesn¡¯t.
I was 19 when we got married.
Md you corrupted me with sex and charm
and the longer it takes you
to make yxur fortune,
the less sexy and charming you are, honey.
What? What are you looking for?
Me balls.
They were hanging there a minute ago.
My mother said it was a mistake manying you
because I loved you too much.
It wont last.
I dont wanna make any mistakes, Gerry.
Well, you¡¯re in the wrong species, luv.
Be a duck.
My baby.
We¡¯re not a mistake
just because we don¡¯t have any money.
Md we are gonna last.
You know howl know?
Because I still wake up every morning
and the first thing I want to do
is see your face.
Oh, I¡¯m sorry.
I see people buying bigger apartments
and having babies.
I get so afraid sometimes
that our lifes never gonna start.
Baby.
Were already in our life.
Its already started. This is it.
You have to stop waiting, baby.
Md Hal, you can¡¯t keep eating me head off,
telling me to leave.
I¡¯m not going anywhere.
I¡¯m not your dad
or don¡¯t you know that yet?
I should get my shoes.
They¡¯re all over the place.
They¡¯re gonna think I don¡¯t love them.
Shake it, baby. Do the stomach shake.
My eye. I¡¯m blind.
Oh, I just wanna lick
your little Glaswegian chocolate.
Okay, okay. I can¡¯t believe
I¡¯m in love with a leprechaun.
Oh, wait. The light.
¡ª You were up last.
¡ª What? No.
¡ª But I¡¯m not up now, am I?
Baby, look at, I¡¯m injured. Ow, me eye.
¡ª God. A pain in me hole.
¡ª Oh, that¡¯s a good girl.
Oh, come get back to bed
or Ill start without you.
¡ªShit.
-You okay?
Shit, no! My toe!
I tell you what. Someone should get a light
on that side of the bed. That¡¯s ridiculous.
¡ª Ill get my nest husband to do it.
¡ª Oh, come here.
Nest husband. Next husband. Come here, you.
Tm sorry I lose my mind sometimes.
Did it hurt you? Let me look.
Will you shut up and kiss me, okay?
Crazy bitch. Pain in me hole.
Oh, Daniel,
we forgot those Thanksgiving decorations.
¡ª Will you take them down, please?
¡ª Sure, Mrs. Reilly.
¡ª Where do you want me to put them?
¡ª Patricia.
In the skinny closet. Have you got the key?
No, I don¡¯t.
Well, I¡¯ll make you a set next week.
Oh, and ask Gerry¡¯s drivers
to close the curtains, will you?
Sure.
¡ª Oh, John.
¡ª Oh, Denise.
¡ª Hi.
¡ª Oh, it¡¯s good to see you.
Do Ihsve to help?
¡ª No, you do not have to help.
-Good.
Sharon, you look great.
¡ª Oh, this is good.
-So do you.
¡ªAmllate?
¡ª No. This is gorgeoos.
Oh, wait till you see Gerry.
¡ª You¡¯re gonna die.
¡ª Oh, yeah?
Well, as Gerry would say,
¡®Lets get this party started.¡¯
Gerry Kennedy, did not want a lot of words.
He preferred music.
He was a unique young man
as you can see by the urn he had
designed by the love 0f his life,
his wife Holly.
His life may be over for now,
but we can still hear it.
He lives in us forever, in our hearts,
like his favorite song.
Got a lucky one
Came in 18 to one
Joe got a feeling
This years for me and you
So Happy Christmas
I love you, baby
I can see a better time
When all our dreams come true
Youre a bum, youre a punk
Youre an old slut on junk
Lying there almost dead
on a drip in that bed
You scumbag, you maggot
You cheap, lousy faggot
Happy Christmas your arse
I pray God its our last
The boys of the N.Y.P.D. choir
Still singing ¡®Galway Bay
Md the bells are ringing out
For Christmas Day
Mom! How you doing?
¡ª Ciara.
¡ª Sis, good to see you.
Oh, good to hold you.
Hello, Gerry.
¡ª Hi, I¡¯m Denise.
¡ª Malt
¡ªhove your tie.
¡ª Oh, thanks.
¡ª Are you single, Matt?
-Yes.
¡ª Are you gay?
Okay.
Did Holly call his parents?
Why aren¡¯t they here?
I did, spoke to the mother.
His father¡¯s just had another operation.
He¡¯s not sopposed to travel.
So, why didn¡¯t she come alone?
I mean, it¡¯s Ireland, it¡¯s not Japan.
He was their only son.
Dont ask me.
¡ª Hi!
¡ª Hi.
¡ªhike your chain.
¡ªThanks.
-Denise.
¡ª George.
¡ª Are you single?
-Yes.
¡ª Are you gay?
¡ª No.
¡ª Are you working?
¡ª You make a ravishing widow, sis.
¡ªThanks.
I¡¯m so glad you¡¯re here,
but it¡¯s so far. I would¡¯ve understood.
No, I¡¯m done with Australia.
Besides, Gerry wrote me. I had to.
He wrote you?
Yeah, a couple 0f months ago.
Probably because of Mom.
He knew id have a ton 0f melodrama
or her to play with
while you pull yooroelf together.
Can I get you anything?
¡ª Sorry about your loss.
¡ªThanks.
How did he die?
¡ª A brain tumor.
¡ª Nice!
So thats a great looking urn.
I wish I were that creative.
I buried my dog in a stereo box.
Its not the same.
¡ª I love your suit.
¡ªThanks.
¡ª Are you single?
-Yes!
¡ª Are you gay?
¡ª No.
¡ª Are you working?
-Yes.
-Denise.
-Sam.
Thank you.
Okay. Okay.
PJI right.
When Gerry and I went to a bank
to apply for a business loan,
I was a little nervous.
Gerry told me,
¡®Relax, these people are never
gonna give us the money anryxay,
so we might as well have some fun.¡¯
No, don¡¯t clean.
No, I have to do something.
I can¡¯t talk anymore.
Wanna stay with us a few days
while your sister¡¯s here?
No. I think...
You know, I guess I should be home.
I think I need to be...home.
Well, this is your home too, you know.
But that¡¯s good. Get back on your feet.
That¡¯s a good thing.
Hey, it¡¯s Geny. Rent a Gaiway Limo.
Leave a message.
Hey, it¡¯s Gerry. Rent a Gaiway Limo.
Holly? Its Mom. Are you all right?
ke you showering? Dont make me worry.
Tm worried. Youre not calling me back.
Please call.
I know it¡¯s hard, honey,
but don¡¯t lock yourself in.
It¡¯s been over a week. I¡¯m here, okay?
Hey, it¡¯s Denise.
Listen, I buzzed your apartment.
Nobody¡¯s heard from yoo. Where are yoo?
PJl right, call somebody. I love you.
Ill make him live. I will.
Whatever you might do, I can do more
because I know how to fight better than you.
Why can¡¯t I be Bette Davis?
WI right. I mean, the job makes you cranky
at home every bloody day, anryoay.
You wanna have a baby? Lets do it.
¡ª See? I hate when you do that.
¡ª Do what?
¡®Lets have a baby.¡¯ La Ia Ia.
In a five¡ªfloor walk up, we can barely move
You cant act like everything
just gonna work out by itself, Gerry.
Why do I haoe to be the responsible grown¡ªup
who worries?
If you¡¯re killed, I¡¯ll be free.
If I¡¯m killed, it really doesn¡¯t matter.
If we both die, good riddance!
Go ahead, crash it. Crash it!
Gerry, get the light. Its your turn.
I just want to see you
When you¡¯re all alone
I just want to catch you if I can
I just want to be there
when the morning light explodes
On your face it radiates
I cant escape
I love you till the end
Do all Irishmen sing?
Ill love you till the end
Only the really well¡ªhung ones.
I cant fall asleep alone.
¡ª I¡¯m right here, baby.
¡ª I had a terrible dream.
Don¡¯t tell me.
Gerry, I dont want to go back to work.
¡ª What shoold I do?
¡ªQoit.
Stay here with me.
I don¡¯t have a plan, Gerry.
That¡¯s okay, luv,
your plans never work out, anay.
That¡¯s true.
Md all because of the man that got away
No more his eager call
The writings on the wall
The dreams you dreamed have all
Gone astray
The man that won you
has gone off and undone you
That treat beginning
has seen that final inning
Dont knnw what happened
Its all a crazy game
No more that all¡ªtime thrill
For youve been through the mill
Md never a new love will be the same
Good riddance goodbye
Happy Birthday!
You¡¯re 30!
Hey, Holly, these were falling out
of your mailbox.
What is that smell?
I wasnt expecting company.
Mom, dont clean.
Tm not. Ill just organize the garbage.
We did try to call first.
¡ª Are you drunk?
¡ª No.
¡ª Do you wanna be?
¡ªCiara!
¡ª What happened to your heed?
¡ª Pimple.
¡ª You¡¯re not showering?
¡ª Oh, you always squeeze it too hard!
¡ª What is that smell?
¡ª It¡¯s me, all right!
¡ª Dont be like that.
¡ªLike what?
Like the only lonely widow in Gotham City.
I¡¯m not, I¡¯m just exhausted.
Yeah, well, what are you doing?
Two shows a night?
You know, if you want us to leave,
that¡¯s foe.
But you do know that at some point,
this all has to stop.
PJl right.
Just give me a second, okay?
III get cleaned up.
¡ª Okay, troops, let¡¯s sweep the area.
-Yes.
I haven¡¯t called the office. Are they mad?
Nah. Theres no rush.
Even Larry said take all the time you need.
The job is there when youre ready.
That was nice of him.
¡ª He¡¯s an asshnle.
¡ª He¡¯s still an asshole.
Do you think it¡¯ll be all right
itt stop my life right here?
Become the Miss Havisham
0f the Lower East Side.
Never leave my apartment till Tm old.
¡ª Sit in my wedding dress.
¡ª Which you never had.
¡ª With an old piece of wedding cake.
You gotta be rich to be insane, Hol.
Losing your mind is not a luxury
for the middle class.
¡ª That¡¯s so not fair.
¡ª No, it¡¯s not.
Holly? Something¡¯s been delioered for you.
What is this?
I dont understand. Did you do this?
No.
Wait a minute.
John, tell me the truth. Did you do this?
No. I did nothing, I swear.
Hey, baby. Surprise.
I know this probably feels
a little bit morbid,
but Ijust hate the idea
that Em not gonna be there
to see you freak out over turning 30.
I mean, it kills me not to be there.
¡ª That¡¯s funny.
¡ª No, it¡¯s not.
Okay. No, it¡¯s not.
You¡¯re gonna bess impressed.
I have a plan, baby. Can you believe it?
I¡¯ve written you letters.
Letters that will be coming to you
all sorts of ways.
You know, I thought I¡¯d wait
until your birthday
because I figured you werent even stepping
out 0f the house for a while.
Letter number one will be arriving tomorrow.
Now, you must do what I say, okay?
Okay?
Md dont try to figure out
how the letters are coming.
Its too brilliant, and itil ruin my plan.
Just go along with me on this.
Because the thing is,
I just cant say goodbye yet.
So, for starters
I want you to get dulled up,
and just go out and celebrate tonight.
Go out with your girlies.
Thereby free you from a party
with your family,
especially your mum.
Oh, man, your mum¡¯s there, isn¡¯t she?
Shit. Sorry, Patricia.
It isn¡¯t that I don¡¯t love you, Mum.
But she need to get a little crazy.
So have a slice of the bloody cake,
put on your party dress
and get out of the apartment.
¡ª Denise, make a plan.
¡ª Tm on it!
Ill help.
Just leave me with John, okay?
Md know that wherever lam,
I¡¯m missing you.
Happy birthday.
I love you.
Do it now. Let it go.
¡ª Come on.
¡ª Look, it¡¯s a prioate gay club.
Yes, but we are on the list.
My colorist called and he¡¯s gay.
Gay colorist in New York?
That¡¯s like sand on the beach, sister.
Listen, Crystal. Don¡¯t mess with her.
Hes a very good colorist.
Md shes the princess of Finland.
Md shes here on matters
of critical political importance.
Md shes here to extend the hand
of friendship from Finland
to homosexuals throughout the tn¡ªcity area.
What?
Thanks.
Lee, ynure fired.
Okay. Snaps is the name of the tame.
The name of the game is Snaps.
Make sure you pay attention.
Ready?
¡ª Have you got it?
¡ª Mariah Carey?
Yeah.
I don¡¯t get it.
¡ª Paul.
¡ª God, he¡¯s been dead, like what?
¡ª Fifteen years.
¡ª Unbelievable.
¡ª Fifteen?
-Can you believe that?
¡ª Does it get any easier?
¡ª Do you remember Steve?
It doesnt. It really still hurts.
¡ª He was a good guy.
¡ª Honey, dont be so Miss Doom and Gloom.
YouII be fine, darling. Youll be fine.
Dont worry about it.
Snaps is the name of the tame.
The name of the game is Snaps.
¡ª Do you hear me?
¡ªYeah.
Ready?
Keep looking.
Derek Jeter!
What? Oh, come on! How?
This is a stupid game!
Sorry.
What are you doing?
Trying to figure out
why God killed my husband.
Well, if you need any help with that,
let me know.
Sorry.
¡ª Daniel?
¡ªYeah.
So why do you think...
¡ª Your husband died?
¡ªYeah.
I don¡¯t know.
Maybe you¡¯re being punished for something.
What?
Being too happy? Too beautiful?
I dont know.
God can be a pretty jealous guy.
Well, I don¡¯t believe that.
I¡¯ve never been too happy
and I¡¯m not too beautiful.
I think you¡¯re hot.
Sorry, I have a syndrome.
I dont really have a filter.
I dont pick up on social cues.
You mean youre rude?
Yeah, but now it¡¯s a disease
I can take medication for.
¡ª They have pills for rudeness?
¡ªIknow.
Md they can¡¯t figure out the Middle East.
Go figure.
Hey, you¡¯re Irish.
Maybe it¡¯s an Irish curse or something.
Well, Gerry and I did love the Yankees
which was pretty much against our religion.
Well, there you go.
That eoplains a lot, actually.
I love the Yankees too
and I lost my fiancee last year.
Really?
Yeah, she slept with my best friend.
She left me.
My best friend was a woman.
Her last words to me were
Id still be with you
if you werent a man.
Md I¡¯m like, ¡®Well, castrating me
is definitely the first step
toward achieving that particular goal.¡±
It¡¯s still my fault, though.
I introduced them.
I always had this fantasy about making love
to two women at the same time.
Except in my fantasy, I was still in the bed
for the second end third time.
-Sorry.
¡ª Then this¡¯ll make you feel great.
The best friend that my ex¡ªfianee
slept with was my ex¡ªex¡ªfiance
and she was my business partner,
and we started the business with my money.
So I ended up losing the business,
my partner and my fiancee.
Howd you get over that?
I went through like a major hooker phase
all year.
¡ª But that didn¡¯t help.
¡ª No, it helped a lot.
I just started to run out of money.
It¡¯s actually a lot cheaper to date.
Do you think that you¡¯re gonna ever find
another woman to love?
No. No I think I repel the women
that I want the most.
¡ª Thats not true.
¡ª No?
No?
Thank you, Daniel.
You can start closing up downstairs.
Right.
What do you want?
Oh, good. A friendly voice.
What happened last night?
Lemon drops and tequila, my friend.
The moment where a 30¡ªyear¡ªold body
does not recover
quite as fast as a 20¡ªyear¡ªold body.
Stop screaming at me.
¡ª Are you working?
¡ª Hell, no.
But I told him were gonna start next week.
You and lore gonna go out starting Monday.
Is that okay?
No, I was planning on
staying in bed and dying today.
Well, you can¡¯t.
You gotta go check the mailbox, remember?
Call me immediately.
Save yourself bruises
and buy yourself a bedside lamp.
Md remember,
a disco diva must look her best.
Go buy yourself a knock¡ªout outfit.
YouII need it
for when my next letter comes.
Need it for what?
Md lknow you hate your job,
but Ill help.
Look fore sign. YouII know whet to do.
P.S. I love you.
I still know you¡¯re around.
You¡¯re still here, aren¡¯t you?
So who lived here before?
A family. Theyre having another baby.
-Dv you have any children?
¡ª Three. Girls.
¡ª Teenagers.
¡ª Thats nice.
Ted, Sharon says
there¡¯s another offer on the table
and we have to move on this,
so Isay we do it.
I think if you offer another hundred grand,
they¡¯ll back right down.
Well, Vick, maybe we should talk about it.
We don¡¯t have time, Ted.
We have to tell her today.
But we said we didn¡¯t want to go
over a certain...
I know, but we love this apartment,
and it is what it is.
There¡¯s nothing else out there.
This is what a good apartment costs.
But we were already looking beyond our cap.
¡ª I wanna be near the river.
¡ª I think we should think about another area
¡ª Jam not living in Brooklyn, Ted.
¡ª It¡¯s a lot!
¡ª Forget it.
¡ª Will you listen to him?
¡ªWhat?
He¡¯s obviously worried about this.
¡ª Look at him. He¡¯s pale.
¡ª Hol.
Who are you to tell me
how to talk to my husbaod?
Tm just sayiog you shouldnt push this
on him if he doesnt wanna do it.
¡ª Hol?
¡ª Ill push whatever the hell I want on him.
Hes my husband. I want this apartment.
¡ª We¡¯re doing this.
¡ª Say no, Ted
It is amazing to me
that you are still talking.
¡ª Ted, don¡¯t listen to her.
¡ª Ted, she¡¯d being a tyrant.
She¡¯s got your balls on one of those things
that, you know, clink back and forth.
¡ª You know what I mean?
¡ªYeah.
¡ª You bitch.
¡ª Brat.
¡ªShut up.
¡ª You shut up.
No, you shut up.
Twill end you, and when I do....
You know what?
¡ª Ill tell you something right now.
¡ª No. No. No. Okay, tell me.
He¡¯s my husband, and Ill talk to him
the way I wanna talk to him!
Md I¡¯m not living in Brooklyn!
Do you know who lam?
What¡¯s wrong with Brooklyn, lady?
ke you Holly Kennedy?
If I am, will you sing at me?
-Yes.
¡ª No, I¡¯m not.
Look, please don¡¯t make this an issue.
I gotta sing and deliver a letter.
A letter? Whats the song?
Ysh Mo Be There.
Please dont. Just give me the letter.
I could get reported.
By who, the leprechaun union?
You know, I was in an off¡ªBroadway play
with Al goddamn Pacino.
I dont need this shit.
¡ª You want the balloons?
¡ª No.
Fine.
You bastard.
There¡¯s absolutely no way I¡¯m doing this.
¡ª Yes, you are.
¡ª No, I¡¯m not.
¡ª Oh, yes, you are.
¡ª Oh, no, I¡¯m not.
Remember the last time?
stI you wanna do is ride around, Sally
Ride, Sally, ride
il you wanna do is ride around, Sally
Yeah!
One of these early mornings
You gonna be wiping those weeping eyes
Those weeping eyes, yeah
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
Thank you very much.
Oh, my God.
¡ª One more!
¡ªOkay.
I guess its time to give somebody else
a chance here now. Who wants a shot?
Mybody else here willing to give it a go?
Yourself? No?
Young lady. Come on. Don¡¯t be shy!
What about Holly?
¡ª Stop it.
¡ª Holly.
I dont know about that, John.
Holly¡¯s my wife, by the way.
My beautiful wife.
Mdl do, I love Holly, I do.
But she would never have the guts
to do something like this.
Oh, no.
In fact, she ate me head off
about coming out tonight.
You know, she had a long day at the office.
Shell never do it. Yep.
Oh, you think so?
You think she¡¯d get up here?
Okay, III bet you 100 dollars,
she doesnt get upon this stage.
Make it two.
What is she doing? What is she doing?
That¡¯s my wife, the surpriser.
How can I put this in a way
soas to not to offend or unnerve
But theres a rumor going all around
that you aint been getting semed
Pd right.
They say that you ain¡¯t ¡°You know what¡±
in, baby, who knows how long
It¡¯s hard for me to say what¡¯s right
when all I wanna do is wrong
Get off, 23 positions in a one¡ªnight stand
Get off, I¡¯ll only call you after
if you say Ican
Get off, let a woman be a woman
and a man be a man
Get off, if you want to, baby,
Here lam, here Jam
¡ªOh,God!
Do you mind coffee?
How do you feel? You look good.
I¡¯m sorry, baby, butt have to say
you were really good before you...
My nose is broken, Gerry.
My ankle is twisted. Happy?
What, are you mad at me?
I didnt wanna go out tonight
and you made me.
I hate karaoke
and you forced me to go up there.
Oh, come on, honey. It was nobody¡¯s fault.
Oh, come here, baby. Give me a...
Give me a kiss.
Well, how long you gonna be mad for?
I never let him off the hook.
Mytime I was mad,
I made him feel bad about it.
I was mad at him
when we left the house that night.
because our apartment was too small.
Its so stupid.
Baby, you were married.
Married people make each other
feel like shit on purpose sometimes.
It jost feels good.
Gerry knew you were crazy about him.
He told me all the time.
Well, I wish I would¡¯ve told him that night.
So tell him now.
Its slightly dirty. Just slightly.
Oh, he¡¯s delicious, isn¡¯t he?
You could serve coffee on thst ass.
Do you have to be so vulgar about men
like they¡¯re pieces of meat?
I¡¯m sorry, John. I forgot you¡¯re sensitive
about your f at ass.
You know, Denise,
that¡¯s why you¡¯re not married.
Women act like men,
then they complain men don¡¯t want them.
Oh, is that why?
Okay. Because I thought
it was something different.
I thought it was because
I thought that I deserve the best.
Md hes out there.
Hes just with all the wrong women.
Md let me be clear.
After centuries of men looking at my tits
instead of my eyes
and pinching my ass
instead of shaking my hand,
I now have the divine right
to stare at a man¡¯s backside
with vulgar, cheap appreciation,
if Iwant to.
¡ª Well said.
¡ªIthoughtso.
New York City, how we doing?
Hey, guys, we¡¯re here!
Let¡¯s give a warm welcome
to our nest singer.
Md rumor has it
this is her return engagement,
sol want you to put your hands together
for Holly.
This is for you, Gerry, you son of a bitch.
Ijustwanna tell you
nothing you don¡¯t want to hear
iI Iwant is foryou to say
Oh, why don¡¯t you just take me
where I¡¯ve never been before
I know you want to hear me
catch my breath
I love you till the end
Okay, let me get this straight.
You¡¯re straight, you¡¯re single,
and you own your own business?
Its my own club.
Tm doing a big renovation right now.
Its gonna open in the spring.
I could show it to you if you want.
Its over on 10th Avenue.
¡ª Wanna go?
¡ªGreat.
Yeah. Let me just do one thing first.
¡ª Whets my name?
¡ªTom.
¡ª Where have you been?
¡ª With all the wrong women.
Hey, Gerry. You lost weight.
Thanks for inviting me.
¡ª Youre a terrible singer.
¡ªYes lam.
Id be really embarrassed if I were you.
Did you take your medication today?
No, I thought I¡¯d come here instead.
Say, I¡¯m feeling kind of hungry. You feel
like getting a bite or something to drink?
No, Im...I don¡¯t think so.
¡ª All right.
¡ªThanks.
I don¡¯t mean to throw this at you
from left field, but what do women want?
I mean, I can¡¯t figure it out.
They want us to ask.
They dont want us to ask.
They want us to make a move,
not make a move.
They want us to be on the bottom.
They want us to be on top.
Use hair products, dont ose hair products.
What do you people want?
I¡¯ll tell you, but you have to promise
not to say I told you.
¡ª I swear.
¡ª Because its a sacred secret.
Sacred secret.
¡ª You ready?
¡ªYeah.
¡ª Are you sure?
-Ithinkso.
Come here.
We have absolutely no idea what we want.
I knew it!
I knew that! Son of a bitch!
Yeah.
Look, if you ever just wanna get out,
just do anything, just...
I¡¯ll wait for your call.
Md just so you know,
I¡¯m not looking for a thing right now.
¡ª Tm just flirting in good faith.
¡ª I appreciate that.
Maybe we can defy God
and go see a Yankees game.
Yeah.
Well be really weird friends,
joined by self¡ªpity, bitterness and vomit.
¡ª I like that.
¡ª Me too.
My leather jacket is for you.
I always loved the way that looked on you.
But the rest of my stuff, you don¡¯t need it.
Make some space in that bloody apartment
for yourself. Go on.
It¡¯s time, baby.
P.S. I love you.
I think you¡¯re a little bit perverted.
I mean, you bring me
to an Irish famine memorial
and we¡¯re eating corned beef sandwiches.
That¡¯s pretty sick.
Gerry thought, it was the best way
to honor the dead.
You know, show them how well we¡¯re doing.
I¡¯m sorry I always bring him up.
Yeah, I¡¯m starting to get
a little bit sick of it.
Now that¡¯s a real honest¡ªto¡ªgoodness couple
right there.
They¡¯ve probably been together
since the Flood.
We¡¯re so arrogant, aren¡¯t we?
We¡¯re so afraid to age,
we do everything we can to prevent it.
We don¡¯t realize what a privilege it is
to grow old with someone,
someone who doesnt drive you
to commit murder.
Or doesnt humiliate you beyond repair.
Its sweet.
Its good, huh?
¡ª Can I ask a favor?
¡ª Sure.
I started bagging up Gerrys stuff.
Couldnt finish. I think I need someone
who didnt know him to get rid of it all.
Id be happy to help you get rid of Gerry.
Do you have to say it like that?
What, I want to say it like what?
I didn¡¯t say anything.
¡ª What is wrong with you? Take a pill.
¡ª Nothing. What?
¡ª Whats wrong?
¡ªNothing,I...
lye just never been alone with another man
in this apartment besides Gerry.
You want me to stand out in the hail?
You can just throw me the buses.
No. Thats okay.
Sorry. I¡¯m gonna change.
Feel free to look through stuff.
If there¡¯s anything of Gerry¡¯s you want,
just let me know.
Okay.
I cant remember the last time
somebody held me like this.
¡ª Did you find a new husband yet?
¡ªShut up.
Where have you been?
I havent felt you around lately.
Please. I¡¯ve been so around.
I can feel you hugging me.
That¡¯s because Jam.
You look great.
This is the one.
¡ª Are you Barbara?
¡ª Yes, may I help you?
Ihopeso.
Youre his wife.
He was here?
So I dont understand.
Ynure taking a vacation?
Its a trip.
Gerry planned the whole thing
for me and Sharon and Denise.
Do you think its the best time to vacation?
Gerry made all the arrangements.
Ihave to go.
Have you spoken to Daniel?
Thought you two were spending time together.
Were just friends, Mum.
You know, I¡¯ve stood by
and not said anything about all this,
but now I think its time it stopped.
¡ª What do you mean?
¡ª It¡¯s not healthy.
Gerrys not gonna be able
to keep this up forever, is he?
His life ended, and so will his letters.
At some point, you¡¯re gonns have
to face things on your own.
It was a gift from Gerry.
Md how can you say that?
My husband was 35 years old.
He wasnt supposed to die.
But he did. It was awful.
Its what happens.
But his death is a part of your life now.
Md you have to deal with it.
Stop saying that
like Fm not dealing with it. Jam.
How? By waiting for a letter
from a dead husband?
Taking a vacation?
When your father left,
I had two children to support.
Well, excuse me for not having any children.
That¡¯s not howl meant it and you know it.
Your father leaving was just as devastating.
But I did what I needed to do
and got on with it.
¡ª It¡¯s not the same thing.
¡ª And why not?
My husband died. He was taken.
He didn¡¯t wanna go, he didn¡¯t wanna leave.
Yes, my husband wanted to leave.
Md it¡¯s so much easier
being abandoned by choice, is it?
I¡¯ve had my say. I won¡¯t say anymore.
So where¡¯s he sending you?
Oh, my God. Get the bags.
¡ª Oh, right.
¡ª She just elbowed me.
Yeah, you know what? If that¡¯s an indication
of how this trips gonna be,
I wont have it.
Is that her bag?
Holly, is that her bag? Leave it.
¡ª I mean, this is heavy.
¡ª Dont take it in.
Holly?
¡ª This is heavy.
¡ªIknow.
Holly?
Look.
Hey, Big Mama.
Make sure my baby has a good time.
Make sure you and John
do everything you wanna do,
wheneoer you wanna do it.
Md make sure my baby does things.
¡ª I want you to take her fishing.¡¯
¡ªOh,God.
Hes been wanting to get me on a lake
since forever.
And be sure to give yourself a big,
sweaty pony¡ªboy kiss from me.
Jerk. He will never let me forget
my bachelorette party.
-Joey the Pony Boy.
¡ªTony.
Tony, I remember him.
I bet Ihave a letter too.
Where do you think hed hide one for me?
Bedroom.
¡°Denise, take Holly to Whelan¡¯s,
my favorite pub.
There¡¯s beautiful music to be heard,
beautiful people to be around.
Md, Denise, you¡¯re going to heaven
for being my baby¡¯s friend.
Tm making all the arrangements up here
for you.
Got a few hot men lined op.
I hear Ben Franklins
hung like a race horse.
Love you.
I dont know how you do this.
Let me see it.
What?
He didn¡¯t leave me a letter.
Well, probably didn¡¯t love you
as much as us.
You know, this was the...
in three minutes
Oh, my God, look at that. Look at that!
Oh, my God.
Please let me buy him as a souvenir.
¡ª He¡¯s coming this wsy!
¡ª He¡¯s coming in!
How iong hss it been?
How long has what been?
How long has it been?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, you¡¯re gonna go talk to him.
¡ª Oh, yeah.
You just heard him play,
say how much you like it.
¡ª Are you kidding me?
¡ª Flatter him. Go.
We don¡¯t have those in the States!
¡ª Go, go, go.
¡ª We don¡¯t make those up!
¡ª Youre ready.
¡ª Go! Do it for us. Go on.
Whered she go?
What are you doing? Go ahead!
Tm an old married widow.
Oh, you¡¯ve got much better stuff
than those tarts. You¡¯re experienced.
Plus, you¡¯re American. You¡¯ve tot
foreign exotic stuff going for you.
There is nothing exotic
about being an American.
¡ª He doesn¡¯t know that.
¡ª We¡¯re gonna help you.
¡ª Just take it off.
¡ª No! No! No!
¡ª Yeah, yeah, yeah!
¡ª Listen! You¡¯re gonna do what we say!
Tm gonna hurt you.
Because Tm going to pull your hair!
Put your shoulders back. Fix your hair.
¡ª Youre so seoy!
¡ªGo!
You look hot! Do it!
Hi.
I just wanted to say
I really loved your music.
You¡¯re beautiful. I mean, sorry...
¡ª Your music is beautiful.
¡ªThanks.
¡ª Holly.
¡ª William.
¡ª Youre American?
¡ªYeah.
¡ª And what brings you to Ireland?
¡ª Holiday.
Oh, well, with my girlfriends.
¡ª Hi.
Good.
¡ª Good to have you here.
¡ªThanks.
I have one more song to play.
Will you stay and have a listen?
Its an American song about a local girl.
¡ª I think youII like it.
¡ª Sure.
Good. Grand.
So I¡¯ll see you after, then?
Okay, sure!
This is an American song dedicated to Holly.
I hope you enjoy it.
Well, I took a stroll on the old long walk
IY a day ¡ª1¡ªay¡ªI¡ªay
I met a little girl and we stopped to talk
Of a fine soft day¡ªI¡ªay
Mdl ask you, friend
Well, what¡¯s a fella to do
Because her hair was black
and her eyes were blue
Mdl knew right then
Id be taking a whirl
Round the Saith ill Prom with a Gaiway girl
¡ª Thats a very nice jacket!
¡ª I won it in a bet.
We were halfiaay there
when the rain came down
O a day ¡ª1¡ªay ¡ªI¡ªay
Md she asked me up to her flat downtown
O a fine soft day ¡ªI¡ªay¡ª1¡ªay
Mdl ask you, friend,
what¡¯s a fella to do
Because her hair was black
and her eyes were blue
Enough of this.
Why does he keep wanting me to remember
all these things that make it harder?
¡ª It¡¯s cruel.
¡ª I don¡¯t know, baby.
I dont think he means to be cruel.
What does he mean?
I dont know.
Come on, lets go. Were taking you beck.
¡ª I think you should find William.
¡ª No!
I left without saying anything.
He must think Im an idiot.
Well, you¡¯re an American.
They expect us to be idiots.
Don¡¯t push her.
She¡¯s not ready, she¡¯s not ready.
inithough if memory serves me correctly,
Holly,
the longer you go without sex,
the meaner and bitchier you get.
¡ªEat me.
¡ª Hello.
Well, I¡¯m really med at Gerry.
Maybe thats why he did it.
You have to stop wanting him at some point.
When?
¡ª Grab the pole!
¡ªWhat?
¡ª Youve got a fish!
¡ª It¡¯s a fish!
¡ª Youve got a fish.
¡ª Holly, grab the pole!
¡ª Okay, I¡¯m grabbing it!
¡ª Take it out 0f the thingy majiggy!
¡ª Hurry it up!
¡ª No!
Youre not holding the ball.
Turn the knobby thing!
¡ª Will you stop being so butch?
¡ª Just watch it!
¡ª Help me!
¡ª Tm trying to get the fish!
Stop with the fish! My nails are wet!
iI right!
Oh, my God!
What happened to our oars?
Oh, my God.
Help?
¡ª Help!
Help!
I hate cosmetics companies.
They get you addicted
to the perfect lipstick or nail polish
and then six months later,
they discontinue it.
You have to buy your favorite colors
like youre storing up for the apocalypse.
That was my last bottle.
I still think that one of us
should swim ashore
and it should be the one of us
whos already inflated.
Okay, no, that¡¯s good. Here!
¡ª There, go swim ashore.
¡ª Is that absolotely necessary?
Yeah, now you can go swim ashore.
keyou happy
that I just inhaled all these toxins?
You jump into the brown lake!
Stop fighting! You¡¯re acting like babies!
¡ª All right. Shut up!
¡ª No!
Nice.
Maybe we¡¯ll eventually
drift towards the shore.
What shore? That could take months!
Better not take more than nine or else
theres gonna be another person on this boat
What?
I wasnt gonna say anything
until we got back.
Tm having a baby!
¡ª Baby? Sharon, wow.
¡ªIknow!Iknow!
¡ª When are you due?
¡ª March.
Oh, thank God.
You can still be in my wedding.
¡ªWhat?
¡ª I¡¯m getting married!
Tom proposed. I said yes,
and we¡¯re planning a New Year¡¯s Eve wedding!
Gosh!
Congratulations!
-You okay?
¡ªYeah.
No, yeah!
No, I mean, it¡¯s just, this is just
a lot of information to get in one boat.
Oh, baby, I¡¯m sorry.
You know, I wasn¡¯t gonna say anything
until we got back, this is your trip.
¡ª This is your trip.
¡ª No, no, it¡¯s okay.
Yeah, no, me too.
But you know we might die here,
so Fm not going down as a spinster.
¡ª Youre getting married.
¡ª Youre having a baby.
¡ª Oh, my God!
¡ª What, are you kidding me?
¡ªWhat?
¡ªIknow!
Whos the cook?
¡ªTern.
¡ª Me.
We all helped.
Denise is getting married. Isnt that treat?
Sharons pregnant!
¡ª Congratulations to both of you.
¡ª Thank you.
Food was great.
I don¡¯t think I came up for air once.
You know, it got a lot darker
while I was busy.
Yeah, it gets dark at night here.
¡ª You work on the lake?
¡ª Two days a week.
Kind of a patrol man.
ithough, I gotta say,
first time lever had to save anyone.
I feel really badly about you
having to drive all the way back this late.
¡ª That¡¯s enough, thank you.
¡ª Yeah, in this rain, forget it.
Please feel free to stay till morning.
Yeah, we have a pull¡ªout couch,
a bed that pulls out.
It is a long drive.
¡ª I would love a shower.
¡ª What a great idea!
Oh, my God.
There¡¯s one downstairs, it¡¯s fantastic!
I¡¯ll get you some linen and towels.
I¡¯ll show you.
Great. You can take your wine...
What are you, crazy?
Hes staying the whole night.
Hes gonna be here all night long,
all night long.
Hes gonna be here all night.
¡ª No.
-Yes.
I love him.
This is crazy.
Oh, my God,
you have to get pregnant immediately!
¡ª Immediately!
¡ª We¡¯ll have our kids together!
¡ª How cute is that?
¡ª How does it feel?
I know, I have this weird feeling
like I have this boy inside 0f me.
Oh, Jesus! Oh, I¡¯m sorry!
I thought you were upstairs!
I need to just get my clothes.
Ill get out of your way.
Sorry about that.
Would you like a drink?
Should I just lick it off the counter then?
¡ªOh,no!
¡ªYeah.
Sorry, no, I just, it¡¯s been a long time
since I¡¯ve seen a man that naked.
I mean you have a...
How about that drink?
¡ª You¡¯re very sweet.
¡ªOh,God.
The last time a guy said that,
he followed up with,
But I dont date 13¡ªyear¡ªolds.
Well, lucky for you, neither do I.
¡ª Cheers!
¡ª Oh, I¡¯m sorry! Sorry.
¡ª Hi.
Oh, I cant do this, I¡¯m sony!
It¡¯s not you, oh, I¡¯m...
Look st me, I¡¯m just shaking,
I just, I don¡¯t know how to do this.
I don¡¯t even know if I want to,
I haven¡¯t been held in...
Oh, never mind. I¡¯m just screwed up.
I¡¯m trouble. Yeah.
I like trouble.
Oh, no, I don¡¯t mean cool,
¡®Pulp Fiction¡¯ trouble.
I mean, mental case. Wacko trouble.
I¡¯m out of my league here.
I mean, I haven¡¯t had a new man
in over 10 years.
I had this old one, I mean, he wasn¡¯t old,
he was just old to me
because I had him so long,
he was my husband, but he died.
Kissing him like that,
I¡¯m not surprised, poor lad.
No, it¡¯s not gonna work.
I feel like I¡¯m trying on a new pair
of shoes I really want to buy,
but they just don¡¯t ft.
Sorry.
ni1 right then,
how about going barefoot for a while?
There¡¯s no man, alive or dead,
who¡¯s gonna fault you for living.
You¡¯re very sweet.
He was a good man, I reckon,
your man who died.
Yes, a very good man.
William? Could you drive me
to Enniskerry in the morning?
Sure.
¡ª You got friends there?
¡ª Family. Sort of.
In¡ªlaws. I should see them.
What¡¯s their name? Maybe I know them.
The Kennedys.
¡ª Not Rose and Martin?
¡ªYeah.
You know them?
¡ª Youre not Gerrys Holly?
¡ªWhat?
Ynure the girl from the pub that night.
I was in Gerrys band.
¡ª Not Billy Gallagher?
¡ª The one and the same.
Its all right.
It¡¯s all right, you know, me and Gerry,
we shared everything together.
Oh, no, no, no, I didn¡¯t mean it like that.
What I meant was,
you know, he wouldn¡¯t have a problem.
Well, he might have a problem
but, you know, there¡¯s not much
he can do about it now, is there?
Holly, come here. Come back to bed.
Now, lets talk.
I heard he died.
Tumor, was it? Yeah.
You know, Gerry and 1, we...
We hadn¡¯t seen each other
in a long, long while.
Sad when that happens to best friends,
isn¡¯t it?
He, He was a wonderful lad.
It¡¯s all right, you know. It¡¯s okay.
You know, these things,
they happen now and again, not very often,
but now and again.
Would you like me to tell you some stories
about me and Gerry?
Joe got plenty.
Yeah?
Okay here you go. Come on, sit back.
You know, he was,
he was my very, very best mate.
Starting back when we were terrors
running about at 5 and 6.
Oh, he made me laugh.
There was this time,
I don¡¯t remember how old we were,
probably, you know, 10, 11.
We jumped on a train...
We received those packsges you sent.
Come in. Come in.
Martin? Look who it is.
Oh, well, look at that.
Come here, dear. So nice to see you.
He was always one for writing. Wasnt he?
¡ª Shouldve gone professional.
¡ª No.
He did it for the love of it, Martin.
Now, where is it? Oh, here it is.
When Holly visits,
take her to my fort in the backyard
and give her this envelope.
He knew that I¡¯d come visit you?
Oh, suppose he did.
¡ª Martin.
¡ª All right.
It¡¯s not really a fort,
it¡¯s just a stone wall.
He used to call it that when he was little.
He goes on about other things,
lovely things.
He hadn¡¯t much strength
in the end though, did he?
Makes me sick to think we weren¡¯t there
when he died for the funeral.
But you could hardly walk
just after your operation.
Maybe you¡¯ll come and visit us
a bit more now that he¡¯s gone, eh?
Martin, don¡¯t put that on her.
Youre under no obligation.
Its not like were blood family.
Id like to come visit.
Md I¡¯m sorry we didn¡¯t in the pest.
I just thought you were angry with me
for taking Gerry away.
She wanted you dead, you know.
¡ª Martin, don¡¯t you dare!
¡ª No, I don¡¯t blame you.
You know, my mother,
she never quite got over the ides either.
Yeah, well, you were both so young
and it happened too fast.
But Gerry loved you. I saw that.
Isaw that.
To my Gaiway Girl,
You¡¯re an angel for seeing my folks.
I told you my mom didn¡¯t hate your guts.
Well, you know, not anymore.
You are now standing in my fort
where I did all my big thinking.
This is where I stood thinking about you,
after the very first time we met.
You didnt look real to me at first.
I never saw so many colors
on one girl before,
but you looked like yoo belonged out there,
all right.
You and all your colors.
Do you remember the first thing
you ever said to me?
Tm lost.
Oh, you didn¡¯t look lost, not to me.
So, what are you looking for oot here?
Wicklow Mountains National Park?
Wicklow Mountains National Park.
¡ª Tell me, how long you¡¯ve been walking for?
¡ª A few hours.
Well, you¡¯ve probably been
in the National Park for a yew hours, then.
Oh, my God. This isa park?
It¡¯s so cold!
The paper said it was gonna be warm.
It is warm!
I know you¡¯re lost,
but you do know
you¡¯re in Ireland, don¡¯t you?
Well, I better heed back.
Md where is that?
Tm staying at a B&B in Dun¡ªlouga¡ªhairy.
Dunlagohairy?
No, I think you mean Dun Laoghaire.
¡ª Youre kidding?
¡ª No.
Would I lie to you?
¡ª Dun Laoghaire?
¡ª Dun Laoghaire.
¡ª Okay. Thanks.
¡ª Oh, you¡¯re grand.
But youre going the wrong way, you know.
That way? Okay.
I think you quite enjoy this getting lost,
don¡¯t yoo?
You know, actually,
I don¡¯t mind so much, not here.
So how did you come to be here?
Oh, on my way home, college trip.
We started in Greece.
Jesus, that¡¯s a long walk.
That¡¯s a bad joke.
¡ª What are you studying?
¡ªArt.
¡ª Art?
-Yeah.
¡ª Oh, so you¡¯re an artist then?
¡ª I don¡¯t know yet.
That¡¯s great. Do you make anything, or...
¡ª I dont know yet.
¡ª Good luck with that.
Would you mind if we walk a ways together
since we¡¯re going in the same direction?
Ill stay on this side of the road.
Dont even have to talk.
Just, quite nice, you know, sometimes,
walking along with someone without talking,
once you get your feet wet.
Of course, the no¡ªtalking thing didn¡¯t last.
Before long, I couldn¡¯t get you to shut up.
But you were so cute,
trying to impress me
with William Blake and all your grand plans.
I had no idea what you were talking about,
but I couldn¡¯t help loving
the way you talked.
Oh, I must create a something
or be enslaved by another man¡¯s something.
Wait, twill, twill not...
Twill not reason or compare.
My business is to create...something...
Oh, God!
Did you just make that up then?
No, it¡¯s William Blake,
but I completely screwed it up.
No, you didn¡¯t, you made it better.
I understood it.
I didnt have a clue, actually.
il I know is, if you don¡¯t figure out
the something, you¡¯11 just stay ordinary.
Md it doesnt matter if its a work of art
or a taco or a pair of socks!
Just create something new and there it is.
Md it¡¯s you, out in the world,
outside of you.
Md you can look at it or hear it
or read it or feel it
and you know a little bit more about you.
A little bit more than anybody else does.
¡ª Does that make any sense at all?
¡ªYeah.
Youre saying you want to paint socks.
Maybe!
I loved you right then and there.
Hey, I like this jacket.
It looks good on you. Got it on a bet.
What was the bet?
Well, mind you, I was a few Guinnesses
for the worse at this point,
but a fella bet me
that I couldn¡¯t get a certain girl
to kiss me without a provocation.
¡ª What girl?
¡ª His girl.
¡ª How did you do it?
¡ª Theres nothing to it, really.
A fella just has to tell a woman the truth
without words.
Its like a signal you send out.
The woman, she just picks it up.
Md what¡¯s the truth?
That kissing her would be the end of life
as I know it.
Md thats true
of every girl youve gotten to kiss you?
Well, I could turn it on and off
when I was younger and I had no principles.
When every girl that I was lucky enough
to kiss was the end of life as Iknewit.
Md now?
Now I only send it out when I think
she might be the one that makes it true.
I know where I am now!
Thanks it was really nice to meet you!
¡ª No, I could walk you into town.
¡ª Oh, no, it¡¯s okay!
I know where Jam, I know where I¡¯m going.
I¡¯ll never forget this.
Oh, your jacket.
No, wait! Oh, wait, wait, don¡¯t move.
What?
¡ª Oh, yeah, it¡¯s a wild Irish dog.
¡ªA what?
¡ª You have to stand still.
¡ªOkay.
Get close, like one person.
Now if we sepsrate,
hell feel threatened
and attack our vital parts.
What vital parts? All my parts are vital!
We have to stand still.
Now, just let him sniff around a bit.
Now wait.
Tm really scared.
Would you put your arms around me?
WI right.
¡ª Yeah, that¡¯s probably a good idea.
¡ªYeah.
Do you think we could turn aroond and
face each other withoot freaking him out?
Okay. Sure.
¡ª But lets move very slowly, okay?
¡ªOkay.
Oh, sorry! I haven¡¯t done this in a while.
I¡¯ve been seeing this boy, Timmy,
but we don¡¯t do much.
I don¡¯t know why. Maybe it¡¯s me.
No, he¡¯s a boy who...
doesnt know anything about kissing.
¡ª Thats a mans business.
¡ª Is it?
That was the most perfect,
perfect first kiss.
That was the second.
This is the third.
Brady, come!
¡ªHey,Gerry.
¡ª How are you, Jeff?
¡ª Hey, where you going?
¡ª No, stay! Stay!
No, but, what...You have my jacket.
I know, I¡¯m keeping it unless we meet again.
Ibet we do.
Well, that¡¯s a bet you¡¯re gonna have to win
because if...
if we do meet again,
then that¡¯Il be the end of it, you know.
¡ª The end of what?
¡ª Life as we know it.
¡ª Look, I¡¯m singing at this pub...
¡ª No, no, no, no, no, no!
Don¡¯t tell me. If I happen to walk
into the right one, in the right town,
then we¡¯ll know for sure, won¡¯t we?
Md itt don¡¯t,
then thatli just be the most perfect kiss
ever created by two strangers
and well just keep it perfect
for the rest of our lives.
¡ª What¡¯s your name?
¡ª No, no! Wait, no, don¡¯t, don¡¯t.
Life had changed as I knew it.
Md now it¡¯s changed again, luv.
See, I don¡¯t worry about you remembering me.
Its that girl on the road
you keep forgetting.
My business into create.
Doesn¡¯t even matter what you do.
You told me that remember?
P.S.
So go home. Go find it.
Find that thing
that makes you like nobody else.
Ill help. Look fore sign.
It¡¯s Mum.
Sharon called, she said you¡¯re home.
Hey, where are you? Call me.
You havent returned any of my calls.
I want you to come
to my first baby doctors appointment.
What is going on?
Nobody¡¯s heard from you, my maid of honor!
¡ªCalime!
If you need to find any job to get by,
be realistic, Iuv, all right?
I cannot believe
you are not calling me back!
You cant be a secret agent,
and theres no such thing
as a vampire slayer.
¡ª Tm getting married.
¡ª Pick up the phone!
Where are you?
Call me.
His death is a part of your life now.
Jam so mad at you!
Shed be much more interesting
if she wouldnt hold us up.
Here she is.
Great shoes.
Okay, this message is for Holly Kennedy.
Please tell her her friend Denise
is getting married December 31st
and she¡¯s not invited.
Okay? How about that? You¡¯re not invited.
¡ª Look at this.
¡ª It needs to be tighter!
mu right, Twill do whatever you want,
but I¡¯m not so sure, I mean, I¡¯m think...
No, listen,
your bust looks absolutely right,
because let me tell you something,
you don¡¯t want to look too busty.
Yeah, well, see, although, you know,
my breasts are beautiful and firm
they do often have a mind 0f their own
and they can go off in different directions
without adult supewision.
So could you please just take it in
a quarter¡ªinch? Just a quarter¡ªinch.
¡ªOkay.
Could you give us,
excuse us fore minute, please?
¡ª Sure.
¡ªThanks.
You look beautiful.
Well, I could¡¯ve used some help.
This is the 12th dress I¡¯ve tried on. So...
I¡¯m sorry.
Well, you were supposed to be
my maid of honor,
but of course I didn¡¯t hear from you.
Sharon feels too conspicuous
since she¡¯s popped.
So, guess what?
I had to ask Tom¡¯s 51¡ªyear¡ªold sister
who looks like Jerry Springer
and doesn¡¯t like me.
PJI because my best friend
couldnt stand me being so happy.
Why? Why is that?
Because our lives were moving on
and you werent
the center of attention anymore?
¡ªYes.
¡ªReally?
¡ª It was awful and I¡¯m really sorry.
¡ª Oh, no, I¡¯m sorry, honey.
¡ª Oh, I¡¯m so sorry.
¡ª I¡¯m sorry.
You were right and I was wrong.
God, I¡¯m such a bitch! I¡¯m sorry!
I was so crazy mad.
I hope you can forgive me.
Oh, you know what, it¡¯s not too late.
You can still be a bridesmaid with Sharon.
¡ªOkay.
¡ªOkay?
Can Task you a favor?
¡ª I want to make your wedding shoes.
¡ª My shoes?
What, did you turn into Geppetto?
Oh, my God! These are gorgeous!
I¡¯ve been taking a class.
It just happened out of the blue.
I really love it.
Oh, my God!
They¡¯re one of a kind.
You¡¯ll be the only bride
in the history 0f the world to wear them.
Love that!
Oh, God, Holly! This is like shoe art.
They¡¯re gorgeous!
We have to show these to ovmeone.
I feel like Gerry¡¯s guiding me.
I mean, shoes!
I love shoes, butt never thought about it.
¡ª You look so great.
¡ªThanks.
¡ª Course, I look great too, right?
-Yes.
When all this started happening,
you¡¯re the first person I wanted to tell.
¡ª Isnt that funny?
¡ª Thats hilarious.
My way we can stretch this lunch out
into a dinner?
Tm gonna change the subject.
¡ª How are you?
¡ª Tm good. Things are good.
Joe got some, some ideas for the future,
some possible business prospects.
I think about you all the time.
That¡¯s a little too much information,
Iguess.
Yes.
But you did say you were thinking about me.
Because you¡¯ve been a real friend
through this all.
So you haven¡¯t thought about me in the nude?
No.
¡ª Not once?
¡ª No.
¡ª Not even without my shirt?
¡ª Gerry, stop it!
Daniel.
Tm Daniel.
Sorry.
You think youre ever gonna feel about
somebody else the way you felt about Gerry
or do you have to wait
for one of your letters to figure that out?
Where are yoo going?
I really like you,
but I cant be the invisible man.
Tm tired 0f being the shoulder.
I want to be another body part you need,
you know?
I wanna be the bad guy.
I want a woman to go crazy over me
and then I wanna use her up
until shes ruined for all nther men.
You dont want tn do that.
No, I don¡¯t want to do that, but I would...
I¡¯d like to date a woman
who actually likes men.
Id like to be somebodys Gerry.
Its all right.
Honestly, its not your fault, its mine.
I didn¡¯t really plan on feeling something
for you, it just sort of happened.
So I¡¯m sorry about that.
¡ª Is your guest coming back?
¡ª No.
Just you on your own, then?
Take a break, will you?
¡ª Mum!
¡ª Whets the matter?
Come on. Come here.
What happened?
When Daddy left, I was 14 and I said...
that¡¯s it, never again. No man.
Md then I meet Gerry.
This wonderful men happens to me
and then, and then he died!
¡ª What was the point?
¡ª I know, honey.
Tm so angry I could kill somebody!
Tm alone and...
it doesnt matter what job I have
or what I do or what I dont do
or what friends I have.
Hes not here.
Tm not here.
¡ª I mean, you¡¯re alone no matter what!
¡ª That¡¯s right.
You know, I didn¡¯t come here for you
to give me some bulishit honest answer.
¡ª Why cant you lie to me just once?
¡ª Tm so sorry, sweetheart.
I cant breathe. I can¡¯t breathe.
Come on, lets go for a walk.
Your father and I used to come here.
They had dances. Well, not really dances.
Wed come with radios and cigarettes
and drink beer and listen to Jimi Hendrio.
I bet you¡¯ve had a hard time walking into
a room full of people on your own, right?
Yeah, I know that.
I know what it is not to feel like
you¡¯re in the room until he looks at you
or touches your hand
or even makes a joke at your expense,
just to let everyone know you¡¯re with him.
You¡¯re his.
God, that man could make me laugh.
Daddy?
I dont ever remember you laughing.
Well, that makes me sad.
Because I did.
Idid.
Did you hate Gerry
because he reminded you of Dad?
A little.
You know the worst thing for a parent,
second after losing a child?
Watching your child
head for the same life you had
and you cant stop it.
It¡¯s a terrible, helpless feeling.
Makes you angry all the time,
and I¡¯ve been angry a very long time.
I¡¯m exhausted.
Do you think we¡¯ll ever see Dad again?
No, sweetheart.
Never.
So you have to stop waiting.
You?
I have to sayl was impressed by how
he worked everything out ahead of time,
every delivery schedule, the mailbox key.
Getting that leather jacket
out of your apartment wasn¡¯t easy
with you acting like Miss Havisham.
He made me promise. I couldnt say no.
I told him I didnt think
it was good for you, but...
I couldn¡¯t say no.
It¡¯s the last one.
So, now alone or not, you gotta walk ahead.
Thing to remember is
if we¡¯re all alone,
then were all together in that too.
It helps me sometimes.
Hi, its Daniel.
Remember what I said in the restaurant?
Please forget it word by word.
They¡¯re gonna build a new Yankee stadium.
I dont know why I said that.
Tm making small talk. I hate small talk.
I hate the people who make small talk.
I should, I should stop.
I¡¯m stopping. Shit!
Gerry?
My uncle can get us in anytime we want.
He turned the lights on for us.
Its amazing.
You sure?
Its okay.
¡®Dear Holly, I don¡¯t have much time.
I don¡¯t mean literally,
I mean, you¡¯re out buying ice cream
and you¡¯ll be home soon,
but I haoe a feeling
this is the last letter.
Because there¡¯s only one thing left
to tell you.
It isn¡¯t to go down memory lane
or make you buy a lamp.
You can take care of yourself
without any help from me.
Its to tell you how much you move me.
How you changed me.
You made me a man by loving me, Holly,
and for that Jam eternally grateful.
Literally.
If you can promise me anything,
promise me that whenever youre sad
or unsure,
or you lose complete faith,
that youll try and see yourself
through my eyes.
Thank you for the honor of being my wife.
Tm a man with no regrets.
How Iud am 1?
You made my life, Holly,
but I¡¯m just one chapter in yours.
There¡¯ll be more. I promise.
So, here it comes, the bit one.
Don¡¯t be afraid to fall in love again.
Watch out for that signal
when life as you know it ends.
P.S., twill always love you.¡¯
Have you thought about this?
About me, I mean?
Have you?
Yeah.
This isn¡¯t going to work, is it?
¡ª No way, no how!
¡ª Damn!
I mean, that was like kissing my sister!
I¡¯m so relieved!
I got this letter and I thought he must have
been feeling all self¡ªsacrificing and...
but hes really full of crap,
but if he really meant it,
he¡¯d give me a sign and then...
¡ª I hate signs.
¡ª I got your message on the machine.
Weird, bitter friends?
Forever.
¡ª Whets wrong, friend?
¡ª It¡¯s Gerry.
It¡¯s been a year...
and I don¡¯t feel him around me anymore.
I don¡¯t think he¡¯s here anymore.
I think Gerrys gone. Hes really gone.
Dear Gerry, you said you wanted me
to fall in love again
and maybe one day I will,
but there are all kinds of love out there.
This is my one and only life
and its a great and terrible
and short and endless thing
and none of us come out of it alive.
I dont have a plan except that
it¡¯s time my mum laughed again.
Shes never seen the world.
Shes never seen Ireland,
so Fm taking her beck to where we started.
Maybe now shell understand.
Mum?
¡ª William.
¡ª Hello, you!
You back for another visit?
¡ªHow long?
¡ªIdont know.
Oh, this is my mum, Patricia.
Hello. This is me father, Patsy.
Youve dropped your sweets, Ion.
Mustnt do that around these parts.
Pretty woman like you,
a fella could take it the wrong way.
¡ª So Ill see you around, then?
¡ªYeah.
I dont know how you did it,
but you brought me beck from the dead.
III write to you again soon.
P.S. Guess what?
This film is dedicated in loving memory of
Windland Smith Rice 1970¡ª2005