1
00:00:13,489 --> 00:00:17,175
This bear is coming right up to me.

2
00:00:17,457 --> 00:00:19,254
My name is Gordon Buchanan.

3
00:00:19,659 --> 00:00:20,819
She is enormous.

4
00:00:22,846 --> 00:00:24,768
I'm a wildlife cameraman.

5
00:00:25,769 --> 00:00:28,055
Gosh, look at the size of those paws.

6
00:00:29,567 --> 00:00:32,980
I've spent my career
getting close to big predators.

7
00:00:33,614 --> 00:00:37,061
She is one of the most powerful animals
on the planet.

8
00:00:38,301 --> 00:00:40,212
One of the most intimidating animals
on the planet.

9
00:00:40,738 --> 00:00:43,389
But I've never been this close.

10
00:00:45,768 --> 00:00:47,304
Oh, not sure ifI like that.

11
00:00:48,565 --> 00:00:51,693
I want to do something
that no one has done before.

12
00:00:52,255 --> 00:00:56,385
Reveal the family life
of the world's largest carnivore.

13
00:00:56,895 --> 00:00:58,055
Look, look, look!

14
00:00:59,459 --> 00:01:01,700
From the ﬁrst day they emerge in spring...

15
00:01:01,848 --> 00:01:04,544
The face of a baby polar bear.

16
00:01:05,254 --> 00:01:07,575
I'll follow their every move.

17
00:01:07,971 --> 00:01:08,744
Oh, look.

18
00:01:12,894 --> 00:01:13,952
Pass over.

19
00:01:14,848 --> 00:01:15,826
Hey, little bear.

20
00:01:16,412 --> 00:01:17,265
Fast asleep.

21
00:01:19,380 --> 00:01:21,666
I want to really get to know these bears.

22
00:01:22,208 --> 00:01:23,140
How does that sound?

23
00:01:23,895 --> 00:01:26,739
How does it sound if I follow you around
and we become good friends

24
00:01:27,488 --> 00:01:28,853
until you get big enough to eat me?

25
00:01:47,973 --> 00:01:50,669
I've come to the Arctic to get closer

26
00:01:50,738 --> 00:01:52,592
to polar bears than anyone before.

27
00:01:57,330 --> 00:02:00,663
It's one of the most beautiful places
I've ever been.

28
00:02:01,739 --> 00:02:04,856
And the most extreme.

29
00:02:05,771 --> 00:02:08,695
There's an incredible amount of ice
on the front of the boat.

30
00:02:08,817 --> 00:02:12,139
Every single wave that this boat has hit
on the journey here

31
00:02:12,255 --> 00:02:14,257
has kind of come up into the air

32
00:02:14,410 --> 00:02:16,537
and instantly frozen
as soon as it hits the, the boat.

33
00:02:17,332 --> 00:02:20,745
To reach the bears,
we've got a difﬁcult voyage ahead of us.

34
00:02:21,410 --> 00:02:22,536
Now that the boat is here,

35
00:02:22,582 --> 00:02:24,948
we have to prepare
for the next part of the journey,

36
00:02:25,208 --> 00:02:27,699
which is get rid of all this ice.

37
00:02:29,771 --> 00:02:32,023
This is probably... No, deﬁnitely

38
00:02:32,333 --> 00:02:34,255
the coldest plaoe I have ever been.

39
00:02:34,489 --> 00:02:36,184
But we've got to go,
we've got to get a hustle on.

40
00:02:36,942 --> 00:02:39,058
We've got a day's worth of travelling to go

41
00:02:39,175 --> 00:02:42,258
before we get into the area
where the polar bears are denning

42
00:02:42,488 --> 00:02:45,264
and they are getting ready to get up
and get out

43
00:02:45,380 --> 00:02:47,905
and we've got to get there
as fast as possible.

44
00:02:50,411 --> 00:02:53,744
Our destination is Edge Island

45
00:02:53,818 --> 00:02:54,694
in Eastern Svalbard.

46
00:02:55,177 --> 00:02:58,465
It's home to the world's
densest concentration of polar bears.

47
00:03:04,096 --> 00:03:05,461
By following a family this year,

48
00:03:05,940 --> 00:03:08,670
I hope to help scientists learn more
about them.

49
00:03:24,582 --> 00:03:28,097
We've come at a critical moment
in the Arctic's history.

50
00:03:28,300 --> 00:03:32,100
Since records began,
there's never been so little sea ice.

51
00:03:33,849 --> 00:03:34,952
It's April.

52
00:03:35,099 --> 00:03:38,774
We should be making this journey
across a completely frozen ocean...

53
00:03:38,895 --> 00:03:41,819
by snowmobile and not by boat.

54
00:03:47,660 --> 00:03:50,663
We shouldn't even be able to take a ship
through here at this time of year.

55
00:03:50,846 --> 00:03:53,258
In 20 years of sailing these waters,

56
00:03:53,410 --> 00:03:56,584
the ship's crew have never, ever seen
conditions like this.

57
00:03:56,738 --> 00:04:00,697
So whether it's global warming,
whether it's just freak weather conditions,

58
00:04:00,770 --> 00:04:01,828
we don't know.

59
00:04:01,943 --> 00:04:02,853
One thing we do know

60
00:04:03,021 --> 00:04:08,232
it makes for a very dangerous,
very difficult and incredibly slow journey.

61
00:04:10,535 --> 00:04:14,027
Captain Bjorne Man/el has never attempted
to get to Edge Island

62
00:04:14,129 --> 00:04:15,494
this early in the year.

63
00:04:16,816 --> 00:04:18,260
This is a new situation for me.

64
00:04:18,379 --> 00:04:20,745
You shouldn't be here in April at all.

65
00:04:20,942 --> 00:04:24,139
In this area,
there are heaw currents

66
00:04:24,223 --> 00:04:27,420
and the ice is drifting over the rocks.

67
00:04:27,771 --> 00:04:32,617
If we get stopped in the ice
and drift into a rock, that's it.

68
00:04:35,410 --> 00:04:39,540
It's dangerous for us
but it's disastrous for the bears.

69
00:04:41,769 --> 00:04:43,828
The sea ice
is the polar bears??hunting ground.

70
00:04:44,255 --> 00:04:46,780
It's where they catch most of their prey,
seals.

71
00:04:49,693 --> 00:04:52,662
But with less ice, there are fewer seals

72
00:04:53,490 --> 00:04:55,344
and the bears are going hungry.

73
00:04:59,613 --> 00:05:02,980
By following a family,
I'll be able to see first hand

74
00:05:03,096 --> 00:05:05,257
the effects of climate change
on these bears.

75
00:05:06,019 --> 00:05:07,589
If we can get there.

76
00:05:10,896 --> 00:05:14,138
For four days,
we try to pick a path through the ice.

77
00:05:16,537 --> 00:05:20,541
It's a reminder of just how tough
this year is going to be.

78
00:05:27,129 --> 00:05:28,903
The captain's been trying to ﬁnd
a channel through.

79
00:05:29,020 --> 00:05:31,056
He's got us this far

80
00:05:31,177 --> 00:05:36,672
but we've got to a point where
we're gonna ﬁnd it very difﬁcult to go on.

81
00:05:41,177 --> 00:05:43,418
The captain has wedged the boat in the ice.

82
00:05:44,097 --> 00:05:46,691
This is as close to Edge Island
as we're going to get.

83
00:05:49,019 --> 00:05:50,418
We prepare to go ashore.

84
00:05:52,738 --> 00:05:55,946
Our plan is to ﬁnd a polar bear den
as soon as possible.

85
00:05:59,256 --> 00:06:01,872
Yesterday, things were looking pretty bleak.

86
00:06:02,537 --> 00:06:05,540
Actually, I thought we were gonna have
to turn around and head for home,

87
00:06:06,051 --> 00:06:07,416
but here we are.

88
00:06:07,536 --> 00:06:09,902
We've managed to get in,
lodged ourselves in close to shore

89
00:06:10,050 --> 00:06:12,416
so it's looking good.

90
00:06:12,534 --> 00:06:14,058
We just have to get out there
and start looking for bears.

91
00:06:16,098 --> 00:06:19,750
Helping me ﬁnd a den
is polar bear expert Jason Roberts.

92
00:06:21,536 --> 00:06:22,867
And it's a good thing he's here.

93
00:06:23,381 --> 00:06:24,700
Look, look, look.

94
00:06:27,021 --> 00:06:29,148
It's my very ﬁrst polar bear.

95
00:06:30,661 --> 00:06:32,390
As is always the way,

96
00:06:32,457 --> 00:06:36,143
the animal that you're looking for
more often ﬁnds you than you finding it.

97
00:06:37,222 --> 00:06:38,541
What a beautiful bear.

98
00:06:39,410 --> 00:06:42,459
It's also a potentially deadly bear.

99
00:06:42,662 --> 00:06:44,311
No guns, no guns, no guns.

100
00:06:46,740 --> 00:06:47,468
Fortunately,

101
00:06:47,537 --> 00:06:50,950
there is no one who's had more experience
in dealing with polar bears than Jason.

102
00:06:52,895 --> 00:06:54,544
It's a three??to five?�year?�old,

103
00:06:55,222 --> 00:06:57,383
probably male from the way it's acting

104
00:06:57,504 --> 00:07:00,382
but it's hard to tell at that age.
But most likely males.

105
00:07:01,253 --> 00:07:04,586
It's more inquisitive than anything
and we're giving off so much smell.

106
00:07:05,176 --> 00:07:07,337
But it's most likely easily soared.

107
00:07:07,506 --> 00:07:10,100
Just a bit of a bluff charge
and it will scare it.

108
00:07:11,100 --> 00:07:15,343
So do you ﬁnd these young males
are the potentially the problematic ones?

109
00:07:15,583 --> 00:07:17,949
They are actually the ones
that do the most damage to people.

110
00:07:19,785 --> 00:07:22,151
Completely unfazed by us.

111
00:07:22,503 --> 00:07:26,621
Instead of running and trying to get away,
they're coming straight towards us.

112
00:07:30,052 --> 00:07:33,385
Young bears can sometimes be scared off
by facing up to them.

113
00:07:36,098 --> 00:07:37,053
Hup!

114
00:07:41,097 --> 00:07:41,973
Stay that distanoe.

115
00:07:42,863 --> 00:07:45,468
I suppose
he's a relatively small polar bear.

116
00:07:45,659 --> 00:07:48,264
But compared to us, it's a big, big animal.

117
00:07:48,583 --> 00:07:49,618
It's a big polar bear.

118
00:07:49,786 --> 00:07:51,515
He'd still rip you to pieces in seconds.

119
00:07:51,615 --> 00:07:54,345
This one's persistent. He must be hungry.

120
00:07:54,693 --> 00:07:55,978
He's liking the smell.

121
00:08:00,944 --> 00:08:03,469
The thing is
we can't let this bear get too close.

122
00:08:05,738 --> 00:08:08,696
I've spent 20 years
ﬁlming dangerous predators.

123
00:08:09,534 --> 00:08:11,582
Normally, I go looking for them.

124
00:08:12,097 --> 00:08:14,975
This is the first time
they've come looking for me.

125
00:08:21,739 --> 00:08:23,104
The young bear moves on

126
00:08:23,223 --> 00:08:26,818
and I can now concentrate on the next step,
ﬁnding a den.

127
00:08:45,818 --> 00:08:48,616
Edge Island's slopes
collect deep snow drifs.

128
00:08:49,505 --> 00:08:52,076
Perfect for mother bears to dig dens.

129
00:08:54,019 --> 00:08:56,340
But ﬁnding one is next to impossible.

130
00:08:57,254 --> 00:08:58,983
It is so tricky.

131
00:08:59,942 --> 00:09:02,866
We're looking for... not, not the bears
themselves, that would be the easy part,

132
00:09:02,943 --> 00:09:05,434
but these bears are in their dens
underground,

133
00:09:05,537 --> 00:09:08,950
so what we are looking for
is an indentation in the snow.

134
00:09:10,099 --> 00:09:15,230
It's caused by the body warmth of a bear
underground melting the snow above.

135
00:09:15,816 --> 00:09:18,512
But everything looks like
it could be a polar bear den to me.

136
00:09:19,379 --> 00:09:21,825
The good thing is Jason's been here
many times before

137
00:09:21,893 --> 00:09:22,951
looking for polar bear dens

138
00:09:23,504 --> 00:09:28,077
so he's kind of... he's the expert
and I'm the humble assistant.

139
00:09:28,896 --> 00:09:31,512
But I think it's just a case
of keep searching.

140
00:09:38,145 --> 00:09:40,693
It can take weeks to find a polar bear den.

141
00:09:42,535 --> 00:09:44,457
Time we just don't have.

142
00:09:56,021 --> 00:09:59,263
After two days searching, we head inland.

143
00:10:03,222 --> 00:10:06,100
Finally, Jason spots a sign.

144
00:10:08,503 --> 00:10:11,666
We've just come up the valley,
over the top here

145
00:10:11,785 --> 00:10:15,334
and Jason stopped in front of me
and he's found a den.

146
00:10:17,302 --> 00:10:18,792
??Stay in this spot.
??Yeah, here.

147
00:10:18,896 --> 00:10:19,976
Well, stay low.

148
00:10:21,067 --> 00:10:25,663
You can see there's a hole and just kind of
a lot of disturbance in the snow.

149
00:10:28,378 --> 00:10:29,618
I don't know if the bear is still there.

150
00:10:33,067 --> 00:10:34,944
I'll let Jason go in front this time.

151
00:10:36,381 --> 00:10:39,430
Right, I'll be, I'll be right behind you.
Right behind you.

152
00:10:39,974 --> 00:10:41,828
And if she pops her head out,

153
00:10:42,335 --> 00:10:45,099
the ﬁrst thing we do
is just get down low and not disturb her.

154
00:10:45,426 --> 00:10:49,339
And we've both got signal pistols
so we can't hurt her

155
00:10:49,458 --> 00:10:52,154
but we oan scare her
with an explosion pistol. So...

156
00:10:52,425 --> 00:10:56,225
So what do you think her reaction would be
if she popped her nose out and saw us?

157
00:10:57,021 --> 00:10:59,899
Most likely, her reaction
if she popped her nose out

158
00:11:00,022 --> 00:11:01,626
would be to pull back in if she sees us.

159
00:11:02,302 --> 00:11:04,827
It's...The den is a safety zone for her.

160
00:11:04,897 --> 00:11:08,822
But I've had it once where she's just looked
and went "Oh, dinner"

161
00:11:08,974 --> 00:11:10,817
and then shot out the den straight after me.

162
00:11:11,300 --> 00:11:14,178
And I was on skis then
so I just skied down to get away from her

163
00:11:14,347 --> 00:11:15,746
but she come at full speed.

164
00:11:34,057 --> 00:11:37,823
I reckon if there's a bear in there,
it's gonna have maybe heard us,

165
00:11:38,258 --> 00:11:41,625
almost deﬁnitely smelt us
long before I got there.

166
00:11:43,869 --> 00:11:45,496
It does seem a little bit crazy

167
00:11:45,620 --> 00:11:47,872
heading straight
towards a hole in the ground

168
00:11:47,948 --> 00:11:49,904
that might contain a polar bear.

169
00:12:03,125 --> 00:12:04,308
So it's an open den

170
00:12:04,612 --> 00:12:07,945
but I can't see if this is a track
coming down here or not.

171
00:12:09,297 --> 00:12:12,095
We're close enough.
Now the waiting begins.

172
00:12:14,043 --> 00:12:16,455
What's going on?
They're in no great rush, Jason.

173
00:12:16,575 --> 00:12:19,226
No. It's a bit of a waiting game.

174
00:12:19,373 --> 00:12:22,456
But the unfortunate thing are that

175
00:12:22,526 --> 00:12:24,300
they are better than us
at waiting in the cold.

176
00:12:24,450 --> 00:12:26,224
I suppose she's been in there for months now

177
00:12:26,295 --> 00:12:28,217
so she's not gonna exactly run out

178
00:12:28,295 --> 00:12:30,581
and do the fandango down the slope
just because we're here.

179
00:12:31,045 --> 00:12:31,659
No.

180
00:12:33,217 --> 00:12:35,868
Jason's sure the cub will stay put
for the moment.

181
00:12:36,498 --> 00:12:39,251
So we head back to the boat to thaw out.

182
00:12:41,653 --> 00:12:45,942
But on the way back, our snowmobiles
attract interest from a large male.

183
00:12:48,809 --> 00:12:53,382
Okay. Yeah, Jason, he's coming,
he's coming, he's coming, he's coming.

184
00:12:54,247 --> 00:12:57,216
This is a big, conﬁdent bear.

185
00:12:58,576 --> 00:13:03,252
This bear, like every polar bear,
is intrinsically curious.

186
00:13:03,856 --> 00:13:09,817
He's walked almost a whole kilometre
straight towards us just to check us out.

187
00:13:11,652 --> 00:13:15,770
All other species of bear
mostly eat plants and insects.

188
00:13:16,372 --> 00:13:20,502
Polar bears eat meat
and this one has his eye on me.

189
00:13:22,497 --> 00:13:24,863
??We have to be primed and ready to go...?
??Yeah, we...

190
00:13:25,325 --> 00:13:27,737
This is getting to a point
where it's a little bit dodgy.

191
00:13:28,370 --> 00:13:32,045
This male is paying attention to us
and to us only.

192
00:13:32,495 --> 00:13:35,146
And he's not stopping,
he's getting closer and closer.

193
00:13:35,246 --> 00:13:37,168
Look how close he is. Right there.

194
00:13:37,215 --> 00:13:39,217
So we're gonna have to get ready
to start the skidoos and get out of here.

195
00:13:39,404 --> 00:13:42,055
Okay, he's getting to about, what is he?

196
00:13:42,889 --> 00:13:44,504
Ten metres. Not good.

197
00:13:45,372 --> 00:13:49,092
Okay, drive, drive, drive. Go, go, go.

198
00:13:53,855 --> 00:13:55,527
Slight disaster here.

199
00:13:56,401 --> 00:13:59,814
This bear was paying us too much attention,
we just had to get out of it.

200
00:14:00,246 --> 00:14:03,500
Hang on. Not good.

201
00:14:03,685 --> 00:14:10,579
But that just shows you, they're animals
that we can't entirely trust.

202
00:14:12,684 --> 00:14:14,811
Look at that. Unbelievable.

203
00:14:15,495 --> 00:14:17,144
He got way too close there.

204
00:14:18,574 --> 00:14:20,303
And even starting up the scooter,

205
00:14:20,370 --> 00:14:22,497
something that would normally put
a bear off,

206
00:14:22,606 --> 00:14:24,403
hasn't bothered him at all.

207
00:14:24,732 --> 00:14:26,734
Jason's just gonna see
if he can scare him off.

208
00:14:28,780 --> 00:14:32,819
There you go.
There's a bear that was thinking about food

209
00:14:33,529 --> 00:14:36,578
and he saw us, and we were on the menu.

210
00:14:39,605 --> 00:14:42,529
In April, this male should be hunting
on the sea ice.

211
00:14:43,527 --> 00:14:46,405
But behind him, there's mostly open water.

212
00:14:47,169 --> 00:14:49,296
It's no surprise that he meant business.

213
00:14:50,216 --> 00:14:51,740
And he's still there, he's still watching.

214
00:14:57,326 --> 00:14:59,897
That was about as close to a polar bear
as I want to get.

215
00:15:03,370 --> 00:15:05,167
But to really get to know my family,

216
00:15:06,807 --> 00:15:08,729
I'm going to have to get closer.

217
00:15:13,575 --> 00:15:17,295
To do that safely,
I've brought a secret weapon:

218
00:15:18,327 --> 00:15:19,430
the Ice Cube.

219
00:15:35,529 --> 00:15:39,898
Built of aluminium, toughened plastic,
a lot of nuts and bolts,

220
00:15:40,295 --> 00:15:44,732
it's been engineered
to resist polar bear attacks, hopefully.

221
00:15:49,137 --> 00:15:50,456
The whole idea with this is...

222
00:15:52,418 --> 00:15:54,500
the cameraman sis inside...

223
00:15:55,496 --> 00:15:57,612
doesn't forget to close the door...

224
00:15:59,294 --> 00:16:02,218
and we wait for an obliging bear.

225
00:16:14,323 --> 00:16:16,325
This really doesn't feel too safe.

226
00:16:17,370 --> 00:16:21,579
I'm not worried about the bear
so much as the ice.

227
00:16:22,966 --> 00:16:26,333
Big dark pools that you can see
right down into the depths.

228
00:16:26,967 --> 00:16:30,221
And if it tilts on the side
with the doors on,

229
00:16:30,293 --> 00:16:31,737
there's absolutely no way of getting out.

230
00:16:31,887 --> 00:16:34,424
I'm gonna be stuck in here
just sinking into the ice.

231
00:16:38,856 --> 00:16:41,461
But before I risk life and limb
in the Ice Cube,

232
00:16:42,090 --> 00:16:43,967
I want to see what's happening
back at the den.

233
00:16:45,419 --> 00:16:46,977
Jason and I are keen to ﬁnd out

234
00:16:47,248 --> 00:16:48,658
if there's more than one cub.

235
00:16:54,654 --> 00:16:56,861
You can see...Look at his little face.

236
00:16:57,731 --> 00:17:01,167
I reckon that's the same cub each time
that's poking its head out.

237
00:17:03,855 --> 00:17:06,858
Jason finds it easier to remember bears
if they have a name.

238
00:17:07,575 --> 00:17:09,577
This one he's called Miki.

239
00:17:11,372 --> 00:17:16,662
Look at that. Oh, very, very cute.

240
00:17:26,088 --> 00:17:27,453
Wow, look, there's another cub.

241
00:17:33,701 --> 00:17:37,535
Oh, this is going to be fantastic.
It is gonna be so great.

242
00:17:44,371 --> 00:17:46,453
Jason's named this second cub Luca.

243
00:17:47,418 --> 00:17:49,579
Luca is slightly smaller than Miki.

244
00:17:53,966 --> 00:17:56,537
You can already get an idea
of this cub's character.

245
00:17:57,419 --> 00:18:02,015
It is much more interested
in the outside world than its sibling

246
00:18:02,498 --> 00:18:07,219
and the other cub is probably just taking
its lead from its mother.

247
00:18:08,011 --> 00:18:11,139
The mother hasn't got the slightest bit
of interest in looking out.

248
00:18:11,213 --> 00:18:11,895
Not yet.

249
00:18:14,450 --> 00:18:16,577
And then she appears.

250
00:18:17,732 --> 00:18:19,506
Oh, look, there's the mother.

251
00:18:22,419 --> 00:18:24,068
The mother must be hungry.

252
00:18:24,451 --> 00:18:28,342
She dug this den six months ago
and hasn't eaten since.

253
00:18:29,168 --> 00:18:31,705
And she's had Miki and Luca to suckle.

254
00:18:32,245 --> 00:18:35,066
Whoa, she's enormous.

255
00:18:37,370 --> 00:18:38,348
She's huge.

256
00:18:39,216 --> 00:18:42,174
The cubs are about the size of her head,
actually smaller than that.

257
00:18:47,858 --> 00:18:49,610
Jason's called her Lyra.

258
00:18:50,217 --> 00:18:53,584
For a hungry polar bear,
she's amazingly relaxed with us.

259
00:18:56,012 --> 00:19:00,506
She's adapted to sun/ive long periods
without food, unlike me.

260
00:19:02,886 --> 00:19:05,616
So we have viltgryter

261
00:19:05,810 --> 00:19:09,462
which is some type of wild casserole
for Andy and me,

262
00:19:09,889 --> 00:19:11,174
and chicken and curry.

263
00:19:12,091 --> 00:19:13,661
You got the choice today.

264
00:19:15,091 --> 00:19:15,989
Chicken would be good.

265
00:19:16,981 --> 00:19:18,585
So, are we all ready for a calorie boost?

266
00:19:19,731 --> 00:19:23,144
I'm having to eat more calories out here
just to stay warm.

267
00:19:23,449 --> 00:19:25,371
You think about the majority of mammals

268
00:19:25,496 --> 00:19:28,420
they coincide the birth of their young
with an abundance of food,

269
00:19:28,576 --> 00:19:30,146
but not so with polar bears.

270
00:19:30,373 --> 00:19:34,423
This female piled on pounds way back
last year

271
00:19:34,608 --> 00:19:37,816
because she doesn't eat for six months.

272
00:19:37,982 --> 00:19:41,099
Literally half of the year
she doesn't eat a single thing.

273
00:19:41,246 --> 00:19:43,066
I think that is absolutely astounding.

274
00:19:47,011 --> 00:19:47,943
That's pretty good, actually.

275
00:19:49,700 --> 00:19:53,704
Sorry, bear,
sitting tucking into 500 calories

276
00:19:53,810 --> 00:19:55,016
and you haven't eaten in months.

277
00:19:58,092 --> 00:20:00,140
As soon as Miki and Luca are strong enough,

278
00:20:00,530 --> 00:20:02,942
Lyra must leave the den in search of food.

279
00:20:04,653 --> 00:20:07,656
And that's when I could lose them forever.

280
00:20:08,981 --> 00:20:10,300
To help me follow them,

281
00:20:10,340 --> 00:20:14,583
I'm joining forces
with polar bear biologist Dr. Jon Aars.

282
00:20:17,248 --> 00:20:18,454
Jon, hi.

283
00:20:19,372 --> 00:20:22,170
??Gordon, very good to meet you.
??Yeah, same.

284
00:20:22,342 --> 00:20:23,661
??How are you?
??Hello. Fine, yeah, yeah.

285
00:20:23,780 --> 00:20:26,021
??How's it been going?
??Okay?�ish.

286
00:20:27,263 --> 00:20:29,936
??This is a beautiful female.
??She's still around or...?

287
00:20:30,089 --> 00:20:33,866
She's still around. Up, up there,
just on the side of that slope.

288
00:20:34,293 --> 00:20:38,502
It's good because I think the cubs
seem to be ready and able and...

289
00:20:38,779 --> 00:20:40,576
but she's... she looks great.

290
00:20:42,982 --> 00:20:46,349
Jon uses the latest satellite technology
to track bears.

291
00:20:47,341 --> 00:20:49,138
We'll team up to follow Lyra.

292
00:20:49,888 --> 00:20:51,628
What useful work can I do

293
00:20:52,621 --> 00:20:54,896
and data that I can feed back to you?

294
00:20:54,980 --> 00:20:59,144
We are very eager to get more information
about the cubs,

295
00:20:59,293 --> 00:21:01,295
if they, if they sun/ive or if they die,

296
00:21:01,451 --> 00:21:02,816
what time of year they die for example.

297
00:21:03,060 --> 00:21:07,702
I suppose it's amazing that you can follow
these bears with satellite collars

298
00:21:07,810 --> 00:21:08,708
and get so much data.

299
00:21:09,060 --> 00:21:12,632
But then I suppose there's nothing
quite like being able to actually see them

300
00:21:12,662 --> 00:21:14,300
and see what's happened.

301
00:21:14,496 --> 00:21:17,021
Yes, so it's a lot of information you get
by following the movement

302
00:21:17,136 --> 00:21:19,934
but it's also a lot you miss
when you don't see the bear, actually.

303
00:21:24,060 --> 00:21:25,869
Once Lyra has left the den,

304
00:21:25,982 --> 00:21:28,462
Jon will fit a special satellite collar.

305
00:21:30,091 --> 00:21:32,013
While he tracks the bears from his computer,

306
00:21:32,452 --> 00:21:35,819
Iwill be able to tell him exactly
what they are doing on the ground.

307
00:21:37,138 --> 00:21:39,424
Which at the moment isn't very much.

308
00:21:42,778 --> 00:21:46,703
While they sleep snugly,
we wait for them to reappear.

309
00:21:50,780 --> 00:21:54,625
But there might be a reason why Lyra
and her cubs are staying out of sight.

310
00:21:56,092 --> 00:21:58,504
Below them is a large male.

311
00:21:58,779 --> 00:22:01,782
And male bears sometimes eat cubs.

312
00:22:04,215 --> 00:22:06,911
Spring should be the easiest time
for polar bears.

313
00:22:07,340 --> 00:22:10,707
That's when baby seals are born on the ice
and are simple to catch.

314
00:22:13,780 --> 00:22:17,147
But this year, there's little ice
so fewer seals.

315
00:22:19,217 --> 00:22:23,654
So while Jason watches the den, I try
to see if this male is having any luck.

316
00:22:24,856 --> 00:22:26,733
Oh, snifﬁng down there.

317
00:22:27,574 --> 00:22:29,815
Looks as if this bear's hanging his head
in shame.

318
00:22:30,261 --> 00:22:34,630
But what he's doing is standing over
quite possibly an air hole,

319
00:22:35,138 --> 00:22:36,742
a breathing hole for a seal.

320
00:22:38,497 --> 00:22:41,500
And he's just peering down at that hole,

321
00:22:41,702 --> 00:22:45,092
thinking about how delicious
that seal might taste.

322
00:22:46,497 --> 00:22:49,170
And this is polar bear hunting strategy.

323
00:22:49,450 --> 00:22:53,068
You think of predators,
sort of ambush, chase.

324
00:22:53,809 --> 00:22:54,935
Not a polar bear.

325
00:22:55,621 --> 00:22:59,660
They will just sit patiently
by a seal's breathing hole

326
00:23:00,013 --> 00:23:02,140
and wait for that seal to come up
and take a breath.

327
00:23:03,140 --> 00:23:06,735
And if it does, they're straight onto it.

328
00:23:08,217 --> 00:23:11,266
Only about one?�in?�Z0 seal hunts
are successful.

329
00:23:11,981 --> 00:23:15,621
Waiting patiently is the best way
to consenre energy.

330
00:23:16,215 --> 00:23:17,295
Oh, he's seen something.

331
00:23:19,168 --> 00:23:20,738
Oh, there he goes.

332
00:23:21,497 --> 00:23:22,498
He missed.

333
00:23:23,779 --> 00:23:24,985
Nothing that time.

334
00:23:26,623 --> 00:23:29,353
I wonder.
I wonder if that was a seal coming up.

335
00:23:29,983 --> 00:23:31,268
There was deﬁnitely something there.

336
00:23:35,701 --> 00:23:38,784
I'd love to ﬁlm our bear family close up.

337
00:23:39,620 --> 00:23:41,542
But they're tucked up in the den.

338
00:23:43,371 --> 00:23:47,193
So instead I'd like to test the Ice Cube
on another bear.

339
00:24:06,098 --> 00:24:08,225
Idrop it off by a seal's breathing hole.

340
00:24:10,503 --> 00:24:13,176
It doesn't take long
before we spot a polar bear.

341
00:24:14,786 --> 00:24:17,744
Okay, we've got a huge bear
coming round behind the boat.

342
00:24:18,177 --> 00:24:19,178
Yes, there it is.

343
00:24:19,255 --> 00:24:21,234
I'm just gonna try and get
into the Ice Cube before it gets here.

344
00:24:22,662 --> 00:24:24,539
This could be the first time

345
00:24:24,616 --> 00:24:28,461
anyone has had the chance to film
a polar bear hunting at close range.

346
00:24:36,425 --> 00:24:40,100
This bear is coming right up to me.

347
00:24:41,020 --> 00:24:46,788
Unfortunately, it ignores the seal's
breathing hole and heads straight for me.

348
00:24:48,505 --> 00:24:49,984
She's coming closer and closer.

349
00:24:50,068 --> 00:24:50,818
Oh, my God.

350
00:24:52,254 --> 00:24:53,744
She is enormous.

351
00:24:54,582 --> 00:24:58,074
Jeez. Gee whiz.

352
00:24:59,378 --> 00:25:03,223
Really, it's why I've come here.
To see these animals.

353
00:25:04,020 --> 00:25:07,740
To get to understand them.
See them up close.

354
00:25:08,380 --> 00:25:09,312
Hey, bear.

355
00:25:10,068 --> 00:25:12,741
Oh, my God. She's right here.

356
00:25:13,896 --> 00:25:14,794
Hey, bear.

357
00:25:17,222 --> 00:25:21,022
The bear's nose is thousands of times
more powerful than mine.

358
00:25:21,739 --> 00:25:24,105
It's gathering information
before it approaches,

359
00:25:24,582 --> 00:25:26,709
like it would when stalking a seal.

360
00:25:27,707 --> 00:25:31,359
My scent is strongest at the weakest point,
the door.

361
00:25:33,022 --> 00:25:34,751
Yeah, the door isn't opening.

362
00:25:35,302 --> 00:25:36,508
Okay, just checking the lock.

363
00:25:41,706 --> 00:25:45,233
It's systematically trying from all angles.

364
00:25:45,786 --> 00:25:49,187
Being this close, you get an appreciation
for what this animal is.

365
00:25:49,818 --> 00:25:53,390
It is one of the most powerful animals
on the planet.

366
00:25:54,177 --> 00:25:56,350
One of the most intimidating animals
on the planet

367
00:25:57,537 --> 00:26:00,825
and one of the few animals
that actually see us as food.

368
00:26:03,662 --> 00:26:06,506
The bear's nose has led it to a gap.

369
00:26:08,144 --> 00:26:09,816
You can sniff me.

370
00:26:09,894 --> 00:26:11,464
Gosh, I could have actually touched
its nose.

371
00:26:17,787 --> 00:26:19,391
It's like giving a little.

372
00:26:20,225 --> 00:26:24,355
She's feeling the pressure that she can
actually feel that Perspex is ﬁexing.

373
00:26:24,990 --> 00:26:27,356
She's trying to see
if she can crawl through it.

374
00:26:27,426 --> 00:26:29,030
She's trying to see
if she can bite through it.

375
00:26:30,378 --> 00:26:31,709
It's getting a little bit hairy in here.

376
00:26:32,144 --> 00:26:38,231
Ican feel that he's just pushing all
his weight against this side of the cube.

377
00:26:47,897 --> 00:26:49,592
Oh, not sure ifI like that.

378
00:26:51,224 --> 00:26:52,430
Not sure if that's good.

379
00:27:04,147 --> 00:27:08,026
Her best bet would be to get her full weight
on top of it,

380
00:27:08,146 --> 00:27:11,104
just like she does when she's breaking
into seal lairs and push.

381
00:27:13,628 --> 00:27:17,018
Okay, don't go on top.
On top's dangerous.

382
00:27:17,535 --> 00:27:19,105
Look, it's just towering above me.

383
00:27:19,786 --> 00:27:22,949
If I was to be standing side by side
with this animal,

384
00:27:24,631 --> 00:27:26,713
he would be about seven feet tall.

385
00:27:27,788 --> 00:27:29,949
Oh, you're gonna do it, you're gonna do it.

386
00:27:34,175 --> 00:27:34,903
Hey, bear.

387
00:27:35,941 --> 00:27:39,149
Every time she pushes,
every time she exerts a little bit of force,

388
00:27:39,222 --> 00:27:40,996
she's using up calories.

389
00:27:41,425 --> 00:27:43,507
Is there anything worth eating here?

390
00:27:44,066 --> 00:27:46,796
Is there anything worth using up
her energy for?

391
00:27:48,458 --> 00:27:53,236
Inside there is definitely.
Little old me.

392
00:27:56,380 --> 00:28:00,510
Once it realises it's too difﬁcult
to get in, the polar bear moves off.

393
00:28:04,098 --> 00:28:08,717
Deﬁnitely at this point,
my fear far outweighs my fascination.

394
00:28:10,018 --> 00:28:15,638
This is closer to a polar bear
than I ever, ever imagined I'd ever get.

395
00:28:20,987 --> 00:28:23,376
That's not something
that I'm gonna want to do again in a hurry.

396
00:28:24,575 --> 00:28:25,712
Deﬁnitely not.

397
00:28:28,532 --> 00:28:30,386
IfI can summon the courage again,

398
00:28:31,297 --> 00:28:33,219
I'd like to see Lyra that close.

399
00:28:35,811 --> 00:28:39,349
I was crapping myself throughout.

400
00:28:40,813 --> 00:28:44,579
We were actually laughing a few times,
but at the same time...

401
00:28:44,986 --> 00:28:45,862
It looked hilarious.

402
00:28:47,530 --> 00:28:48,269
Well done.

403
00:28:48,374 --> 00:28:52,868
??Oh, we're so envious, so envious.
??Absolutely. We're so envious.

404
00:28:53,781 --> 00:28:54,816
Pretty intense.

405
00:29:09,453 --> 00:29:11,148
I return to Lyra's den.

406
00:29:12,653 --> 00:29:14,735
I want to see how the cubs are developing.

407
00:29:19,493 --> 00:29:22,496
My family seem incredibly relaxed with me.

408
00:29:23,011 --> 00:29:24,012
Oh, look.

409
00:29:27,135 --> 00:29:32,778
It is funny to think that I'm as common
a sight to this cub as a mountain, a rock.

410
00:29:33,724 --> 00:29:36,852
It is all that cub's known for three
and a half months is the inside of this den.

411
00:29:38,446 --> 00:29:44,498
And it is quite nice to think that this cub
thinks I belong here, when I really don't.

412
00:29:45,803 --> 00:29:50,263
The mother on the other hand,
she may never even have seen a human being.

413
00:29:52,648 --> 00:29:56,209
She's constantly looking down at me
but she doesn't seem to be overly concerned.

414
00:29:56,692 --> 00:29:59,809
Polar bears are like people, every one
of them has got a different personality.

415
00:30:00,770 --> 00:30:02,180
She's not bothered by us.

416
00:30:14,413 --> 00:30:18,088
Miki's doing really well,
he's looking strong.

417
00:30:21,285 --> 00:30:24,368
Lyra tries leading her cubs
further from the den.

418
00:30:26,254 --> 00:30:30,497
She calls to Miki and Luca,
encouraging them to follow her.

419
00:30:33,725 --> 00:30:36,262
Miki leads the charge.

420
00:30:39,693 --> 00:30:43,652
Luca is less adventurous
and reluctant to go too far.

421
00:30:47,646 --> 00:30:50,900
Lyra is assessing
when they'll be strong enough to leave.

422
00:30:56,725 --> 00:30:57,578
Oh, wow.

423
00:31:00,256 --> 00:31:02,053
Just tobogganing down the slope there.

424
00:31:04,975 --> 00:31:06,260
This is just cubs playing.

425
00:31:06,490 --> 00:31:12,178
But with every young animal, every
little bit of play is an important lesson.

426
00:31:14,207 --> 00:31:15,333
Over the next year...

427
00:31:16,084 --> 00:31:20,851
these cubs are gonna have to walk
hundreds of miles over snow and ice.

428
00:31:22,210 --> 00:31:28,297
And this is the ﬁrst time, really,
they've had the opportunity to move around.

429
00:31:42,616 --> 00:31:44,902
It's great to see the cubs so active.

430
00:31:46,179 --> 00:31:48,545
But we need to make a move, too.

431
00:31:51,772 --> 00:31:54,093
The long polar days are exhausting.

432
00:31:54,926 --> 00:31:57,724
We head back to the ship
to get some rest for the night.

433
00:32:09,648 --> 00:32:11,696
The next morning, we are back at the den.

434
00:32:12,570 --> 00:32:13,935
The temperature has dropped

435
00:32:14,257 --> 00:32:16,782
so we've built a snow wall to protect us
from the wind.

436
00:32:22,410 --> 00:32:24,776
We need to be here when Lyra leaves

437
00:32:25,364 --> 00:32:27,468
or there'|l be no way of ﬁnding her again.

438
00:32:29,287 --> 00:32:33,826
This place is spectacularly beautiful
but it's tough.

439
00:32:35,257 --> 00:32:37,293
I don't feel at home here.

440
00:32:38,459 --> 00:32:40,131
I can enjoy the beauty of it

441
00:32:40,209 --> 00:32:44,054
but there's no getting away from the fact
that this is a harsh plaoe.

442
00:32:45,816 --> 00:32:50,731
And I think experiencing this place,
realising how harsh it is,

443
00:32:51,537 --> 00:32:53,698
I have this growing respect
for these animals.

444
00:32:56,256 --> 00:32:58,338
Miki and Luca are amazing.

445
00:32:58,898 --> 00:33:00,695
They're so well adapted to the cold.

446
00:33:01,256 --> 00:33:05,465
But to sun/ive, they need to stay
with their mother for two?�and?�a?�half years.

447
00:33:06,207 --> 00:33:09,062
I think it's incredible to think
that within the next week

448
00:33:09,566 --> 00:33:12,421
those cubs will be following their mother.

449
00:33:13,082 --> 00:33:15,619
They'll cover tens, hundreds of miles.

450
00:33:17,459 --> 00:33:18,938
Lyra is Stan/ing.

451
00:33:19,459 --> 00:33:21,700
She has lost half her bodyweight in the den.

452
00:33:22,459 --> 00:33:26,543
She must eat soon
or else her milk will run dry.

453
00:33:29,458 --> 00:33:30,652
You can see what she's doing.

454
00:33:30,723 --> 00:33:33,851
She's taking the cubs
on their first real walk.

455
00:33:34,364 --> 00:33:37,367
So far, these cubs have just been playing
about the den entrance.

456
00:33:38,693 --> 00:33:42,220
And now they are 50, 70 metres away.

457
00:33:47,365 --> 00:33:51,256
At any moment,
Iexpect them to turn round and head back.

458
00:33:52,333 --> 00:33:55,291
But Lyra just keeps on going.

459
00:33:56,692 --> 00:33:59,855
I think this is it. She is definitely going.

460
00:34:11,818 --> 00:34:15,367
In some ways for a cub,
this is when life begins.

461
00:34:18,848 --> 00:34:20,179
She's definitely going.

462
00:34:23,255 --> 00:34:25,780
She's miles away from the den now.

463
00:34:27,898 --> 00:34:29,377
She keeps looking back, though.

464
00:34:30,007 --> 00:34:33,818
She's thinking,
are these cubs ready for this journey?

465
00:34:34,773 --> 00:34:38,857
She knows of all the dangers that lie ahead.

466
00:34:40,098 --> 00:34:44,979
Despite all of her hard work so far...

467
00:34:45,817 --> 00:34:49,469
the most difﬁcult part of these cubs??lives
is now.

468
00:34:50,694 --> 00:34:53,265
They've left the safety and security
of the den.

469
00:35:01,209 --> 00:35:05,703
Miki is keeping up.
But Luca is lagging behind.

470
00:35:14,459 --> 00:35:16,495
The cub's world has suddenly expanded.

471
00:35:17,288 --> 00:35:21,384
It's not just the den.
It's not just this mountain.

472
00:35:21,929 --> 00:35:25,387
Almost the whole of the Arctic
is their playground now.

473
00:35:26,927 --> 00:35:32,490
And that's a place of great danger,
great hardship.

474
00:35:42,382 --> 00:35:44,850
Lyra will have experienced
hard times before,

475
00:35:46,006 --> 00:35:49,260
but this was the warmest winter on record.

476
00:35:54,177 --> 00:35:56,179
The retreating sea ice means

477
00:35:56,286 --> 00:35:59,210
it's going to be the toughest year ever
for polar bear cubs.

478
00:36:13,980 --> 00:36:15,811
Once the family leave Edge Island,

479
00:36:16,371 --> 00:36:19,863
it will be impossible for me to follow Lyra
by snowmobile.

480
00:36:23,702 --> 00:36:29,015
Even at this early age, Miki and Luca
can travel 10 kilometres a day.

481
00:36:35,449 --> 00:36:40,546
Her track's coming round the mountainside,
taking her way across the ridge there.

482
00:36:42,341 --> 00:36:43,945
Trying to follow those tracks.

483
00:36:44,170 --> 00:36:48,220
Ideally, I'd follow the tracks
very close to them.

484
00:36:48,779 --> 00:36:52,351
But it's way too steep up there
so I've come a lot further away

485
00:36:53,014 --> 00:36:55,266
and just hope that I can pick them up
from here.

486
00:36:55,341 --> 00:36:56,421
And I can see them.

487
00:36:58,449 --> 00:36:59,552
Hang on, hang on, hang on.

488
00:37:00,371 --> 00:37:02,225
Oh, yeah, look, there you go. Look.

489
00:37:09,779 --> 00:37:11,781
Hey, papa whisky there, it's Jason calling.

490
00:37:12,733 --> 00:37:15,065
Is it possible to put me through to Jon?

491
00:37:15,217 --> 00:37:18,266
Jason lets the scientists know
that Lyra has left the den.

492
00:37:18,903 --> 00:37:20,905
Okay, what area are you in?

493
00:37:22,059 --> 00:37:24,425
Biologist Jon Aars hopes to put one

494
00:37:24,543 --> 00:37:26,864
of his satellite?�tracking collars on Lyra.

495
00:37:29,857 --> 00:37:33,554
This is tremendously exciting
because all going well over the next hour.

496
00:37:33,904 --> 00:37:36,816
This is the moment that we should be able
to follow

497
00:37:37,296 --> 00:37:39,150
our female for the rest of the year.

498
00:37:46,371 --> 00:37:48,544
The helicopter is coming down
and getting closer to the bear.

499
00:37:49,184 --> 00:37:51,778
Okay, she's moving down the bank.

500
00:37:54,700 --> 00:37:58,067
The pilot coaxes Lyra to a safer place
to dart her.

501
00:38:00,014 --> 00:38:01,584
This really is our last chance now.

502
00:38:01,654 --> 00:38:04,350
If we don't get her now,
we've had it.

503
00:38:05,294 --> 00:38:06,989
She's not making it easy for us.

504
00:38:13,824 --> 00:38:15,451
The helicopter's just waiting
for an opportunity

505
00:38:15,575 --> 00:38:18,863
for her to be in the right place,
somewhere they can land.

506
00:38:18,983 --> 00:38:20,905
Somewhere they can get a clear shot of her.

507
00:38:23,186 --> 00:38:24,380
It looks alarming,

508
00:38:24,452 --> 00:38:27,910
but Jon has done this hundreds of times
without causing any harm.

509
00:38:29,372 --> 00:38:31,704
All right. She's got the dart in her.
She's got the dart in her.

510
00:38:34,496 --> 00:38:40,628
We're just moving in to where our bear is
and thev've alreadv started the process.

511
00:38:41,498 --> 00:38:44,274
She's only out for a relatively short time

512
00:38:44,420 --> 00:38:46,786
and it just allows the scientists
to do their work.

513
00:38:47,701 --> 00:38:49,498
And then they'll be up and off.

514
00:38:50,778 --> 00:38:54,020
Lyra is one of 20 mother polar bears
being collared this year.

515
00:38:55,934 --> 00:38:59,734
Tracking them will give Jon information
about how far they roam

516
00:39:00,418 --> 00:39:02,864
and whether cubs like Miki and Luca sun/ive.

517
00:39:05,467 --> 00:39:07,423
I, I think she's pretty much asleep now.

518
00:39:07,702 --> 00:39:12,787
We just need to be as much as possible
on the backside.

519
00:39:13,060 --> 00:39:13,936
??The rear side.
??Yeah, on the rear side.

520
00:39:14,217 --> 00:39:16,424
Ithink she's going to sleep quite well now,
quite a while.

521
00:39:17,856 --> 00:39:19,471
So, how long will this process take?

522
00:39:33,624 --> 00:39:36,024
It's quite strange being so close to her.

523
00:39:37,778 --> 00:39:39,575
??Can I come in closer, Jon?
??Yeah.

524
00:39:43,902 --> 00:39:47,622
Hey, cubs. Hello.

525
00:39:49,418 --> 00:39:51,500
Do you recognise me
or just recognise my smell?

526
00:39:53,904 --> 00:39:55,860
Miki and Luca are on a leash

527
00:39:55,937 --> 00:39:57,666
so they don't get separated from their mum.

528
00:40:06,543 --> 00:40:08,340
You are looking quite relaxed now.

529
00:40:08,496 --> 00:40:10,737
Actually, you look a little bit different
to you.

530
00:40:12,138 --> 00:40:13,708
Are you a boy and you a girl?

531
00:40:18,545 --> 00:40:20,911
I'm just going to measure your mother
and see how big she is.

532
00:40:25,341 --> 00:40:29,983
Look at the job that she's done.
These cubs are in perfect health.

533
00:40:30,981 --> 00:40:32,551
Incredibly healthy.

534
00:40:39,497 --> 00:40:40,737
So how old is she?

535
00:40:40,983 --> 00:40:44,703
Well, we guess
she might be about 14, 15, 16 years old.

536
00:40:44,827 --> 00:40:45,555
Really?

537
00:40:47,014 --> 00:40:48,629
She's an experienced mother.

538
00:40:49,107 --> 00:40:51,507
So they will hopefully have a better chance
of sun/iving.

539
00:40:58,419 --> 00:41:01,468
Jon has taken blood samples
to check Lyra's health.

540
00:41:02,342 --> 00:41:05,470
It's a fantastic opportunity
for me to examine a polar bear.

541
00:41:06,655 --> 00:41:07,906
Just being so close like this.

542
00:41:08,015 --> 00:41:10,631
You can see how she's able to live
in this environment.

543
00:41:11,576 --> 00:41:16,138
Her coat is incredibly dense.

544
00:41:16,621 --> 00:41:18,293
You've got all these guard hairs

545
00:41:18,574 --> 00:41:23,375
and underneath,
this thick, thick thatch of, of wool.

546
00:41:25,545 --> 00:41:28,116
Her coat is actually very, very cold
on the outside.

547
00:41:28,218 --> 00:41:30,504
That's because she's losing very little heat
from her body.

548
00:41:30,859 --> 00:41:35,467
You can actually see how she's able to grip
even on very slippery ice.

549
00:41:36,779 --> 00:41:41,295
Huge feet and the pads of her feet
are incredibly textured.

550
00:41:41,466 --> 00:41:45,584
Not rough but velvety
with very, very strong claws on the end.

551
00:41:45,747 --> 00:41:47,430
Not just necessarily for catching prey

552
00:41:47,779 --> 00:41:51,624
but for gripping when she's climbing
these slopes, digging dens.

553
00:41:55,186 --> 00:41:57,393
Now, it's Miki and Luca's turn
for a check?�up.

554
00:41:59,217 --> 00:42:02,664
They're given a light sedative
and they'll snore through it all.

555
00:42:05,652 --> 00:42:07,062
Just lay her down beside the other one?

556
00:42:09,621 --> 00:42:10,428
Relax a bit.

557
00:42:14,858 --> 00:42:17,782
And this will just keep her out
for as long as the mum's out?

558
00:42:18,420 --> 00:42:22,834
Yeah, and also for us to take
a couple of samples.

559
00:42:25,107 --> 00:42:26,222
They are completely out.

560
00:42:28,903 --> 00:42:31,940
And while they are out,
we can check whether they are girls or boys.

561
00:42:33,012 --> 00:42:33,865
This is a boy.

562
00:42:38,030 --> 00:42:39,577
This is a boy as well.

563
00:42:40,467 --> 00:42:42,298
Okay, we've got two boys.

564
00:42:45,420 --> 00:42:49,265
They've been both sedated at the moment
just like the mother.

565
00:42:50,295 --> 00:42:52,115
And there's a little bit of work
to do on them.

566
00:42:52,217 --> 00:42:55,983
Take the weight, size, measurements
and ear tag them.

567
00:42:57,544 --> 00:42:59,990
While these two snooze, we measure them.

568
00:43:00,468 --> 00:43:03,551
In some regions of the Arctic,
cubs have been getting smaller.

569
00:43:04,780 --> 00:43:07,146
Head with 107.

570
00:43:07,467 --> 00:43:11,938
Keeping track of their size is good way
to judge the health of the population.

571
00:43:18,387 --> 00:43:20,582
As they sleep off their sedative,

572
00:43:20,778 --> 00:43:23,303
there's time for Jon to ﬁt
Lyra's satellite collar.

573
00:43:24,108 --> 00:43:26,861
So is the collar already ﬁred
and sending up to the satellite?

574
00:43:26,904 --> 00:43:28,940
Yes, actually, it's been sending
for quite a few days so it's started.

575
00:43:29,061 --> 00:43:29,755
Really?

576
00:43:30,217 --> 00:43:33,937
It should send one e?�mail every four hours
and tell where the bear is.

577
00:43:35,139 --> 00:43:37,391
The collar is surprisingly light.

578
00:43:38,263 --> 00:43:41,938
There's only females
that you, that you collar?

579
00:43:42,107 --> 00:43:44,189
??You can't collar the males?
??You can't.

580
00:43:44,295 --> 00:43:48,038
Because the neck is wider than the head.
So they would just take the collar off.

581
00:43:48,904 --> 00:43:51,395
A satellite collar
with this range and accuracy

582
00:43:51,827 --> 00:43:54,193
has never been available before.

583
00:43:54,654 --> 00:43:58,420
For the first time,
we'll be able to follow a polar bear family.

584
00:44:00,186 --> 00:44:02,700
And it is a little bit of relief

585
00:44:03,420 --> 00:44:07,675
that I'll be able to ﬁnd out
what happens to these cubs.

586
00:44:09,624 --> 00:44:15,221
What I'm hoping to do is follow these three
throughout the rest of this year,

587
00:44:16,420 --> 00:44:19,036
the most difﬁcult year
of these cubs??lives.

588
00:44:20,137 --> 00:44:23,391
And that is something
that no one has ever done before.

589
00:44:24,668 --> 00:44:27,990
How does that sound?
How does it sound if I follow you around?

590
00:44:29,107 --> 00:44:31,780
That would be nice, wouldn't it?
That would be very nice.

591
00:44:32,467 --> 00:44:33,582
Become good friends

592
00:44:34,109 --> 00:44:35,474
until you get big enough to eat me.

593
00:44:37,779 --> 00:44:41,499
It's been amazing
to get this close to my bear family.

594
00:44:47,027 --> 00:44:47,834
Thank you.

595
00:44:48,027 --> 00:44:51,349
Thank you. Thank you very much. Well done.

596
00:44:53,137 --> 00:44:55,423
Jon's field season is over.

597
00:45:01,187 --> 00:45:03,712
Once Lyra wakes up, she and her cubs

598
00:45:03,859 --> 00:45:06,942
will join other bears
out on the remains of the sea ice.

599
00:45:09,935 --> 00:45:11,266
For the next six weeks,

600
00:45:11,543 --> 00:45:13,943
it will be impossible for me
to follow them there.

601
00:45:14,668 --> 00:45:17,273
The ice is too dangerous to travel over.

602
00:45:19,826 --> 00:45:21,748
But as soon as there is enough open water,

603
00:45:22,187 --> 00:45:23,836
I'll be able to return with the boat

604
00:45:24,311 --> 00:45:27,223
and ﬁnd them with Jon's collar.

605
00:45:29,388 --> 00:45:35,349
For now, all I can do is enjoy
my last glimpse as they head off.

606
00:45:37,137 --> 00:45:38,707
Oh, there she is, there she is.

607
00:45:47,984 --> 00:45:54,787
It is epic to see these tiny animals
just setting out on this journey.

608
00:45:58,028 --> 00:45:58,858
Look at them go.

609
00:46:02,310 --> 00:46:04,983
They are an amazing little duo.

610
00:46:19,744 --> 00:46:23,623
The ﬁrst phase of my project
has been a success.

611
00:46:29,311 --> 00:46:30,391
Look at that.

612
00:46:32,388 --> 00:46:34,344
Oh, very, very cute.

613
00:46:35,106 --> 00:46:36,676
I found a polar bear family,

614
00:46:37,310 --> 00:46:39,266
and I've been with Miki and Luca

615
00:46:39,389 --> 00:46:41,550
from the moment they ﬁrst emerged
from the den.

616
00:46:43,540 --> 00:46:48,546
I am part of these cubs' lives.
And they are part of mine.

617
00:46:52,332 --> 00:46:57,178
But it's going to be the most
challenging year ever for polar bears.

618
00:46:58,097 --> 00:47:01,180
This is where the drama really begins.

619
00:47:07,734 --> 00:47:11,101
In the next programme,
we brave the hazards of the sea ice

620
00:47:11,528 --> 00:47:14,258
as the cubs get their ﬁrst taste
of Arctic waters.

621
00:47:15,095 --> 00:47:17,848
Wow, here he goes, here he goes.
Big leap, splash.

622
00:47:20,375 --> 00:47:21,740
That is great.

623
00:47:22,047 --> 00:47:23,093
Asdo I.

624
00:47:25,124 --> 00:47:27,763
Bears descend to the hunting grounds
en masse.

625
00:47:28,405 --> 00:47:30,134
That's amazing. We've got how many?

626
00:47:30,326 --> 00:47:31,816
Three, six, seven bears.

627
00:47:34,404 --> 00:47:36,531
And I get to know Lyra...

628
00:47:36,935 --> 00:47:41,224
She is completely tolerant, really happy
for me to be 100 metres away.

629
00:47:41,577 --> 00:47:43,056
a little too well.

630
00:47:45,297 --> 00:47:46,582
Okay, there she is, you see.

631
00:47:47,251 --> 00:47:48,411
She's still coming towards us.

632
00:47:48,657 --> 00:47:50,852
Never let a polar bear
get between you and your boat.

633
00:47:51,123 --> 00:47:53,819
And in the hardest season for polar bears...

634
00:47:54,012 --> 00:47:58,654
About half of all polar bear cubs
don't even make it past their ﬁrst year.

635
00:47:59,295 --> 00:48:03,811
I'll ﬁnd out
if Miki and Luca can beat the odds.

