Beware, the balance. Bassoon. Softer...
- Hello.
- Teddy, it's me.
Love, I've told you
not to call me here!
This is urgent, I need twenty
people for tomorrow.
Twenty people canceled, because of the funeral
of a supermarket owner.
- They pay them better there.
- Filipov!
- I am sorry. You got the wrong number.
- Andrei semionovitch filipov!
You are banned from the reharsal.
You clean here!
I am sorry, Leonid Dmitrievitch.
But you promised...
No, no. Don't start again, please.
You will lead again in due course.
Not a word about "your orchestra"!
Please follow me.
This is all the respect you have
for the Great Bolshoi?
How can I trust you?
We will speak about your orchestra
when everything is clean.
- It will be clean
- Before tomorrow morning!
Theater Chatelet, Paris....
Official invitation....
Deleted. Vanished.
Never arrived.
Go ahead Goliath!
Go hire Bill Gates to find it back now!
I need the contract for Genkin's wedding.
A thousand guests
- Genkin is in the mafia.
- They are all in the mafia!
They dress up better, they send their
sons to study in London...
What's the difference? He wants
a party with a 1000 people, you understand?
He probably knows only 200 people
at most...
that means, Teddy,
that we will find him 800 people.
we can earn enough to buy
a pot of land,
to grow our vegetables.
We will never have to buy
overpriced veggies again.
My pension went up 100 rubli,
my rent went up 300.
30 rubli for a kg of potatoes
how can we keep going like this?
- We might sell the piano.
- Never.
That stupid Genkin wants to have
more guest than Makarov.
- To show off he's got bigger balls
- Irina!
You will help me, Teddy, right?
You will find some people?
- Irina?
- Hi, Sacha, any news?
- I have called my friend. Everything settled.
- You are an angel, you saved my life.
- Four more.
- That makes only 18.
- We need 19 at least.
- Well, worst case I can go.
- Ok. See you later than.
- Later.
Teddy... I understand.
I know you are tired, but...
I still need another
person.
Coming.
I go and get changed.
- Home for all!
- A job for all!
The nation! The people
is on our side!
History is on our side!
We will built together
a better society!
Long live communism!
- Long live!
- Don't run away, we have to talk.
- What?
Together towards the
great revolution!
Everyday the government
makes new pledges
Twenty eight, twenty nine and thirty.
You have asked me 30 and I brought them to you.
And now you have to pay
me for thirty.
Can we average out?
500 rubli per person.
Plus a hundred each as a bonus
If so, you will all come back
next Sunday as well
600 rubli for two Sundays.
What do you think?
Gavrilov, forget about it.
Every Sunday is the same story.
Our tariff is 400 rubli each person
for each day of protest
- Don't you have faith anymore, Irina?
- You can all go to hell for what I care...
Give me my money, 12,000
Not a ruble short, clear?
- This is extorsionate.
- Come on, come on.
- Extorsion, really.
- Of course.
Moscow Union of Musicians
Come on, Andrei. Just a gulp.
you are not going to die
Come on
You are still our director
You are our leader, aren't you?
- Have you heard that? He said no!
- Come with me.
Read.
Attention Mr. Leonid
Vinitchenko, director of Bolshoi.
Dear Mr Vinitchenko, I have learned
from your website that your orchestra
could be available for a concert
in fifteen days,
on Saturday June 13th.
Los Angeles Philarmonic
was supposed to tour in France
but they canceled at last minute
We would be delighted to have you
in our theater to replace them
in order to offer our audience
an unforgettable night
This is an official invitation
I will arrange a telephic appointment
to clarify details day after tomorrow
at 4pm, Moscow time.
My sincere best... Olivier... Morne...
Duplessis, director
of Chatelet Theater.
It's written in Russian
It's a joke
It's signed. Stamped. There is a French
address. Chatelet Theater.
- So what?
- We are going, instead of the Bolshoi.
Paris, Sacha! Chatelet Theater,
our life dream!
Bolshoi Orchestra in Paris.
At the Chatelet!
Are you insane? Do you want to prentend
we are the Bolshoi?
They are terrible. We are better.
Hide this away, before we
are all going to jail
Teddy, are you there?
- Yeah, we are here.
- Andrei, are you alright?
- Open the door
- He's well, don't worry.
- We are chatting, love.
- You scared me. Such kids.
We have not played for 30 years,
we are a bunch of failures.
- How can you put up a full orchestra?
- Turn right
No money, not an organization
how can we be a real orchestra?
fifteen days to find 80 musicians.
you are out of your mind
- why don't we also provide a ballet too?
- Keep on right
We only need 55 musicians
Stop here. Here we are.
Communist Party. Directorate
Tomorrow the Chatelet will make
a call to Leonid
- and it's all over
- No. We will call them first
What is this?
Communist Party? Are you crazy?
Gavrilov, the KGB!. You are totally
burned. What are we doing here?
Ivan was the best impresario in Moscow.
And he speaks French better than Moliere
- Of course, Moliere is dead!
- He is the man we need.
- He is the man who ruined us.
- He has only obeyed orders.
He stormed on stage during
the Caikovsky violin concerto
and he interrupted it to humiliate
you in front of your audience!
He is the devil! He had an orgasm,
watching you go down!
I am not going in. You can't escape alive
twice from a communist dictatorship
you should know
Wouldn't you like to play
the cello again?
Or would you prefer to drive an
ambulance for the rest of your life?
Ivan gavrilov owes us a concerto.
Owes us "The Concerto"!
Are you still able to be
an Orchestra Impresario?
Which orchestra? You should greet first
Which orchestra?
Good morning. Bolshoi Orchestra.
But not exactly the Bolshoi
- Is the Bolshoi or not? Be clear!
- Yes and no. Both and either.
We need an impresario
for a concerto abroad.
- We? Who is "we"?
- We! You ruined us thirty years ago!
The orchestra you shoved in the
toilet thirty years ago!
All the tour abroad you stopped us from
doing, you piece of shit!
Such an idiot! Thirty years ago
you would have asked asylum anywhere
Even in Patagonia! You would have
immediately betrayed our beloved motherland
You would have talked with the imperialists.
You would have spit on your own land.
The land that nourished you
I had my information at the time
What fucking motherland are you
talking about, you wanker!
You ruined us all. You humiliated us,
you have crashed us!
You stripped us bare,
sent us on the street like dogs
You bastard, son of a bitch!
Fucking idiot!
Stupid ambulance driver
It's only your fault if I drive
the ambulance
It's your fault my family
has left me
You only have to blame yourself.
You could have gone to Israel with them
- I have my information
- This is my country!
- Driver for the dead!
- Stop it, stop now!
We came to talk about Paris.
A concerto at the Chatelet Theater
- The need confirmation by tomorrow
- Who? What Paris?
It's for the Bolshoi
But they play like amateurs now
they are not good enough for this
can you imagine the French press?
this would destroy them
- Did you say Paris?
- They would write something like...
"Russian Orchestras are not as they
used to be, they are only a memory"
- How can we Russians stand this?
- Paris. Why do you need me?
You can help us negotiate, as
the good old times.
You were the best impresario
the Bolshoi has ever had
Paris. Ok, I am in.
Why? What is your goal with this?
What are you hiding? Speak clear.
- What do you want to help us?
- I want nothing.
- You are cheating us.
- Nothing? Really?
Not a ruble
A comrade pass for the metro,
buses, railways...
don't need that, I have one already
I am interested. I am in.
You have my word.
Did you see his smile? You can't trust
that snake! he will cheat us
let's give us. give the fax back.
I have seen the fire in his eyes.
He wants to try it.
Paris.
- How many seats in the Chatelet?
- Dont know. Maybe 1500.
Two thousand maybe.
I have found it on the internet.
Two thousand, I think.
Andrei, I will ask for divorce
if you are not going to Paris
Show me you are still the Maestro
and you can direct this concerto.
I have been waiting thirty years
Thirty years
Concerto.
Enemy of the people!
Down the curtains!
- Does this telephone work?
- I always use it to call Israel.
It works perfectly
And you don't pay for it?
You steal your call from the People?
Telephone belongs to the country,
you steal from the community
- What do you want me to use, smoke signals?
- Shut up! We are on.
Shithead.
- Hello?
- Good morning my dear lady.
My best wishes.
How is your health today?
This is the illustrious comrade
Ivan Gavrilov speaking.
Director of the Bolshoi.
I would be joyful to be merrily
entertained with Mr. Duplessis.
Could you gracefully have him
introduced to me?
What? Just a minute.
I'll check if he's in the office.
A minute?
I call from Moscow! A minute...
Ah, Mr. Gavrilov, what a pleasure!
how are you?
Enormously well, my dear friend!
If I knew that it was you again
to run the Bolshoi, I would have
sent you that fax directly
Do not forgive yourself, please.
It's unforgivable.
Mr Duplessis, I am not calling you
from my office now. We have...
some problems with
the post office
- Don't shout, I can hear you well.
- I beg your pardon.
It is a necessity that me being the
one to bell you, it's safer this way
Alright.
I would like to confide in you
my walking telephone number
- Of course.
- Can you inscribe it?
Sure, I am listening
- Zero, zero. Seven. Nine ten.
- Ok.
fortysix. eighteen.
eight thirty.
Very well. Do you think
you can make the concerto?
Depends on the conditions. We would have to
deny a very lucrative concerto...
On your site I have read that
you are totally available
It's a private concerto.
Very very private.
For the gas king in Eastern
Russia, you see...
It's his concubine birthday...
As you name it.
A descreet and intime concerto
But the orchestra is all invited
I will send you today a protocal
to screw you our conditions
And if it charms you, we can
rapidly pose our seal
Hurry up, we only have two weeks.
What about the program?
- The program?
- Yes.
Naturally, the program...
Idiots, what's the program?
Cajkovskij.
Hello, Ivan?
Ivan, are you there? Hello?
We will play Cajkovskij.
- Concerto for violin and orchestra.
- I can't hear you anymore.
- Oh, no. We start again.
- Excuse me. Did you say Cajkovskij?
Cajkovskij.
Concerto for violin and orchestra.
Can't hear you. Hello?
Ivan! I will wait for your proposal.
- Well done, you cheated me. Are you happy now?
- And you? Thirty years ago?
- What about it?
- Great job. You are still the best.
I know. Negotiation is like going on a
bicicle. If you learn, you don't forget.
What did they say?
Do they agree?
We have them by the balls!
Two thousand dollars per head,
I doubled the tariff.
No, it's a wedding.
Bring the whole family
- Plus 30 euros per day for the expenses
- 350 rubli.
- And of course: free dinner.
- Andrei: four thousand dollars.
The program.
Cajkovskij concerto. What after?
- What do you mean after?
- It's too short
Sacha will bring you all back
home on the ambulance
Cajkovskij serenade and
Prokofiev, concerto n.1
Perfect. Tickets and insurance
will be paid by Paris
Once it was the government to pay
for these expenses, but now it's no more
Trip planning
Day one: arrival in Paris
Outing and rich dinner in the
famous restaurant "le trou normand".
Day two:
orchestra reharsal
And a must: in the evening
boat trip on the Sein
Day three: concerto.
Approved, gentlemen? Approved?
- Of course.
- All clear?
I have got the wedding, thousand guests!
We will have our home grown veggies!
- Irina, sugar please.
- Be right back.
I'll give you a hand
I reckon there will be a hotel
close to the theathre, right?
- He wants to play Cajkovskij!
- I know. And you will help him too
- Me?
- Yes, you. Come on, come on, come on!
I will demand to have the
Hotel Paris Lumiere.
Champs - elysees, it's the best
incredibly luxurious
let's get to the important stuff
Who's going to do the violin solo?
The only violin I want is
Anne marie Jacquet.
- You are kidding, right? She is a star.
- Exactly, that is what we need!
Are we not stars ourselves?
We won't play without Jacquet.
Are we not asking a bit too much?
We need to be demanding.
Capricious. That will make us strong.
And professional.
Are these net or gross amounts?
They look like pay from
before the Perestroika
It must be for your friendship with
Gavrilov. He is doing you a favour.
- Unless it is a trap.
- We need them, Mr. Duplessis.
We have promised to correct the
situation with a concerto
both prestigious and proficuous:
Los Angeles Philarmonic
Without Los Angeles we have a debt
of 1,2 million Euros
- Not the 500 thousand we declared
- Don't blast my balls with numbers!
- What else do they want?
- Three days in Paris.
Plus some weird request...
bateau-mouche... and le trou normand.
- Do you know that restaurant?
- No.
Fuck them! I will tell them no.
You take them on the bateau-mouche!
- They are still very cheap!
- Three days, the Sein, the restaurant...
This let them feel more professional.
The slavic soul.
- What about Anne marie Jacquet?
- What's her cost?
Very high. But her cost, plus
her agent, plus tax, insurance,
the orchestra, their weird requests, it's
still cheaper than the Los Angeles
Fifty per cent margin.
If we refuse Anne marie Jacquet,
We raise to 75.
Without Anne marie Jacquet,
no Bolshoi, no concerto.
If she is not there, they won't come.
Bertrand, you still don't get it!
Call her agent.
No, I understand very well, Olivier,
but I can't do anything about it.
I am very sorry. Yes, I am sorry
too. Good luck, good bye.
- 45 minutes and we have to go.
- Who was it?
Nobody. An interview for a
brazilian magazine
Why you are not married,
things like that.
And they asked you why I
don't play Cajkovskij?
- Cajkovskij? No!
- I've heard you saying...
- She does not play Cajkovskij
- Yes, it's true, they have asked me
- what are you doing?
- I call back the last dialled number.
Duplessis. Chatelet Theater,
Cajkovskij concerto.
In two weeks. Go figure.
Just between Madrid and Chicago
So late in time. And what manners!
- Which orchestra?
- The Bolshoi.
What? You said no to the Bolshoi?
Darling, you have never played
Cajkovskij and this happens between
Madrid and Chicago, it's unfeasible.
Wholewheat bread was not fresh,
I didn't take it. The honey arrives tomorrow.
Guylene, are you joking?
I have always dreaded to
perform Cajkovskij, it's true.
But I dream the Cajkovskij
with the Bolshoi. And you know it, Guylene.
The Bolshoi is not anymore what it was
It's too big of a risk
- what's the name of the director?
- I can't remember, I think it was...
Andrei Filipov Marazov,
something like that...
Yes. It is him. Rings a bell?
Are you kidding? Rings a bell?
The maestro, Guylene. The maestro!
A living legend. Cajkovskij
with him? And you are still thinking?
He has not directed for thirty years.
Call Duplessis.
I will do it, no matter what
Clear?
My friend. She is very tired
I will try my best, but I am afraid....
- There is Madrid first, then Chicago...
- Guylene, how much?
By God! Rivka, come and
see who's here!
Here is the man who sent
Breznev to fuck himself!
- How are your lips?
- How is the ashma?
He does not want to get better,
he coughs like a donkey
I play much better when
I cough. Make yourself at ease
Are there still sinagogues in Paris?
They get along with us jewish?
There are more sinagogues than churches,
one in every corner
Churches are almost all gone,
christian French are all laic
Really? What about Notre Dame?
Haven't you watched on tv?
The funeral of cardinal whathisname?
They recited the kaddish
in front of Notre Dame.
Nowadays it's jewish outside
and catholic inside
Half and half
Will you come with us, Viktor?
- I'd do it for you, Andrei.
- You are great for us.
And Moses should come too.
Our son
It's the Louis Armstrong of the Simphonic
even better than his dad
- God bless you.
- Amen.
- Andrei!
- Sacha! My friend!
- Andrei! Sacha!
- How are you?
Go away, Andrei.
You are a disgrace! Get lost!
Watch out! Slow down!
The Violin!
You move when I call you!
- You know when they arrive?
- In a week. As usual.
Yes, right.
Shall we get moving?
It's in three days. We don't have
percussions nor double bass
I can do double bass with my mouth
let's get going
it's madness, we will never get to a
real orchestra
- Listen, we will go to Paris
- Going is not enough!
- The problem is not to get to Paris!
- Sure, problem is Cajkovskij!
It's been thirty years. I shouldn't
have put up this chaos
You have it in your blood! You remember,
right? You got us drunk with that concerto,
it was an obsession, a part of your body
How many times did you direct
in your head during these thirty years?
I and Irina are tired! Will you free
once and for all that poor Cajkovskij?
- You were against the idea!
- Absolutely not. I adore Paris
Congratulations!
Thanks a lot. Follow her,
she will bring you to your table
Please
Anybody wants to come to Paris?
A concerto at Chatelet theatre.
- Cajkovskij, the Violin concerto.
- No thanks.
What's wrong with you, Andrei?
You got drunk again?
We got guests. Makarov.
Honestly, he looks a bit pissed off.
I am sure of it. Only five hundred
people at his wedding
To my table! Up their arse, my
in-laws! Applause!
- Good evening.
- Have you been invited? This is a private party.
Paris does not want to pay in advance
for plane tickets, they will reimburse us
when we get there.
- Why?
- Times have changed.
All travel expenses must be paid in advance.
Give me a drink.
This is only one of your bloody tricks to
sabotage our concerto.
- You have to find a solution
- What do you expect me to find?
- A sponsor. It's the only solution
- Go for a round between those big cars.
An oligarch.
They all prefer to put money in football
they don't give a shit about music
And definitely not this kind of
borgeous music.
Don't even try it, Gavrilov.
30 years have done since your circus
number during my husband concerto.
You digged him into alchool, you
ruined his life.
Even when we lost the best friends
we have ever had
I never said a thing and I know
I was wrong about it
Now you don't say one more word
about his music or I will chop your balls off.
Excuse me now, I need to finish.
Find him a sponsor
And a flight to take them all to Paris.
And if something goes wrong, don't come back.
You better ask for asylum,
I can assure you that your
Sunday committee
would become quickly sad monologues
to a desert square
You would not find anybody to bring
you even the worst people for a walk-on.
Trust me, nobody! Is that clear?
This time I am ready to
choke you with my own hands
if you hurt my Teddy
Bravo!
Shhh! Silent!
It's now the moment, ladies and gents,
my dear dear guests,
dear lord minister
dear lords of the Duma
it's now the moment to introduce
to you the Gas Zar
the Cobalt King, who represents
the best part of our beloved Russia
A great friend of mine, who is also
the most talented viol... cellist
of the planet! Piotr Tretiakin!
- Applause! Stronger Applause!
- Bravo! Bravo!
Bravo!
Go for it, Piotr!
- Oh, yes! Bravo! Yes!
- Bravo! You are great!
- Bravo!
- Altogether go! Go, go!
Go, go, go. Together!
Great, great, great Piotr!
The best of the world!
I think it is much better to have
ashma than to be deaf
Shut up, that's enough.
Hello. Oh oh, Duplessis?
Ivan gavrilov. Yes, yes, yes!
I don't care. No
Trou Normand, no concerto.
I need the Trou... Normand!
He has hanged up on me.
He wants the Trou Normand.
No, it's not my fault. I can't find
this Trou Normand. Not where he says it is.
We have even Anne Marie Jacquet.
She is alright, but...
where he says it should be, there is a different
restaurant. We will change it for a night!
Tell him we accept all clauses.
Just sign the bloody contract.
It's only a week away, start with the
press campaign
and call france television.
Andrei filipov e
Anne Marie Jacquet. Grand!
Die you son of a bitch!
Wait, wait, don't shoot I beg you!
Mr Tretiakin!
You play gorgeously!
I am Ivan Gavrilov.
You must have heard about me, right?
I heard you all right, you were
talking on the phone!
Sorry, this is a misunderstanding
I truly appreciate your musical talent!
I am the director of the Bolshoi
We need to go to Paris
to do a concerto
in the prestigious Chatelet Theatre.
You are a refined art lover,
would you care to sponsor us?
- You really are the Bolshoi director?
- Yes!
- And you will play in Paris?
- At the Chatelet?
- Yes, Chatelet Theathre!
Cheers, gentlemen. It's a pleasure. See
mommy? The lessons were useful.
Stupid toad. You were supposed to buy a team!
Paris Saint Germain.
That one is cheap. Then you buy
Messi and let him play ahead.
My sincere thanks, Mr Tretiakin.
We will keep in contact
- Mother, my regards.
- I will walk you down.
No, no, no. I am the one to thank you.
My driver will come pick up
the score.
I am honored to play in your orchestra
and believe me, I am ready
Business is not important, it's just
a hobby for me. But music...
Music is all my life!
- Goodbye.
Spasibo bolchoi. Spasibo.
I am a musician, not a
beat-boxer!
Come back, fast!
We need to take back the cheque right away!
The whole Europe will
laugh at us!
can you please calm down, Andrei?
we now have the orchestra.
we have Anne Marie Jacquet,
we have the plane tickets
And a cellist that is a
music serial killer!
What did you say?
I said that I need to give you
a good news and a bad news
Bad news first. To go to France
we need a visa
Half of the musicians don't even
have a passport
Three weeks for a passport.
Eight days for a visa.
Perfect!
And you tell us only now?
And what's the good news?
We have got the Trou Normand!
Fiftyfive passports inclusive of
Visa. Yourself included?
- Including Ivan is fiftysix.
- Make it sixty.
All blank. We will put names
on at last
Can you do something like
that in 24 hours?
No problem. But this is an
expensive thing to do.
How much? We are not millionaire...
The people...
... but we can pay, we will pay
OK, bring your passport pictures.
We will do all there at the airport
- Vassili, we need another favour
- Anything for you, maestro
We are a few instruments short
A few of us had to sell them
during hard times
as they have also sold the concerto
suit and the shoes
It's not easy. But we can speak about this
in Paris. I have many friends there.
It's too much of a risk to wait
till Paris
Andrei! Do you know what
my grandma used to say?
"Do not forgot, my dear grandson,
sun only rises at morning time".
"never in the evening".
was she drunk?
You didn't get it. I'll explain it to you.
Now it is evening. And we are here.
Tomorrow we are in Paris. And it is
morning
Viktor, watch out for Moses
Don't sleep with the windows open.
- Mum, I am thirty five.
- And you still did not get married!
Even Leon the hunchback
managed to find himself a wife!
- Shalom alekum, dear friends!
- Shalom!
Come on, comrades. Hurry up!
As soon as you get to your room
hang up the trousers
those luxury hotels don't always have
the pressing iron in the room
And ask them to shiny your shoes
I don't want you to go around as a...
... beggar. Are you listening?
- Where are the vans?
- Patience, patience!
- already 45 minutes late.
- end of the adventure. happy?
- hey, have you seen any bus at all?
- i have seen a van face
- a van face?
- did you pay them advance?
- of course I have paid them
- then they will never show up! Good job!
Best impresario in Moscow!
Let's try call some taxis.
How many do we need?
We cannot afford them.
Don't panic, we have got plenty of time
- Gavrilov, I am going to kill you
- Calm down, we have got many hours!
Why did we come out so early then?
A good impresario is cautious
and I am a pro.
I thought we could have
a problem with the vans
There they are!
Comrades, one at a time!
Stay in the line, stay in the line.
Calm down, come here.
Thank you, thanks a lot!
With your picture in hand
Don't push, calm down
wait for your turn
double check your data
Come on, come on, don't jam the line
did you prepare the picture?
- yes
- come on, come on. well?
Come on Moses
France Visa only?
Ten more dollars and you get Morocco as well
- I don't know anybody in Morocco
- Get it daddy, you never know
- I have said no.
- Laminated cover? It's an optional
- No
- Three dollars only!
- No, spasibo.
- Leather cover?
- Daddy...
- no.
Where are you going, handsome?
Shall I give you a manicure?
Or maybe I can read your luck?
- Sorry?
- He is with us.
Youlia, yes, I told you already
Read me the contract.
No, non accettable.
- There you go, have a safe trip.
- Here you are, sir.
Have a safe trip.
Mr Duplessis? This is Jean Paul.
Sure, all is good, plane has landed.
Good morning, Mr. Filipov.
Welcome to Paris.
What a honor. Ah, Mrs Filipov...
I forgive you very much, Sir Duplessis.
This is not Sir Filipov.
- And I am not Mr. Duplessis.
- Charmed, I take a bow.
This Sir names himself Sir Tretiakin.
Here lies Andrei Filipov.
I am not Olivier Duplessis,
My name is Jean Paul Carrere.
- Duplessis sends you his best regards.
- Where is sir Duplessis?
- Where is the orchestra?
- Try to have patient.
We travel no stop for
many weeks
Everybody are
obnoxiously exhausting
- Yes I see that.
- You can't see squat.
Let's venture ourselves to the hotel!
Do I make me understood well?
Very well.
Good evening.
Welcome to the Bristol. This way, please.
One at a time, gentlemen
Yes, just a moment
Mr... Mr. Gorshin?
5-0-9, Mr Vilikov.
Tomorrow reharsal. In the evening Mr
Filipov will dine with...
madame Anne Marie Jacquet.
As per your request.
And to end the night, we have booked
the most beautiful bateau-mouche
for a trip on the Sein.
It will last about 2 hours and 20 minutes
- What about the Trou Normand?
- That is for tonight.
- We have reserved the whole place.
- Cheater, thief!
- Give it to us, bastard!
- What's wrong with him?
- We want half of everything.
- Cigarettes. To smoke.
- And drinks! Drinks!
- Expenses. They claim their travel expenses.
No problem, we will give you
all travel expenses tomorrow morning
Give us the money. Bastard. Thief!
We will kill you!
- There are no expenses tonight!
- Give us the money or we will kill you!
You are waited at the Trou Normand
in half an hour for dinner!
Our money! Shell it up!
You are a dirty thief!
- Come on, let them reason
- I would pay them, if I were you...
- Just a second, listen to me!
- They are savages!
They will kill me.
They want their expenses immediately!
- They will wait
- No, no, no they won't!
I cannot take money on my credit card
for the whole orchestra!
- Why not?
- Mr Duplessis...
Last time you have reimbursed me
four months later!
They took away credit card and
cheques from me for a whole year!
- But they gave them back in the end
- Yes they gave them back. Just yesterday!
Then don't blast my balls!
Give them the money or you're fired!
- Alright, Mr Duplessis.
- Did you understand what I said?
Sure, there's no problem.
Gentlemen, attention please
Gentlemen, listen to me
Our young friend here
understands your needs,
and he brought us the money
Hurray!
- Comrades, don't push!
- You need to sign a receipt
We are waited for dinner at the
Trou Normand! Let's go eat!
- One at a time, the receipt!
- Let's go to the Trou Normand!
Calm down, calm down!
Slow down! One hundred euros each.
Thanks. Ah, sir.
Calm down, I beg you!
Tomorrow morning reharsal
The van leaves at 10.00am sharp.
Don't be late, I beg you!
Have you got a key?
Yes, it's me.
O my God. Guylene!
I am... happiness to see you.
- How are you? You is not changed.
- Of course, sit down.
Be honest.
Did you come to speak with her?
Why you talk this?
Me not at all
Are you sure?
Look me in the eyes.
I have only come for concerto
She has got her life, she is grown up
I don't want problems. It's already
difficult enough as it is
I can never do this
What do you think am...
- you thinks that I can... never.
- Good. We agree then.
Right, Andrei?
Good night.
Excuse yourself, Sir.
Have you by god visioned the others?
- They have all gone
- To Trou Normand, alone?
I don't know, maybe
they have walked there
- Yes
- are you ready? I am starving
Andrei, do you really intend to
play Cajkovskij serenade?
And Prokofiev number 1?
You hate Prokofiev.
We will play Cajkovskij
and nothing else.
I don't care of the serenade
and of Prokofiev.
- New shoes. Show them to me.
- Don't touch.
- You have got all Anne Marie Jacquet CDs!
- From first to last.
And all newspaper articles
I have managed to find
You never say! So you are a
big fan.... or maybe....
- how is it going with Irina?
- Sacha, try to think.
- How old is she, do you think?
- Who? Anne marie jacquet?
- Twentysix at most
- Not quite. Look at her better.
She is twentynine.
What happened twentynine years ago?
How would I know?
By God, you don't mean that
she.... she is...
Yes. Congratulations.
You managed to understand.
It's her!
French Communist Party
- Good evening sir.
- Good evening to you.
- Good evening.
- Is this the Trou Normand?
Trou Normand, exactly.
This is the Trou Normand... and you?
and you...
and you are the Bolshoi?
Don't upset yourself, please.
The others won't be delayed
- They will land from 8th arrondissement
- From the 8th! Very beautiful 8th
by chance, comrade Maurice is
perveined?
No, he is not perveined
- Would you care to sit down?
- Many thanks.
Not a problem, choose a sit.
Wherever. Here, there. Where you fancy.
- Here, here.
- Very good. Here you are.
Jessica! Come on! We are starting.
Come on. The Bolshoi!
Here we are! Please.
Yes, please?
One hamburger. The most least expensive.
No cheese. No bacon,
little meat, lots of bread...
- ninetyfive cents.
- Really? Then make it two
And two glasses of water,
inside the tap
So much cheaper than the mcdonald
we have in Moscow
I have even taken 10 bags of
mustard and ketchup each
- They are free anyway
- Ivan is waiting for us at the Trou Normand
I am not going to have dinner with Kgb.
Does Irina know about all of this?
- About Anne Marie Jacquet?
- Eh.
- No, it's a secret.
- Have you ever spoken with Anne Marie?
She doesn't know anything?
You have come here just to direct
the orchestra, right?
You can't mix the professional life
and private life
You are here to direct... Cajkovskij.
Only to direct Cajkovskij...
till the end.
Promise me that you won't say
a word to Anne Marie
What shall we do?
Shall we wait longer, sir?
No, no. Please table the foods.
I am very hunger
Perfect!
We are also very hunger!
Yes, go.
More, more more.
Are you already Teddy?
You sound so sad
All is good, my love. It's just
that I miss you a bit, that's all
I miss you too, my Teddy.
Sleep well, you need to rest.
Irina, I am afraid I can't do it.
I wish you were here, you know?
But I am there, Teddy!
You will do it, I believe in you
I hang up now, or we will spend too much.
I love you. Please call me before the concerto
Have a great reharsal tomorrow.
Many kisses my love
Kisses
- There you go.
- What is this?
It's late, I am very sleep.
We close.
It's ridiculous. You fart!
Do you royally believe that
I will shell 1107 euro
for a jar of cous cous?
- It was for 60 people.
- But I was only me.
I am not talking about the food you had,
but of the food I cooked
and I had to throw away.
I should make you pay double for this.
- No more talking, please pay
- But it is the Chatelet Theater
that has to remunerate!
They reserved the reservation!
Listen to me. I will let you
belly dance on this table
for the rest of your life if you don't pay.
My name is Ahmed al Qaeda.
- Yes yes yes. I pour, I pour it all
- Good. Pour.
You have delay. Were was you?
I am sorry Ivan but I had to attend
an endless party committee
- I am happy to see you
- what happened to the trou normand?
- It was our headquarter
- Ah... we lost some members
we had to sell.
We will need to sell the direction too
There are more offices than members.
We can't cover up expenses
Let's go to a french bistrot,
would it suit yourself?
True French coffee
You need to ransack
It's now the time
of a true change
To put back the communist party
on the roof of France
and of the world!
To shine the example to all!
Are you alert?
Russian Television
Good morning.
Maestro! Mr Filipov.
What a pleasure to have you here.
It's all sold out, your fans
have answered to your call
Maestro, we did not forget you
There is not one free seat
- Wonderful, right?
- Spaciba bolchoi.
Olivier Morne Duplessis,
to honor you and eternally grateful
- Spaciba bolchoi
- What's up, do you think I am crazy?
Why do you keep saying that,
I know you are the Bolshoi
no! Bolshoi means "big",
I thank you "very much"
On, in that case, thanks
bolshoi to you!
He kidnapped my hand
can we fill this
areal to the maximum?
Don't worry, we have a thousand members
One per cent at the election. Almost two!
So, 44 millions voters,
divided by....
we will place it right there,
alright?
- What is it?
- The flag! The symbol!
Of the party congress in
Moscow 1966.
Can you memorize those elections, momo?
Hundred per cent of votes.
Hundred per cent.
The whole people unified
by a just cause
How can I forget. Hundred per cent.
Nobody has ever done better
Oh, I am delayed.
I need to speed me up. I entrust it to you
Come, come. Trust me, come.
- Start with the cables, come on
- Hurry up
Mr Duplessis, can I have my money back
They stopped my credit card
I need to give a cheque to the bank
by four o'clock
- Calm down. Everything at its time
- But this is its time!
Yesterday I saved them. They were
in a russian restaurant, not at the
trou normand.
And I have had to pay the bill
for all of them
At six o clock in the morning
1500 euro of drinks
they did not eat.
I gave them an uncovered cheque
If you saved them, as you say,
where are them now?
Can you hear any music, by chance?
Any unknown Cajkovskij?
A "Silence for violin and orchestra"?
A problem in communication?
It's an orchestra or a quartet?
Where is the orchestra, Mr Filipov?
Where is it?
I am honorable to re-meet you.
Do not bother yourself, please
They will come here
very immediately
They are not French, believe me.
And not at all Germans.
For Russian people, it is a
matter of education
to overcome a bit in delay.
Try to understand this.
- It shows you a courtesy
- Ivan gavrilov?
- Yes.
- You are late!
With all your goddamn
spasiba bolchoi!
Why should have we picked them Russian!
Americans, English even better...
Where are them? Where are them?
This is your job!
Not too expensive, caviar, taste
- How much?
- 200 euro. Friendly price
More than in a supermarket!
No, thanks.
- But it is better, isn't it?
- No.
- Caviar is not in anymore
- Do you want to teach me my trade?
Dad, if we had chinese mobile
phones, we would have sold out by now!
A russian Jew selling Chinese mobile
phones? It's a sin!
It's like a pigmey cooking
a catfish
even if it is organic, it is
still not kosher
- dear, so good to meet you
- my pleasure
Hurry up!
Here is our maestro!
- Glad to meet you
- Nice to meet you too
It is really arousing to
meet you!
We are a little late, but nothing
too serious
- The Slav temperament, I imagine
- Yes, more or less
- What about this one?
- Everything up there. Close to them.
Ok, boss.
Igor, Yuri, up your arses!
Lady.
Get off the way!
Can anybody get Jean Paul here?
You could have brought the Chinese
mobile phones, smarty pants!
I did bring them, look!
I have given one to each musician
to clear the customs
Everybody except Andrei, Sacha e Ivan,
they don't know about this
Fifty. Consim card. Free talking
world-wide. It's counterfeited!
- a gread deal, daddy
- dear son!
When your mother will know what
you have done! You are a genius
Exactly like your dad!
We are rich, eventually!
There is a problem, dad.
They guys won't give them back...
- What? Who? Dumbass, call them.
- They don't pick up
- Give that to me
- It's useless
- Tell me their numbers
- They are in the phone
Beware, don't scratch it
Watch out for the door
Let's call their mobile.
They might be in a traffic jam
There is nobody in the hotel
We need to make it on our own
How? Cajkovskij with only
three instruments?
It's ridiculous! How long
shall we wait?
No, don't stop. It's nice
- What's your name, sir?
- Alexandr Abramovich Grossman.
Pardon I beg, beg pardon
it is a very happy compliment for me
I no good, bad I am,
greatest difficulty for me
- I is the least good of the orchestra
- Are you joking?
No really. Maestro tell me...
play! play! Sacha, bad bad
Others no play never. I always
Need many play to get
good leveling
It's true. I don't feel like trying
because there are cameras, you see...
- It could kill the spontainety
- So no reharsal?
No reharsal. We beg forgiveness
if you came here for nothing
But we think spontainety is important.
Music is spontainety.
Considering that Bolshoi's tecnique is...
.... so perfect...
You think we are snub,
I understand. But no is tecnique
Soul. Spirit.
You ask where is musicians
They are learning.
Suck inspiration in Paris.
Ville Lumiere, Louvre, Rodin Museum,
Pompidou centre!
- Right, Sacha?
- I am sorry! Andrei!
They are my cousins who live here
The only instrument we are missing
is a bagpipe. Unfortunately one
of our leases did not go well
Police is everywhere here.
Bring everything here
Put it on the chairs
Violins here, reed on the other side.
Cello goes there, clarinet above that
Costumes on the corner, come on
Double bass and oboe up there
Flute goes close to the horn
Shoes all here
There is the plug, start pressing
Quick, we need to start
Socks, come on, hurry
Come on, y'all
So cool, Andrei
We can rent it for weddings.
How much do they want for a night?
That's enough.
Call Duplessis
Here you go, darling
I don't steal
- How did you do this?
- How did I do what?
That arpeggio, so nice
How did you do that?
- With me fingering!
- What technique did you use?
I have never seen it before
Excuse me, where did you learn that
Andrei! Where did you take
this babe from?
What are you talking about?
I beg your pardon
I am a bit confused
- Shall we get rid of these things?
- I am sorry if I have been capricious
- No problem, miss
- Come on, hurry!
Can we have dinner tonight?
Are you still available?
- Yes, of course
- Then tonight at 8.
You do not have the TV rights.
Do you understand the word "rights"?
I am the orchestra sponsor.
Without me there is no orchestra.
- Do you understand the word "orchestra"?
- Don't be offensive, will you.
- Who are you?
- The Director, Olivier Morne Duplessis.
Never heard before.
We have an exclusive contract
with France Television
Your own problem. I did sell
the concerto to Russian tv
Fifty million people will watch.
The president, my dear friend,
will watch live via satellite.
I have invited him over
in my dacia
Do you want us to cut the gas
provisions to western countries?
Ask the germans what they
think about this...
You wanted the russians....
it's a situation we need to
solve, huh....
it's specified in the contract
that we are not responsible of
natural deportment
natural deportment?
Sure. A TV signal gets lost
in the sky....
reaches the wrong satellite and
casually arrives to another country,
or another planet
- It's a natural deportment
- We can't be on top of everything.
There are satellites that capture
musical notes, various images
- Do you agree, Mr Tretiakin?
- I don't give a shit
We will find them, you see.
They won't sabotage us after all this
- You don't believe it yourself
- Me?
It's true. We are nothing else
than failures
What did I have in mind?
I am having a nightmare!
It's them!
You are my orchestra!
It's your fault, you're too fat!
You are fat and slow
Do you want to go back down there.
I could spend the whole night searching.
Calm down
- Finally
- Andrei. Mr. Duplessis.
Silence please. I'll speak
I have never seen such an
unprofessional behaviour
Do you think I could swallow the story
of Russians not reharsing?
- Mr. Duplessis, our orchestra...
- Don't say anymore
Listen to me. This is a warning.
You have a contract and you need to honor it
If you are not there tomorrow
two hours before the concerto, I cancel all
You don't believe me?
I have done it once and I'll do it again
- Nobody back yet?
- No. Not even the keys
- I have placed a note under the door
- Don't give a fuck about notes or keys
I have seen them in the metro,
go look for them
- If you cancel it, we are all fired
- Do you think I am an idiot?
We have never sold so much
Tv, radio, internet,
mobile phones, cd, dvds.
The return of the legend, together with
Anne Marie Jacquet. Ah, fantastic!
It's always the same thing
With Russians you need psychology
you need to beat them up to
make them walk. Ah ah
Send them a fax to the hotel
with tomorrow schedule
So they have no excuses to delay
Ok, I'll send it pronto
Urgent fax to the Bolshoi
- Please, sir.
- Leonid Dmitrievich, a fax for you!
It can wait. I am on holiday.
I'll go for a nice trip. Paris!
- To the concert.
- Mr Filipov...
- Andrei. If you don't mind
Is it true that you had to fight the
regime to defend jewish musicians?
And not only them, but the whole orchestra...
It was nothing heroic
Understand?
There was not much choice.
Difficult time.
- Complex... complex choices...
- Yes
we had to do. understand?
This concerto... is...
like... understand?
A confession.
A cry.
There is a life in each note, Anne Marie.
Notes... all... search...
harmony. Search... happiness
- Can I confide something in you?
- Yes
I have been raised by an
extraordinary person
Guylene. You have seen her, at the
reharsals. She is a mother to me
Besides being my agent,
my manager.... she is a friend
The only one I have
I have not met my parents
- I beg your pardon.
- No, you don't have to
I beg you. Continue
I am looking for the eyes of my
parents since I was a baby
Everywhere, on the streets
When I play, I'd like to have
their glance.... on me
For an instant.
Just a second
They were brilliant people,
Richard and Sophie Jacquet.
Two great scientists.
He was a biologist, she was an
anthropologist
Guylene told me, she was their
best friend
They died right after I was born
A plane crash, on the alpes
All right, gentlemen?
Sir.
I introduce you Ivan Tikhomirov
and Igor Nabokov.
- My pleasure.
- Pleasure
Great musicians.
- What a night, huh?
- Paris is magic!
Who are you calling? Who?
- Don't worry, everything is alright
- It's a beautiful night, yes.
Eventually I managed to fulfill my dream
to come to Paris
What a joy to play this wonderful
theathre. Chatelet!
Dad, they said 10 o clock. They are
not here. They left, can you see?
It was 10.30
Come on, then.
On the Bateau-mouche.
Why did you ask for me?
I very worked much... at
concerto Cajkovskij.
Because I maniac.
Ill.... understand?
I always think... concerto....
reach... supreme harmony
Musical absolute.
Perfection
Then I searched...
solo violin.
I found. Lea. Lea Strum.
Brilliant, unique
Big friends immediately. All big
friends then, Lea, Yitzhak, her husband
We continue to practice.
Search. Not a normal life
Crazy
One day my friend told me Breznev
wants to kick out jewish
I go panic
Lea is jewish
Together we decide...
to play concerto Cajkovskij.
I did not defend jewish,
Anne Marie.
I, selfish, defend concerto.
Crazy dream
Me needed, Lea and jewish...
to reach harmony
Then?
12 june 1980.
Concerto.
- were you ready?
- No.
Yes. How you know?
Bolshoi theathre.
Sold out.
Many people.
World journalists
Managers, musicians.
Concerto.
Start
Miracle happens
Sublime.
Magic violin raises
me and orchestra...
towards heaven.
higher and higher.
We and audience fly to
supreme harmony
But concerto interrupted at half
Never arrived to supreme harmony
Breznev stopped concerto at half
to humiliate us in front of audience
Breznev cut winds
We fell to floor
Then...
Jewish all out
Lea, Sacha, all.
- You have been sent away as well?
- Yes but all had ended
I could play not with not them
What happened to Lea?
Lea and Yitzhak have done
interview at Radio Free Europe.
American radio, forbidden in
Soviet Union. Them...
criticize Breznev.
understand?
- Then?
- Nothing.
You want me to replace Lea
She did not want me
I am not Lea, though.
You have not directed for 30 years.
I have never played Cajkovskij.
We have never even reharsed
I understand your story,
your sorrow
But I am not Lea
And together we will not
reach supreme harmony
I dreamt this concerto
together with her
You should see a doctor
You cannot make the past happen again
I don't think we should do this
concerto together
It is a sure failure
Do you want me to take you home?
- When he wants to, please call him a taxi.
- Yes, madam
I will do it.
I am very sorry
yes
Then?
Nothing
- What happened?
- Nothing. Cancel the Chatelet
- You really could not avoid it, huh?
- Don't yell at me
- Nobody is yelling. And the vodka?
- It's French
Stupid
It's over, it's all over
Concerto, cajkovskij,
the orchestra, Anne Marie, kaput.
Good job Breznev, you won again
Irina deserved children, a good husband
I destroyed her life. Give this to her
You give it to her. Don't do the
same mistake twice
What happened then it was none
of your fault
- I brought Lea to be crazy
- Not true
She was possessed of your
same folly
Let's go, let's go
come one
Gentlemen.
Guylene, beg you, beg you.
I speak need with her
He too much alchool.
Drunk. Say stupidity
Very... emotioned for you.
But does nothing!
Beg you. Concerto,
the most important for him
No concerto, dead!
You kill him
- Sir, please go away
- Guylene! Let him in
You don't have any rights
- Most good in world. Breznev...
- I know the story
Career finished, he ruined.
He most biggest director
He genius. They transformed
him in failure
- Him alcohol.. alcohol...
- alcoholic
- Alcoholic. I jewish like...
- Lea e Yitzhak Strum, I know.
I do not ask you you love Andrei
Just, play violin
Beg you.
You come, play concerto
I am very sorry for Mr.
Filipov and his friends
But a concerto will never be
a psychotherapy sitting for me
That man is sick
He asks me to become somebody else
To dive into the same folly of
that unluck violinist
I don't want to do that.
Goodbye.
Sir...
what if... after concerto...
you find... your parents?
What do you mean?
Well, that...
Oh my god.
Music very often help
we to grow
Give answers to us
We afraid
We afraid, before play music
Afraid of truth
I don't understand you.
Speak clearly
Clearly? Nothing clearly
Nothing ever clearly
I poor idiot, all wrong in my
life, all lost,
wife, children, and I give
lessons to you
You ask me words. But words are
dirty, words are betray
Only music is still beauty.
But music is trapped in us.
Music no want to get out of us
Why?
Beg pardon to bother.
Pardon.
Goodbye
Goodbye, Guylene
Mr Grossman.
Either you said too little...
or too much....
Why do you know Guylene?
And what does it mean:
"after concerto,
you find your parents"?
And you are jewish?
You don't care about shabbat or kippur.
Do you think it's good enough to be called
Moses to be jewish?
How do you think to speak with God
using a fax?
- Please answer me.
- Sacha!
You are so pale
Do you need an aspirin?
Madam
Shut up. Madam,
forgive me. Goodbye.
Ah... she... she... she...
My dear, play this concerto,
play cajkovskij.
At the end, maybe you will find
out the truth about your parent
I am sorry if I lied to you
for all these many years
I wanted to protect you
To take care of you
Many years ago Andrei Filipov gave me
Lea Strum hand written score
I give it to you. It's yours.
Don't look for me.
When you will read these words
I will be already far away
I love you. Guylene.
- Hotel Paris lumiere.
- Sacha Grossman, please.
Eternal bliss give to him, my Lord,
and perpetual light shines on him...
Come back. for Lea.
Paris
Stop, stop, stop
Tonight only!
I AM THE Bolshoi!
Tonight no talk of money.
Cajkovskij. It will be magical
No money tonight. Just music.
Cajkovskij. The composer.
- Madame Minister, Sir.
- Good evening.
- Your excellency.
- Good evening
- Ambassador. Madam.
- Evening
where are our seats?
I, don't...
fiftyone, fiftytwo and
fifty three
- who is missing?
- Sacha. Calm down, they will get here.
- Trumpets. Viktor and his son.
- They have sent us a sms
- Call them then!
- They took away my mobile
All straight, then right at the river
and left on Chatelet square
How can you live in Paris.
You don't know Chatelet theathre?
- What does it mean "later"?
- Means see you later
- you cannot leave
- you are here, that is the important part
I have been listening Cajkovskij for
thirty years, I know him by heart
More than his mother or himself.
I have better things to do
There is no more important things, Ivan,
of the concerto
Sure there is. My speech at the party.
There is a big committee
- Let me go.
- You came all the way to Paris
just for a pathetic party
committee?
Don't you have enough of your
shitty speeches in Moscow?
You don't understand. I came here
to build the biggest dream.
Do you understand me?
The biggest dream!
I know what you mean....
"Proletariat of the world, get united!"
United... one against the other.
You are so selfish. You only care
about the concerto
you think about yourself.
just yourself!
The orchestra is a world.
Ivan, ivan, a world.
Everybody contributes with his own
istrument. With his talent
For the time of a concerto, we are all
united and we play together.
Hoping to arrive to a magic sound.
To harmony.
This is the real communism
For the length of a concerto
Maestro! Can I introduce you to
Raymond Laudeyrac?
It's a great pleasure. I cannot wait
to hear your... ideas.
It's our most influential critic, but
don't worry, he is always like that
He detests russian music,
especially Cajkovskij.
Good luck, it will be a success!
Anne marie, this is Olivier. I am with
Laudeyrac who wants to say hi.
All together towards tomorrow
Comrades! Comrades!
The moment has come!
Once again Moscow supports us and
it sent us....
Ivan Gavrilov!
A real russian leader!
- Ivan Gavrilov, you?
- No! Thank God you are here!
A scandal, a real dishonor!
I was alone, I have been crushed
Jewish got back in charge!
Leonid, it's the providence who
brought you back to help me
Quick quick, they are about
to start
hurry up
that way
Camera 1 on me, close up.
Camera 2 on me, very close up.
Camera 3 on my hands.
Camera 4 on my orchestra.
- Camera 5 on my audience. Clear?
- Clear and sound.
Camera 1 test.
Camera 2 test. Camera 3?
Ok with 3.
- Honestly incomprehensible.
- So strange
Absurd
No, I don't understand
Concerto for violin and
orchestra in D major
It's opera 35 by cajkovskij.
It was written in 1878
in Clarens, close to Geneve
in collaboration with
violinist Joseph Kotek,
who gave him suggestions on the
execution of the concerto.
He should also have been the first
solo violin....
I can't work this way.
They will ruin my reputation
It's my bar, they are my clients.
I am the only one to sell
But try to understand. It's the third
time I call you
There is also the leaflet included
Yes, 300 euro.
Spasibo. Spasibo bolshoi.
They are here.
Run!
this way, this way!
where are them?
Gavrilov! Open up!
If you are up there, please prove it to me
This is the moment.
Do the miracle, give me a proof
I would never have guessed!
You really do exist!
Anne marie,
I have not told you all
Because of the interview with Radio
Free Europe, Lea and Yitzhak,
were arrested by KGB. They had a
six months old baby
Seeing KGB about to arrive, they gave
the baby to a neighbour
- Bring her to France
- Who gave us
Bring to France. Please.
What was destiny of girl, daughter of
jewish, enemy of the state
condemned to lifetime gulag?
Irina, Sacha and me sent her
to France
with a friend, a theather agent
who was in Moscow
Lea and Yitzhak were
deported in Siberia
Until the end of her life,
Lea played in her mind
concerto by cajkovskij.
they call her... the crazy.
she died of cold and hunger in 1981
Yitzhak died of sorrow
six months after
Cajkovskij...
violin concerto.
I dragged Lea in her folly
Lea was your mother
Enemy of the state
Down the curtain
Forgive me
Mum, there is daddy in tv.
He is playing in Paris!
Sacha...
in Paris?
Orchestra Andrel Filipov
5 additional shows
- Bravo!
Bravo!