Attention!
DEVILS ON THE DOORSTEP
Left!
Forward!
Little Thresher!
Er Bozi!
Sensei!
Have you all been good?
Have some candy.
Good boys!
Watch this.
Which hand?
Smart kid. Try again.
No.
This one!
Clean water, no dirty water.
One, two, three.
Or I'll knock your block off.
Understand?
Yes. You'll have clean water tonight.
1945, NORTH CHINA
THE JAPANESE OCCUPATION
- Let me look at you.
- What for?
Please, let me look!
At what? No!
Come on!
Be quick
Don't stop!
- Who's there?
- Me
- Who?
- Hurry!
- What'll you do?
The usual
- Who is it?
- Me
Close your eyes
Name
Dasan Ma
What's this village called?
Rack-Armor Terrace
What are you doing up so late?
Thinking
Well, think away
Listen to me
I'm leaving two things with you
I want them both back. Both
Don't let the Jap devils find out
Any slipup
and you're a dead man
But they've got a blockhouse here
It could be hard
It'll be all right
“The darkest place
is under the candlestick.”
- Understand?
- Yes
If there's trouble,
who's responsible?
You
Who was it?
Don't know
It's alive!
I'll tell that guy!
Dasan Ma!
Listen. In your spare time,
interrogate them
We'll collect them on
New Year's Eve
together with their statements
Understand?
Yes
Who'll collect them?
Me!
It was like this
Just like this!
Then he jumped the wall and ran off
So what was his name?
Didn't say.
called himself “me.”
So, what'd he look like?
Don't know. My eyes were closed
How about his clothes?
Was he tall?
With your eyes closed,
can you see me?
How many were there?
I didn't dare open my eyes!
So what exactly did he say?
He said he'd leave ‘em here
till New Year's Eve
when he'd come for ‘em
He sounded really fierce
He said, “The darkest place
is under the candlestick.”
I'll kill you, turtle-fucker!
You can talk family business later
Dasan's been with your son's widow
for some time
We have to talk
With these good-for-nothings?
Go to bed!
Dad, have some water
Don't call me dad.
Shameless slut
A father-in-law
can't talk this way
Go for me, then!
I'm fed up with you!
- I'll kill you, turtle-fucker!
- cut it out!
Good fortune is having no troubles,
but misfortune can't be avoided
Well, is it fortune or misfortune?
What should we do?
Take ‘em to the blockhouse.
I'm in with their chief
- What?
- Hand ‘em over
That's no good. What'll I say?
when that guy comes back for ‘em?
Tell him to see the Japs.
What would he dare do?
You kidding?
This guy ties up Japs in sacks!
What wouldn't he dare do?
- What are you? A collaborator?
- Seems like it!
I'll throttle one with each hand
and then we'll bury ‘em!
That's it!
We'll just dig a hole.
I'll do that
You would? But that guy said
if anything happens to ‘em
or if the Japs find out
we'd be killed!
- Killed?
- Who'd be killed?
He said he'd kill everyone
in the village
Nothing
- What?
Forget it
Speak
I thought we could run away
and leave the sacks here.
What could he do to us?
Sit down!
You made me say it
If we all have to die anyway,
why don't I just kill you?
Stop it! If you don't, I'm going
come back
Sit down
It's unheard of.
He's threatening us all?
I'll throttle ‘em, and we'll bury ‘em
Bury ‘em
No good will come from this
Such deeds are not
the work of idle men
Provoke neither those
who dwell in the hills
nor those who come from the sea
New Year's Eve is five days away.
On that day they'll come
Steal away with them
and disaster will be averted
San
For the sake of the village,
act with care these next few days
- Er Bozi.
- Yes, Old Uncle?
Don't tell your mother about this
She's got a big mouth
I'll keep it to myself, all right?
All right. We can go home
Wait!
There's something else
That guy said
we should interrogate them
Interrogate them?
About what?
Sensei!
Have some candy
Boy good!
Have another
Er Bozi, come here!
coming. Sensei
Late no good
If you're late once more
one, two, three
I'll knock your block off!
Understand?
Now, go away!
ORAL STATEM ENT
Name?
Speak
Go on
Name?
Speak
Don't kill us
DON'T KI LL US
- First tell me your name.
- Hanchen Dong
- Age?
- 2 8
- Occupation?
- Translation official
What sort of official is that?
I turn Japanese into Chinese
and Chinese into Japanese
So… what's his name?
Kosaburo Hanaya
Have him tell us himself
Shoot me. Kill me.
If you've got the guts. Cowards
How come his name's so long?
Come on,
we don't want to be killed
We don't understand.
Turn it into Chinese
H is name's Kosaburo Hanaya.
He's 2 5
Has he killed Chinese men?
Violated Chinese women?
Have you killed Chinese men?
Raped Chinese women?
Of course.
That's what I came to China for!
He's new to china.
Hasn't seen any women yet
He's killed no one. He's a cook
What's all this talk?
They kill me now or I'll kill them.
Why are you doing this?
I want to anger these cowards.
I won't cooperate with swine!
Will you two stop chattering?
Speak slower
Wait for the questions
He begs you not to kill him
What else?
could you ask him
who was that me,, person?
Who was me,,?
Listen
I want you to tell me who is "me"?
You?
Now I'm stumped
How would I know who you are?
Not me.
The me,, who nabbed you
Just tell us who brought you here
If we knew,
we wouldn't have let him get us
You mean you don't know either?
Where are we anyway?
Who's interrogating whom.
Stick to the questions
Just do it
He begs you not to kill him
Don't be afraid. Listen
I'll read it back to you
Don't kill us
Hanchen Dong. Chinese
2 8. Translation official
Don't know
Kosaburo Hanaya. 2 5
Japanese
Just arrived in china.
Hasn't killed anyone
cook. Don't kill me.,
Is that correct?
Is it?
More or less
Well then do what must be done
Hold on!
I've got more to say!
Kill me!
I'm not afraid to die!
It's a small unit!
There are five machine guns!
You can kill us, but never insult us!
They have nine telephones,
two radio sets --
I'll never surrender!
Or betray the motherland!
An ammunition depot!
We'll be victorious!
Long live the emperor!
- And 1 4 horses!
- Shoot me!
That's it!
Good. I'm old enough
to be your grandfather
To me, you're still kids
This business,
we were asked to do it
Give us your fingerprint.
We'll transfer you
Old Uncle. He's wounded
It's bleeding
Escape
We've got to escape
We've got to
No matter what it involves
Fool. There's no escape.
Better to die now
These peasants won't allow it
It's the guys who captured us
who'll decide our fate
Idiot. I want to die
You don't get it, do you?
Pig-brain
Bastard. What'd you say?
I said, “You're a clever man. ”
Bastard
- Sensei.
- Have some candy
We're in here!
Hurry! Help us!
San, what'll we do?
Help!
Shut him up!
Stop shouting!
Bastards!
- San!
- Help!
- Yell, Dong, damn it!
- Hel p!
Don't smother him
- Use Japanese!
- Hel p!
- Help!
- Try and shout now
San, what'll we do?
Help!
San!
Er Bozi!
San, are you crazy?
Get down!
- What are you doing? Get down.
- Move
Help! We're in here!
Quick! Help us!
- Go on, shout.
- Hurry! Help!
What's wrong? Shout
I'll help
Save us!
Save us! Help!
A gunboat is passing by
You think they can hear you?
I tried out front,
and they couldn't hear
How noisy is that
It passes here every day.
Shout your head off if you like
It seems it passes here everyday
What were you thinking?
We'll try again next time
Forget it
Between the noise of the boat
and the band, they'll never hear us.
All right, enough talk. Eat
Nothing beats a good meal
But we'd better change
your bandage first
I'll change your bandage
- I'll change your --
- Move over
It's for your own good, you idiot
Dong, tell this woman
she may touch me now,
but I'll touch her later
- More than once or twice.
- What did he say?
-And more than just touch.
-Just ignore him
Hanaya, she's helping you
Don't you have a conscience?
It's the Chinese
who've got no conscience
- First they shoot, then they help.
- Stop talking
Mongrels can't even shoot straight
If they could, you'd be dead
I'll kill myself now
San!
What the hell is going on?
What now? You faking it?
You want to kill yourself?
Use a sharp stone, not wood
You stupid fucker
- Sister-in-law, ignore him.
- I'm not your sister-in-law
Shut up and eat
Thank you, brother.
Brother, do me a favor
Let me go.
We're both Chinese, after all
Will you shut up?
- Hurry.
- I am
I was captured once before.
captain Eight let me go
Don't give me that.
I have nothing to do with this
We'll be pals
if you do me a favor
Of course. Name it
come as you are,
leave as you are
Don't make trouble.
And don't die on me
All right?
I'm treating you well enough.
Why are you so thoughtless?
He's coming to
I'll tell you one thing.
If you keep this up
I could get nasty
- Who's there?
- It's me
Wake up. It's dawn
Was it cold last night?
It wasn't warm
- What's happening in there?
- Quiet so far
If they don't settle down,
they'll be the death of me
Have a look
Brother. I'm so hot.
can't you take this off me?
I won't kill myself, I promise
Better hot than dead.
Show some thanks, will you?
I'd be damn pleased if someone fed me
and wiped my ass every day
But why suffer like this, brother?
I heard you coughing all night
You were freezing
Let's make this simple. Release us
I'm not putting your life in danger.
So don't put mine in danger
All right? If I let you go,
I'm a dead man
Why aren't you eating?
You've got to eat something
Why isn't he eating? Move over
You
Lighten up
You can't live without eating.
You're human
come on, have some.
Eat
That's good
What the hell?
Bastard!
Humiliating an Imperial Army soldier!
I'll kill you! Chinese pig!
- What's he want?
- White flour
White flour?
Where am I gonna get that?
I wouldn't mind some myself.
Just eat
Don't try to act like
a captain-san here
If he doesn't eat, he'll starve
Starve?
Don't eat, then. But this is it
Let's go
I sent them to get flour--
Bastard! I'm not eating,
And neither are you!
They'll never find flour
Without it,
you can go on a hunger strike
They're scared we'll die
They'll let us go
We'll be saved
Fool
What? Flour?
Do I look like I'm made of flour?
- Eat me, why don't you?
- Now that's silly
Isn't it a capital crime
to hoard that stuff?
Trying to send me to the gallows?
Auntie. This is a matter of decency
Decency?
You've a mistress in your bed
and  Japs in your cellar
You've got some nerve
talking about decency
Son of a bitch
- You swearing at me?
- No, not you. Er Bozi
I'm his mother.
curses at him travel straight to me
You don't understand.
He swears at me too
He hasn't kept his word.
He said he wouldn't tell you
If he lied to me
he wouldn't be my son.
He'd be yours
Whatever you say
But I really need your help
Auntie.
You're fond of me, aren't you?
I've done so much for these two men --
for the sake of the village
I've slept with my clothes on.
I've spent nights in the cellar
I've used all my bedding
to pad the walls and floors.
I've wrapped those men in my blankets
That's your fault
I had no choice.
The Jap's threatening suicide
He won't eat
unless his food's made of white flour.
Otherwise, he'll starve himself
It's a mess
If you care about me
you won't let me leave empty-handed,
will you?
That's exactly how you'll leave today
A man's going to starve
Let him starve.
Japs are monsters anyway
That's no good. If they starve,
our village is done for
I'd rather die than be a collaborator
What are you talking about?
This guy risks his neck to bring ‘em,
asks us to look after ‘em
And we let ‘em starve?
What's a collaborator?
That's a collaborator
Keep talking, there's no flour
Then…
what's in here?
- Nothing.
- There's flour inside the chest
in a cloth bag
- Who told you that?
- Who?
The one who keeps secrets.
He tells me stuff too
That dam n son of mine.
I don't care anyway. There is none
Auntie
How's this?
I'll repay you double what I take
- Triple it. There's none.
- Four times
Five times
and there's still none
How about six?
Seven and I'll give none
All right, eight then
Dong. Teach me some Chinese
- Why?
- I want to swear at them
To use the most terrible words
I'll infuriate them
and they'll have to kill me
The Chinese hate people
who curse their ancestors
Bastard!
Teach me now
Yes, sir
cut it out
At a time like this,
thinking of that
You've heard them call us
brother and sister-in-law
Besides, when I saw Auntie,
I told her all about us
What'd you say?
I said… it is what it is
Have you no shame?
She said no story, no flour
She wasn't nasty about it
Things are what they are.
Why not just admit it?
Don't push it
They've all been too busy
to think about us
After tonight, when those two leave
how can I walk in the streets
with everyone talking behind my back?
What can I do?
If a big man like you doesn't know,
why ask me?
Well
I'll… marry you
You have to anyway
- What are you saying?
- You have no choice
- Who's there?
- Me
It's him
It's me
Don't use that word.
It scares me
I've got their statement.
When that guy comes
give him this.
I'm glad I didn't forget
Anyway, we've done it
Right
Once they've left
we can celebrate New Year's
all over again
They're here, Dong
The time's come
I hear their footsteps
I can see them taking up
their weapons
I want to turn the curses
you've taught me
into bullets to fire at them
I want to enrage them
Insult them
Enrage them
Dong
Good-bye forever!
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law!
You're my granddad,
I'm your son!
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
You're my granddad
I'm your son
The words are nice.
Why does he sound so angry?
Japs sound the same
whether they're happy or angry
Why do you think we call them devils?
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law!
You're my granddad
I'm your son
Enough, enough
I get the message
But your generations are mixed up.
If I'm your granddad
you're my grandson.
Not my son. See?
How come they're not angry?
The Japanese are always cursing them
They're used to it
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law!
Okay, okay. Shush.
Twice is enough
We've made you dumplings
Just what you asked for
- Did you teach him that?
- Yes. It's the spring festival
I taught him propitious phrases
to thank you both
Nice of you
Now, eat up. It's your last chance
By tonight, you'll be on the road
- Let's bring the table over.
- Okay
Hold on. We'll set this up.
Eat heartily
Hoarders
I'll kill you for sure
- No chance of that.
- Why not?
“On the road” means “to die”
in Chinese
This is our last meal
We're goners
Why don't they act
like they're gonna kill us?
Even when the Chinese kill someone,
their expression doesn't change
How are they gonna kill us?
- You afraid of dying?
- Of course not
I just feel stupid dying this way
But I'm not afraid
I won't beg for mercy.
I won't
Shall we do it?
Move aside
Let ‘em finish their meal
Untie them
Please, one favor
Send my parents a message for me,
in the northeast
Of course. Don't worry
You'll be on the road soon
And whatever happens, happens
Enjoy your dumplings
All right! I will!
And then I'll go on the road
I lived by my mouth.
Now I'll die by it
If only I hadn't learned Japanese
In my next life,
I'll come back a mute
Eat up
Or we'll be late
Tell him we've still got to trouble you
to get back into those sacks
What?
They're putting us back
into those sacks
What now?
The Japs are like this.
They cry, they sing
Well, maybe
before he goes,
we should give him a drink?
I want a drink
He'd like a drink
Just what we were thinking
Let's get some wine from old man Qi
San
Do you think
they'll give us a reward?
Advance
- It's time for lunch.
- I'm not going
Not going to the block house
For lunch?
No. We're having
Chinese chicken today
You serious?
Knowhow to get a chicken
from a Chinese?
“Excuse me, may I have a chicken?”
Idiot. You wouldn't get
a fart that way
Watch me
Bastard! Handover that chicken!
You're pathetic. You'll get thrashed.
Watch me
You gotta stare 'em down.
Act like a devil and scare 'em
Get it?
Bastard! Give me that chicken!
Holy crap!
What the hell?
Halt!
Bastard
You scared the shit out of me
What you do?
I'm from the village
No leave village
- You go back.
- Go
Go over there
Come here
Head down
Here, have another.
Come here
Stand back
- No go out, understand?
- Yes
- No go out.
- I understand
Understand? Son of a bitch
- Understand?
- Yes
- Good.
Let's go
See?
That's how you deal with them
I see
Hold on. Get it
Don't let it get away
Halt
You're back?
What's wrong? Speak
What's all this?
Say something
I'm going to eat you
Look, it's him
You. Damn it.
What are you doing here?
I ordered you to stay
inside the circle. Bastard!
Japanese
You must be dreaming
No step out. Understand?
- Yes.
- Maruyama. The chicken
captain-san.
This what you're after?
- Bastard. Handover that chicken.
- Forget it, moron
captain-san
Want me to kill it?
- Now you're talking.
- Let's sit over there
- No.
- Bastard!
I heard it. “Bastard.”
It's for real
Japanese speaking Japanese
Soldiers of the Imperial Army
You stay here.
I'll get some kids to make noise
The Japs want more water
It's true.
There are Japanese up there
Thank heavens
- How'd they get here?
- I ran into them
- You idiot.
- Knock your block off
captain-san
Go fan the fire
Our chicken is nearly ready
I'm going to scream
They still won't hear you
Hanaya.
I've got an idea
Don't worry about us
We've got our own lunch
We'll save you the bones
It's goddamn delicious
Why did he hit you?
- I said knock your block off.,,
- can't you say the opposite?
Well, you try
I can only say bakayaro.
It's worse
Say baka-no-yaro
cut the crap. I'll watch them.
If they head for the cellar
I'll take ‘em on
Please save us
Please save us!
Attack!
Son of a bitch
Sensei
San, he's gone inside
Move. Move
What are you doing with that?
captain-san.
It's for killing the donkey
- Donkey?
- Eat donkey
This moron is terrified
at the very sight of us
He thinks we can eat
a donkey
Idiot
♪That pretty maid♪
♪Is a bird on high♪
♪I'm going to do my best --♪
Maruyama. Get your gun
What are you doing?
I'm getting you another chicken
This guy-- very good
Save it. We eat next time
- Understand?
- Yes
- We should be at our posts.
- Right. Playtime's over.
Two telephone lines to set up
Why's he always waving
a knife around?
Go back. No move
- You scared?
- Course not. Not with you around.
Sensei
Look at this
Dam n it
What now?
That idiot is still inside the circle
You're something else.
You've got these mongrels worked out
My respects
I can teach you a few things.
I'm still learning too
- You? Still learning?
- You're never too old to learn
How was that chicken?
Delicious
- Fucking bastards.
- What are you doing?
Where's he going?
Japanese soldiers!
They're coming!
Fuck you, J ap. Fuck
Fucking bastards!
Move!
Turtle-fuckers!
What the fuck is this about?
So you pull this on me?
Trying to get me killed?
Get this straight
You try and get me killed
and I'll kill you first
I left the village
crossed the river
climbed the mountain
entered the town
went to ask for Pockmarked Li
- Get to the point.
- This is the point
You always leave the village,
cross the river
If I didn't leave the village,
how could I cross the river?
- Give me some water.
- Go on
- Where was I?
- crossing the river --
Get to the point
- You saw Pockmarked Li.
- I didn't say that
- Yes, you did.
- I said I saw captain Five
What did captain Five say?
He said,
“Didn't I tell you what to do?”
I said,
“No, I've never met you before.”
He said, “Are you from Lower Village?”
I said, “No.
I'm from Rack-Armor Terrace.”
He said, “Rack-Armor Terrace?
We've never left anyone there.
Do whatever you have to.”
I said, “Like what?”
He said, “Isn't there
a blockhouse there?
What are you waiting for?
Do the deed.”
So this captain said “do the deed.”
Yeah.
He gestured like this
“Do it.”
Tell us again.
What was that gesture?
Was it like this? Or like that?
- Show me again.
- Like this? Or like that?
- Like this.
- So he meant kill ‘em
- No.
- What do you mean?
Like this. Like this
Of course he meant kill ‘em
Looks like it
There's an old saying:
Better to obey than have respects to pay
Well, better obey then
Old Uncle, if he wanted us to kill ‘em,
why didn't he say so?
Why say “do the deed”?
Men in high positions
can't always say what they mean
It was so clear. First those guys
yelled out to the brass band
Then, today,
they tagged the chicken
What's next?
Our necks are on the line
Did he say how to do it?
No
Or who should do it?
No. He doesn't know us.
How could he?
He knows you
He thought I was from Lower Village.
I never saw him before
- This is a hard one.
- What's so hard?
There's peeling the skin.,
Japs are all bastards.
More water
You peel one, I'll throttle ‘em
Twist their necks and bury ‘em!
Shut up
Bury ‘em?
That's an idea
So…
- San.
- Old Uncle
It's not that I'm afraid.
How can I put this?
It's just not right
We were told to look after them
We can't just decide to kill them.
It's not good
Besides, that captain Five
who Li u Wang found
didn't drop ‘em on us
H is orders don't count
What if captain Four or captain Seven
comes for ‘em? What then?
So why don't you go yourself?
Go find captain Four or Seven
Don't be stupid
It's up to you really.
You got them here. Shouldn't you do it?
What? I got them here?
You think I went to their homes
and invited them round?
I had a gun to my head.
That's how I got them
He forced me to look after them.
If we don't, he'll kill us all
These last six months, I've eaten badly,
hardly slept, and I'm in debt
While you all slept soundly
I haven't been under a quilt
all winter
Why? Isn't it for our whole village?
Give me that water
Slurping all over the place
Dasan's got a point
- Of course I do.
- Well…
- Er Bozi?
- Don't look at me like that
I'm not a coward.
You must have a good reason to do that
I've got a big mouth.
Just like my mother
One slip of the tongue
and we're all done for
We are still here
because I've kept my mouth shut
I sensei this and that all day long
to keep from talking
That's my contribution
Some contribution. Sensei.
You collaborator
- You do it then.
- Well, Li u Wang?
Me? I could do it. What am I afraid of?
But let's get this straight
You know the saying
stick your neck out,,? That's me
I was nearly killed today
Why do I go on about the village,
the river? Because it makes me sick
In my dreams it's leave,
cross, leave, cross
And you scold me for slurping?
Give me that
I'll throttle ‘em
and we'll dig a pit and bury ‘em
Shut up! Shut up!
If none of you will do it, I will
- That's not right.
- No?
We'll draw lots then.
Fate will decide
Whoever gets the red bean is it
Old Uncle,
it's too big a job for one person
Well, add a second one
Forget it.
I've got both
Give me some water
Give him some water
Here you go, San
San
What can I say?
What's there to say?
Leave ‘em to me. I'll throttle ‘em --
Shut up!
I need two people.
Helpers
- I'll dig the pit.
- So will I
Good
You two dig the pit.
Dasan will do the deed
Let's not put it off.
Let's move tonight. Agreed?
Yes
San. The hole's ready
It's right here.
We'll wait down there
They've brought this over for you
To help you over the shock
Er Bozi's mother says
don't worry about repaying the flour
She says try and put it
out of your head
- Eat up. I'm off.
- Yu'er
What is it?
Yu'er
Don't touch me!
Whatever you do, don't touch me
If for nothing else
for the child in my belly
- Are you all right?
- Don't touch me
- Who's there?
- Me
Stop saying me.,
Here's some food
- Where's your mom?
- She's not coming
No?
This is terrible!
Uncle San
I'll kill you, turtle-fucker!
I didn't kill anyone
That's it
Advance!
- You.
- What's with you?
Anybody see you?
No one
Quick. Shut the door
Ma, I'm back
So you are
Only one candy today.
What's with Uncle?
Nothing. Don't worry
- I'm going to Grandpa's.
- Off you go
Yu'er
Let's…
run away
We'll take Little Thresher
and the old man
Well?
Starting tomorrow,
don't take them any food
What?
If I don't, who will?
There are Japanese captives
inside the Great Wall
Too long.
The kid'll never remember it.
True
Nihonjin means uncle
Chojo is candy
Iruyo is give
Repeat after me
Nihonjin chojo iruyo
“Japanese inside the Great Wall. ”
You say it
Japanese inside the Great Wall
He can do it!
Japanese. Japanese
Japanese
Japs?
Sensei
The great Japanese
The great Japanese have no candy
for you today
- chop off my head!
- What are you doing?
Me too! Go ahead!
I can explain!
- Those guys are at Fenghuotai?
- Yes, inside the wall
You taking them food?
They still alive?
- Yes. Listen --
- Why?
Enough's been said
First they shout out to the brass band
then they tag the chicken
Now they're using Little Thresher.
Three times unlucky
We're going to lose our heads
No doubt about it
- I ask you. Should they be killed?
- Sure
So why didn't you do it?
It's either them or us
Where'd those guys come from?
Who brought them?
What are you saying?
I don't know who brought ‘em here
You don't?
It would take at least two men
to drag those two sacks.
Even four
Four? Try five or six
And you saw nothing?
- Don't you have eyes?
- They were closed
Really? You opened the door?
You did it with your eyes closed?
No, I closed ‘em after
I say you saw everything
I didn't. It was dark.
I couldn't see a thing
cut it out.
Tell us what you're getting out of this
Nothing
Nothing? I don't believe it.
If not, why protect them?
You said you'd pay me back eightfold.
Where's that coming from?
Yes, we all see through it now
You're just bullshitting about
the threat to the village
Who is this killer? Let him come
I'll sit at home and wait.
Is he going to kill me? Would he dare?
Only your life's in danger
- can you pipe down?
- Pipe down?
What am I afraid of?
The Japs have been here for eight years
Eight years
And have they touched a hair
on my head?
My behavior is right and proper
Wherever I go, they look up to me
Ma. Enough
Little Thresher, don't hide.
You speak Japanese?
You can go to the blockhouse
but First show Uncle San
what you've learned
Go on
The Japanese are inside the Great Wall
Don't hit him!
H it me if you dare!
come on!
I'll be frank
The child in my belly was conceived
the night those men came here
If Dasan kills ‘em,
it will curse my baby
You want us to kill ‘em?
And then you ignore us?
Dasan looks like a ghost
Now that they're still alive,
you come at us with this business
We can't do anything right.
You know all the answers
We didn't kill anybody.
We can't kill and we won't!
We can't
I'm afraid. I couldn't do it
Yu'er, how can you talk like that?
We all see what's going on
between you and Dasan
but have we said anything?
You defend him
like he's your husband
If you can't kill anyone,
why should we?
You're scared to bear a cursed child.
And us?
We'll all be cursed souls soon enough
Dasan. I want my flour back.
Eightfold. Pay me back now
Look at yourself.
Do you look like a man?
Whether Dasan's a man or not
is for me to say
Don't tell me
you'd know better than me
Wanna go to the blockhouse?
Go then!
I'll lead you there!
No big deal!
I'll tell you this, though
If they come down after us,
no one will escape
We'll all pay with our lives.
Who are you threatening?
If we go, we die
and if we stay, we die
If it's all the same,
just behead me now
Please, get it over with.
Otherwise, I'm not moving
Say something, Old Uncle
Good fortune is having no troubles,
but misfortune can't be avoided
I'm the youngest.
Kill me first
I'm in this too.
Let him kill us all. Here
Don't push me
If you push me,
I could do anything
Fine. It's not too late for action
- I'll help you dig the trench.
- Me too
- Let's do it.
- Me?
Do it?
I'll run away
Next
Come here
- It's all beans.
-All right
- Move.
- Hold on! Halt!
Show me
This way
Beard, different with photo
Cut short
Understand?
- Cut short.
- Short
- Understand, you?
- I understand
Move it
Next
Bearded guy, come here
Welcome the Japanese
to the neighborhood
800 years ago,
we were all one brood
We all write with characters
and our soups use pickles
When they beat us,
it really tickles
If they call me bakayaro,
I think it's good
The Imperial Army
gives us “mixi” food
We love the Imperial Army
like family --
- Where you from?
- Rack-Armor Terrace
- Name?
- Dasan
- Who sent you?
- Old Uncle
Old Uncle?
No wonder you called me
brother-in-law
What's up?
Well, where to start?
You want to hi re an assassin
Am I right?
Didn't Old Uncle tell you
about my marksmanship?
He said you can hit a fly
at 1 00 paces
That's right -- but with a gun.
A nine-chamber automatic
The further the target,
the more accurate the shot
Naturally
There's a blockhouse
at Rack-Armor Terrace, yeah?
Yeah
- The village is as small as an ass cheek?
- Yeah
How can you use a gun then?
This is a job for a sword
But Old Uncle is asking you.
You can't say no, can you?
- can't do it.
- You can't do it?
can't do it
All right
- What are you doing?
- Going home
You can go,
but you gotta leave the beans
What? You won't help,
but you want the beans?
I can't help you out,
but you gotta leave them
You want to kill a Jap
but don't want anyone to know, right?
Right
- It's a secret, right?
- Yeah
So, I'll keep your secret.
It's like this
If I don't take something as payment
how can you trust me to keep quiet?
I don't need your beans.
I just want you to feel okay about this
Silly man.
You've simply come to the wrong place
I make tofu. If you throw in sorghum,
would it still be tofu?
The more sorghum you put in,
the less it'll be like tofu
In the future, remember:
if you want a swordsman
don't go to the one with the gun.
Do you get my logic?
- No.
- No?
Let me show you what I mean
Attention!
What'll we do?
Take a detour
Halt.
What are we afraid of?
Running means
we've done wrong
Sensei
Get down
They must have lost this battle.
They usually kowtow before me
They're back.
Yayoi. Look
They've been gone so long
At last they're back
Yayoi, what's wrong?
Matsuno?
Matsuno!
Idiots! Go back Inside!
What's all this fuss?
Shameless hussy
Look at him
You need wits and bravery
Silly man
It's not just a family matter
Besides,
I've got a Chinese heart too
So you do
Let's go
Brother-in-law.
Where are you taking me?
- To the military police.
- What?
To the bathhouse
You know the em press Tz'u-hsi?
Yeah
How about the eight ministers?
Yeah. U h, no
Didn't think you would
Darlings of the court.
All beheaded
Know who wielded the sword?
No
- Old man Li u.
- Really?
The day of the beheadings,
a sea of people surrounded North Gate
It was packed
- South Gate.
- Right, South Gate
Did they come to see
the eight ministers?
No
They cheered at every head
old man Li u cut
Watching him use his sword
was like tasting the finest wine
They even celebrated it in poems
Old man Li u, does he worry
that people will hate him?
No. They never hate him.
They're grateful
The descendants of those he's executed
bring him gifts
every day, every year,
every generation
Old man Li u,
which generation are we up to?
See? The fifth generation
Do you know why?
No
Because he's helped them
up to heaven
H is blade is like a passing breeze
Before they know it,
they're in the land of the immortals
Their last vision
is of Li u with his sword
Gratitude wells up within them
You know how they show it?
No
Their head
rolls exactly nine times
looks back at him
and blinks three times
The corners of their mouths turn up
You've heard of greeting death
with a smile,,? That's it
Say no more
What can I give you to do this job?
Oh. If old man Li u likes you,
he won't take a cent
If he doesn't,
mountains of gold won't move him
Say no more. Old man Li u
I can't even offer you beans
But I'll kowtow on behalf
of my whole village
“The Great Wall still stands,
yet the emperor ch'in Shih Huang
is no more!”
Few Imperial Army soldiers
get taken prisoner
Fewer still are
the prisoners of peasants
I might be the only one
Oh, Fate
At least I've killed about
20 Chinese
Worthless though their lives were
Aren't 20 lives worth your one?
Sure
The Chinese are people too
It's a pity
A soldier should die in battle
To die at the hands of these peasants
is so unheroic
Heroic?
I can help you
How the hell can you help me?
I could eat your flesh
like sashimi
Shut your traps.
For fuck's sake
What do you think?
I'm speechless.
You're a master
How's the time?
The moon is bright, the stars are few.
Perfect
And how are they?
- They've eaten their last meals.
- Let's do it
A Jap?
I'm speechless
A Chinese?
- Words fail me.
- The Jap first
collect the corpses
- You've worked hard.
- It was nothing
He's still alive! Grab him!
- They're not dead!
- Impossible
They're jumping around!
Headless chickens
jump around too
Stop
But their heads are still
on their shoulders
Let me go!
- Got him?
- Grab him
- What's going on?
- They're not dead
Try again!
I'm not called
“One Strike Liu” for nothing.
They're just not fated to die
My brilliant reputation has been
destroyed in an instant
I never imagined that because of you
I'd lose my honor
Especially this late in life!
Heaven help me!
Old Uncle.
The slate is clean between us
All of you take care.
We'll meet again
But -- But --
Teach me to curse my emperor.
They'd love that
They don't know who he is
Teach me to say nice things.
I'll do anything not to be killed
Hanaya, you've said all the n ice things
there are to say
What?
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
You're my granddad,
I'm your son.,
- I won't say that again.
- Remember?
I'll never curse them again
You never did curse them
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
You're my grand dad,
I'm your son.
That's what it meant
You tricked me!
Educated people are so evil
I hate you educated people!
- What sort of shitty samurai are you?
- I'm no samurai! I'm a peasant!
My family raises silk
Not samurai!
If a warrior dies with no witnesses,
he's no warrior!
You're no fucking actor either,
just a sergeant
I hate stupid Japanese people like you!
Low life peasant!
No fucking dignity at all!
You're the lowlife!
- Worse than the peasants!
- Bastard
The people here gave up
their own rations
to keep us alive these six months
That woman even dressed my wounds
She's got feelings for me
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
She'd do the same for me
if I was wounded
- You're so pathetic!
- Bastard!
Stop it. Stop it
- Shut up!
- Shut up
It's not going to save
your fucking life
I've got an idea
Hanaya says
if we take them back home,
we'll get two carts of grain
It'll be New Year's Day every day
Lives for grain
- You go.
- You go
- You first.
- You first
Speak
I say no deal
- I agree. No deal.
- No deal
- Why not?
- Don't know. Doesn't feel right
- I say let's do it.
- Why?
Why not?
I al ready said why.
It doesn't feel right
That's not enough.
What'll we gain by not doing it?
If you say no, take ‘em home yourselves
and look after ‘em like a wife
What'll we gain?
You tell us
what the disadvantages are?
What if that guy comes back for ‘em?
He said he'd be here on New Year's Eve.
Half a year has passed
What if he never comes?
We gonna keep ‘em our whole lives?
Does a deal
count as collaboration?
collaboration?
You always throw that word around
You help Japs kill Chinese,
you're a collaborator
But asking them for some grain?
If you return the Jap but don't ask
for grain, that's collaboration
Who grew it anyway?
We Chinese did
We've got our backs to the sun.
Our sweat flows, irrigating the soil
Why should the Japs
get it for free?
I'll take the grain from their mouths
and put it in ours
And not just ours.
All our relatives will get their share
That's collaborating?
You'd call me a collaborator for that?
Well, no
If everyone was like us
and took the Japs
and traded ‘em in
what would the world be like then?
The Japs would be the collaborators
Say we agree
- I say no.
- Explain yourself
You're in with sensei,
but I slapped Hanaya
True.
And what about One Strike Liu?
- Say we disagree.
- What do you mean?
I was gonna say
Li u Wang,
the fact you hit Hanaya hardly counts
How often have the Japs hit you?
One Strike Liu
is a more serious matter
What do we do then?
I've been thinking about it
We'll say the guy
who captured ‘em came back
to kill them
We talked ourselves blue in the face,
but got rid of him
saving their lives.
That's believable
- I believe it.
- And why not? They're not dead
We saved ‘em, didn't we?
And for that, they're gonna punish you?
They've got to reward you
It still doesn't feel right
Why not?
I found One Strike Liu,
and I'm not worried
You won't eat food that's
put in your mouth? Are you a coward?
I give you men. You give us grain.
I've done you no wrong
Would you treat me badly?
Aren't our hearts made of flesh?
I'll throttle ‘em both
- and twist their necks like fried dough.
- Forget the fried dough
No flour, no fried dough
Li u Wang is right.
If we don't go,
we can't get the grain
Grain.
There'll be enough grain
to feed the whole village for a year
Auntie, I said
I'd pay you back eightfold
It'll be eighty-fold
- You said it, not me.
- I sure did
Forget the two carts of grain
If it was two carts of shit,
I'd still do it
I'd do it for nothing
I don't want them another day
If you're scared, don't come.
Fine. I'll go myself
I'll take those two carts of grain
bag by bag
I'll bring it back to you myself.
I'll deliver it
and put it in your mouths if I have to.
You'll eat it and be grateful
And you'll feel remorse in your gut
cal m down.
No one said they weren't going
- No.
- No
So, we're going?
What an effort
Give me some water
Why do you have to make him cry?
Yes.
I'll make the decision for us
Hanaya wants to see you
Yes
Hanaya.
I want to ask you three things
Answer truthfully
How will you guarantee our safety
and how will you raise
the question of the grain?
I'll tell you how
We all come
from the same county
Captain Inokichi Sakatsuka
is from my village
We grew up together. We're friends.
Translate
He says:
We all come from the same village.
I know captain Sakatsuka
We grew up together.,
No wonder. The same village
- So he's a peasant too. Just like us.
- A son of the soil
Yes, that's it
I'm a son of the soil
But I'm a sergeant too,
in charge of food supplies
The Imperial Army has a policy
of rewarding those who help it
So I can promise
you will get your grain
He says --
And I also want to say
that I've been well treated here
You saved my life.
You'll be perfectly safe. Translate!
I'm a sergeant
in charge of foodstuffs
The Imperial Army rewards those
who help it. You'll get your grain
You've looked after me well
You saved my life.
Your safety is guaranteed.,
I thought he was a cook.
Now he's a sergeant?
Brother, I was afraid you were going
to kill us. So I made that up
Made it up?
Maybe you've made up all this too
At a time like this, would I dare?
What?
They're afraid I'm making this up
You better not be, Dong!
It's a matter of life and death!
Stop lying
If I was playing games now
I'd be the loser
- What are you talking about?
- He's afraid I'm lying
If I was, I'd only be hurting myself
Sit back down
Sit down
Listen.
I don't care what rank you hold
Since you've been in our village,
we've fed you
looked after your wounds,
cut your hair and beard
In your heart, you know
we've treated you well
- Very well. What else is there?
- Ask him
He says they've fed you, healed you
cut your hair
and treated you well, right?
Like members of their own family
Especially Dasan and his pregnant wife.
They've been great
You've treated us like family,
especially Dasan and his wife
Look, let's not talk about that
Don't talk about that
What's the second question?
And the second question?
You answered it
before I even asked
Well
is there anything else?
You've answered everything.
He finally looks happy
The swordsman wasn't one of you
I could tell from his accent
he was one of those who captured us
You persuaded him to leave
and saved our lives
I've told him this. We thank you
It was nothing
We were talking about the swordsman
- Nothing to do with you people.
- That's right
So long as you know that
That's fine
Sit back down
Since that's the case,
I'll read this back to you
If you've no problem with it,
you can sign it
They've got an agreement to sign
The Japanese Kosaburo Hanaya
arrived in our village at year's end
It was cold. He was frightened
disheveled, and wounded by a bullet
Who brought him here, we do not know
Six months passed.
Winter turned to summer
The villagers were kind and righteous
They did all they could to help --
clothing, sheltering and feeding him
despite the hardship
We've all been through this turmoil.
We'll never forget this experience
Hanaya in gratitude promised us
two carts of grain as a reward
We happily accepted this offer
Now Hanaya and his translator
return to you
And hereafter,
both sides will live in peace
Signed by the Chinese and the Japanese.,
Captain!
Hanaya is back!
- What's happening?
- Hanaya is back!
Captain!
Hanaya is back?
Yes. Hanaya is back
I'm back
I'm really back!
I'm back!
- How come he's still alive?
- What happened to h is uniform?
Did he get taller?
Attention!
Captain, sir!
Kosaburo Hanaya
has returned to the ranks!
Dasan. Look. What a mess
Oh, no
This is terrible.
Get off. Off. Give me a hand
Pull 'em apart
- Push.
- He won't budge
We didn't plan this
“We didn't plan this. ”
We didn't tell him to do that
“We didn't tell him to do that. ”
Fucking hell
captain-san.
We're so sorry
Turn around!
-Attention.
- Yes, sir
- Know why we're beating you?
- No
What? Stupid pig.
- Now you understand?
- Yes, sir
Say it. Why are we beating you?
I shouldn't have come back alive
You think dying would've solved it?
Yes, but --
Your name's inscribed
in the Yasukuni Shrine
I've already. informed your father
You're the goddamn hero of the village.
And now you're back, alive
You have lost face for the village
and the Imperial Army
Worse, you've returned
with a herd of Chinese swine
Bastard
They weren't the ones who captured me.
They saved me
First they captured you,
then the pigs saved you
You know how many died in that battle?
If they didn't ambush us, who did?
I was taken to them
only after I was shot.
I never meant to surrender. I--
What are you saying?
Swine
Tell us, were you a prisoner or not?
Speak
Yes
I passed out,
and when I a woke
I was tied up in a sack
Because you passed out,
you think it's all right?
Couldn't you have committed suicide?
I had no opportunity!
Bastard! You need an opportunity
to commit suicide?
But --
- You think you deserve to live?
- Move!
You bastard.
Why aren't you helping?
Feel sorry for him, do you?
You want to forgive him?
Hanaya wants to say something
- Bastard!
- I'm sorry
Truly sorry.
So truly sorry
And that makes everything all right?
Let him speak.
Soon they'll have you on the rack
with chili water up your nose.
Scared?
Get a grip on yourself
What are you scared of?
Everyone's here
A chopped-off head leaves a big scar.
Blame it all on me
You can say I captured the Jap
If we were scared,
would we be here?
We're just hanging around.
Why can't we talk?
I thought everything was fine
until your donkey started acting up.
He's got no sense of timing
He could have chosen
another horse besides the Jap's
Please forgive me
Please forgive me. I'm so sorry
Hanaya,
let me read this letter to you
Yes, sir
The son of the Hanayas'
is a great hero
Each time I pass by their door,
I lower my head in shame
Hanaya is the pride of our village
Son. Kill more Chinese pigs
for your father
Serve the emperor well.
Solemnly yours --
San. You kept Hanaya
locked up for six months
couldn't they do the same to us?
Why do you always think the worst?
You call that locked up?
I call it looking after them
Besides, we didn't capture him.
He wasn't our prisoner
But now we're locked up here
with nothing to eat or drink.
So aren't we the prisoners now?
Prisoners?
Don't you have two legs?
You came here yourself
If you're a prisoner,
you're your own prisoner
Dad.
How can you sleep?
- This is no good. Move.
- San
I've got something to say
to your captain-san
Get back!
- I've got something to say --
- Get back!
- I've got --
- But I must talk to him.
- Get back!
Move again and I'll kill you
Then --
Kosaburo Hanaya
On August 15, 1945
Zixuan Zhao, Dasan Ma
Kosaburo Hanaya, Hanchen Dong,
solemnly agreed to these terms.
- Hanaya.
- Yes, sir
You groveled enough.
Why not mention this as well?
I was about to
- Bastard.
- Shut up
Captain,
you don't have to honor the agreement
Shut up! Fool!
Hanaya left h is fingerprint
Unlike the Chinese,
the Japanese are honorable people
Get out!
Yes, sir
- I humbly take my leave.
- Get out
- Hanaya.
- Yes, sir
You've signed an agreement
The Imperial Army honors
its pledges.
I have no choice
but to carry this through
Hold on. In my experience,
the Chinese are unreliable mongrels
If they say east, think west
I'm sure it's not as simple as it seems.
There must be someone behind this
Shut up. Bastard
Hanaya. Standup
This matter--
I'll do this for you
All right?
Yes, sir
Attention!
Who signed this agreement?
What, afraid to admit you signed?
I signed
Good. Come here
Dasan Ma
Good.
Here, come
San
♪Fifty years♪
♪Passes♪
♪Like clouds♪
♪In the sky♪
♪An illusion♪
Lieutenant Nonomura
What is it, Inoue?
Phone call
Urgent phone call
From Western Fortress Town
They haven't called in
over a month
They must have a mission for us
Charge!
- Follow me!
- Onwards!
Is that Old Uncle?
Old Uncle here
It's me, Dasan
- Is that San?
- Yeah
What's up?
The grain will be there tonight
It'll arrive by dusk
- What?
- Get everyone together
Everyone must be there
Do you understand me?
- What?
- can you hear me?
Huh? What?
I said, do you understand me?
I hear you
Gather everyone together
- Right?
- Right
San
- Have a safe journey.
- I will
Take care
Yeah
I'm finished
Yes, we know
Captain.
Lieutenant Nonomura would like a word
Hello?
Yes, organize a celebration
with the navy and infantry
He's so far away. But he sounded like
he was in the next room
Wasn't that amazing?
It's no wonder --
What are you talking about?
He says the captain is
the kindest of men
and the Imperial Army has
the finest of things
Hanaya stayed with you
for six months
He consumed much food
and put you out
So
I will give you
the two carts of grain.
and add four carts as a reward.
Six in all. How's that? Translate
The captain said,
because of the grain eaten by Hanaya
he will add four carts as a reward.
Six in all. How's that?
- Six carts of grain?
- Thank the captain-san
I'm speechless
What's he saying?
His gratitude knows no bounds.
He wishes to kowtow before you
All right. Load the carts.
Get their people together. Hurry up
Quickly, load the carts,
before the Japs change their mind
- Load the carts? Great.
- come back
- You've got to bow to the captain-san.
- captain-san
- Well, San?
- What happened?
You're going on the rack
with chili water up your nose
They've given us the two carts
pl us four more. Six in all
That's wonderful!
Let's load ‘em up
You can slap me if you like
Go right, Captain
can you take this for me?
I want to pick up Yu'er
and collect a few others as well
Won't the old man get angry?
Don't tell him. Let him brood.
Forget him
Okay
Long live the emperor!
Company, attention
- Nonomura at your service.
- Sakatsuka at yours
Old Uncle!
We're back!
Right turn!
We've got the grain!
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
You're my granddad,
I'm your son
Where's my stool?
Rabbit-fucker
Eat up
We walk the straight
and narrow path
A healthy foot doesn't fear
a twisted shoe
Eat, drink and be merry
Lieutenant Nonomura,
strike up the band
I want to say a few words.
Can they play the army theme?
Oh, dear. I'm sorry.
The naval tune is the only one we know
We're just navy reserves, you see
Music is our little hobby
Then play your navy song
You don't mind?
Attention!
Straighten up, Horie
- Well?
- Excellent
Thank you
How is it? Good?
Woman
- Man.
- Man
- Woman pl us man equals good.
- Good
Good wine
Good!
The army and the navy together
have invited the village to this feast.
We've prepared lots of good food
We hope everyone has a great time
The army and the navy together --
Don't talk with your mouth full
Have invited all of you here.
It's a free meal
So enjoy yourselves
One, two, three
♪Leaving home, we b ravel swore
to return triumphant♪
♪How can I die before victory♪
♪The bugles play
The flags float like a sea♪
♪The earth, grass and trees are on fire
The fields stretch out before the eye♪
♪The Rising Sun flags
and helmets advance♪
♪I pat my horse's mane
Who knows one's fate♪
♪Thinking of today's battle
of my comrade covered in blood♪
♪Dying with a smile♪
♪Long live the emperor♪
♪His last, unforgettable cry♪
A happy occasion lifts the spirits
Just now,
the Imperial Army has played music
and sung a song
What shall we do in turn?
I am an old man,
willing to make a fool of myself
I'll sing for you
♪The flowers and willows♪
♪Love the spring sunshine♪
♪The moon and wind♪
♪Love the autumn chill♪
♪The young maid♪
♪Loves the talented man♪
♪The hero♪
♪Loves valor♪
I forget the rest
He said he forgot
the rest of the lyrics
♪You and I, we are an egg♪
♪I'm the white and you're the yolk♪
♪The white surrounds the yolk♪
♪Just as I embrace you♪
♪Into the wee hours♪
♪We dance, enthralled♪
♪Bathed in moonlight♪
♪We are ecstatic♪
There's an old saying
People fear meeting,
trees fear stripping
Tonight I'll also risk em barras sing
myself and sing a song
♪I slipped in to sneak a look
at the young man♪
♪With my fingertip I poked a hole
in the window♪
- You know, the paper window?
- Yes, I know
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
Drink! Drink!
♪He was as handsome as a prince♪
♪Dark brows, big eyes
A very special face♪
♪My heart thrilled to the sight♪
♪Back home I told my mother♪
♪She wasn't pleased♪
♪I made a face and lowered my head♪
♪I pouted, I turned away♪
♪I stiffened my neck and threw a fit♪
♪I said, don't try
and marry me to another♪
The captain praises your singing
Your mother's a real tease
If there are more songs like this,
there'll be trouble
Pity they're all sung in chorus
We sing ours individually
Why don't you sing one yourself,
to entertain us?
All right
Kosaburo Hanaya,
give these people a song
Hanaya, standup
Were you speaking Chinese just now?
Let's hear it.
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
And?
You're my granddad,
I'm your son
Translate, Dong
Happy New Year,
brother and sister-in-law
You're my granddad,
I'm your son
Give me a gun
Kosaburo Hanaya
is the scum of the Imperial Army
I invite you to shoot him
with this gun
for our drinking entertainment
Well? Who'll do it?
Hanaya represents the scum of the army.
The captain invites you to shoot him
For our drinking entertainment.
Any takers?
How can he be scum?
For six months you lived
under Nonomura's blockhouse
Is that true?
It's no small amount of time
Why didn't you contact Nonomura?
If he was on the h ill,
don't tell me he couldn't see you
We had no opportunity
What do you mean?
- We were locked up in the cellar.
- I didn't ask you
Hanchen Dong spoke the truth
What?
You didn't do too badly
So
besides learning some Chinese,
what else did you do?
It's only on account of your promise
that I'm feeding these mongrels
So that explains it
So, asking them to kill you now
is rather appropriate, isn't it?
Come on.
Execute him, why don't you?
come on, everyone, shoot him
If you don't
then I take it you forgive him?
If you don't,
that means you forgive him
Turtle-fucker!
Nonomura. A favor
Can we hear the whole tune
from the top?
Yes, sir
This is our first visit here
We'd never heard of Rack-Armor Terrace.
It means “put down weapons. ”
The story goes, a long time ago
a famous general retired from battle
and came here to live an ordinary life
The Chinese say to “rack one's armor”
and return to the fields
is an extreme form of virtue
I wish to express my deep respect
Although the Japanese Army
is fighting in China
this won't go on forever
One day. I too will rack my armor.
And yet
in a place that so dislikes warfare
a Japanese soldier
of the likes of Hanaya
was kid napped and held captive
It appears Rack-Armor Terrace
doesn't deserve its name
And you are not
as wise as your fore fathers
I've given you your grain
I've fulfilled my end of the bargain
But I have a question for you
Who was it
who brought this scum here?
I don't know.
You have to ask Hanaya
- Hanaya, answer the question.
- I really don't know
Look. Even he doesn't know.
How could I answer?
Why not drop it?
He's been returned.
Isn't that the end of it?
Well, where's Dasan Ma gone?
To fetch Yu'er
Yu'er?
How many men is she bringing?
How many guns?
She's pregnant.
She's staying at her mother's
As for people, probably two or three.
But no guns
They'll be back soon. We're waiting
for him to divide the grain
Divide the grain? Surely not
He's gone to get the men
who captured Hanaya
It looks like he's scared you.
Don't be afraid
He'll be back soon. You'll see
You think I'm afraid?
course you are.
You've got your guns out
If that's not fear, what is it?
Look at me.
I'm eating and drinking
I'm not worried about anything.
Just relax
Bastard!
Why all the cursing?
I understand bakayaro
How can you say that?
You fucking --
Li u Wang!
Don't let anyone get away
Don't stop. Keep playing
Bastards! Surround them!
Don't! Don't go!
Mongrel.
We should've killed you long ago
You've got the heart of a wolf
- Translate.
- We should've killed you long ago
New soldiers
-A rare opportunity
- Yes, sir
Pull it out yourself
Harder. Twist it
Who was it who brought
this scum here?
Where's Dasan Ma?
The baby's nearly due.
We'll get another share of the grain
and I'll marry you
Turtle-fucker!
I'll kill you, Jap turtle-fucker!
Ma!
Get up. Standup
Japanese inside the Great Wall
Let go. Go away
Nonomura.
You've been with them for too long
You're getting too close to them --
like an auntie to these b rats
- Brat!
-Japanese inside the Great Wall
Grab him!
You bastard!
Drag the old bastard over!
I'll throttle you, turtle-fucker!
Let go, you old swine!
You'd dare strangle
an Imperial Army soldier?
Hold him!
How come it's not cutting through?
Let me try
Stop dicking around! Bastard!
Let me do it. Move
Throw him on the fire
Die, you old mongrel!
Ma!
Swine.
You wanna die? I'll help you.
Hurry! Come on!
Throw him in! Hurry!
You haven't seen me rest, have you?
Let's burn the grain and the village!
Charge! Advance!
Long live the emperor!
No need for you to die
The emperor has made a proclamation
The Imperial Army
has racked its armor
But we weren't defeated
on the battlefield
Such a pity.
On account of this imperial order
we have to stop fighting
The war situation is no longer
to Japan's advantage
The enemy has employed
a new, cruel bomb
which has taken
a toll of many innocent lives
and has an incalculable
destructive power
Should we continue to fight
not only would the Japanese nation
be obliterated
but human civilization
would be extinguished
Such being the case
how are we to save our subjects
and atone before the spirits
of our ancestors?
This is why we accepted
the joint declaration of the powers
Very good!
Go away or I kill you!
♪The smoke of war has desisted♪
♪For eight years china resisted♪
I have no money.
Will you take this?
All right
♪We've got the Japs
holding their sorry asses♪
You buy. Very good
I'm not buying this
Fucking J ap.
Go blow up your mother with it
Bastard. I'll kill you
- china, U K, US, USSR!
- Together no one beats us!
Quick, move this garbage
I don't understand
I'm sorry, sir.
I don't understand you
Do you want to buy something?
I'm ordering you back to the barracks
In Tokyo, in Japan,
these are very valuable
I'm ordering you to stand still
I'll throw in the hat for nothing
♪And so the invasion
has come to an inglorious end♪
♪We welcome this day of victory♪
♪And the recovery♪
♪Of our beautiful land♪
Move it.
But we were singing for them.
Do we deserve this?
Fucking bastards
- Company, attention.
- One, two, three, four
Right
Attention!
At ease
Reporting to the major.
All46Japanese POWs are here
Reporting to the major:
All 46 Japanese POWs
are gathered here
Good. Back to your ranks
Back to ranks
As for those scum
who aided the Japanese
to slaughter their own com patriots
we will not treat them lightly
Bring Hanchen Dong here
You have aided tyranny
and avoided arrest.
Your crimes are great
Your hands are stained
with Chinese blood
Only execution will quell
the masses, anger
Do you have anything to say?
Is there anything you can say?
Reporting to the major:
He's laughing
Laughing?
Sure he's not crying?
Reporting to the major:
He's definitely laughing
Well, he can go laugh
in the netherworld!
com patriots,
if you know of other such scum
report them immediately.
There will be a reward
I now order
the immediate execution
of the collaborator, Hanchen Dong
cigarettes for sale
cigarettes
Brother. Wife
Understand?
You're Japanese?
Yes. Japanese
Woman
Work… girl
My… your… work… wife
Her… your… little sister… work
Don't you understand?
can we come home with you?
No, we don't want to
buy cigarettes
- Go away.
- Look. Someone's coming
I wanna buy cigarettes. Smokes
It's going to rain. Be quick
I'll have a pack of cigarettes
cigarettes
Goodman
Can I have two for free?
Give me a light
A light?
Goodman
Turtle-fucker
Murder!
commander Liu!
There's trouble!
commander Liu, trouble!
Help!
What the hell's going on?
What are you doing?
Grab him!
Stop it!
Help!
Dasan Ma!
What are you doing?
Turtle-fucker!
Chinese Army, help!
Stop!
Thank you, Chinese Army.
Thank you
The Japanese have surrendered.
The war is over
Peace has come at last
Yet in the last few days
one man has violated the agreement
which Generalissimo Chiang
President Truman,
Prime Minister Churchill and Stalin
in the interest of world peace,
signed at Potsdam
thus disturbing the social order
and terrorizing people
That person is Dasan Ma,
who you see before you
Perhaps some will say
Dasan Ma only killed Jap devils,
and call it “resistance.,,
But what is ”resistance,,?
Battles fought with Japanese troops,
the struggle against invasion
Those are acts of resistance
But Dasan Ma's wanton slaughter of POWs
who had lost the will to resist
was a false resistance
Perhaps some will argue
that such profound hatred
was the result of Japanese atrocities
Who of our 400 mill ion com patriots
doesn't hate the Japanese?
My own parents
were killed by Japanese bombs
My left leg
was shattered in the final battle
Who could be more motivated to kill
former Japanese soldiers?
Who has the best reason for revenge?
Me. Major Gao
And who is most constrained
from such action?
Me. Major Gao
Because I am a soldier,
I must follow orders
I take this opportunity
to reissue this warning:
only Nationalist soldiers
can legally accept the surrender
of Japanese troops
War hasn't only brought
catastrophe to china
but to the people of Japan as well
Are they not human too?
I ask you.
Who among you
would tolerate
to see your husband's head chopped off?
Anyone?
No one!
I ask you too.
Who among you
would wish to see your wife,
on her way to buy a bolt of cloth
have her hand cut off?
Anyone?
No one!
Dasan Ma. Do you have
anything to say for yourself?
Is there anything you can say?
Gag him
Listen, everyone
Ever heard a cry to heaven,,?
- He is braying like a mule.
- That's a cry to heaven.,
What distinguishes man from a beast?
You don't deserve
to be called Chinese
You don't even deserve
to be called human
How can a Chinese soldier sully
his hands with the blood of such scum?
Inokichi Sakatsuka
Attention!
I nokichi Sakatsuka
I order you
to execute Dasan Ma
Shoot him
He orders you to carry out
the execution
Really?
That's what he said
What?
You dare to disobey my command?
We've put down our weapons.
We cannot use firearms
I could obey your order,
using a Japanese sword
It's our customary weapon
Translate that bit
about the sword accurately
Reporting to Major Gao:
We've al ready handed in our firearms
We're not permitted
to use them anyway
However,
we must obey your order
The Japanese warrior always
carries a sword
could he use a sword?
What a pain.
Okay, give him a sword
- What a good story this is.
- Indeed
We'll write a great skit about this
Kosaburo Hanaya
Hanaya
Reporting to Major Gao:
The preparations are complete
Please issue the go-ahead
- Do it!
- Yes, sir!