We've been living peacefully outside the border
Why must we come back here?
lt's been 10 years. Have you come back for her ?!
No. The reason for my return is that, l hear...
the Plum Blossom Bandit has reappeared
Yes, what's that got to do with us?
Twenty years ago, the Plum Blossom Bandit
was a well known master in the martial world
He has harmed a lot of people
l wanted to look for him 10 years ago
He just vanished suddenly
l think he might want to look me up now
lnspite of knowing all this...
then what are you doing back?
He must have gone to look for me at my old house
Are you worried that he might hurt your cousin?
lf you love her so much...
Why did you let her marry Long Xiaoyun?
l know that he once saved your life
But l've never heard of anyone who would...
give up his fiancee and property for gratitude
That happened ten years ago
There's no need to bring it up
Aren't you cold? You want a sip of wine?
Are you deaf?
So you're not deaf. Have a sip
l can't afford it
Don't worry, it's my treat
l don't want to take things from others
l don't want to drink wine which l didn't buy
Have l made myself clear?
Yes, quite
Then please leave
l will
Say, when you can afford it...
will you treat me to a drink?
Certainly
Sit down please
Over there
Your wine, young master
There're a few from the Golden Lion Escort Agency
They're escorting something from out of town
Number two
Do you remember that time we came across
... the Four Tigers of Tai Xing?
How can l forget? That day they tried
... to steal from you
But they are no match for you
So you're 'Sudden Wind Sword' Zhuge Lei?
May l ask your names? Sorry l didn't recognize
You aren't worthy of knowing our names
Just leave what you are escorting
... and we'll spare your life
Put down your swords
And we'll let you live
Are you 'The Black and White Snake?''
Well, at least you've heard of us !
Since the two want this package
Go on, take it
Looks like there's another grand master here
We've almost missed you
lf you're interested in this package
And if you can defeat us;
Not only we'll give this to you
We're willing to give you our heads
Your heads are worth nothing
Did you say that?
Yes
lt's a pity mine is worthless
lt's too much, l just want 50 taels
Fine, if you can kill me...
l'll give you 50 taels
My money !
Take it, take all of it
So, it's you !
l can afford to buy you a drink now
With pleasure
l look for good drinking company
... and a good place
l hate crowds
Please
Judging from the awe they had in their eyes...
you seem like someone well known
lt's not a good thing to be famous
My name is Li Xunhuan, and yourself ?
Ah Fei
Ah Fei ?
Right
l'm an orphan who grew up in the wilderness
l envy the birds flying in the sky
Hence my name !
Strange name indeed. Cheers
You shouldn't be drinking while coughing
Yes, l shouldn't touch any alcohol
Then why do you drink?
Do you have a sad past?
Have l asked anything you don't want to answer?
No
Then why did you ask?
Okay, l won't
Even if you want to ask, it'll have to wait
We've got company
Yes, one on the tree on the left
Four at the temple ruins
One behind the tree
Li's Legendary Dagger, Never a miss! So overrated
Give up the package
And we'll leave you alone
l've got the package
Let's have another drink before l head off
Go! Chase...
Wait for me here
Who are you?
Li Xunhuan
Finally you are here
You've been waiting for me?
A hero called Ah fey has killed many
except one; he told me to keep an eye on him
And wait for you
Where's the person?
Here
What are you doing here?
This is the only house around
After l've got the package
... l wanted to rest here for a night
Who'd have known that your young friend's here !
Have some tea
Thanks
Are you alright, sir?
l'm not used to drinking tea
Then have some wine
-Do you have any? -Yes
Great
Just a minute
l'll give you the package
Please let me go
What's inside the package?
Why are so many after it?
You honestly don't know?
Now that the Plum Flower Bandit reappeared
lnside the package
is the unique
Gold Threaded Vest. lt's like an armour
No wonder !
Wine, sir
Thanks
Please let me go
l'll give you everything
l've an old grandmother
Three children
A lot of people are after this package
So are you
l kept my mouth shut before you had your tea
Now that you've had a sip of poison tea
... at the most l can wait here one more hour
You'll die of poisoning
l wasn't a part of it
Who are you?
Maybe you should know...
who killed you !
What a pretty girl
l'd watch out should l see you again
Do you think you'll see me again?
Of course, you know the tea is poisoned
But you didn't know that when l was coughing
... l spit out the tea
Come on
lmpressive !
Don't fight them. lf you use your energy
... the poison inside you will circulate faster
The girl forced me into poisoning the tea
But l was responsible for poisoning the wine
The wine too?
Couldn't you taste it?
You are ...
One of the Seven lncredible Men
The mean and shameless one ... Hua Feng
l see
Not anymore
Now l'm the richest man in the martial arts world
For l own the Gold Threaded Vest
You ... you ...
lt's called, Fisherman gains when snipe & clam fight
Master
Chuanjia
Hurry, go after him
Sure
He is over there
Dead !
Maybe he's got the antidote
Be careful
He could have other poisonous weapons
Don't scratch yourself
l know
Nothing at all
l knew it
l'm never that lucky
Excellent wine
Where do you think you're going?
Despite charging us, you didn't treat the patient
What'd you mean by coming here and drinking wine ?
Haven't you heard
... that l've a habit ?
What habit?
l don't treat patients when l drink
Damn it, l'll kill you
l wouldn't treat the patient, if you want to kill me
Let's talk this over
No one needs to get hurt
Mind your own business
Don't run
Odd indeed that the one who is telling us not to run
... is instead running away himself !
Do you now know who l am?
Sorry, may l know your name?
ln that case...
You save me not because you wanted my cure
Why do we need your help to cure us?
Your master's poisoned by my Cold Chicken powder
l'm the only one who can cure him
No one else can
Someone stole the powder from me a year ago
And now you've been poisoned
Come on,
Nothing is better than drinking to death
Let's have a drink first
Mr. Mei, you said you'll cure my master
Why are you drinking?
Why should trivial matters such as life and death
... get in the way of drinking?
lf you don't give me some wine, l won't help
Master
Come on
You know that our master...
can only live for two more hours?
Why aren't you doing anything?
l wouldn't be Mei Er...
if you know when l've cured you
l've already cured him
The wine is the antidote
Thank you, doctor
What are you doing?
What are you doing here?
l'm Tian Qi
Please excuse my two friends
l'm here to apologize for them
Sounds good
Someone's hurt by the Plum Blossom Bandit
Could you treat him first?
ls he badly injured ?
A minor wound on his shoulders
ls that it? Then l don't have to go personally
Just take the medicine. Where is he ?
Xingyun Manor
Who's the injured person?
Master Long Xiaoyun
Xunhuan
Yes, it's me
You're really here
l brought some medicine from Mei Er for you
Plum Blossom Bandit has resurfaced !
Right, he's now in Baoding City
He has injured many
Where did it all take place ?
My back garden. The Plum...
Blossom Forest in front of Cold Fragrance Chamber
Why there?
Because Lin Xianer lives there
Who's Lin Xianer?
The number one beauty of martial arts world
Do you have any idea...
how many have fallen head over heels for her?
What's her connection to you, Brother Long?
Why's she living in the Cold Fragrance Chamber?
Let me fill you in the details
l heard that Miss Lin's father...
was killed by the Plum Blossom Bandit
She has announced that...
she'll marry whoever kills the Plum Blossom Bandit
... regardless of age, status and wealth
She'll marry that person
She's going to meet with a group of heroes
... here today
Hence she has been putting up at the chamber
Master Long
Master Gongsun and many heroes
... have arrived
lf it weren't for Lin Xianer's beauty...
l doubt so many important guests will show up
Even if it were a great feast
Clean up the guest rooms in the East Chamber
Yes
You must be tired after yourjourney
Take a rest in the guest room
Then l'll introduce you to everyone
lt's time of the red plum season
Wonder how plum blossoms are like at the pavilion !
Fallen plums like the snow...
lt's been 10 years. Wonder how the plum blossoms are
You're back
10 years. You're still drinking as you were
Ten years seems like a long time, but it passed by
lf l don't drink, life seems like such a burden !
Who told you to do so?
Myself
Why?
Because l owe my life to someone
To be benevolent to your savior you feigned idiocy
You got drunk all the time, frequented the brothels
Yes, l was hoping you'd give up on me
... and marry Long Xiaoyun
Do you think l'd be happy?
After you've left
l found out the truth
l wanted to kill myself
And then l thought...
l'd better stay alive
Because there's a chance we'll see each other again
Too bad, things have changed now
The past is in the past
Lady Lin
Where's Master Li?
He's right here
Master Li, all the guests have arrived
Master Long invites you to Cold Fragrance Chamber
Please
Let me introduce you
My sworn brother Li Xunhuan
Li Ning of Wudang Clan
Pleased to meet you
Golden Fist Deng Lie
Delighted
Wang Chen, Golden Palms of Hua Shan
Pleased to meet you
Master Tian Qi, the lron Sword
Delighted
This is the renowned Master Gongsun
Pleased to meet you
Master Li was a legendary character ten years ago
l'm glad to finally meet you
Same here
He's Longsheng, young master of Hidden Sword Manor
He's proud and aloof, with incredible swordplay
Nonetheless he is infatuated with Lin Xianer
He's most eager to have Plum Blossom Bandit dead
Master Zhao is here
Master Zhao
Sorry l am late
No problem
Master Zhao, why are you here with so much gold?
There is a saying:
lt's everyone's duty to rid the society of evils
l hate the pests of the society
That's why l'm here today
l hope to eliminate a public enemy
And l brought along 10,000 taels of gold as...
a reward for the one who kills Plum Blossom Bandit
Where's Miss Lin?
Miss Lin ...
Please sit down
My father was murdered, l can't wait to get my revenge
That's why l take this opportunity here
... to say this in person
Whoever kills the Plum Blossom Bandit
regardless of age, status and wealth
l, Lin Xianer, will keep my promise to marry him
What Miss Lin is about to do...
has set a good example forjustice
l admire your courage
l don't deserve such praise from Master Zhao
This is ...
My sworn brother Li Xunhuan
No wonder he's so good with the daggers
Have you two met?
Yes, and l've offended him
Can l have a word with Master Li alone?
Certainly
You should know why l'm here
You need that Gold Threaded Vest
because you'll go up against the Plum Blossom Bandit
That's right
ls that it?
lf you want to find out more...
Meet me here at midnight
And l'll let you know the details
There have been two deaths here
One is the younger brother of the Master lron Flute
The other is the only son of Master Zhao Zhengyi
They died at midnight
Why at midnight?
Because people say the Plum Blossom Bandit
always shows up around midnight
The Plum Blossom Bandit ?
Longsheng... young master of Hidden Sword Mansion
That's me
Why do you want to kill me?
Someone wants me to kill you
Hurry... inside
Look
Master You?
Someone over there
What's going on?
Who told you to come here?
Miss Lin Xianer
Bullshit
Miss Lin Xianer has left in the evening
l saw her off personally
That can't be,
l was just talking to her earlier
lf she hasn't told me to meet her here
... what would l be doing here?
To kill
To kill?
That's right
At midnight the Plum Blossom Bandit will show up
A concerned person
At midnight,
you killed Master You
Get him
You've got it all wrong
We all were set up in a trap
Let's sit down and talk this over
We're not interested
Looks like all of you...
are hell bent to kill me now
Don't come any closer
That was a warning,
next time it's gonna be for real
Zhao Zhengyi, you said earlier that
you want to get rid of the pests in society?
Why don't you do something !
Right, are you waiting for Master Tian Qi ?
Or Master Gongsun ?
Xunhuan, Xunhuan
That's so strange, you all wanted me dead
Why don't you do something?
l think you've got it wrong
My sworn brother won't be the Plum Blossom Bandit
Xunhuan, please hold your temper
Brother Long
Master Zhao, we must kill him today
What are you doing?
Stop it, everyone
Let him go first
No matter what crime he has done
... l'll take full responsibility
We just can't let the Plum Blossom Bandit walk away
That's right
Xunhuan, why don't you tell them ...
that you're no Plum Blossom Bandit?
lt took them a while to catch a suspect
l don't want to ruin their excitement
Chuanjia
Let's go, young master
Xunhuan
Do you remember the day we first met?
The Justice Eight accused you for
... killing their head Meng Tianjie
l told you to leave just like you're doing now
You remember what you said then?
l said l didn't kill anyone
l won't leave...
before this matter is cleared up
Then why are you telling me to leave now?
l think you won't believe l'm the Plum Blossom Bandit!
But before they get to the bottom of all this...
they shouldn't hurt you now
There's no need for further investigation. We're right
He is the Plum Blossom Bandit
Shut up
Ah Fei
Who are you? What do you want?
l want to teach you a lesson
My friend
Very impressive, at such a young age
l'm Zhao Zhengyi, the impartial person
And your name is ?
l want to be your friend
l don't have a name,
and l don't want you as my friend
Your package
So you killed Hua Feng
That's right, he was carrying the package
l knew he couldn't be a good person
l went back to look for you, but you weren't there
Then l found out you're here
What's going on?
They said l'm the Plum Blossom Bandit
Bullshit
Come on, let's go for a drink
Wait
lt's just the Plum Blossom Bandit we're after
You shouldn't get involved
Who said he's the Plum Blossom Bandit?
l said so
Shiyin
What's going on?
l have no idea
Tell the others that you're the Plum Blossom Bandit
Are you crazy?
How would l be the Plum Blossom Bandit ?
l'll ask you one more time
This is your last chance. Are you ?
Yes, l'm the Plum Blossom Bandit
You heard him, everyone
lf his word is to be trusted...
He is the Plum Blossom Bandit
Young man, that's not fair
l mean this is how the martial world functions
The one with the quickest sword is the boss
So?
Anyone else?
Let's go
Wait
How do you know l'm not that Bandit ?
l grew up in the wilderness, like an animal
l've an instinct to distinguish good and evil
lf l leave now...
They will be more certain that
... l'm the suspect
Xunhuan is right
He can leave when we're sure of the facts
Right
Fine, l'll be in the deserted temple in the outskirts
Come look for me should you need me
Great
Young brother
l don't need the Gold Threaded Vest, you take this
l got it, bye
So you're here for the package
The Plum Blossom Bandit?
You got hit with my Plum Blossom Nails
You shouldn't be able to move
Li Xunhuan was right
He knew someone would come after this vest
Before l left
He told me to wear it
Very impressive
What are you doing here?
Here's your belongings. Leave now
Why must l leave?
Can't you tell they're doing this on purpose?
l've suspected it,
since the first day l came back to the country,
there's a trap waiting for me
The Gold Threaded Vest, Lin Xianer
and now they call me the Plum Blossom Bandit
Who is trying to hurt me?
Since you know that someone's trying to hurt you
You should better leave soon
Have you seen the spider webs?
Yes
We're like the spiders
We all want to make our own web
Then we can live in it forever
For everything that we've done
For money, love, friendship, for ourselves
We've made our own web to tie us up
Then we're trapped in it
No matter what we do, we can't get out
Some people call this fate
Why are you back, cousin?
Destiny !
Xunhuan...
Shiyin, what are you doing here?
She's here to see me
Although l released your vital points the other day
But l worried for your health
Here's some herbal tea for you
Thanks, Brother Long
Xiaoyun,
you know that he's not the Plum Blossom Bandit
Why don't you help him clear all this up?
Don't worry,
we'll soon know the truth
They've already sent someone...
to inform Master Xinmei of Shaolin Temple
They'll send a representative here soon
The Shaolin Temple is famous forjustice
They won't wrongly accuse people
Master, master
What is it?
Master Zhao said it's urgent
He's waiting for you in the hall
Folks, what's going on?
We've just received news
Master Xinmei will arrive soon
That's great
The bad news is ...
Mr. lron Flute is also on the road
He's famous for retaliation
lf he launches a fight,
We're no match for him
lf he gets here earlier than Master Xinmei
... and kills Li Xunhuan
Then what can we tell the Shaolin Temple?
Li Xunhuan's friend is a problem too
We must watch out for him
Don't worry, l've an idea
What? Your master is in danger
l heard that someone will kill my master tonight
He's a martial arts expert
Where is your master now?
Locked in the stock room
Li Xunhuan
So this is a trap !
l presumed you to be just
l told you to mind your own business
Get him
Don't worry, he won't run far
Mr. lron Flute
You're hurt? Got ambushed?
Why are you asking me? Since you've observed it
l don't like to attack people behind their back
lf they didn't attack me from behind
There's no way they could hurt me
You're very arrogant
l don't want to harm you since you're hurt
But l must teach you a lesson...
for being arrogant
Since you're hurt, l'll let you take three moves first
Why are you leaving?
l don't want you to die here
Why would l die?
Because no one can take my three moves
You want to try ?
Forget 3, no one can take one move
l said l'll let you take three moves first
That was one
Two more
Two
Three
Fine, that's it
lmpressive ! You were right
lt's hard to hurt you unless from behind
l've learnt one thing today
l can't let anyone to take three moves first
And you should have learnt one thing
Every move should be fatal
Mr. lron Flute, have you met the young man?
Yes
Did you kill him?
No
l'm here to kill Li Xunhuan
Xunhuan
Why would they let me out of the stock room
... and drink here?
l heard that Master Xinmei...
will arrive tonight
You'll go to Shaolin Temple tomorrow
No he won't
Why not?
Because l'll kill him tonight
Mr. lron Flute
Why don't you ask me why l want you dead ?
l don't want to offend you. And anyway...
lf l explain anything, you won't believe me
Then why would l bother !
Right, l'd kill you no matter what
Mr. lron Flute
No wonder my younger brother died at your hands
You're very good
So l killed your brother
You should tell me
What does he look like
So that l can say hello to him in hell
Bullshit
Amitabha Buddha
Master Xinmei
Master lron Flute,
why the rush to kill Li Xunhuan?
l must avenge for my brother
l heard that you'll always get even
You'd never do anyone any favors
l wonder if you could make this an exception
Let me and Li Xunhuan go to Shaolin Temple
Because my chief said he doesn't believe...
Li Xunhuan to be the Plum Blossom Bandit
Fine. With you here...
lt won't be easy for me to kill him
But if you're sure that he's the Plum Blossom Bandit
... then l want to be the one to kill him
Thank you
Where am l ?
The guest room
You saved me?
You fainted outside
Where are my clothes?
l helped you change
l feel dizzy
Take a nap
What is it, Zhaolong?
Our master said that...
Li Xunhuan will head for Shaolin tomorrow
Take the Gold Threaded Vest to your master
lnform him that Ah Fei is injured; that he's here
l'll make sure he recovers slowly
Yes
lnform the Five Poisons Kid
That Li Xunhuan will be on the road tomorrow
Tell them to kill him on the way
100,000 taels of gold, 5 pearls will be delivered soon
Yes
Li Xunhuan, you must die
Take care of yourself on the road
Don't drink too much
l know
Why don't you clamp his vital points?
Lock him up in chains
That's right
lt's not necessary
He might run
He'd be already gone if he wished
Chuanjia, what are you doing here?
l heard that the master will head for Shaolin today
l'm here to escort
lt's an arduous journey
Twenty years l've worked for you
However tough the journey, l'm not afraid
Very loyal indeed !
Let's go, Master Li
Another bowl
Come... serve the guests
Master, they don't have the wine you like
Only the local stuff
lt's fine
Don't touch anything
What's going on?
lt's poisoned
How do you know?
Look
Who did this?
l um...
Speak up
Not him, or he'd be gone already
What do you think he's staying here for?
Right, l don't know what happened
My brother cooked the dishes
That's my brother
What's going on?
Who did this?
Look
Five Poisons Kid
That's him
Looks like you've got friends
But you've got more enemies
l've heard that the Five Poisons Kid
... has many ways to poison a person
And if he is determined to kill someone...
then the person will die for sure
That's right. Unless he never eats !
Let's take a break here
Sure
You have a rest too, Master Li
Master Tian, you must be starving
Of course. We haven't eaten in three days
Old man, here's 10 taels
Can l have the steamed buns?
Ten taels?
That's right
Dear, honey
We have ten taels
Look, we've got food
You can't eat the buns
Nonsense
You saw him eating it
But we can't eat it
Because the Five Poisons Kid isn't after him
How come he won't be poisoned?
There's antidote in the soup
He drank the soup beforehand
How do you know it's poisoned?
l know the man has left
The house is empty
Steamed buns
Fresh and hot
Behave children
Come here and eat your noodles. Be quiet
l'll give you five taels
l'll take the buns
That ...
Since the children want to eat the buns
l'll swap the buns with noodles
That won't be fair to you
Never mind
Say thank you
Thank you!
Let's go eat the buns, open up
l think l can have these noodles now
lf the Five Poisons Kid could predict that
the kids don't want to eat the noodles
and that l'd swap with them
And he's poisoned the noodles
Then l have nothing to say even l'll die
Go on
Let's eat
l know what you're trying to do
You want us to starve
So that you can escape easily
You can't eat that, Master Tian
This place is deserted
There's not another house around here
You know, if l'd want to poison someone
... l'd rather do it here
Go take a look inside
l think the whole family is gone
lt's really empty
Finally we're almost there
l don't understand you. Why do you insist...
on bringing my master to Shaolin temple?
We invited Master Li
... because there've been thefts
of martial arts scriptures in Shaolin Temple
What's that got to do with the Plum Blossom Bandit?
When the scripture thief
... killed our people,
He left a mark of the Plum Blossom Bandit
You think my master is the Plum Blossom Bandit?
No, but l do suspect someone
l haven't said anything for l've got no proof
lf anything happens to me...
please tell my fellow Shaolin disciples
The name of the suspect is written
...on the last page of my journal
The last page of yourjournal
Throw it away, don't touch it
A poisonous toad... Run !
Chuanjia
Master, l think l've been poisoned
You must be working for the Five Poisons Kid
That's right
Chuanjia
l know l'm dying
Take care of yourself
Chuanjia...
Look
Poor snake
lt's a shame ...
Are you the Five Poisons Kid?
That's right
l've been expecting you...
for l promised someone l'll kill you
Master, be careful
Five poisonous cold needles
You know quite a lot
Don't worry about me, just run!
The Legendary Master Li and your daggers
Master Li, l'm delighted to meet you
Thank you
Master, l'm just an ordinary man
l'm lucky to meet you today
lt's a pleasure
There's no need to be so modest
Thank you for escorting Master Xinmei here
l appreciate it very much
You're very welcome
Master
How do you know he didn't hurt Master Xinmei?
Shut up
Don't you know that Master Xinmei...
has been poisoned by Five Poisons Needles?
Anyone could have poisoned him
You are right
Do you think that ...
l've hurt Master Xinmei?
Only you could answer that
No, someone else can give you an answer
Who?
Master Xinmei himself
Why don't you ask him when he wakes up?
Time for dinner
Where do you think you're going?
What happened?
You killed Master Xinmei while we were eating
And you're pretending you didn't do it?
What?
Get him
Stop it
Master Li
What's going on?
Master Xinmei was killed
You're the murderer
You're wrong
About the scriptures thief, Master Xinmei said...
He has the name of the suspect
He's written the name on the last page
... of his journal
The last page has been torn off !
That's simple
l would tear out the last page...
and make up a story if l was the murderer
How would the thief know...
about Master Xinmei's journal?
You can get up now
Do you want your golden vest back ?
No, l'm here to see you
l always thought flowers are the most beautiful...
things on earth... but today l've seen a woman
... who is more beautiful than flowers
You think l'm pretty?
Have you been in love before?
No
You know nothing about me
l was in a coma for the past few days
This is the first time we've spoken
Don't ponder upon this
Don't move
What is it?
There's a poisonous spider on your neck
Thank you
lt's so strange
A poisonous spider in such a beautiful environment
You can'tjudge a book by its cover
l've heard that poppy is a pretty flower too
You were holding the spiderjust now
lf you got bitten, you could die
Hmm, l didn't think about that at all
Maybe l was in a hurry
There's only one kind of love...
which makes you disregard your own life
That's the love between a man and a woman
You'll understand more later
But l'll always remember that
You've saved my life today
And l'll remember you've been kind to me
So...
Have you heard anything about Master Li?
Why do you care about Li Xunhuan so much?
Because he's my only friend
l heard that Master Xinmei was murdered
Shaolin Temple has kept Master Li in house arrest
... until they've found the Plum Blossom Bandit
Now that a second Bandit has surfaced...
lt's proof enough that,
Li Xunhuan is not the Plum Blossom Bandit
Would you know of anyone...
who is rich and nasty that l should kill ?
You are Shen Laosan ?
Do you know why l'm here?
Let go
From Shaolin ?
Stop it, master
Why do you want to catch him ?
He's the accomplice of the Plum Blossom Bandit
Of course we can catch him
My friend is innocent
l hope you'll let him go
lf he's the Plum Blossom Bandit
Then you're his accomplice; just as guilty
Zhao Zhengyi, you've gone too far
What if l have?
You must be fair
For your namesake
You can't bully someone like this
Master Zhao, no one else is here
No spies, only you
What do you want?
We want to nab the Plum Blossom Bandit
We want to find the scriptures stealer
What if they are two different persons?
lf we can locate the scriptures
l promise you, Shaolin won't get involved
You must return the scriptures in three days
Three days? That's a long time
l only need an hour
Yuanfeng
Yes master
Search the rooms of Dongning Chambers
Follow me
Why are you searching our rooms?
Because Master Xinmei told me
... you are the scriptures stealers
The Yijin Scripture which was stolen...
recently is still inside this temple
Master, we've found the scriptures
... in their rooms
They must have planted the stolen scriptures
Here's the Yijin Scripture
We've been framed for sure
How would you know that...
where we placed the scriptures?
Look, they are not the scripture stealers
Wouldn't find even if they try hard
l'd say, even if we planted the scriptures here
We couldn't have placed it in the secret compartment
Master Xinmei has told me that...
He suspects the scriptures stealer is an insider
One who has access to the library
And only the senior masters at Dongning Chambers
... are eligible; that's why l took a risk
lf Mater Xinjian would've been a little more calm...
My plan wouldn't work
Don't move
Let me get hold of the Plum Blossom Bandit
Master Zhao, if you want to take the credit
l'll pass him to your custody later
The martial world wouldn't have that many grudges
... if not for people like them
A bunch of hypocrites !
Let's go
Wait
l've promised Master Xinmei...
that l'd catch the scriptures stealers
A promise is a promise
C'mon, let's see how you actually catch me
Don't move
Come on
Who's the Plum Blossom Bandit? Who told you to steal?
What did he say?
He said it's me
What are you trying to do?
To seize the Plum Blossom Bandit
You are too rash
l'll kill you if you move again
You ...
Ever thought the Bandit perhaps mightn't be a man ?
Not a man? Then what?
A woman of course
A woman?
Right... since the beginning
The Plum Blossom Bandit has been trying to set you up
And these people who are against us
... are all male, martial arts experts
Only a very beautiful woman...
Could make this happen
And there's only one woman who knows that...
l was going to kill Shen Laosan
l heard the news from Shaolin Temple
l knew you'd come here to look for me
You've been trying to kill Master Li... why?
He killed my father
Who might he be ?
My father worked for the Plum Blossom Bandit
You killed him ten years ago by Tai Lake
That's why you try to set him up
There was a monk called...
Xinjian who contacted me
He said that the Plum Blossom Bandit is still alive
l could have my revenge. We set up a trap
... for you
We used the martial arts experts...
as pawns. They all lust after beauty
Then the deaths of Zhao Zhengyi's son
... and Mr. lron Flute's brother
We were hoping that they'd get rid of you
So you knew who's the Plum Blossom Bandit all along?
No. Didn't have a clue
l've only contacted Monk Xinjian
Now it doesn't matter who's the Plum Blossom Bandit
Because l must kill you
l'd advise you not to
Because even if you practise for another 10 years
You're not Master Li's match
That's my problem
Miss Lin, have you ever thought that...
l did everyone a favor by killing your father?
He's my father after all
Miss Lin, l owe you a favor
l don't wish to see you die here
You better leave
Mr. lron Flute, you heard her
She's the one who killed your brother
What are you doing?
Avenging my brother
l didn't kill him
The real Plum Blossom Bandit did
Who'd believe you?
Come on then
You all spread out
Mr. lron Flute, this is a duel
C'mon, move
Wait
Mr. lron Flute, Zhao Zhengyi, if you want your revenge,
you should find the real killer
Where is the real killer?
l know
Shiyin
Cousin, l think you know who's the real
... Plum Blossom Bandit
Tell them
l will if you don't
Shiyin
-Shiyin... -Miss Lin
Cousin, you ...
You should know
You ... it's been ten years ...
Shiyin
Wait
Don't go
l know where he is
l'll take care of it
l've been expecting you
Why did you kill Shiyin?
That's because...
l must kill all those who know my secret
That includes you
This duel should have...
taken place ten years ago at Tai Lake
Nevertheless it's happening today
So you're the real Plum Blossom Bandit?
Yes, you tried to catch me ten years ago
l knew l was no match for you then
That's why l set a trap
And pretended to save your life
Then l've been living in Xingyin Manor
l sent Xinjian to steal the scriptures from Shaolin
And l've been practising all these years
So even if you attempt to take my life today...
lt won't be as easy as ten years back
So you've never loved Shiyin !
No
And frankly speaking, l didn't save your life then
Ten years ago...
At the time when you thought l saved you;
lt was in fact the beginning of a revenge.
Only that l used sentiments rather than weapons
However, when it comes to using sentiments...
You've got to be like me... heartless !
Otherwise l'd be like you
Your whole life's been controlled by sentiments
You were living in regrets and pain
Before Xinjian died, he told me that...
you're the Plum Blossom Bandit. l didn't
... blow your cover for l still had faith in you
That's your main weakness
You believe in sentiments among people
You easily gave up the woman you love...
and your property and wealth
Of course, the world might say you're sentimental
But you're just a silly fool
Let me tell you once again
You can't be a sentimental swordsman
And the sword you wield...
ought to be a merciless one
Are you done with your tale, Long Xiaoyun?
l said that before
lt's a simple story...
about revenge of the Plum Blossom Bandit
Now it's my turn to tell my story
l want to know how you dodged my daggers
Little Li's Legendary Dagger, Never a miss!
You never expected me to use this magnet
The last 10 years l managed to find a lot about you
You never carry more than 12 daggers
There's a sword at the back
To kill an unarmed man
lt's something very novel to me
l wanted to use Lin Xianer's eagerness for revenge
And l also wanted to exploit the hypocrites
... as my pawns
But l'd never have thought that...
l have to kill you personally
l've told you before, l must kill you
Because you're sentimental, and l'm ruthless
Another sentimental man
Don't move
Maybe you didn't think l've the Gold Threaded Vest
Hold it !
lf you step one inch further
l swear that this broken sword
... will be pierced through your throat
The magnet is too far away
Even with the broken sword...
l still have time to kill him
Although you could avoid...
all the man-made weapons
But you can't escape
... from the ice made by the gods !