It's hormonaI.
I mean, I don't usuaIIy faII back on...
It's women's issues.
But chiId-proofed how? Gates and stuff?
Dude, she did the drawers.
We don't even know if this whoIe
fertiIity thing's gonna work...
she's screwed in these IittIe jobbies
where you can't even open the drawers.
At aII?
No. They open an inch,
then you gotta dig your finger in.
-It's a nightmare.
-I guess sooner or Iater--
Yeah, a Iot Iater.
She did the upper cabinets.
Kid wiII be 30 before he can reach them,
assuming we have a kid.
It is naturaI for her to feeI protective.
Don't even-- You have women's issues.
PIease. You of aII peopIe.
Oh, come on. It's a jinx.
It guarantees that we won't get pregnant.
And it takes me about 20 minutes to get a fucking beer.
Guys. Guys!
StockhoIm went south.
SeriousIy?
I thought they were Iooking good.
What cracked?
I haven't seen the footage.
Word's just going around.
WeII, that's never been a stabIe scenario.
Everyone knows you can't trust Swedes.
That means there's just Japan. Japan and us.
It's not the first time it's come down to that.
Japan has a perfect record.
We're number two. We try harder.
-If we faiI, then--
-PIease. We haven't had a gIitch since '98.
We know what we're doing, Lin.
Or we have it written down... somewhere.
You guys better not be messing around in there.
Does this mean you're not in the betting pooI this year?
Big money.
I'm just saying, it's a key scenario.
No, I hear what you're saying.
In '98, it was the chem department's fauIt, right?
Where do you work, again?
Wait. It's coming back to me, now.
It's gonna be a Iong weekend
if everyone's that puckered up.
You wanna come over Monday night?
I'm gonna pick up some power driIIs. Liberate my cabinets.
Are you even Iistening to me?
Professor fuckwad.
Why haven't you stuck that asshoIe's picture on the dartboard yet?
It's not that simpIe--
Oh, my God! -Your hair. It's bIonde.
-Very fabuIous, no?
-I can't beIieve you did it.
-But very fabuIous, right?
Hurry up with the ''very fabuIous.''
I'm getting insecure about it now.
No, it Iooks awesome.
Curt's gonna Iose it.
Curt's gonna thank me. And so wiII you...
whiIe we're burning this picture.
Not ready.
SeriousIy, this isn't his fauIt.
What's not his fauIt?
Fucking his student
or breaking up with her by emaiI?
I knew what I was getting into.
Oh, pIease.
You know what you're getting into this weekend?
This.
And if HoIden's as cute as Curt says he is...
possibIy getting out of it.
That is the Iast thing that I want.
If you treat this Iike a setup, I'm gonna have no fun at aII.
I'm not pushing...but we're packing this!
Which means we definiteIy won't have room for--
What if I get bored?
These wiII heIp?
Soviet Economic Structures?
Aftermath of the...
No!
We have a Iake and a keg.
-No more Iearning!
-Think fast.
Faster than that.
Sorry. Sorry. Move aIong.
-Nice!
-Is that HoIden?
We'II be right down.
He just transferred from State.
Best hands on the team. He's a sweet guy.
And he's good with his hands.
I'm kinda seeing this girI...
but you're way bIonder than she is.
But I was thinking, you know, maybe...
What is this?
What are you doing with these?
Okay, I get it. I'II Ieave the books.
No, who gave you these?
Who taught you about these?
I Iearned it from you, okay?
I Iearned it from watching you!
SeriousIy, Professor Bennett, he covers this whoIe book in his Iectures.
You shouId read this.
Gurovsky. Now this is way more interesting.
AIso, Bennett doesn't know it by heart...
so he'II think you're insightfuI.
And you have no pants.
Oh, shit!
-That pretty much it? -Fucking better be.
You know, JuIes, it's a weekend,
not an evacuation.
Trust me when I say there is nothing in those cases...
you won't be gIad I brought.
I'm shutting' right up.
Oh, my God.
Marty!
Fuck is wrong with you, bro?
PeopIe in this town drive in a very counterintuitive manner.
That's what I have to say.
Do you wanna spend the weekend in jaiI?
We'd aII Iike to check out my cousin's country home.
Honey, that's not okay.
StatisticaI fact...
Cops wiII never puII over a man with a huge bong in his car.
Why?
They fear this man.
They know he sees further than they...
and he wiII bind them with ancient Iogics.
Have you gone gray?
You're not bringing that thing in the RambIer.
What?
A giant bong in your father's van?
What are you, stoned?
Hey, man.
Dana, you fetching minx!
You have any food?
-Everybody ready? -Yeah!
-Yeah? -Okay, I'm ready!
Let's get this show on the road! Fuck, yeah!
Nest is empty. We're right on time.
I hope this is the right road.
It doesn't even show up on the GPS.
It is unworthy of gIobaI positioning.
That's the whoIe point.
Get off the grid, right?
No ceII phone reception...
no traffic cameras.
Go somepIace for one goddamn weekend where they can't...
gIobaIIy position my ass, man.
This is the whoIe issue.
Is society crumbIing, Marty?
No. Society is binding. Right?
It's fiIIing in the cracks with concrete.
Everything's fiIed or recorded or bIogged, right?
Chips in our kids' heads so they won't get Iost.
Society needs to crumbIe.
We're aII just too chicken-shit to Iet it.
I've missed your rants.
You wiII come to see things my way.
Identification, pIease.
Mr. Sitterson.
-Mr. HadIey. -Thank you.
-What's your name?
-DanieI Truman, sir.
This isn't the miIitary. You can drop the ''sir''.
But Sitterson does Iike to be caIIed ''ma'am.''
-Or ''honey toes.''
-He'II aIso answer to ''honey toes.''
You cIear on what's gonna be happening here?
I've been prepped. ExtensiveIy.
Did they teII you that being prepped
is not the same as being prepared?
They toId me.
I'II hoId my post, Mr. HadIey.
Good man.
Okay.System's onIine.
Acquiring target.
Let's see what we got.
AIright.
I'm thinking this thing doesn't take credit cards.
I don't think it knows about money.
I think it's barter gas.
HeIIo?
Hey, HoIden.
-HoIden! -I don't think there's gonna be--
You come here uninvited?
Fuck! Dude.
Sign says ''cIosed.''
Yeah, we were Iooking to buy some gas.
Does this pump work?
If you know how to work it.
We aIso wanted to get directions.
We're Iooking for-- What's it caIIed?
TiIIerman Road.
Do you know if it's this way?
TiIIerman Road takes you up the hiII, there.
Dead-ends at the oId Buckner pIace.
My cousin bought a house up there
You go through a mountain tunneI, there's a Iake.
-WouId that be the... -Buckner pIace.
AIways someone Iooking to seII that pIot.
You knew the originaI owners.
Yeah, not the first.
I seen pIenty come and go.
HeII, I been here since the war. -Which war?
-You know damn weII which war!
WouId that have been with the bIue and some in gray?
Brother, perhaps, fighting against brother in that war?
You sassing me, boy?
You were rude to my friend. That whore?
-What'd you say? -I think we got enough gas.
You got enough to get you there.
Getting back...
that's your concern.
WeII, good Iuck with your business, sir.
I know the raiIroad's coming through here any day, now.
That's gonna be big.
Streets paved with actuaI street.
Fucker.
Guys, take a Iook.
This must be it.
Oh, my God. It's... beautifuI.
One spider and I'm sIeeping in the RambIer.
I mean it.
Come on. Give me a hand.
This is awesome.
It is kind of cooI.
You gonna kiII us a raccoon to eat?
I wiII use its skin to make a cap.
Everybody get your suits on.
In 1 0 minutes, we're heading to the Iake. Yeah.
I was not informed there wouId be caIisthenics.
Yeah, I don't think so.
Whoa. No way.
Ah, shit.
This is happening.
HoId up!
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
That's just creepy.
It was pioneer days.
PeopIe had to make their own interrogation rooms.
Who did your cousin buy this pIace from?
We shouId check the rest of the rooms,
make sure this is the onIy one.
'Cause you know Marty wants to watch us pounding away.
I didn't even Iike hearing that.
Don't be an ape, Curt.
How about we switch?
Not that I'd--
I mean, I'd put the picture back but you might feeI better if we switched rooms?
I reaIIy wouId.
Thanks. For being decent.
It's the Ieast I couId do...
since Curt and JuIes soId you to me for marriage.
They're not subtIe.
WeII, I'II just be fIattered and keep it to myseIf.
Yeah, I'm not Iooking for--
But, I'm stiII gratefuI that you're not a creep.
Hey, Iet's not jump to any concIusions there.
I had kind of an internaI debate about showing you the mirror.
Shouting on both sides. BIood was spiIIed.
So, you're bIeeding internaIIy?
Pretty bad.
WeII, JuIes is pre-med.
You shouId probabIy taIk to her.
Okay.
Yeah, I don't think so.
I gotta say, I Iike my room.
Over here.
PIaces everyone.
We are Iive.
Engineering, we got a room change.
PoIk is now in two,
McCrea is in four.
Operations, do you copy?
We need a scenario adjustment.
Miss Lin.
We've got the bIood work back on Louden.
Her IeveIs are good.
But we're recommending a fifty-miIIigram bump... of Rhohyptase to increase Iibido.
SoId. Do we pipe it in, or do you wanna do it oraIIy?
Ask me that again, onIy sIower.
You're a pig.
Guess how we're sIowing down cognition.
I don't know.
The hair dye.
Dumb bIonde. Very artistic.
Works its way into the bIood,
through the scaIp. Very graduaI.
Chem department keeps their end up.
I'II see it when I beIieve it.
-ControI? -Yeah, go ahead.
I have the harbinger on Iine two.
Oh, Christ. Can you take a message?
I don't think so. He's reaIIy pushy. No way.
To be honest, he's kind of freaking me out.
Okay. Put him on.
Mordecai, baby, what's happening?
How's the weather up top?
The Iambs have passed through the gate.
They are come to the kiIIing fIoor.
WeII, you're doing a great job out there.
By the numbers, man. You got us started off just right.
So, we'II taIk to you Iater, okay?
Their bIind eyes see nothing of the horrors to come.
Their ears are stopped.
They are the gods' fooIs.
WeII, that's... how it works.
CIeanse them.
CIeanse the worId of their ignorance and sin.
Bathe them in the crimson of--
Am I on speakerphone?
No. AbsoIuteIy not.
Speakerphone, no. No, I wouIdn't do that.
Yes, I am. I can hear the echo.
Oh, my God. You're right.
Hang on one second, I'II take you off.
That's rude.
I don't know who's in the room.
Fine. There. You're off.
Thank you.
Don't take this IightIy, boy.
It wasn't aII by your numbers.
The fooI nearIy deraiIed the invocation with his insoIence.
The ancient ones see everything.
And they wiII not be--
I'm stiII on speakerphone, aren't I?
Oh, my God. Mordecai.
I can't beIieve it. I did it again!
Mordy?
What happens next?
Oh! That's coId!
How coId? Is it worth it?
Come on, JuIes. Life is risk.
Yeah, I might just risk Iying out in the sun for a whiIe
Boo.
Hey, what is that? What?
In the Iake, right there.
Oh, come on.
No, you guys, I'm serious. Right there.
There! There! God, Iooks just Iike my girIfriend!
Oh, my God!
There's something eIse in the Iake!
It's a gorgeous man!
I'm gonna kiII you! Don't kiII the gorgeous man!
We're endangered!
AII right. Last chance.
It's post time. Dig deep, peopIe.
Betting windows are cIosing. Okay.
Okay, who's stiII out?
Let's see.
We got engineering, we got R & D, and we got eIectricaI.
Did you see who they picked?
They're practicaIIy giving their money away.
You shouId taIk, Aquaman.
What do you mean? Ah, nothing.
Okay, aII right.
I'm not even sure we have one of these.
ZooIogy swears we do. They'd know.
Okay.
AII right, peopIe.
Hey, what do you got?
No, they've aIready been picked.
What? No. Who took them?
Maintenance.
Maintenance? They pick the same thing every year.
What do you want from me?
If they were creative, they wouIdn't be in maintenance.
You're gonna have to spIit this if you win. You wanna switch?
I don't know, I don't know. What do you think?
More than anything, I just want this moment to end.
Not betting?
Not for me. Thanks.
Seems a IittIe harsh, doesn't it?
It's just peopIe Ietting off steam.
This job isn't easy,
however those cIowns may behave.
Does the director--
Do they know about this downstairs? The director doesn't care about this stuff.
As Iong as everything goes smoothIy upstairs...
as Iong as the kids do as they're toId
But then it's fixed.
No, no, no.
How can you wager on this when you controI the outcome?
No, we just get 'em in the ceIIar.
They take it from there.
No, they have to make the choice of their own free wiII.
Otherwise the system doesn't work.
It's Iike the harbinger.
It's this creepy oId fuck, practicaIIy wears a sign, ''You wiII die.''
Why do we put him there? The system.
They have to choose to ignore him...
and they have to choose what happens in the ceIIar.
Yeah, we rig the game as much as we need to...
but in the end,
they don't transgress-- They can't be punished.
So what's it gonna be, Truman? You in?
Window's cIosing.
I'm fine.
Okay.
That's it, gang!
The board is Iocked!
Oh, Iet's get this party started!
Let's get this party started!
Okay, who wants a beer?
There you go.
Okay, my turn.
JuIes.
Truth or dare?
Let's go dare.
I dare you to make out with--
PIease say ''Dana,'' pIease say ''Dana.''
That moose, over there.
Marty... have you ever seen a moose before?
Whatever that mysterious beast is.
That's a woIf.
I'm Iiving in a womb of reefer, Ieave me aIone.
JuIes...
I dare you to make out with that woIf.
No probIem.
Who? Me?
WeII, yes, I am new in town.
How did you know?
Oh, my God. That is so sweet of you to say.
I just coIored it, in fact.
No, no, no.
There's no need to huff and puff.
I'II Iet you come in.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Now, then...
Dana. Truth.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm just skipping ahead.
You're gonna say dare.
She's gonna dare you to do something
you don't Iike...
and then you'II puss out and say that you wanted truth aII aIong.
ReaIIy?
Okay, JuIes.
Dare.
What the heII was that?
It's the ceIIar door.
The wind must've bIown it open.
That makes what kinda sense?
What do you think is down there?
Why don't we find out?
Dana.
I dare you.
How Iong do I have to stay down here?
Oh, you know, just 'tiI morning.
Dana.
You okay?
Yeah.
Sorry, I just scared myseIf.
WeII, you caIIed for heIp. That voids the dare.
Take your top off.
What?
I don't make up the ruIes.
Oh, my God.
Look at aII this.
Guys...
I'm not sure it's awesome to be down here.
Guys?
Dude, seriousIy,
your cousin is into some weird shit.
I'm pretty sure this ain't his.
Maybe it was the peopIe who put in that mirror thing.
Some of this stuff Iooks reaIIy oId.
It's beautifuI.
Maybe we shouId go back upstairs.
I dare you aII to go upstairs.
Guys?
Guys, Iisten to this.
''ApriI fourth.
''Father was cross with me
and said I Iacked the true faith.
''I wish I couId prove my devotion...
''as Judah and Matthew proved on those traveIers.''
What is that?
Diary of Anna Patience Buckner,
1 903.
''Mama screamed most of the night.
''I prayed that she might find faith...
''but she onIy stopped when Papa cut her beIIy...
''and stuffed the coaIs in.
''Judah toId me in my dream...
''that Matthew took him to the bIack room,
so I know he is kiIIed.
'I want to understand the gIory of the pain Iike Matthew...
''but cutting the fIesh makes him have a husband's buIge...
''and I do not get Iike that.''
Jesus. Can we not?
-No. Go on.
-Why? -I want to know.
''I have found it... ''in the oIdest books,
the way of saving our famiIy.
''My good arm is hacked up...
''and et, so I hope this wiII be readabIe.
''That a beIiever wiII come and speak this to our spirits.
''Then we wiII be restored and the great pain wiII return.''
And then there's something in Latin.
Okay, I'm drawing a Iine in the fucking sand, here.
Do not read the Latin.
Read it.
What the fuck?
Read it out Ioud.
-DoIor-- -No, no. Stop being a fucking baby.
-Curt! -It's a diary.
It doesn't even mean anything.
-Dana!
-''DoIor supervivo caro.
''DoIor subIimis caro.
''DoIor ignio annivos.''
We have a winner!
It's the Buckn'e'rsT,Iadiesand gentIemen! congTheBuckners.puIIa'W '.ance!
Who share the pot with RonaId the intern.
Yeah!
That's not fair. I had zombies, too.
Yes, you did. You had zombies.
But this is ''Zombie Redneck Torture FamiIy,'' see?
They're entireIy separate species.
Like the difference between an eIephant and an eIephant seaI.
There's aIways next year.
They're Iike something from a nightmare.
No.
They're something nightmares are from.
Everything in our stabIe is remnant of the oId worId...
courtesy of you-know-who.
Monsters. Magic. Gods.
You get used to it.
ShouId you?
Oh, man. I'm sorry.
He had the conch in his hands. I know. A coupIe more minutes,
who knows what might've happened?
I am never gonna see a merman. Ever.
Dude, be thankfuI.
Those things are terrifying.
And the cIeanup on them is a nightmare.
So, the Buckners.
Yeah, weII, they may be zombified, pain-worshipping, backwoods idiots--
But they're our zombified, pain-worshipping, backwoods idiots.
With a hundred percent cIearance rate. True.
So shouId we caII Japan?
TeII them to take the rest of the weekend off?
Yeah, right. They're Japanese.
What are they gonna do? ReIax?
I'd just Iike to see them faII on their asses, for once.
Oh, God, don't even joke.
Every other branch has air-baIIed.
We need the Japanese crew to get it done.
There's too much riding on this.
Fuck, yeah, baby.
This is so cIassy.
Come on, Iike you wouIdn't want a piece of that.
Can we not taIk about peopIe in pieces any more tonight?
Are you feeIing IoneIy, Marty?
Marty and I were sweeties in our freshman haII.
We made out once.
I never did buy that ring.
But we're stiII...
cIose.
I have a theory about aII this.
That's our cue to baiI.
Tommy Chong here has a theory.
Come on, baby.
Don't worry, you can teII it to Egghead, here...
if he's not too busy devirginizing Dana.
JuIes, do you wanna go Iie down?
That's exactIy the point.
Come on. Mush. Mush.
Don't push me around.
Not around, baby. Straight Iine.
You seriousIy beIieve nothing weird is going on?
Conspiracy?
The way everybody's acting.
Why is JuIes suddenIy a ceIebu-tard?
And since when does Curt puII this aIpha-maIe buIIshit?
I mean, he's a socioIogy major.
He's on fuII academic schoIarship...
and now he's caIIing his friend an egghead?
Curt's just drunk.
I've seen Curt drunk.
JuIes, too.
WeII, then, maybe it's something eIse.
You're not seeing what you don't wanna see.
Puppeteers.
Puppeteers?
Pop-Tarts? Did you say you have Pop-Tarts?
Marty, I Iove you,
but you're reaIIy high.
We are not who we are.
I'm gonna go read a book with pictures.
Thank you.
''The pain outIives the fIesh.
''The fIesh returns...''
or ''has a meeting pIace.''
What is that?
The Latin that you read in the basement.
You speak Latin?
Not weII. Not since tenth grade.
Weird how it aII comes back.
WeII, it's a weird kind of night.
I'm sorry about tonight.
Everybody--
Do I Iose points if I teII you I'm having a pretty nice time?
No. You can teII me that.
What are you running away for?
Don't spiII on me!
Did I get a IittIe beer on your shirt?
I guess it'II have to come off, huh?
Not here.
Baby, come on.
We're aII aIone.
I'm chiIIy.
Okay, guys. That's it. Let's go.
We've got a job to do.
Your basic human needs disgust me.
Get out of here.
Do we have temperature controI in this sector?
On it.
Engaging pheromone mists.
It's so dark.
Take me inside?
Come on. This is why we came here.
It's romantic.
Okay, baby. Let's see some boobies.
Show us the goods.
Does it reaIIy matter if we see her---
We're not the onIy ones watching, kid.
Gotta keep the customer satisfied.
You understand what's at stake, here?
Score.
JuIes!
Fuck.
Curt!
No. No.
PIease! PIease!
No!
This we offer in humiIity and fear.
For the bIessed peace of your eternaI sIumber.
As it ever was. As it ever was.
Nemo, man, you gotta wake up.
Your shit is topsy-turvy.
I'm gonna go for a waIk.
Okay. I swear to fucking God, somebody is taIking.
Or I'm pretty sure someone is.
I'm gonna go for a waIk.
Enough!
What are you saying?
What do you want?
You think I'm a puppet, huh?
You think I'm a puppet. Gonna do a IittIe...fucking puppet dance!
I'm the boss of my own brain, so give it up.
I'm gonna go for a waIk.
I don't wanna--
I mean, I've never--
I don't mean ''never''--
Hey.Nothing you don't want.
He's got a husband buIge.
I thought there'd be stars.
We are abandoned.
Fuck! Fucking run!
Curt!
Dead bitch!
Jesus, what happened?
-Curt!
-The fuck!
Where are you hurt?
Is aII of this from you?
It's okay! Curt, you're okay!
Where's JuIes?
She's gone.
We've gotta get out of here.
No. No.
Dana, don't open that---
I'm not Ieaving here without JuIes.
That dead girI's out there!
Dana, come on!
What is that thing?
Fuck!
I don't know, but there's more of them.
More of them?
AII sawayou.ng girI...
but she was missing an arm.
Oh, my God. Patience.
The diary.
-We gotta Iock this pIace down. -He's right.
We'II go room by room. Barricade every window and door.
We gotta pIay it safe. No matter what happens,
we have to stay together.
Fuck!
CaIm down.
Watch the master work.
This isn't right.
What? What's the matter?
This isn't right. We shouId spIit up.
We can cover more ground that way.
Yeah. Yeah. Good idea.
ReaIIy?
AII right, you guys,
get in your rooms.
What the fuck?
What the--?
That's not good.
Out of the way. Out of the way.
Chem department, I need 500 CCs of Thorazine...pumped into room three.
No, no, no.
Stand by, Chem.
Judah Buckner to the rescue.
What the fuck?
Fuck! What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
I'm on a reaIity TV show.
My parents are gonna think I'm such a burnout.
No! No!
HeIp me! HeIp me!
Must be getting excited downstairs.
Greatest show on Earth.
Come on!
Use the bed! Come on! Come on!
HoIden.
-It's empty. -Go.
-Curt? -UnIock the door.
I can't. Get down to the basement.
This is the bIack room.
Nice.
From the diary.
This is where he kiIIed them.
This is where he kiIIs us.
No way. No.
He's not gonna kiII us
We just gotta find a door.
Okay?
Let's just check the waIIs, okay?
Curt?
I mean, there's gotta be--
You Iike pain?
How's that work for you?
These fucking zombies.
Remember when you couId just throw a girI in a voIcano?
How oId do you think I am?
Let's move! Come on! Come on! Go!
What about Marty?
They got him.
The eviI is defeated.
Now Kiko's spirit wiII Iive in the happy frog!
Fuck you!
Fuck you! Fuck you! Fuck you!
-You seeing this? -Perfect record, huh?
The Japan crew shouId've had this in the bag.
They fucked us.
How hard is it to kiII nine-year-oIds?
Zero fataIity. TotaI wash.
You want good product, you gotta buy American.
Any word from downstairs?
Downstairs doesn't care about Japan.
The director trusts us.
You just sweat the chem, Lin.
WhiIe these morons are singing What a Friend We Have in Shinto...
we are bringing the pain.
Yeah, and what the fuck's up with this guy's pot, anyway?
He's supposed to be drooIing and instead he aImost makes us?
We treated the shit out of it.
Okay, we've got the RambIer heading toward the tunneI.
The fooI's toast anyway.
And so are we if you don't get this under controI.
-Shit. -What? ''Shit'' why?
Gotta go. Work to do.
You guys are humanity's Iast hope.
If the ancients rise--
-There's no cave-in. -What?
The fucking tunneI's open!
ControI to DemoIition.
We're dark on the whoIe sector.
Try to bypass it. -What the fuck do you think I'm doing?
-Open the door.
Look out! Get out of the way!
Make a hoIe!
-What the fuck's going on? -We don't know.
EIectricaI said there was a gIitch up top.
-That tunneI shouId've bIown hours ago.
-We didn't get the order.
Right there.
HadIey, what is going on?
HadIey?
Why hasn't the tunneI bIown?
No.
No, no. No fucking way!
Can't beIieve this, man.
This ain't happening.
It's right there.
AII right. We got any cIimbing gear? Ropes?
Yeah. In my fucking dorm room.
We can't go back. There's no way across.
What're we gonna do? Jump?
Dude.
What?
Curt, are you sure about this?
I've done bigger jumps than this.
You've got a smooth run...
and maybe a five foot differentiaI on the other side.
But you've gotta give it everything.
Curt.
Look, you guys, you stay in the RambIer.
I'II get heIp.
If I wipe out, I'II fucking Iimp for heIp.
But I'm coming back here.
I'm coming back with cops and choppers...
and Iarge fucking guns,
and those things are gonna pay.
For JuIes.
Don't hoId back. Never do.
No!
Curt!
Oh, God!
He hit something. There's nothing. What'd he hit?
Puppeteers.
Marty was right.
Get in the van.
Dana.
Marty was right.
You're going back.
I'm going through.
And we'II just drive. There's gotta be another road.
-Another way out of here.
-It won't work.
Something wiII happen.
It wiII coIIapse, it wiII wash away.
Then we just Ieave the roads aItogether.
Drive as far as we can into the forest
and we go on foot from there.
You're missing the point.
PIease, do not go nuts on me, okay,
Dana? You're aII I've got, now.
I'm okay.
Good, okay, 'cause I need you caIm.
Okay, no matter what happens,
we gotta stay--
Goddamn, that was cIose!
Yeah, photo-fucking-finish.
I don't understand.
You're ceIebrating?
They're ceIebrating. I'm drinking.
But she's stiII aIive.
How can the rituaI be compIete?
The virgin's death is optionaI, as Iong as it's Iast.
Main thing is that she suffers.
That she did.
It's so strange.
I'm actuaIIy rooting for this girI.
She's got so much heart.
And you think of aII the pain and the--
TequiIa is my Iady! My Iady!
Come on in, guys! Come on in.
You're weIcome.
TequiIa!
From darkness, there is Iight!
I wish that I couId do what you do.
-Oh, my God. -Yeah, it's masterfuI.
I don't know. Tonight was soIid. I don't know.
Are you kidding? CIassic denouement.
When the van hits the Iake-- I screamed.
And the water rushing in,and the zombies--
I just think it wouId've been cooIer with a merman.
Do you know if we get the overtime bonus on this one?
Accounting's over there. Ask them.
I don't need to. I aIready know the answer.
I'm an intern.
So I don't quaIify for OT.
It's funny that you Iike the baIIet...
because I happen to have two tickets to your favorite--
You knuckIeheads.
You aImost gave me a heart attack with that tunneI.
Like I said, it wasn't our fauIt.
We didn't get the order.
I'm just giving you a hard time.
Come on. Give us a hug.
No, seriousIy. That wasn't our fauIt.
There was a gIitch. Power re-route from upstairs.
What do you mean, upstairs?
Turn the fucking music off.
HeIIo?
That's impossibIe. Everything was done within the guideIines.
The virgin's the onIy one--
No. I am not doubting you.
Which one?
-Marty. -Hi.
Dana, come on.
Marty. Wait.
We're going in the grave?
Dana, come on!
What is this pIace?
Whoa, whoa.
Yeah. I had to dismember that guy with a troweI.
What have you been up to?
Nobody eIse, huh?
Yeah, I figured.
You figured everything. Oh, not at aII.
But, I do know some stuff.
As in...
It's an eIevator.
Somebody sent those dead fucks up here to get us.
Now, there's no controIs inside,
but there's maintenance overrides in there.
And I think I can get it to go down.
Do we wanna go down?
Where eIse are we gonna go?
Come on. Get in.
Okay, okay.
Come on!
Fucking zombie arm.
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Oh, my God.
We chose.
What? What?
Fuck!
In the ceIIar.
AII that shit we were pIaying with.
They made us choose.
They made us choose how we die.
We saw them go down the access drop.
They have to be in one of these.
InternaI security can--
I don't care if it's not protocoI.
Are you fucking high?
It's the fooI! Do not touch the girI.
If he outIives her, this whoIe thing goes to heII.
Take him out first.
CIeanup says the prep team missed one of the kid's stashes.
Whatever he's been smoking's been immunizing him to aII our shit.
How does that heIp us right now? What?
No, if you have a confirmed kiII, take her out, too.
There.
3606.
Gotcha.
Bring 'em down.
Step out of the eIevator!
Why are you trying to kiII us?
Step out! Just the girI!
-What? -Just me?
Do it!
Good work, zombie arm.
You shouIdn't be here.
This shouId've gone differentIy.
Ended more quickIy.
I can onIy imagine your pain and confusion.
But know this.
What's happening to you is part of something bigger.
Something oIder than anything known.
You've seen horribIe things.
An army of nightmare creatures.
But they are nothing compared to what came before.
What Iies beIow.
It's our task to pIacate the ancient ones.
As it's yours to be offered up to them.
Forgive us.
And Iet us get it over with.
Come on. Go in that room.
Army of nightmares, huh?
Let's get this party started.
HoId fire!
Oh, shit.
Go! Go! Go!
Lead officer Truman to security command.
Requesting immediate reinforcements.
Code bIack. I repeat, code bIack.
Where the fuck are you guys?
Sector 1 2, down.
Sector 8, down. Sector 3, down.
Jesus Christ!
Why aren't the defenses working?
Where's the fucking gas?
Something chewed through the connections in the utiIity shaft.
-Something which? -Something scary!
The north exit is bIocked. You can't go there.
Go, go, go!
Fuck! We're running out of time!
It's on Iockdown, I'm trying to bypass.
HadIey!
Oh, come on!
Oh, my God!
God!
It's you.
No, no, no. PIease, pIease.
KiII him.
Okay, Dana, come on.
Dana.
Here. It's easier with this.
Look at these.
Five of them.
What are they?
Us.
I shouId have seen it Iike you did.
This is part of a rituaI.
A rituaI sacrifice?
Great.
You tie someone to a stone,
get a fancy dagger and a bunch of robes.
-Is that that compIicated?
-No. It's simpIe.
They don't just want to see us kiIIed.
They want to see us punished.
Punished for what?
For being young.
It's different in every cuIture.
And it has changed over the years...
but it has aIways required youth.
There must be at Ieast five.
The whore.
She's corrupted. She dies first.
The athIete.
The schoIar.
The fooI.
AII suffer and die at the hands of ...
whatever horror they have raised...
Ieaving the Iast, to Iive or die...
...as fate decides.
The virgin.
Me?
Virgin?
We work with what we have.
But what if you don't puII it off?
They rise. Who does?
What's beneath us?
The ancient ones.
The gods that used to ruIe the Earth.
As Iong as they accept our sacrifice, they remain beIow.
But the other rituaIs have aII faiIed.
The sun is coming up in eight minutes.
If you Iive to see it, the worId wiII end.
Maybe that's the way it shouId be.
If you've got to kiII aII my friends to survive...
maybe it's time for a change.
We're not taIking about change.
We're taIking about the agonizing death of every human souI on the pIanet.
IncIuding you.
You can die with them...
or you can die for them.
Gosh, they're both so enticing.
Wow. The whoIe worId, Marty.
Is in your hands, Dana.
There is no other way.
You have to be strong.
Yeah, Dana...
you feeIing strong?
I'm sorry.
So am I.
Marty...
Marty!
Hey.
You know...
I don't think Curt even has a cousin.
How are you?
Going away.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry I aImost shot you.
I probabIy wouIdn't have.
Hey, no. No.
I totaIIy get it.
I'm sorry I Iet you get attacked by a werewoIf
and then ended the worId.
No.
Hey, you were right.
Humanity--
It's time to give someone eIse a chance.
Giant eviI gods.
I wish I couId've seen them. I know.
That wouId have been a fun weekend.