Pretty windy out.
- That better not be the violent one.
- It's not, Mom.
Dad, look what I can do.
I've been practicing.
- Spectacular, kiddo.
- Cool.
You're inside out.
I knew that.
Doesn't work for you?
I can't believe you taught him that.
I didn't. He did it on his own.
- Charlie, did you brush your teeth?
- Yes.
- Charlie.
- I brushed them.
- Look at this, Con.
- Let's go. I'm serious.
You're driving me bonkers, Mom.
Remember when you said no
to buying Omnidell?
- Remember what the price was?
- One fifty.
Close. Sixty-one.
- I'll do it, Mom.
- No, I'll do it.
You know what it's going for now?
- Say "E. "
- E.
- Guess, Con.
- Edward, I don't know, all right?
- Now rinse.
- Seventy-four.
Really rinse. And pee.
Seventy-four. Should have bought it.
Shit.
- So buy some.
- Too late, Con. Too late.
Lift the seat, honey.
Don't forget to put it down.
When you finish.
- Do you really need all that stuff?
- Mom, no one wears these dorky hats.
- You do and you're not a dork.
- How do I look?
Very handsome.
Love you.
Okay, come on, let's go.
Come on.
You shouldn't go in.
I have stuff to do for the auction.
And there's a birthday soon.
Latrell Sprewell jersey, Mom.
Don't forget.
- He's on the Yankees, right?
- Mom, you're driving me bonkers.
You're driving him bonkers.
Jesus.
Taxi! Shit.
Taxi!
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry.
I'll get your things.
Taxi! Taxi!
My books.
- Could you help me get a taxi?
- Okay.
- I'll watch your books.
- Thanks.
- Bad day for taxis.
- It's this horrible wind.
Yeah, you shot down there
like a bullet!
If you flapped your arms,
you'd be home now.
I'll remember that next time.
- That's not good.
- I know.
Listen, that's me up there.
The flowerpot.
I'll get you a Band-Aid, okay?
Hold onto something.
Don't blow away.
Or you can come on up
and clean it off, no?
Come on.
I'm not an ax murderer. I promise.
Shit.
Fucking elevator.
One more.
- Pardon the mess.
- Are you a writer?
I'm a book dealer.
Bathroom's right down there,
on the left.
Go ahead. There's a medicine cabinet.
You can sneak a peek
at my prescriptions.
Hello?
- I made you some tea.
- Thank you.
- Do you box?
- I used to, when I was young.
This is an amazing place.
- Yeah, but it's not mine.
- No?
The owner is a friend, a sculptor.
He's in Paris.
That's cool.
We can stay here, me and my books.
Can I use your phone?
I have to call home.
Sure, there's a phone just behind you.
Thank you.
Gloria? Hi, it's me.
Good, good. How's Charlie?
Hi, honey. How was your day at school?
Yeah? What was the best part?
Guess what? Can you believe it?
Mommy missed her train.
Ice.
About an hour.
You should start your homework.
I promise to tell you all about it
when I see you. I love you. Bye.
That was my son, Charlie.
He's 8. He'll be 9 next week.
I'm Paul Martel. I'll be 28 in July.
I'm Constance.
And I'm late. I have to go.
Before you go, take a book.
No. I couldn't.
Sure you can. A souvenir.
Go down there. You know, like before.
Okay.
Keep going. Stop.
Now right.
No, right.
Okay, now the second shelf
from the top. . .
. . .take the fourth one from the left.
Got it?
- Think so.
- Open to page 23.
Drink wine, this is life eternal
This, all that youth will give to you
It is the season for wine, roses
And drunken friends
Be happy for this moment
This moment is your life
I have to go. Thank you.
- Can you find your way out?
- I hope so.
That's my bedroom.
It was nice meeting you, Constance.
Come back if you need more books
or medical attention.
Hey, Glo.
- That wouldn't be the TV on, would it?
- I was just turning it off.
Sure you were.
- The wind knocked me down.
- Yeah?
You all right? You need anything?
- Gross. Were you in a fight?
- No, just fell over.
- Does it hurt?
- Little bit.
- Cool!
- Where are you going?
- To get the camera!
- Try this.
- Why do you need the camera?
- It's for school. We're doing blood.
Okay, now look like it really hurts.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
This will be great.
The wind blew her down.
She bled and everything.
- Everybody's hats blew off.
- Quite the war photographer. You okay?
Yeah. It took me down
like an old lady.
- It was humiliating.
- Dad, look at the pictures.
At least we got the evidence.
Anyone we can sue?
No. There was this nice guy
who helped me.
It was like this, Dad.
It was a twister.
Dad, look. It was like this.
- Wow.
- It's a tornado.
He lived around there. He got me
some Band-Aids and put me in a taxi.
Was he good-looking?
I feel sick.
- You do your homework?
- I can't. I don't know how to do it.
Come on, I'll help you.
Then you can help me with mine.
Did you get his name, this guy?
We could send him a bottle of wine.
Cheap wine.
Con, stand there a second.
Wait a minute.
Stay there a second.
I'm trying to figure out the. . . .
The thing I can't figure out
is the zoom-thing.
There it is.
Okay, hold on, stay there.
Got the zoomy-thingy zooming.
Stay there. I'm trying to figure
this out. I wanna see if it focuses.
Cool. Very cool.
So beautiful. If you only knew.
Look at you. God, what a beauty.
Something the matter?
Nothing. Nothing at all.
- This is really good.
- No, it isn't. Go away.
I think I'm really zooming.
I found the zoom. Found it.
Dad.
- Shit.
- Mom.
I can't sleep.
I'll be back. I'll be back.
Don't fall asleep.
It works.
Mom, are you nuts?
You forgot my lunch.
I did not. It's by the door.
Come with me.
- What are you chewing?
- Nothing.
Spit that out. What is that?
- That's lovely.
- Mom?
I don't want to be a dumb bunny.
Honey, it's a play. There's lots
of other bunnies. It'll be cool.
- You're bonkers, Mom.
- So you tell me.
- Love you.
- Love you too. What's that?
Thank you.
Bye.
Hi, this is Paul Martel. Leave
a message after the beep. Thanks.
Hello? Hello?
- Hello?
You're there.
This is Connie Sumner,
the one from the windy day.
Oh, that one.
How's the knee? Did you ice it?
Yes, I iced it and I elevated it.
You name it, I did it.
It's much better.
I just wanted to call and thank you.
I wanted your address
because I wanted...
- Where are you?
- What?
I said, where are you?
I'm in Grand Central.
It's really hard to hear you.
- Come and see me.
- What?
Yeah, take a break.
I'll make you some coffee.
Coffee?
- Okay.
See you. Bye.
Fuck.
No permanent damage, I see.
- We take Medicaid, Blue Cross. . . .
- I'm uninsured.
No. I'm afraid we don't
take charity cases.
It was a joke.
Look at this. Jack London.
First edition of White Fang,
in the original dust jacket.
And I got it for a buck fifty.
- What's it worth?
- About 4000 times more.
- Those are in French.
- I took it in school.
Do I want to take off something?
Your coat. Would you like
to take off your coat?
Yes, my coat.
Thank you.
But I can't stay very long.
I have some errands I have to run.
- I'll get the coffee.
- Okay.
- It's in Braille.
- Braille.
No, no, Braille.
He was French.
Close your eyes.
- What?
- Close your eyes.
My mother makes me chicken
Her chicken makes me cough
I wish that when she made it
She took the feathers off
It doesn't say that.
- I had better go.
- Yeah?
I'd better go.
Take care. Don't fall.
- Thanks for the coffee.
- You didn't drink it.
- Lindsay, hi.
- Connie.
- Let me buzz him.
- Thanks.
Hey, what a surprise. Look at you.
- Hi, Bill.
- Hi, Connie.
- Am I interrupting?
- No, I'm leaving.
- I'll get you the budget later.
- All right, thanks.
- Would you like a coffee?
- No, thank you.
That's nice.
I didn't know
you were coming in today.
You're freezing.
What is that?
I was around the corner
and I brought you a present.
Wow. What's the occasion?
Nothing. I don't know.
It's a medium,
but they said it runs large.
- Look at that.
- You don't have to try it on.
I'm the boss.
I can do whatever I want.
What do you think?
Hold on just a second.
Yeah?
Okay, but hold the other calls.
- You're busy. I'll go.
- Sit.
- I'll go.
- No, sit.
Hello, Henry?
So, what is this suspension problem?
No, I never received it.
Well, get it to me.
It's not good enough. I'm sitting here
with 200 trucks I can't use.
Well, set up a meeting.
And I want Frank Birnbaum there.
Because when I tell someone
to do something, I want it done.
I'm sure you will.
So, what else you up to?
- Auction.
- Yeah? Who'd you hit on?
The usual suspects.
Who?
- Bob Gaylord.
- Bob?
Get Bob to pledge and they should
send you to the Middle East.
So tell me.
What?
What do you think?
It's a keeper.
- Hello.
Here I am again. I brought muffins.
- What is this music?
- Do you like it?
Yes.
Do you want to dance?
- Now?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- I have to warn you, I tend to lead.
- Of course. You are American.
- You've done this before.
- What?
How many girlfriends have you had?
Two.
- Really?
- Would I lie to you?
I don't know. Would you?
Your eyes are amazing. You should
never shut them, not even at night.
You should learn to sleep
with your eyes open.
- I'll work on that.
- Will you?
Hang on.
I think this is a mistake.
There are no mistakes. There's what
you do, and what you don't do.
I can't do this.
Forgot my coat.
- I can't.
- What?
What's wrong?
I don't know how to do this.
It's wrong.
- Hit me.
- What?
Hit me.
- Hey, Ed.
- Hey, Bob.
- Haven't seen you in a while.
- No.
- I've been working late this week.
- Really? How's the boy?
- It's his birthday.
- How old?
Nine.
So any major armed robberies?
No. No, not this week.
Speaking of which,
watch out for Connie.
- She'll have you sign over your mortgage.
- What?
- Did she try to hit on you for money?
- No.
I thought she talked to you about
this school auction, or whatever.
Not me.
I've been out of town.
Maybe she talked to Maggie.
Yeah, I guess I got it wrong.
Anyway, we owe you a dinner.
Yeah.
He's out.
Can I get you anything?
No. No, I'm fine, thanks.
- Tough day?
- No, not really.
What about you? How was your day?
It was good.
You know, the usual stuff.
Sure you don't want anything?
No.
- Con?
- Yeah?
Do you love me?
Of course I love you.
What a silly question.
I guess. . .
. . .I'm just feeling silly.
I'll be up in a minute.
Okay.
Oh, sorry.
What are we doing here?
Having lunch.
- I shouldn't be doing this.
- You shouldn't have lunch?
Not with you.
I think we should leave.
Listen.
See those guys over there
paying the check?
- Yes.
- Okay. If the guy on the right pays. . .
. . .we leave right now.
If the guy on the left pays. . .
. . .we stay.
And I kiss you.
No.
Give me that.
I win.
- No.
- C'est la vie.
Don't do it. Don't.
- Room for two?
- Of course.
Nice music. What is it?
It's. . .
. . .African, I think.
I like it.
Here.
Let's go to bed.
- Come on.
- Stay here with me.
- I'm cold.
- Stay.
- Stay here with me.
- I'm cold.
Let's go.
How about lunch today?
You free?
I have all this fundraiser stuff.
Auction things to pick up.
We can do an early one if you want.
How about 12:00?
12:00?
Yeah.
Will I be hungry at 12:00?
We could go in together.
I'll wait for you.
- I won't be ready for another hour.
- That's all right. I'll wait.
- Oh, shit.
- What?
I just remembered. . .
. . .I have a facial at 12:30
at Georgianna's today.
Oh, well.
You gotta stay beautiful, right?
Georgianna's, huh?
Waste of money.
Yeah, Manhattan.
A beauty salon called Georgina.
Oh, yeah, right. Yes, Georgianna's.
That's right.
Thank you.
Hello, I'm calling to confirm
an appointment today at 12:30.
Sumner. Connie Sumner.
S-U-M-N-E-R.
Could she be down for another time?
No, thank you.
Connie?
It's Connie.
Tracy?
- Hi. I was gonna call you.
- They all say that. . .
. . .when I call about bunny costumes.
You know Sally from Planned Parenthood.
- Hi. It's been a while.
- Too long.
- You look amazing.
- So where you headed?
I was going to look for some
window shades for the kitchen.
We're gonna go and have coffee.
Why don't you join us?
- Oh, I'm gonna be late.
- For window shades?
- Come on.
- Okay.
Hi, how are you?
I'm just gonna make a phone call.
- Sure.
- Let me get that for you.
- She could've used my cell phone.
- Oh, you're right.
Hi, it's me.
You won't believe this.
I'm at that cafe around the corner.
Why do you introduce me
as Sally from Planned Parenthood?
It makes it sound like
I'm handing out condoms.
I'm stuck here.
Will you wait for me?
Wait for me.
I called Gloria to remind her
to pick up the dry cleaning.
Charlie is so adorable.
Thank you.
I can't eat.
- I'll have a coffee.
- Well, I guess I'll have coffee too.
Excuse me again. Ladies' room.
God, she looks good.
- You think she's had work?
- Why would she? She's still gorgeous.
They do it early now
before it goes to shit.
I have friends out there.
You take me to the best places.
Let me.
- She's not like that. She's really nice.
- Of course she is.
That makes it worse.
She's nice and she's sweet.
And her ass is in exactly
the same place it was in college.
Are you taking tennis?
Oh, I wouldn't call what I do
"taking tennis. "
- There you are. I was starting to worry.
- No, I'm fine.
We thought that heartthrob
abducted you.
What heartthrob?
You didn't see him at the counter?
He was gorgeous.
- I miss everything.
- Your button's undone.
Oh. Thank you.
That's him.
I can see the appeal.
If he looked at me twice,
I'd be on my back.
- You would not.
- I would so. Why not?
A couple of reasons:
Adam and your kids.
You know, Trace,
they wouldn't have to know.
It could be something I did for myself,
to broaden my horizons.
Like taking a pottery class.
- An affair isn't like taking pottery.
- Could be.
It would start out like that.
Then something would happen. . .
. . .someone finds out or someone
falls in love and it ends disastrously.
They always end disastrously.
No.
When?
It was a long time ago.
And it's the one thing in my life
I would undo if I could.
Did you just fuck me
across the street?
I did.
We could end this now
and no one would get hurt.
Yeah. I think if we ended this now,
I'd get hurt.
- So no matter what, someone gets hurt?
- Maybe not.
Maybe we'll get tired of each other.
God, I hope I get tired of you.
You're in my mind.
You're the only thing in my mind
when I wake up every morning.
You're in my brain
before I even open my eyes.
- What do you think of?
- That depends.
If it's a day when I don't know if I'm
gonna get to see you, I'm anxious. . .
. . .thinking of excuses to come to
the city to see you.
And the days you know we'll meet?
On those days. . .
. . .I'm. . .
. . .calm and hating myself.
This is what we have over here.
I'll have it ready for you
this afternoon.
Ed, what's up? Sounded important.
I've heard you're talking with
Dunbar and Brinks and other companies.
Where did you hear that?
Well, look.
I suppose they could be wooing me,
if that's what you mean.
Apparently a lot of people
are wooing you. Or who's wooing who?
What are you talking about?
So I talked to some people.
- So what?
- This is about loyalty, Bill.
I'm letting you go. You'll have
my recommendation if you need it.
I have a family, Ed.
You had a family here.
No, wait a minute.
You're telling me about family?
You don't know the first
goddamn thing about it.
Look at your own fucking family, Ed.
Take a goddamn look at that.
- Ed.
- Frank.
Thanks for coming on such short notice.
This is personal, it's not business.
Think about it.
You might not want to get involved.
But I need someone I can trust.
I want you to follow somebody.
I want you to follow my wife.
- It's burning, Mom.
- What?
It's burning. The chicken.
Shit.
It's boiling, Mom. It's boiling!
Thank you.
Watch it. Watch it.
Chicken's a little dry. I'm sorry.
It's fine.
I have to go to Chicago tomorrow.
- For how long?
- Not long. Probably just a night.
What time's your flight?
Eight o'clock.
A.M.?
Dianne Dreyer's son is marrying
Amy Lynn's daughter.
- I'm never getting married.
- Why not?
I hate girls.
You might change your mind.
That happens sometimes.
I won't.
- What?
- I fired Bill Stone today.
- That's what's bothering you?
- Nothing's bothering me.
Why did you fire him?
- He's not accountable.
- What's accountable?
- Isn't it like people who eat people?
- No.
That's a cannibal, honey.
Anyway, I can't trust him anymore.
So if you run into Dolly, you'll know.
- What?
- I can't believe you!
What did I do?
Shit!
Come on!
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
Honey, you okay?
- You must have been so worried.
- Stop, Mom. People can see.
Hi, this is Paul Martel.
Leave a message after the beep.
Mom?
You're supposed to be in bed.
- You're crying, Mom.
- Oh, honey.
Mommy's just a little sad, that's all.
Come on, I'll take you bed.
Let's get you into bed.
Don't be sad, Mom.
Dad will be home tomorrow.
His name is Paul Martel.
He lives at 433 Mercer Street,
Apartment 3.
She sees him during the day.
Usually goes around lunchtime.
Stays about two hours, maybe three.
They go to the movies?
They did that day.
Otherwise, they're in his place.
Pick up.
Hey, lady!
Forgot your keys.
Wait!
Who is she? Who is she?
Calm down! What are you doing?
How many are there? Five, ten?
What am I, the Monday one?
Did I get my day wrong?
She's just a friend, okay?
Just a friend.
- You're a fucking liar.
- Me? I'm the liar?
I can't do this anymore.
Fine. Go back to your suburb
and car pool, your tennis...
What are you doing?
- Fuck you.
- That'll make you happy.
Fuck you.
No, I can't.
Paul, it's over.
I can't.
- I hate you. I hate you.
- I know.
Stop it, I can't.
- Are you gonna fuck me?
- You want me to?
- I want you to.
- Say it.
- I want you to fuck me.
I want you to fuck me.
Thank you. Thank you very much.
Thank you very much, indeed.
Yes?
- You're Paul Martel?
- Yes.
How old are you?
Who are you?
Edward Sumner.
Connie's husband.
May I. . .?
May I come in?
Yeah. Sure.
- Would you like a drink?
- Yeah, why not?
I have Scotch, vodka, orange juice. . . .
Vodka.
Is it cold?
Yeah.
I keep it in the freezer.
So do I, at home.
So tell me, how did you. . .
. . .meet my wife?
By accident.
On the street. There was
a windstorm, she hurt her knee and. . . .
You're him.
She told you about that?
Yes.
How's it going?
Fine. Fine. I mean, okay.
- This is where you meet?
- Yes.
- She likes it?
- I guess. She never complained.
Do you stay in all the time,
or do you go out too?
It depends. Sometimes we go out.
And she likes that?
She likes this neighborhood?
More exciting than the suburbs,
I guess.
Do you know we have been
married 11 years?
We have a son.
She told me.
More?
Yes, please.
He's the reason that we left the city.
Connie thought it'd be better for him.
She told me it was your idea.
You talk about me?
A lot of books.
A lot of buying and selling.
I didn't know it did that.
- Where did you get this?
- It was a gift.
From her.
- Why would she do that?
- I don't know.
Maybe she just wanted
to buy me something.
She didn't buy this for you.
I gave it to her.
- I can't do this.
- What?
I can't do this. I can't do this.
I'm feeling sick. I can't...
You want some water?
I'm feeling sick. I'm...
I feel...
I'm not well. I'm not feeling well.
I'm not...
I'm not feeling...
God!
You can't die.
Hi, this is Paul Martel.
Leave a message after the beep.
Hi, it's me.
Listen.
I don't like saying this
to your machine...
...but I have to end this.
I just... I can't do it anymore.
I can't live like this.
I'm so tired of lying
and hurting my family.
I'm sorry.
And I hope...
I don't know what I hope.
I'm sorry.
Messages erased.
Does that pinch?
No.
- Do you know your solo?
- Yep.
Can I hear it?
- Need a hand?
- No, I'm fine.
Thanks.
Where were you?
You okay?
You were spectacular, you know that?
- Wasn't he great?
- Great.
He was great. Great.
Really great.
I have to help clean up. I'll kiss
you good night when I get home, okay?
- Sorry, Ed. Looks like I nailed you.
- It's all right.
It's all right, Jerry.
You better check to see
if this will open.
It's nothing. This is fine.
- Did he dent you, Dad?
- Yes, he did. Yes.
Can we call the cops, Dad?
- Let's check the trunk.
- We'll talk tomorrow.
- It'll just take a second.
- No!
Oh, my God.
Charlie, look at your dad
and tell me what's wrong.
What?
His shoes. They're different colors.
Honey, you look awful.
What happened last night? Did you
sleep? I got up and looked for you.
I just. . .
. . .got some air.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
Do you like it here?
What? Of course I like it here.
We don't have to stay here.
We can move back to the city.
Honey, what has gotten into you?
Are you okay?
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine. Fine.
- Are you okay?
- I'm fine.
Everybody's fine.
And we're not moving anywhere.
The cops are here, Mom.
- What do they want?
- I'm sure it's nothing.
N.Y.P.D., Mom.
Mrs. Sumner? I'm Detective Dean,
this is Detective Mirojnick, N.Y.P.D.
Something happen?
Is something wrong?
Do you know a Paul Martel?
- Yes, not very well. Why?
- Do you know where he is?
No.
At home, I would imagine.
Do you know where he lives?
SoHo, isn't it?
Your name and number
were found on his desk.
- Has he done something wrong?
- We don't know.
He's been reported
missing by his family.
His wife doesn't know where he is.
I didn't know he was married.
Separated.
When did you see him last?
I don't know, it's hard to say.
He's a book dealer.
I barely know him.
I was going to buy books from him.
- And did you?
- No, not yet.
Has something happened?
You think he's all right?
It's hard to say at this point.
We're working on it.
- Anyway, thanks. Thanks for your time.
- Thank you.
I like these snow-glass things.
My boy has some of these.
- If you hear from him, let us know.
- Certainly.
Dad! Cops came to our house today.
Cops? What did they want?
Someone's missing.
And they have to check everyone,
you know.
Who was it?
Honey, sit up straight.
- Who was it?
- I don't think you know him.
He sells books.
I forget where I met him.
Was it a bad guy, Mom?
Why did they want to talk to you?
I guess he had my name and number.
Why would he have your number?
I think I bought a book from him.
- Be careful. Take it easy.
- Hey, Charlie!
Oh, my darling.
Oh, I wished you lived closer.
Lord, bless this food to our use,
and us to thy service.
And help us be ever mindful
of the needs of others. Amen.
Amen.
Very nice, Edward.
All right!
I have a story you don't know
about Edward. Gather close.
Hello, Mrs. Sumner.
Sorry to bother you on the weekend.
I'm Detective Dean.
- This is Detective Mirojnick, N.Y.P.D.
- Okay.
We were hoping
to talk to you for a few minutes.
Sure.
- Charlie, we're going up on the porch.
- Can I come?
No, sweetheart. Stay out here.
Play with Poppy, we'll be right back.
I don't know if your wife mentioned,
we were here a week ago.
About Paul Martel.
Yeah, the man who was missing.
Well, he's not missing anymore.
His body was discovered last weekend.
God, that's terrible.
Oh, my God.
Do you recall where
you met Mr. Martel, Mrs. Sumner?
- I told you.
- No, ma'am, you didn't.
I'm sorry.
I can't remember.
A fundraiser, I think.
Can you be more specific?
Juilliard.
Juilliard?
The music school.
- Yes, I know what Juilliard is.
- Of course you do. I'm sorry.
Were you there too, sir?
Yes. Yes, I think I was.
Well, maybe you met Mr. Martel.
No. No, not that I remember.
Maybe you'd recognize him.
No, I've never met him before.
- Is that him?
- Yes. Yes.
You ever been to his apartment?
No.
No, I hardly knew him.
- I didn't know why he had my number.
- Maybe he liked you.
Look, that's enough.
So you've never been to his apartment.
How about the neighborhood?
- Hang out down there?
- No.
No, not often. . .
. . .or no, never.
Never. I can't remember the
last time I was in SoHo.
It was four weeks ago, actually.
You got a parking ticket in front
of Martel's apartment, four weeks ago.
Oh, that. Right. I had coffee
with friends at a little place.
I forgot.
- It was Tracy and Sally.
- Oh, yeah. Yes. Yep.
Look. . .
. . .my wife has told you everything
she knows, so have I.
If you don't mind,
we'd like to get back to our son.
All right.
- Why don't I give you my card?
- I have your card.
Right.
- Enjoy your weekend.
- You too.
Sumner, please.
Oh, my God.
Connie?
Hi, Tracy.
I'm just picking up
my silk suit for tonight.
I was thinking of wearing the black.
I'm giving it to Goodwill. Let someone
else be gorgeous for a change.
What should we bring, aside
from our sparkling personalities?
- How we doing?
- Fine.
- Need help?
- No.
Well, the white is not cold,
so I'm gonna put it in the freezer.
Just remind me it's in there,
all right?
Most people drink red anyway.
I love these things. Is there any
place you guys haven't been?
The Rosenthals got
795 for their place.
- In two days they had six offers.
- Sealed bids is how they do it now.
What do you think
this place is worth, Ed?
I don't know. If you sell
your house, where do you go?
- At those prices, Tahiti.
- Bangkok.
Connie, where is this one from?
Fiji.
Remember, Jeff,
I asked you to take me to Fiji.
And then you took me to Hawaii.
We went fishing every single. . . .
What happened, Edward?
What did you do?
Did you hurt him?
Edward?
You did, didn't you?
Jesus, Edward.
Talk to me.
Tell me what you did!
No, you tell me what you did.
How you fucked him, over and over
and over. You lied to me!
- Over and over and over.
- Edward, please...
No, you don't talk to me now.
I gave everything. . .
. . .for this family.
Everything.
And what did you do?
You threw it all away,
like it was nothing.
For what?
To the fucking kid.
You didn't think I'd know?
I wouldn't feel it?
I knew it from the very first day.
Because I know you, Connie.
I know you and I fucking hate you.
I didn't want to kill him,
I wanted to kill you!
Oh, my God.
Edward. Oh, my God.
Mom, look what I did.
Honey, it's okay. That's okay.
I'm sorry, Mom.
It's an accident.
Everybody has accidents.
Why aren't you in bed, Mom?
I don't know.
Charlie, look at me.
I want you to know. . .
. . .that I love you,
more than anything in the world.
And I want you to know
that your daddy and me both. . .
. . .will always, always love you.
No matter what.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Come on, sweetie.
Let's go fix up your bed
all nice and fresh, okay?
All right.
You can come on up
and clean it off, no?
Come on.
I'm not an ax murderer. I promise.
Taxi.
Thank you.
What are we going to do?
I'm so scared.
I'll turn myself in.
No.
No, we can get through this.
We'll take it one day at a time.
No one will know.
We'll know.
3200, 3500, 3800, 4000. . .
. . .42, 45, 4800!
We can disappear.
We can raise some money.
Sell everything
and just leave the country.
Senorita?
Mexico.
Why not?
We can get a little house
on the beach.
Take a different name.
People do it all the time.
What will we tell Charlie?
Tell him it's an adventure.
We could fish all day.
We could learn to play the guitar.
I would serenade you
to sleep every night.
We'll just live the rest of our lives
on that beach.
And then when we die,
we can just push out to sea.
What do you think?
Sounds perfect.