- ( jazz music playing )- ( audience laughing )
( drumming )
( people chatting )
You, um--can you turn-- your light.
What?Oh, l'm such a moron.
How's the flick?
Oh, you know.Adam Sandler gets in a mess.
Wife gets pissed.Rinse and repeat.
Predictable. Formulaic.Fart jokes. You wouldn't like it.
How would you knowwhat l like?
Ahem-- l wouldn't.I wouldn't know.
Well, maybe you shouldfind out sometime.
Hi. Um, can l getsome popcorn, please?
( whirring )
( laughing )
( buzzing, clicking )
Oh shit!
What the...?
Hey, Hal?
What the hell?
( tapping )
Hal?
What the hell's going on?
( door creaks )
Kim?
( generator humming )
( baby crying )
Man:Hey. Hey! Hey, you!
Everyone's gone.They're all gone.
Got anyonein the theaters?
No, man.I haven't seen a soul.
Security guard: Jesus.Same down in the food court.
- Projectionist: You know what happened?- We're on backup power.
Heading down to maintenanceto find out more.
( voices whispering )
( guard chuckles )We're being punked, right?
Projectionist: Yeah, Alan Funt'sgonna pop out any minute.
- Guard: Who?- Forget it.
( faint whirring )
What the hell is that?
Projectionist:What did you see?
Wait here.
- Guard: Who's there?- Projectionist: See something?
Huh?
( guard screams )
( generator pops )
( shrieks )
Woman:Anybody here?
Hello?
Anyone here?
Where is everyone?
Anybody here?
Hey. Hello?
( faint moaning )
( beeping )
( voice whimpering )
( wheezing )
Help me, please.
I need help, please.
( gasps )
- ( man shrieks )- ( beeping stops )
( whimpering )
No.
( whines )Manny. Manny.
My baby. Manny!
( grunts )
Paige?
I waited for you.
( yawns )
You here? Paige?
( faint dripping )
Son of a--
What the hellis going on here?
( panting )23 goddamn flights.
Piece ofjunk.
Yo, Jesus,what's up with the--
( voices whispering )
This is yesterday's.
( crunches )
( wind rustling )
( gulls calling )
- ( explosion )- ( gasps )
( voices whispering )
Paige?
Anyone?
Where are you?
Ah.
Damn it.
( faint squealing )
Hello?
Somebody there?
( crow cawing )
( distant dog barking )
( engine sputters )
Shit.
Hey!Open the door!
Open upthe fucking door, man!
Hey, man, l need--l need a light.
They're all spent.Gimme one of your lights, man.
Open the door.
( voices whispering )
Gimme one of your lights.Please.
God damn!
- ( man grunts )- ( bike clatters )
( engine sputters )
( ignition beeps,engine starts )
( engine stops )
( distant music playing )
( shadows howling )
( music continues )
* Hello little boy,don't you remember me? *
* Well, l'm the same onewho brought you from Tennessee *
* Yes, you came to the city,got your wig real high *
* l said, you came to the city,got your wig real high *
* Now don't forget daddy,l'm the one who put you wise *
* Please don't high-jive me baby,l ain't the jiving kind *
* No, don't high-jive me daddy,l ain't the jiving kind *
* 'Cause you'll find l'm hipand you'll up and lose your mind *
* Down in Tennessee,you was ragged and beat *
* Walking round barefooted,drinking Sneaky Pete *
* Don't get me solemn,l know just what to do *
* lf you make me mad,l'll tell the whole world about you... *
( music continues )
( sighs )
( music skipping )
( music continues )
* Hello little boy,don't you remember me? *
* Hello little boy... *
( generator chugging )
( rumbling )
Boy:Don't move!
Put the gun on the floor.
- It's a flashlight.- Just put it on the floor.
You mean this gun?
Put or drop?
Put the fucking gunon the ground!
Come on.The light too.
- You want me to turn it off?- The light too!
Now!
All right.
Okay.What now?
( music continues )* Have you ever loved someone... *
Why don't you lower that barrel a littleand we'll talk this shit out, huh?
Can l at leasthave my drink?
Ls that permitted?
Hey!God damn it!
Come on! Shoot me!
Do it!Shoot me!
You're afraid to.
- No l'm not.- Yeah you are.
You shoot me,there's nobody left. Right?
Right.
What's your name?
James.
James...
like Jesse James,gun and all.
L'm Luke.
L've seen your face.
- Oh yeah?- TV.
That's right.
News 7.L'm the new field reporter.
You're always yelling at peoplewith the microphone.
Look, James,here's the truth.
L'm just happyto see another face.
You know what l mean?
Why don't you put the gun downand we'll have ourselves a drink?
Come on, l'm buying.
It'll be my pleasure.
( CDs clicking )
- Luke: Where'd you find this?- James: Lt's my Mom's.
She keeps it under the bar.
- Your mom owns this place?- Nah, bartender.
She around?
Up the street.Went to check the light in the church.
Light?
Yeah, a guy came bysaying he saw light in that church.
A guy?How long ago?
He's gone now.
( Luke sighs )
You got a nicegenerator down there.
How much gasyou got left?
I don't know.
My mom told me to keep feeding itevery few hours though.
You a strong kid,Jesse James?
- Strong enough.- Good.
Drink up.You're gonna need it.
Why?
Here.Batteries work.
You're gonna help usget us both out of here.
L'm not going nowhere.L've got to wait for my mom.
She just went up the streetto the church.
She told meto stay right here.
We need to get out of this city.You understand?
L'm not going nowhere.
We're moving out when shecomes back with some people.
What people?There are no people.
Don't matter.She told me she'd be back.
Have you taken a lookoutside lately, James?
Lt's like 11:00 in the morning
and it's fucking pitch black!
L've been out therefor the last three days.
And every day the suncomes up later
and goes down sooner.Every day, less daylight,
more people just gone!
You understandwhat l'm saying?
I don't thinkyour mom's coming back.
- Yes she is!- No she's not.
I don't knowwhat in Christ is going on here,
but l'm not hanging aroundin this dump to find out.
You want to just waittill the gas is up in that genny?
Knock yourself out.L'm out of here.
Fair exchange.Good luck.
L'm serious, all right?L'm going.
- L'm gone.- Then go, motherfucker! Go!
Where is he?
Manny, baby,it's Mama.
Randy! What'd he dowith my Manny?
- Hey, lady--- Please.
- You seen my Manny?- I don't know. I don't know.
- My baby.- I don't know.
- Randy, where you at?- Hey, lady, there's nobody else here.
Randy! Randy!
He took my baby.
I know he took my baby.
Look, l'm real sorryfor your--
- Where's my baby?!- Whoa whoa whoa!
- Where is my baby?!- Don't you point that gun at me!
- Where's my baby?!- God damn it!
( sobbing )
Help me. Help me.
( shadows shrieking )
( gasps )
( panting )
( thumps )
( music continues )
So how'd you get this farwithout a light?
You didn't have onewhen you came in here.
- How old are you?- 12 and a half.
Manny'snine months today.
James:That's your boy?
Yes.
L'm James. That's Luke.
Rosemary.
You a doctor?
Woman on P.A.:Dr. Williamson.
Dr. Williamson,please report to the E.R.
Dr. Williamson, pleasereport to the E.R.
( baby crying )
( siren blaring )
- ( women screaming )- ( cars crashing )
( bird chirping )
Gloria?
Manny? Manny!
Please, God.
( screams )
James:Are you a doctor?
( stammers )Ph-physical therapist.
Manny's dad comes hereto drink, so l thought that--
l thought that hetook our baby here.
I...
It's okay.
I do have light.
I got a lot of light.
The batteries kept dyingon my flashlight.
These last.
Why does the powerwork here?
Luke:Backup generator.
Won't last though.
You're the first peoplel've seen in two days.
- Why?- Why what?
Why us?
Why are we the onesleft behind?
( faint voice yells )Help!
Somebody help me!
Luke:Just stay close to the light.
Stay in the light,all right?
Man:Help! Help!
Help!
Someone help me!
Sounds like he's hurt.
Bad luck for him.
What?
We can't just leave him.
Man:Someone help me, please.
Go get him then.
( man yelling )
- L'll go.- No.
No, you stay here.L'll go.
Give it to me.Move.
Lock the door.
Then open itwhen you hear me coming.
Fast!
Come on,let's get inside.
Man:Hello!
( screaming )
- Help me.- Shh.
Help me.
- All right. Come on.- No! No!
You're coming with me.It's all right.
- No!- It's okay. Come on.
Projectionist:They're here. They're here.
- No. It's just me.- They're here.
- Luke: Oh shit!- They're here. They're here.
Come on, not now.
- They're here.- ( shadows moaning )
They're out there.
- Here.- Don't leave me.
- ( shadows shrieking )- They're coming.
All right, come on.One more time.
( voice whispers )James.
- James...- Mama.
What are you doing?No, James!
I got to find my mom.I got to go.
She's waiting for me!
We have to stay in the light.
L'm sorry.
He ain't coming back,is he?
( grunting )
We're almost there.
( shadows moaning )
( projectionist groans )
( Luke moans )Come on!
- ( shrieking )- Hey!
Hey!
Open the door!
Rosemary:Come on! Hurry up!
( snapping )
Hey. Hey.
Hey.
( blues ballad plays )
What, am l in heaven?
Luke:Better--
( groans )A bar.
I gotta go. I gotta go.
- No, lie still.- I gotta go.
What's your name?Can you tell me your name?
My name is Paul.Paul.
- Paul, that's my name.- Rosemary: Good.
You have a concussion,so we need to keep talking.
- Okay?- Paul: Okay.
All right.
That light.
How'd you get there?
I...
l was workingat the Fairlane Center
when the whole mallwent dark.
All the people were all gone.
So l was on my wayout of there
when my light starts dying.
And then someone cameout of the dark and hit me.
I was taken somewhere.
And then my light came back onand l was outside.
I don't even knowhow l got there, but l--
l walked till l foundthat bus shelter.
Taken?
Taken.
I don't know where.
I don't know where
but there were these voices.
These whispers.
No bodies. No faces.
- Souls.- Only shadows.
And l was drowningin them.
So l started screaming.
Started screaming.
But there was no sound.
There was no sound.
It was like l was fighting,fighting for air.
Like l was fighting to exist.
Sounds like some kindof fever dream.
No.Dreams are much more
broken apart, more obscure.
I was taken someplacefor three days.
Rosemary:We need to keep you warm.
This was in real time.
Luke: So did you get a lookat the guy that hit you?
Paul: I told you-- l told youit wasn't a person.
You saw it too, didn't you?
I knew it.
When l was lying there,
waiting for the bus,
l had time and l wentthrough the list--
of all the ways everyonecould just disappear--
flesh-eating bacterias,
nanotech run amok,
a particle collider accident,
parallel universes,neutron bombs,
- gamma ray bursts...- Alien abduction.
...singularities,wormholes, black holes--
- Stop it!- The thing is, the math doesn't add up.
The mathdoes not add up.
My boy is missing.
His mother...
It just doesn't add up.
This is no accident.There's a reason.
You gonna lay yourCatholic guilt on us now?
So why are you here, Luke?
You know?
No idea.And l don't care.
Well, you should.
We all--we all should.
Why didn't we gowith everyone else?
- Paul: Because...- Why?
Like when you shut downa movie projector,
it doesn't just stop on a dime.It winds down.
We're the last spin on the reelbefore it stops for good.
I know l've done thingsin my life--
awful things.L've hurt people.
L've made mistakes.
We all have.
So what are you saying,that this is punishment?
For what?
- That's between you and...- And God?
Between me and God?I think God's closed up shop
- just like everybody else.- Don't say that!
You trying to tell methat he deserves this shit?
- Leave him alone!- I think you're just pissed off
- 'cause Jesus didn't beam you up.- Stop it! No!
We don't need somefucking left-behind sermon.
What we need to do is--oh no, no.
( jukebox skipping )
( shadows moaning )
Sweet Jesus. Sweet Jesus.
- Lessen the load.- What?
The power load on the genny,you got to lessen it.
Turn off anythingwe don't need.
James, get the games.The jukebox.
Luke:Turn 'em off! Turn 'em off!
Get the neon signs!
( chugging )
Paul:Strip the top off!
- Ah!- Looks like somebody rerouted it
up to the barafter the main grid died.
Yeah, my mom.
At leastwe got plenty of gas.
It doesn't matter.It doesn't matter.
The electric chargeis fading anyway.
Like the batteriesand the flares...
And the carsand everything.
It's just impossible.
But the bus shelter,the one you were under...?
Luke: Solar-powered--an experimental one-off.
The city was thinkingof going green for a while.
- I did a piece on it.- Okay, so solar's working.
Yeah.Too bad the sun's not.
( banging )
James, where's this go?
Sonny says it's where we gowhen the shit hits the fan.
Sonny had a point.
All right, rocket scientist,how long?
- How long what?- How long we got?
- How long till it dies?- All: Yeah.
Couple hours. I don't know.Couple minutes.
There are no known laws of physicsoperating here, okay?
I don't fucking know!I don't know! I don't know!
- Hey! Whoa whoa!- What are you doing?
- I don't know!- ( Rosemary whimpering )
Rosemary: Please, God,please, God, save us.
( groans )
Luke: Come on,take it easy.
Okay. Okay.
( gasps )
Rosemary:Please, God...
please, God,please, God, please, God.
Please, God.Please, God, help us.
There's this island--
this island right offthe Carolinas
called Roanoke.
In 1587 it was--
it was the firstEnglish colony.
117 men, women and children
are living there.
And one day a boat comesfrom London with supplies.
But lo and behold,there's nobody to supply,
'cause everybody's gone.
The whole entire colonycompletely vanished.
Left everything behind--food, livestock, clothing.
They sent search partieslooking for everybody for days
and the only thingthey find--
you know what they find?One word.
One word.
Just scratched--
scratched on a fencepost--
"Croatoan."
James:Croa-what?
Croatoan.
What does it--what does it mean?
I don't know.Nobody knows.
It's just a big mystery.
Maybe it's a messagefrom the local Indians or--
or a word, or...
just a last word.
Nobody knows for sure.
But maybe it's--
maybe it's a warning.
A warning like an error warningyour computer gives you
right before it crashes.
A warning from who?
Does it really matter?Huh?
Someone just hitthe restart button
and the lost colony was just thislittle warning right before the--
right before this--this-- this big reboot.
- Whoa!- Paul!
Paul: Feels like a semismashed into my skull.
Rosemary: That's becauseyou think too much.
James, wet the towel,sweetie.
There we go.
We need ice.
L'm just gonnaraise your head up.
Just breathe.Breathe. Breathe.
Rosemary:Keep breathing. That's it.
Slow down. Slow down.
( inhales )
Luke:Hello?
Anybody here?
Stephen?
Somebody here?
( clicks, grunts )
( shadow squealing )
( gasps )
Control room.
( audio squeaking )
Anchorman: ...reporter Luke Rydercontinues his series
on a storm of controversysurrounding alleged security lapses
at the West Havennuclear power plant.
Yeah, you definitelydon't want to miss that.
And speaking of storms,Paige...
Well that's right,Carolyn and Stephen.
We're tracking a very large frontmoving in our direction.
Kind of an unusual storm...
( audio squeaking )
...the good news isthis low pressure system
is followed by a very nicehigh pressure front, so things...
( Paige gasps,screams )
( audio squeaking )
...so things...( screams )
Man:Lt defies any logical
or rational explanation.
Hey! Hey!
Man:You can't say that it's evil.
You can't say that it's humanor not human.
But it is...
the new law of nature,
and we have to adapt.
Last nightafter the blackout
l heard my brother call out to mefrom the darkness.
My brother diedeight years ago
in an automobile accident.
It can trick you.Stay near a light source.
But do not trust any light
other than the one that you hold
in your own hand.
This is David Breardan,at WDID in Chicago.
If you're receiving this broadcast,then your phone circuit may still work.
Please, call or text meat this number--
312-555-83--
( system whines )
Damn it.
Hello?
Woman's voice:Luke.
( voices whispering )
( moaning )
( shadows moaning )
( panting )
- ( Paul groans )- Rosemary: All right.
( sighs )
We need to getout of here-- now.
He can't go anywhere.
- ( slams )- ( gasps )
Don't you get it?Why we're here?
At this exact place?All of us?
L'll tell you why.
The light.
The light's protecting us.
Protecting us?Ever see moths fly into a flame?
What are you trying to say?You trying to say this is a trap?
Luke:A trap, a dead end.
But whatever's out thereis in here now.
Point is when thatgenny dies, we die.
Maybe that's howit should be.
What?
All of ushave seen them--
those souls
out there in the dark.
How do we knowthey're not the people
we've already lostcalling us over?
How do we knowthat that's not heaven
and this is...
( shadows moaning )
Lf my boy's with them,then that's where l'm meant to be.
And if he's not...
then l ain't going nowheretill l find him.
( groaning )
( sighs )
Look.There's a truck,
l don't know, maybe five,eight blocks away.
The power's drained,but it's not dead.
Now if we can get it started,
we all have a chanceof getting out of here...
maybe get you to a hospital.
Oh yeah?A hospital where, man?
- Where?- Chicago.
The morning after it happened,l caught a satellite feed.
There are survivorsout there like us.
Paul: So where arethe rescue parties, huh?
Lt's been three days.I don't see any search parties.
I don't know, all right?
All l know is l'm gonnaroll that truck to this genny.
L'm gonna string some jumper cablesfrom the genny to the truck's battery.
L'm gonna start that truck
and l'm gonna get outta herewith or without any of you.
How you gonna roll it?You can barely walk.
Then a little help would be nice.
James, we have a vehicle.
All right, we cancover more ground,
you know, maybelook for your mom.
Your son.
We can wait till morning.
You surethere's one coming?
( generator chugging )
( panting )
The first couple days,
you know, l kept asking myself,"Why am l still here?
Why me?"
You know,just talking to myself,
running from place to placeshouting my name like an idiot,
anything to remind methat l exist.
L'm here
because l will myselfto exist.
( shadows squeal )
You know what?Maybe l'm wrong.
Maybe this is justa passing storm.
Maybe it ends tomorrow.
You said it yourself,Paul--
a big reboot.
Which means that this could all bea new beginning, right?
Not an end.
But we can't waitaround here to find out.
Those rations downstairs,put as many as you can
into these garbage bags, all right?We'll need to bring them with us.
And keep an eyeon that generator.
It goes black, you take thisand get out of here.
What about Paul?L'm supposed to watch him.
Hey, you heard what l said.
Here.
Take this, all right?
Lt's good luck.
L'll bring us back a real one.
Paul:God, you're beautiful.
Let me tell you something.You were born for the movies.
I think you missed your calling.
Yeah, king of missedopportunities, that's me.
But l never misseda reel change.
- Never. Okay, once.- ( Rosemary chuckles )
Tell me, as a woman--
as a beautiful woman--what do you think?
You think l mighthave a chance?
I mean, l'm talkinghypothetically.
Not with you, but just in general,you think l'm...
you know,you think l'm--
God, l'm sofucking stupid,
going onand on and on.
Luke:Hey, we gotta go.
No no, hey!
Come back.
We will.
Don't let himfall asleep, okay?
Be brave.
( door shuts )
- ( lights crackling )- ( voices whispering )
( dog barking )
( shadows shrieking )
- ( Luke panting )- Rosemary: Come on.
Come on! Lt's dead.
I just put batteries infour minutes ago.
Luke: This'll do it.It's right over here. Come on.
Luke: I must've checked 500 carssince this happened.
God damn, if this isn't the only onewith a battery that still works.
Why does this one work
and all the others don't?
Lt's a Chevy.
( groans )There is no reason. All right?
Lt's random, you know.Toss of a coin.
Why l'm still here and the suckerwho was driving this boat isn't,
l don't know.I had a light. He didn't--
Just tell mewhat l have to do.
Luke: Push!Keep pushing!
James:You're fine.
You got a girl?
A what?
Paul: A what?Not a what, a girl--
a main squeeze.
James:I got a ma.
You got a ma.
Of course you got a ma.Everybody's got a ma.
We all got a ma, but...
"Umbrellas of Cherbourg."
That's the moviethat l'm gonna screen for her.
1964.
Catherine Deneuve.
The music, the colors--
she's gonna love it.
Paul?
Paul. Paul!
( shadows moaning )
Paul, wake up!
Go put on a song.
A what?
Go put a song onfor me.
- But Luke says--- l don't care what Luke says.
Just give me one more song.Go ahead.
See if they got "Forever"by the Marvelettes.
They got it.
( softly )Play it.
( clicks )
( music playing )
( music warbles )
( weakly )* Darling, forever *
* Forever *
* You can break my heart... *
( music continues within )
* l'll play the part... *
* ...Of a fool *
* Just to be with you... *
Recording:* Forever *
* Darling, forever *
* Forever *
* You can call me names *
* Take my love for granted *
* But l'll always be just a fool *
* lf l-- if l could be with you *
* l'll be your slave *
* For the rest of-- of my days *
* Love you more *
* In so, so many ways *
* Just to be with you *
* Thrills me through and through *
* And darling, forever *
* Forever... *
Paul:James! James!
James! James!
James!
James:Paul! Come on.
Come on, wake up!
( Luke, Rosemary grunting )
Luke:Hold up! Hold up!
Rosemary:Lt's just a few more blocks.
Luke: No, l've got to stopfor a second.
( groaning )
My ankle.I just need a minute.
- ( music playing )- ( beeps )
( music warbles )
( sputtering )
James...?
( clicking )
( music drags )
( gulps )
James!
James...!
They're all dead.
Your son.Does he talk yet?
Manny, right?
Does he talk?
He kind of makesfunny sounds.
He can nearly say "Mama."
And sometimes he'll--
he'll point at a light
and he says "Ly-yy."
"Ly-yy, Mama."
Lt's almost "light,"but not really.
What's in Chicago?
( lamp clatters )
Anna, my wife.
We're separated, actually.
I left for my careerand she stayed for hers.
She's still there, Luke.
Funny thing is, l don't thinkshe'd want to see me...
even now.
You'll be together again.
You will.
( sighs )
I just putfresh batteries in.
- They just keep dying.- Oh my God.
Look. Hey!
- Come here.- Luke: Hey there.
- It's okay. Come here.- Come here. It's all right.
- ( shadows moaning )- Luke: Don't be afraid. Come here.
- Luke: Shit!- Wait! No!
Come back!
- ( groans )- Luke!
- ( groans )- Luke, get up!
( screams )Hit the lights!
Hit the headlights!
Come on, hit the lights!Hit the headlights!
Rosemary:Get out of there!
Paul:James?
Oh no. James!
- James!- * Your good, good thing *
* ls about to come to an end... *
Rosemary:None of them work.
Rosemary:Doesn't work.
This is the only onethat works.
Shit!Come on!
Lt doesn't work.
What are we gonna do?
Luke, they're here.
- ( Luke grunting )- Where are you going?
Where are you going?
Luke, they're here.
They're dimming.
Okay. Yeah.
( chugging )
James?
( creaks )
( voice echoing )Paul.
( grunts )
- Luke: That's better.- Hold this steady.
- All right?- That's good. Give me your lighter.
Luke: Come on. Come on.Give me your lighter.
- Rosemary: Lt's in the bar.- What?
- It's in the bar!- ( groans )
Where are you going?Rosemary.
Luke: Whoa! Hey,what are you doing?
- Rosemary: Stay close.- It's not enough light.
Rosemary:Come on!
( voice echoing )Paul...
Rosemary: We can--we can make it.
It's really close.
James?
Rosemary:Almost there.
Rosemary:This is it!
- James?- Paul.
James.L'm coming.
James?
Rosemary:Here!
Paul!
( grunts )
( Rosemary screams )
James.
( panting )No!
No! No!( grunts )
( soft music playing )
- ( children's voices laughing )- Who's there?
- ( music stops )- ( shadows moaning )
Stay away. Stay away!
Stay away from me!No!
- No.- ( voices whispering )
I exist.
I exist. I exist. I exist.
James...?I exist. I exist.
I exist.James! I exist!
I exist.
( soft music playing )
( panting )
Paul...?
Paul!
Recording:* ...'Cause somebody else will *
* You don't have to love mewhen l want it... *
Hold this.
( shadows shrieking )
Luke:Oh.
How'd you knowthose matches were there?
I used to bum cigarettesoff the duty nurse.
You worked here?
No.
Manny saved my life.
Made mewant to clean up...
made me want to live.
I can't lose him, Luke.
I can't.
( shadows shrieking )
Luke:This torch won't last.
We gotta go, Rosemary.Come on.
There's a storage roomin the back.
There's alcohol
for the needles.
Rubbing alcohol.
For the torch.Fuel, right?
Yeah, let's go.
No, you rest your ankle.
You wait here.L'll go.
( music skipping )
( baby's voice crying )
( crying continues )
Manny?
- Rosemary?- My baby.
My--
No. No.
Rosemary.
Rosemary's voice:I exist.
I exist.
( sputtering )
( shouting )
( voice whispering )James.
James...
( shadows moaning )
James!
Hey.
Where's Paul?
He's gone. He's gone.Rosemary?
Hey.
Hey, we're gonna make it.All right?
Hey, we're gonna make it, all right?But l need your help.
- Okay?- Okay.
Come on,give me more slack.
Luke:There.
Luke:All right.
I gotta go downand prime that thing.
You're gonna have to turnthe ignition on your own, all right?
James:I can't be alone, man!
- Listen, you're not alone.- Don't go, don't go!
- You're gonna leave too.- It's me and you now, buddy. All right?
- Don't go, man.- Hey, listen to me, okay?
We're gonna see morning,l promise.
A storm passing, right?
- That's right.- Right?
That's right, a storm passing.
( generator sputtering )
All right, when l say now,turn the ignition.
Okay.
Now!
( engine stalls )
- Come on!- Now!
( engine sputters )
Come on!
- Now!- ( screams )
( engine sputtering )
( engine roars )
( panting )
( grunts )
Come on!Shit.
( tires squeal )
( exhales )
L've gotta shut the hood.
You gotta keepyour foot on the gas
otherwise we're gonnalose power, yeah?
- Yeah.- Don't take it off.
Okay. Okay.
- You did good back there.- So did you.
- You ready?- Yeah.
Go!
Mama.
James, the gas. Hey.James! Hey!
What are you doing?Hey! Shit!
( engine roars )
- ( horn blares )- James!
James, get back here!
Shit shit shit!
Fuck it.
( tires squeal )
( voices whispering )
( voice whispering )James.
James.
Mom.
Mom, it's me.
- ( shadow screeches )- ( crashes )
Get in the truck!
- I saw my mom.- Get in the fucking truck.
James, no!
James!
( grunting )
James:Mom?
James!James, no!
( engine sputters )
Anna.
( echoes faintly )Anna...
Luke!
( shadows shrieking )
( shadow moaning )
My name is James Leary.
I exist.
I exist!
( fading )I exist.
I exist.
( birds chirping )
( dove coos )
( wings flapping )
( distant crow cawing )
( faint tapping )
That's my bed.
Girl:You don't have to go.
Don't go.
L'm Briana.
L'm James.
It works?
Lt won't go out
as long as there's day.
What's that?
( birds chirping )
Look.
( horse nickers )
( voices whispering )I exist. I exist.
- I exist.- I exist.
( crow cawing )
( piano playing )
* l don't have to beg youto hold me *
* 'Cause somebody else will *
* You don't have to love mewhen l want it *
* Your so-called friendssay you don't need it *
* When all the timethey're trying to get it *
* Look out-- your good thing *
* ls about to come to an end *
* Your real good thing *
* All those nightsl watched the four walls *
* l did not have towatch them all alone *
* When other mensaid they wanted me *
* l didn't have to tell theml was your very own *
* You have all the love l've got *
* Even ice melts to water and gets hot *
* Look out-- your good thing *
* ls about to come to an end *
* Your real good thing *
* ls about to end *
* Getting myself back together *
* ls gonna be a big problem, l know *
* But when the right mansays he wants me *
* You can bet l won't say no *
* 'Cause your real good thing *
* ls about to end *
* Your real-- your good thing *
* Your good thing, baby *
* Your good thing, your good thing *
* ls about to come to an end *
* Yeah yeah yeah *
* Yeah, your good thing *
* Your good thing. *
( instrumental music playing )