Spring, Summer, Autumn, Winter..
And Spring
Spring
Wake up.
- Master!
- Yes, my boy?
Where do you want to go?
I want to pick herbs for medicine.
Then let us go.
Come along.
I'm going to pick herbs now, Master.
Watch out for snakes.
- Wait for me, Master.
- Yes.
I've picked a lot of herbs, Master.
Really? You've picked a lot?
Careful!
Stop! Throw this away, my boy.
Why? It looks the same.
Even though it looks the same,
this is a deadly plant.
The other one can save lives.
It still looks the same.
How can I know?
Look closely. Here at the tip
you can see a white line.
If you ate this plant, you'd die.
You mustn't pick
this sort of plant next time.
- Is this one alright to eat?
- Yes, this one is good.
Master, there is a stone on my back..
Please take it off.
- Does it torment you?
- Yes, Master.
Didn't you also do it to the fish?
Yes, Master.
Didn't you also do it to the frog?
Didn't you also do it to the snake?
Yes, Master.
Stand up!
Walk around!
I can't walk, it's too heavy.
How do you think the fish,
the frog and the snake endured it?
It was wrong to do it.
Go and find all the animals
and release them from the stones.
Then I will release you from yours.
But if any of the animals, the fish,
the frog or the snake is dead,
you will carry the stone in your heart
for the rest of your life.
Summer
You look so very healthy.
This tree is over 300 years old.
You will grow
as healthy as this tree.
Greetings.
Come in!
Will she recover, wise one?
I believe that her soul is suffering.
When she finds peace in her soul,
her body will return to health.
Please take care of her!
Excuse me!
You are not allowed to sit on that.
The master will be angry with you.
Why are you praying all of a sudden?
Would you like to come along?
Gently!
It must prepared with your true heart!
Drink!
It will clear your head.
The boat is floating away!
Stop it!
Have you recovered now?
Yes, I have completely recovered.
Strange.
When I can't see you,
I go insane.
What is wrong with me?
No idea!
Cold! It's cold!
What shall I do?
I did wrong, Master.
Forgive me.
That happens by itself.
It is just nature.
Are you still sick?
No.
Then it was the right medicine.
Now that you have recovered,
you can leave this place.
No, Master! She can't!
Lust awakens the desire to possess.
And that awakens the intent to murder.
Get in!
Autumn
That was tiring, huh?
MAN, 30, FLEES AFTER MURDERING WIFE
You have grown a lot!
Get in!
So? Have you led
a happy life up till now?
Tell me something
interesting about your life.
The world of men has grown
agonizing for you, hasn't it?
Leave alone, Master.
Can you not see I am suffering?
What causes you to suffer?
My only sin was to love.
I wanted nothing except her.
So?
She went with another man.
Ah, that was it.
How can that be?
She said that she'd love only me.
- And then?
- I couldn't bear it any more.
Didn't you know beforehand
how the world of men is?
Sometimes we have to
let go of things we like.
What you like,
others will also like!
But still, how could she do that?
The bitch!
- Is it so unbearable for you?
- Yes!
Master!
Young fool!
Though you can so easily kill,
you yourself cannot be easily killed.
Carve out all of
these characters with the knife.
And while you cut out each one,
drive out the anger from your heart.
Holy one!
We've come to investigate something.
- Drop the knife!
- Otherwise I'll shoot!
What are you doing?
Continue cutting!.
Prajnaparamita Sutra.
It helps restore inner peace.
Please let him finish!
How long will it take?
Until tomorrow morning.
- No connection.
- No?
It's quite a deep valley, isn't it?
What?
They make white paint
from these mussels.
Stand up!
It's time to go!
Detective Choi,
let's go as we are.
Detective Chi,
the boat won't move.
Ah, now it's going.
Winter
And Spring