Seven gone, six returned!
Mother, it looks like
the battle of Jinsha was...
...utterly to our disadvantage
According to this prediction...
we might lose a brother
Yes
But it's worthwhile to sacrifice one son
...for the sake of Sung Dynasty
As for my seven sons
I wonder which one will be a martyr
The queen's father is here
Daughter, I've bad news.
Your brother...
Your highness
Arise
Thank you, my queen
What is it, father?
Your brother Pan Bao
...was beaten to death in a tournament
My brother's dead? Who killed him?
Yang Ye's seventh son, Yang Si
Yang Si? Father, I must...
My queen
Leave now
Yes, my lady
I'll plead with the emperor
to condemn him
No, that's not the way to do it
Yang Ye has a secured position
in the court
We must get rid of the Yang family
What's your suggestion, father?
We'll kill them all at the Jinsha battle
Kill
Forge ahead
Charge
Impressive spear-wielding
of the Yang family
It has lived up to its reputation
Today is your doom day
Traitor
5th brother...
6th brother...
Eldest brother
Kill
Tartars
3rd brother
Let's go
Kill
3rd brother
Wait, catch him alive
Bring him back
2nd brother
Yang Ye
Pan Mei
Arrows
7th son
Traitor!
Shoot
Loyalty... kill
Charge
7th brother, father...
Father, we're a family of loyalty
Why would the emperor
listen to the traitors
...and sent us into the trap?
This is the end for us
Traitor, Tartars
Come out, all of you...
I've found them...
6th brother...
Stop it
No, not them
Kill
6th brother...
Mother...
Good day, mother
Don't worry too much, mother
Father and our seven brothers will
...certainly win the Jinsha battle
That's right, mother
With our spear-wielding second to none
Stop it, 9th sister
The Tartars
...would be terror-stricken
But there's no news up to now
Pan Mei's sudden plea to the emperor
and he assigned our family to the north
There must be something going on
The prediction says
seven gone, six returned
Could there be another interpretation?
- 6th brother
- Son
Come out here, Tartars
They've come back from a victory
Son, where's your father?
Pan Mei...
Where are your brothers?
Traitor
Son, where're your brothers?
Tell us
Go on
Sixth brother
What are you doing?
Sixth son...
Focus, my child
Tell me
what happened?
Right, tell our mother
Why are you here alone?
I'm home?
Yes, you're home
How many Tartars have you killed,
brother?
Tell me
Kill
How many? Not one
Jinsha Battle was a trap
Pan Mei... you wanted to kill us all
My eldest brother was stabbed to death
Second brother got cut into half
Third brother died even more tragically
He was trampled to death
by men and horses
Fourth brother was captured
Fifth brother is missing
And my baby brother was killed by arrows
Mother
What about your father?
Killed at Liling Tomb. Father...
Yang Ye
Why are you kneeling? I will too
Pan Mei
Sixth son...
Seven gone, six returned!
The battle of Jinsha
only my sixth son returns; it's fate
Prince, what can I do for you?
Pan Mei, according to our plan
We've wiped out the Yangs at Jinsha
Why haven't you kept your promise...
of withdrawing the Sung army
at the border?
So that my Liao troops
can march straight in?
You have my absolute loyalty
But I've one concern
Yangs' fifth and sixth sons
are still alive
Men
Prince
Our plan was perfect
Our weapons were made to counter
the Yang spears
How could they manage to escape?
You should give them a second chance
...to make it up
We must deal with this soon
If they make a comeback...
it will affect our invasive strategy
We'll try to intercept them
from different directions
We've got to uproot the Yangs
Tartar
You robber
Are you a deserter from the Yang family?
No, I'm not a deserter
No? What are you doing here?
What are you doing here?
None of your business. Who are you?
Who am I? I live here
I'm a hunter
Sorry about it
Warrior, I mistook you for the enemy
So you're fighting the Tartars
That's right, after the battle of Jinsha
We got ambushed
No wonder you're hiding here
No, I'm not afraid to die
If not...
then what are you doing here?
The Queen's father
set up a trap to kill us
Pan Mei used to be in the same camp
as Yang Ye
Yes, we'd never have thought that
...he would try to kill us all at Jinsha
Yang warrior, let me tell you
I was a general working for Pan Mei
I know him well
He has always been jealous of your family
...for the outstanding service
to the country
He's afraid that
his status will be threatened
Then he worked with the Tartars
to ruin your family
Pan Mei, you traitor!
I'll risk my life to testify against him
I want him torn to pieces
You won't have the chance to do that now
Right
He and the Tartars are on my trail
He wants to kill you all
Yes
My brothers are dead
My father Yang Ye died at the Liling Tomb
I'm the only survivor
General Yang
Yes, I hope you can give me a hand
...and testify against Pan Mei
There's no use, General Yang
Pan Mei is now in power
The Emperor won't listen to me
He will, after the disaster at Jinsha
I witnessed that
You're the only survivor
But what proof have you got?
Our family is loyal to the emperor,
he'll trust me
You're over confident, General Yang
Say even if Pan Mei
doesn't capture you...
he will surely accuse you
He'll accuse you of being a traitor
and a deserter
You have a point
The emperor has issued out decree
stating that...
I'm a traitor
If the emperor says so
What's the point of going back?
I can’t just sit here
and see my country...
Your country doesn't appreciate
your loyalty
Then to avenge for my family...
You must, but this isn't the time yet
Wait for your time
Learn from me. Forget about it for now
I can't
Surround it
Go through the tunnel
I must fight my way out
He ran into the tunnel...
Where's Yang's fifth son?
Don't know
Search
Yes
Give him up if you want to live
He's gone
Go
After him
Sixth brother
Leave him alone
Let him have his peace
...and hope that he'll recover soon
Knock
Yes
Open up, open...
Who is it?
Who dares to knock so rudely?
Who?
An imperial edict
Who's the envoy?
General Pan Mei, the Queen's father
Pan Mei
Traitor
Sixth brother
Pull him inside, hurry
I'll kill you
I'll kill Pan Mei
Open the door
Search
Yes
How dare you?
General Pan
Our family is in mourning!
How could you disturb us now?
I'm here to arrest the traitors
Who?
I've led the Yang family troops to Jinsha
and discovered that
your family haven't fought
...their best.
They're in conspiracy with Tartars
The emperor has ordered for their arrests
Ordered for the arrests?
Ours is a family of patriots.
The Emperor...
has bestowed on us
"Family of Loyalty" and has...
given me this dragon-head staff
to rid the wicked
Mrs. Yang, you...
General Pan, just do your job
My husband and my seven sons
were ambushed
...in Jinsha battle. They're all dead!
You should have checked first as to...
who is it that
you are trying to arrest here!
This is our family's hall of fame
We take no intrusion
According to my sources,
two are still at large
Who?
Your fifth and sixth sons
If they're still alive
and upon their return home...
I'll personally escort them to the court
Please let the emperor know that
I will be just. See the guest out
Yes
Please, General Pan
Fine, Mrs. Yang. Goodbye
Mother
My fifth son, where could you be now?
Kill
Warrior, you laid down your life for me
I understand you are hoping
I'll stay alive
So that I can avenge for our country
You are right
The country won't appreciate my loyalty.
I'd rather live as a hermit
and wait for the right time
Kill
Master... please don't...
Sixth son...
You Tartars
Sixth brother
Back off, you both
Let him vent his anger
Kill
Sixth brother
You...
I'm devoting myself to Buddha
You are...
I'll shave my head to become a monk
Our temple is in the middle of nowhere
You came a long way to our temple
What could we do for you?
Master, I've decided to become a monk
I am ready for it
Amitabha Buddha
You have anger and sadness in your eyes
I think this is an impulsive decision
Please wait, master
Why don't you ask who I am?
Amitabha Buddha
I'm a monk.
Worldly affairs don't concern me
There's no need to ask
Mister
I'm Yang fifth, an accused traitor
Please don't lie before the Buddha
Master, I'm indeed Yang fifth
No, you're not
I am
A bladeless spear?
This can't be the Yang's spear
Please don't again falsely claim
to be a Yang General
I truly am Yang fifth
Yang fifth?
Mr. Yang, please forgive my rudeness
Master
I can't go home
and I can't avenge my country
I broke the blade,
and decided to become a monk
You have your heart
set in the worldly matters
You can't proceed with
the tonsure ceremony
Master
I want to shave my head
Please don't stop me
Master
I want to be a monk
Promise me you'll shave my head
Don't be rude
Our temple is a place of sanctuary
You should be on the battlefield
A victor can live a glorious life
But what if he loses his battle?
The dead is unkind, the living disloyal
Amitabha Buddha
We are free
from the mundane world's matters
I hope to start afresh here
You have hatred; and are very depressed
Perhaps you shouldn't be here
You're too barbaric
Very impressive
I want my head shaved
The hair is on HIS head
If he doesn't want them,
no one could stop him
Yes, abbot
Thank you, abbot
Buddha of immeasurable Life
Amitabha Buddha
Revered abbot, you lied
Why don't you shave my head?
If you don't...
Then I'll burn down your temple
5th brother
Mother, the sixth brother
is still deranged
He's in no state
to testify against Pan Mei
Under the circumstances...
Our family name is being smeared
9th sister
6th brother, pull yourself together
We must testify against Pan Mei
Let's go
6th brother, we're in mourning now
We can't go to meet the emperor
6th son
I must go
Kill...
General Yang, you're awake?
Is this the Qingliang Temple?
Yes, this is the backyard
Then I've become a monk
I've become a monk!
General Yang, please stay put
You haven't eaten in days
I've been in a coma for that long?
Bring in some food
General Yang,
the abbot has ordered that...
after you get better,
you've to leave the temple
Tell your abbot
I'm now a monk
And I ain't gonna leave this place
Got it?
No wonder the abbot says...
What?
He said you can't be a monk
I can't, huh?
What are you doing here?
Agreed, I don't have
a peaceful mind needed for...
chanting scriptures,
but I could be a guard here
and practice with the others?
This exercise room is a place
for the monks
You have no Buddha in your heart
How could you practice with us?
Don't worry
Although I'm not in peace
But I'm an experienced soldier
I'm not afraid of the wolves
Yang fifth
When you are hitting these wolves
...you've got to attack their limbs
So that the others can smell the blood
And know about the danger
Then they wouldn't dare to come back
You're wrong
Even the wolves
are trespassing our garden
But as monks we mustn't kill
We would only de-fang them
No matter how fierce the wolves are...
without their teeth they are nothing
And we'd have taught them a lesson
Then they wouldn't dare to come back
Here we practice the poles
Hence we're skilled to de-fang them
Hence the name:
The "Club to de-fang the wolves"
That's wrong
If you knock off their teeth
...and not kill them;
They'd gather their strength
after they recover
...return to strike again
How many monks
...can face them then?
I can see that you're still blood thirsty
Master, I simply
wish to be a monk guarding the temple
I don't aspire to be a student like you
Since you've taken me in
Why don't you let me practice with you?
Are you challenging me?
You're right
But he has got his point
All he has in mind is for...
the best interest of the temple
With the way he thinks...
He has already broken our rule of
'no killing'
Masters, I'm reckless because
...I'm unacquainted with the rules
Please allow me to learn from scratch
Your Yang's Spears style
Every move is fatal
You must first cultivate your mind...
before you practice in the exercise room
Yang fifth
Yes master
I assure you that
I'll be as calm as still waters
You've turned
the Yang's Spear-wielding into...
poles style. You've mastered it very well
Master, then is this the time...
for me to join the others
in the exercise room?
No matter what
Our temple is not a place for you
What you're saying is...
Leave this temple soon
No, I've given up everything
...to become a monk
I'll never leave the temple
What happened?
Master Zhihong has left the mountain
Who's trespassing?
Amitabha Buddha
What are you doing here, master?
To perform rites for the dead
of the Yang family
Religious rites?
You're here all alone, is it?
Yes, it's just me
Where's your robe?
I've to travel far. It's not convenient
Where are you from?
From the borders
Catch him
Yes
Let him in
The general has ordered to let him in
Yes
Master, you can't go in...
What's going on?
Master
Miss 8th, the monk is here
to collect alms
...and now he wants food.
He has pushed his way in
Pushed his way in?
Yes
He wants vegetarian dishes?
If it's food that you seek...
you should have waited outside
Amitabha Buddha...
I want vegetarian dishes
...cooked by Mrs. Yang
You're way out of line
If you're not a member of the family
...you can't step inside. Get out
Amitabha Buddha
Who are you?
Miss 8th, I am...
Did Pan Mei send you?
Stop it, 8th daughter
Mother, the monk is rude
He barged in...
and asks for vegetarian dish
cooked by you
Simply outrageous!
9th daughter
Amitabha Buddha
Miss 8th, please invite the master in
Mother, he is sent by Pan Mei
Don't be rude. Invite the master in
Yes mother
Please, master
Mrs. Yang
I came here to solicit alms
and to get some vegetarian food
How would I know General Pan Mei?
6th Brother
Young master
Sorry about my son
You aren't hurt, are you?
Mrs. Yang
I didn't mean to upset anyone here
Master, since the battle of Jinsha...
my son has been acting sort of demented
Amitabha Buddha!
6th son
Mrs. Yang, your son is valiant
What a shame
Had it not been for the shock...
he'd be as good as Yang fifth
Fifth son
Master
6th Brother
How come you mentioned my 5th brother?
Where is he? Tell us
Stop it
Master Yang
A cue can enlighten the one concerned
Mrs. Yang, I must leave now
Master
6th brother
Stop it
Master, as for my vegetarian dish
Where shall I send it to?
Qingliang Temple at Wutai Mountain
Master
Stop it, 6th brother
So 5th son
at Mount Wutai's Qingliang Temple
Why hasn't he come back?
I'll go look for him
You haven't yet recovered
Pan Mei has spies everywhere
God forbid if something happens to you...
we won't be able to testify...
in front of the court against him
Let me go, mother
I have a plan
The monk is here. Get ready
Please, I got ambushed
Help me
Tartars have infiltrated the town
You Tartars
What were you doing
at the Yang residence?
Tell me
Where's Yang fifth?
Tartars
Tell me if you want to live
I don't know who's Yang fifth
Come on, tell me
It's not safe here, take him back
Yes
Where could Yang fifth be?
Tell me
You are all useless
You couldn't handle one monk
When will we take over
the Sung territory?
Fine, I'll raid the Yang's residence
Let's see what Mrs. Yang
has got up her sleeves
Yang Fifth might be home
Calm down, your highness
It's just a matter of time...
before you reign over the Sung territory
If you raid
the Yang's residence hastily...
that will only gather
the officials' strength
That won't do us any good
Then what's your suggestion, Pan Mei?
Since the monk visited the Yangs
They'd have movements tonight
And we'll follow whoever leaves the house
Then we can catch all the fishes
8th daughter, 9th daughter
Pan Mei has been trying to hurt us
all these years
We must find your fifth brother
no matter what
...so that we could absolve
our reputation
Mother, I'm a good fighter
Let me go
Don't interrupt,
mother will tell us what to do
9th daughter, you are too impulsive
It's a long way to Wutai Mountain
Pan Mei has spies everywhere
You'll only wreck this
Wang
Here, madam
Get everything ready, 8th miss will leave
Yes, madam
9th daughter,
you're responsible for 6th brother
He can't step out of this house
Yes, mother
Mother, 5th brother is headstrong
I'm afraid that...
Take this jade pendant off my staff
He wouldn't dare forget his dear ones,
I guess
Wait
It stinks!
Where are you heading to at this hour?
We're going to dump the leftovers
Leftovers?
If we don't dump these
...the whole residence will stink
Put it down
We had the order not to give them
a hard time
Yes
Go
Check for people
No, over here
Put it down
Miss
Get the horse
A young kid
Follow him
You can't go in
I've already
observed the religious disciplines
I want to see the master tonight
Please, Brother Fifth
Wait for a few more days
A few more days
A few more days?
Yes
Brothers
Why aren't you practicing the poles?
Why are you meditating here?
What are you doing?
Where's the master?
Brother Fifth
The master's dead
Killed by the wolves?
Tell me
Was he killed by the wolves?
Abbot, how did he die?
Amitabha Buddha
Brother Zhihong knew that...
you're not focused on being a monk
He traveled to your home
My home? He...
He did it to help you
Hoping you could rebuild
your family's reputation
Such good intention! So righteous!
He got killed on the road
Pan Mei the traitor
Yang Fifth
Go and fulfill
Master Zhihong's dying wish
Abbot, I'm responsible
He died because of me
I'll fulfill his last wish
Good
But do you think you're up to it?
With all the practice that
I've been doing...
...I think I can handle it
Well done
Thank you, abbot
Have a good day
We have a guest
Are you staying in our inn, sir?
You rat, how dare you...
rob me in broad daylight?
Mister
The jade pendant on your waist
What about it?
It is...
Where did you get it?
None of your business
You stole it
Nonsense
Then where did you get it?
It is...
Who are you? Tell me
The golden knife
Yang's golden knife
You are...
Where did you get this from?
Don't know
Speak up
Jinsha Beach
You traitor
Who are you?
I'm the 8th child of the family
Miss 8th
I was seriously injured
defending this knife
Fortunately the inn owner
...took me in
Thank you, old sir
Don't mention it
The Yangs are a family of martyrs
All the citizens respect and admire them
Miss Yang, in this time of chaos
You're here on your own
Are you on a mission?
I'm here to look for my 5th brother
He's still alive?
Yes
But I haven't seen him anywhere around
A monk from Wutai mountain visited us
Going by his hint,
brother could be at the mountain
Is General Yang a monk now?
That's possible
After the heavy blow to our family...
my brother could've been
fed up of earthly life
That's why my mother gave me this pendant
Hoping to order him home
to testify against Pan Mei
So that we could clear our reputation
Great, let's head to Wutai mountain
A large party is coming this way
Call everyone out from the inn
Pan Mei the traitor
We are outnumbered
If we fight our way out
We can never make it to the mountain
Miss Yang, don't act on an impulse
We've got to lay low for now
Bring the lady to hide in the kitchen
I'll think of a plan by tonight
Yes
What is it, sir?
Are you harboring
the court's prisoner Yang 5th?
Yang Fifth? No
No?
That's right
We tracked a girl
from the Yang's residence
...all the way here
You must be connected to her
No way, I have never met her
No problem
Burn the inn down
Yes
Wait, your highness
Yang Fifth might not be here
But his 8th sister must be around
If we burn this place down...
then we won't be able to catch her
They'll probably meet up here
Your highness, General Pan has a point
Lock this place up, no one can leave
Good idea
Proprietor, this applies to you
and your staff
No one can leave
Yes
Where are you going?
Some refreshments for the boss
Come on, Xiaosan, where's my food?
Snacking at this hour?
Yes, for the boss
Sirs
I have a snack at this hour every night
Let him go
Thank you
Thank you, sirs
Hurry, Xiaosan
What are you doing?
Tying up the coffin
At this hour?
Yes, sir
We must deliver the coffin
for burial before dawn
Otherwise it might turn into a vampire
Turns into a vampire?
Yes
Don't try to trick me
Take it away...
Yes
Wait
Open it
I can't...
Why not? Just do it
I can't. The corpse stinks
Open it
You believe me now? Close it
What's this?
A mortuary object
The golden knife?
The Yangs!
Yang 8th, you aren't going anywhere
Xiaosi
Yang 8th,
where do you think you're going?
Traitor, you're in no position
to talk to me
Were you looking for Yang Fifth?
Just tell me everything
Then I'll let you live
Otherwise I'll make sure
you die a terrible death
Go
Stop it
There's no need to run after him
General Pan, he...
Your highness, let him go
Yang Fifth will show up before dawn
Men
Yes
Lock her up
Yang Fifth
Hurry... what's going on?
Someone's lying there
Bleeding badly
What? Bleeding badly
Mister
Yang Fifth
Yang Fifth...
What is it?
Abbot, this man
He works at the inn
at the bottom of the hill
He's looking for Yang Fifth
Fifth...
Mister, I'm Yang Fifth
We've never met before
The Dragon Head Staff?
Miss Yang
My 8th sister
She...
She got ambushed in the inn
Fifth...
Amitabha Buddha
I must go to her, abbot
My sister is a woman, but she's brave
The worldly matters
have nothing to do with me
The Buddha has a weapon
to fight the evils
Then it's only normal that
I do what's right
Remember what you promised us
I look at the Buddha,
and I think of my family
You can't break the rules
in front of Buddha
Abbot
I treat everyone equally
I'm sorry about this
Very good
What are you doing here
with so many poles?
Are you here to stay
or asking for directions?
Neither. I'm here to deliver the poles
What poles?
The poles of righteousness
You can break one,
but you can't break them all
Where are you from?
Wutai Mountain
You must be connected to the Yangs
You barbarians
Catch him
Go
Yang Fifth, you'll die as a monk
I fear no death
Where's my sister?
She's in the coffin below
8th sister
Pan Mei, you'll pay for everything
Yang Fifth, you won't get away today
Come on
8th sister
8th sister, you...
5th brother
5th brother, come home
Sister
Leave me. Go, quick
No
8th sister
5th brother
Abbot
Kill
Thank you
You broke the rule, abbot
I didn't, we're here
to chase away the wolves
You've got your revenge
Let's beat the wolves
Yes
Traitor
You traitor
Amitabha Buddha
8th sister
5th brother
Take his body with you back to the court
5th brother,
please don't go back to the temple
He won't return
5th brother...
8th sister, the world is my home
5th brother