- Yes, sir.
- l got a little grease in this lining.
lt'll take a half-hour to check it.
You want me to fill her up, too?
- You better check the oil, too.
- Yes, sir.
- You boys just passing through?
- Yeah.
Pittsburgh? Coming in or going out?
- Going in, to a sales convention tomorrow.
- What do you guys sell?
We sell drug supplies.
He is going to get an award.
He sold $17,000 worth last month.
Fastest boy in the territory.
Yeah. Fastest and the ''bestest.''
- Another round, one for him and yourself.
- Thanks.
Sure is a hot day for driving.
Late afternoon is better.
You have plenty of time.
You can make Pittsburgh
in two or three hours.
He's right.
What do you say, Charlie?
Play a little pool? Wait out the heat?
lt'll cost you money. Always does.
Come on, stop stalling.
Grab yourself a cue.
Good thing he can afford it.
Keep them coming. J.T.S. Brown.
You miss again, you lose again.
What is the kid in hock for so far?
About $60, $70.
Next game, $10.
Nice looking boy, clean-cut.
lt's too bad he can't hold his liquor.
l made it, boy! l finally made it!
Come on, pay up, pay up, sucker!
You ought to shoot craps with that luck!
- What do you mean, luck?
- You know what l mean.
You couldn't make that shot again
in a million years.
l couldn't? Okay, set them up
the way they were before.
- Why?
- Set them up the way they were before.
l'll bet you $20 that l make that shot
the same way again.
Nobody can make that shot,
not even a lucky lush.
How is that?
- ls that the way they were before?
- Yeah, that's it.
Come on, put it up.
Set them up again.
Come on, set them up again.
You're drunk, boy.
l'm not betting you anymore.
What do you mean?
Let's leave. We have to be
at that convention in the morning.
Up the flagpole with the convention!
Come on, l got my money on the table.
- l don't want it.
- l'll try you.
Don't be a chump. Don't bet
any more money on that damn fool shot!
You figure l'm a little drunk,
l'm loaded on hemp...
...and you just want in real friendly
while the money's still floating?
Okay.
Go ahead. Set them up.
You want some easy money? Here's $105.
One week's commission.
You want to take the whole thing?
Then you get a crack at your easy money.
- l'll take a piece of that action.
- Me, too.
- No, l want him!
- l'll take it out of the till.
l'll meet you in the car, chump!
'Morning, Henry.
Quiet.
Yeah, like a church.
The Church of the Good Hustler.
lt looks like a morgue to me. Those tables
are the slabs they lay the stiffs on.
l'll be alive when l get out.
- Any table?
- Any table.
No bar?
No bar, no pinball machines,
no bowling alleys, just pool. Nothing else.
This is Ames, mister.
''This is Ames, mister.''
Nice, clean pocket-drop.
How much am l going to win tonight?
$10,000.
l'm going to win $10,000 in one night.
Who's going to beat me?
Come on, Charlie.
Okay, nobody can beat you.
$10,000!
What other poolroom is there
where a guy can win $10,000 in one night?
l can remember hustling an old man
for a dime a game.
- We got company.
- Are you looking for action?
- Maybe. Want to play?
- No, hell, no.
- Are you Eddie Felson?
- Who's he?
- What's your game? What do you shoot?
- You name it, we shoot it.
Friend, l'm not trying to hustle.
l never hustle people that bring
in leather satchels. Don't hustle me.
l'm Eddie Felson. l shoot straight pool.
Got any straight pool shooters here?
- What straight pool game do you like?
- The expensive kind.
You came to play pool
with Minnesota Fats?
That's right.
- Want some free advice?
- How much will it cost?
Who are you, his manager,
friend, his stooge?
He's my partner.
- Well-heeled partner?
- We got enough.
Take the boy home. Fats doesn't need
your money. You can't beat him.
No one's beaten him in 15 years.
He's the best in the country.
You got that wrong, mister. l am.
Okay, l told you about Minnesota Fats.
You just go ahead and play him, friend.
Tell me where l can find him, friend.
He comes in this poolroom every night
at 8:00 on the nose.
Stay here, he'll find you.
- You shoot a good stick.
- Thank you.
- Do you shoot straight pool, mister?
- Now and then, you know how it is.
You're Minnesota Fats, aren't you?
They say you're the best in the country,
where l come from.
ls that a fact?
They say that old Fats
shoots the eyes off them balls.
- Where are you from?
- California. Oakland.
California. ls your name Felson?
Eddie Felson?
That's right.
l hear you've been looking for me.
Yeah, that's right, too.
Big John,
do you think this boy is a hustler?
Do you like to gamble?
Gamble money on pool games?
Let's shoot a game of straight pool.
$100?
You shoot bigtime pool.
Everyone says you shoot bigtime pool.
Let's make it $200 a game.
Now l know why they call you
''Fast Eddie.'' You talk my kind of talk.
Sausage, rack them up!
- How do you feel?
- Fast and loose, man.
ln the gut, l mean?
Tight but good.
Willie, hang on to that.
You break.
l didn't leave you much.
You left enough.
Six in the corner.
Fifteen, in the corner.
Ace, in the side.
Eight.
Ten.
Eleven.
He is great! That old fat man.
Look how he moves. Like a dancer!
Twelve, cross-eyed.
And those fingers, them chubby fingers...
...and that stroke...
- ...like he's playing a violin.
- Five ball.
Eight ball.
Four long.
Cross corner.
Nice shot.
Safe.
Seven ball in the corner.
Six in the corner.
One twenty-five, game.
Thirteen.
Five.
Ten.
Game!
Two in the corner.
Thirteen.
One twenty-five, game.
Ace in the corner.
Three ball.
Quit. He's too good.
l'm going to take him!
Your shot.
You miss?
You don't leave much when you miss,
do you?
That's what the game's all about.
Two ball, side pocket.
Very good shot.
l have a hunch, Fat Man,
it's me from here on in.
One ball, corner pocket.
Did that ever happen to you?
Suddenly you feel like you can't miss?
l've dreamed about this game,
Fat Man, every night on the road.
Five ball.
This is my table, man, l own it!
Fifteen ball.
Seven ball.
Four ball.
Game!
Eleven ball.
Rack them!
Ten ball in the corner.
One ball in the corner pocket.
Game!
Pay the man again, Fats.
- How much are we ahead?
- Approximately $1,000.
Fats, let's shoot for $1,000 a game.
Get me some White Tavern whiskey,
a glass and some ice.
Preacher, get me some bourbon.
J.T.S. Brown, no ice, no glass.
Get it at Johnny's.
You got a bet.
Cash me in.
Two in the corner.
Seven.
Ace in the corner.
Two ball, side pocket.
One twenty-five, game.
Ten ball.
Will you cut that sunshine out?
Hey, mister.
- The name's Gordon, Bert Gordon.
- Mister!
You've been sitting in that spot for hours.
Would you move? lt bothers me.
Five ball.
That's game.
- How much we got?
- We have $1 1,400 cash, in my pocket.
Preacher, get me some breakfast.
An egg sandwich and coffee.
You want something, Charlie?
Wait. You're coming with me to eat
at the hotel. The pool game is over.
No, it isn't, Charlie.
The game is over when Fats says so.
You wanted $10,000, you got it.
- Get with it, will you, Charlie?
- Get with what?
You can't see it, can you, Charlie?
You never have. l came after him.
And l'm going to get him.
l'm going with him all the way.
The game is not over until Fats says so.
ls it over, Fats?
l'll beat him, mister. l beat him all night
and l'll beat him all day.
l'm the best you've ever seen, Fats.
Even if you beat me l'm still the best.
Stay with this kid. He's a loser.
What did he say?
Twenty-five hours. For twenty-five hours
you've been playing straight.
- Get me a drink, will you?
- You don't need a drink.
Shut up!
Just get me a drink!
$18,000, Eddie! We're ahead $18,000!
l thought this game was over
when Fats said it was.
No. lt's over now.
Fast Eddie, let's play some pool.
Let's go, Eddie.
You look beautiful, Fats.
Just like a baby, all pink and powdered up.
What are you trying to do, Eddie?
You beat him bad. Want to kill yourself?
- Are you chicken, Charlie?
- Maybe that's it. l'm chicken.
Go home. Just leave me the money.
Go to hell!
Give me that money!
Come on now. Give it to me. lt is mine!
Here. Be a damn fool!
You really look beautiful, Fats.
l'll break.
Nine ball.
Fifteen.
One twenty-five.
Wake up, Eddie.
We lose again.
ls this all we have left?
lf that's all you got, that's all we got left.
Willie, give me the stake money.
l have about $200 here.
The game is over, Eddie.
Fats, l got about $200 here.
You can't run out on me.
Watch me.
Fats, come on.
l'm sorry, Charlie.
Give me a towel, will you?
Are you sure?
Can l get you something?
Later.
A long wait for a bus?
Yes.
How long have you been waiting?
What?
Since 4:00.
Just a cup of black coffee, please.
Ma'am, wait a minute.
Would you like another cup?
All right. Thanks.
What time does the bus leave?
What bus?
Your bus.
8:00.
That wouldn't give us much time.
You're right.
Hello and goodbye.
Have a nice trip.
Thanks. l will.
Give it to me.
- How much do l owe you?
- lt was paid for by the lady.
- Give me some bourbon, J.T.S. Brown.
- Sure.
- Want a chaser?
- No.
Did you have a nice trip?
Fair.
May l sit down?
Why not?
We already know each other's secrets.
Thanks for the breakfast.
Two ships that pass in the night
should always buy each other breakfast.
Can l buy you another drink?
Another one for me and the lady.
You look different...
...more relaxed.
lt's the lights and the Scotch.
How come you didn't catch your bus?
l wasn't waiting for a bus.
Then why go to the station?
For the same reason you went.
At that hour, you haven't got much choice.
Besides, l only live three blocks from there.
Where do you live?
Around.
l know where you live.
ln a locker in a bus station.
What's it like living in a locker?
Cramped.
Do you always drink like this
so early in the morning?
Do you always ask so many questions?
Not always.
Sometimes l wake up and l can't sleep,
not without a drink.
The bars don't open until 8:00.
Mac, over there, has faith in me.
When l'm broke he trusts me.
Don't you trust me, Mac?
Check.
When l'm not broke,
l usually have a bottle in my room...
...in which case l sleep very well indeed.
You talk kind of funny, but l like it.
l used to be an actress.
What do you do now?
l'm a college girl, two days a week.
On Tuesdays and Thursdays l go to college.
You don't look like a college girl.
l'm the emancipated type,
real emancipated.
l didn't mean that. Whatever that means.
l mean you just don't look young enough.
l'm not.
Then why go to college?
Got nothing else to do
on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
What do you do on the other days?
l drink.
No more.
l'm getting sleepy.
Thank you very much, Mr....
Eddie, the name is Eddie.
The name should be Eddie.
What should my name be?
l don't know, whatever you like it to be.
l like it to be what it is, Sarah.
That's a Biblical name.
Do you want to know its meaning?
l could always get us a bottle.
No.
A fifth of Scotch.
What do you want me to do,
step out in the alley?
No.
l'll take you home.
All right.
lt's all right. l'm not drunk, l'm lame.
Why me?
Please! You're too hungry.
Take it. lt's yours.
The room is $1 .50 a night,
or $7 by the week.
- By the night.
- ln advance.
A bottle of beer.
Hey, mister, is it okay if l grab a cue?
- You're Eddie Felson!
- Who is he?
l saw you play at Ames the other night.
l'll play you a game
and keep one hand in my pocket.
Man, you're way out of our league.
- What are you stuck for?
- A three. That's enough for me.
Thanks.
Can l buy you fellows a drink?
You know, you shoot good,
but you also shoot lucky.
Yeah, l shoot lucky.
- Why did you do that?
- l wanted to see what kind of day it is.
A day like any other.
- People come. People go.
- Give me a drag.
- What time is it?
- 1 1 :00.
l'll be back later.
Why?
Come here.
You need a shave.
You mustn't go looking like that.
There's a razor and shaving cream in
the bathroom, compliments of the house.
Why did you say that, Sarah?
- How do you know my name was Sarah?
- You told me.
l lie. When l'm drunk l lie.
So what's your name today?
lt's Sarah.
Eddie...
...l've got troubles
and l think maybe you've got troubles.
Maybe we should leave each other alone.
My things are at the hotel.
l'll bring them over later.
l'm not sure.
l don't know.
What do you want to know, and why?
Thank you.
- Where have you been all day?
- At school. lt's Thursday.
Oh, l forgot.
You were asleep when l left.
l didn't want to wake you.
Did you go out?
l went out for a couple of hours.
A present.
You know,
l've been living here for almost three years.
Now, in three days,
it seems like l know everybody.
When l pass people on the street...
...l want to stop them and say,
''Listen, l've got a fellow! ''
Thanks.
Eddie, where do you go when you go out?
Museums, art galleries, concerts.
l believe you
when you say you go to school.
- Do you want to go with me?
- Are you kidding?
See that book?
l began it when l first got here,
l haven't finished the first chapter.
Did you read all those books?
Got it all in your head?
When l'm sober. They get a little mixed up
when l'm drunk. Usually they're mixed up.
Stop talking about yourself
like you're a lush. l don't like it.
You should go to a clinic,
and get some treatment.
l'm getting treatment right here.
l'm hungry.
Take your choice.
l got enough so we won't have to leave
the house till Tuesday.
What did all this stuff cost you?
- When you got money, you'll pay.
- l want to know, to keep the score.
The bills are right here.
You didn't say what you wanted.
- Don't you ever cook anything?
- Eggs. How do you like them?
Raw.
l cut my finger.
- l got something in my bag.
- lt's not bad.
Eddie, what's in that case?
- Haven't you opened it?
- No. Why should l? lt's yours.
lt's a machine gun.
A guy told me, in the big city
l'd need a machine gun. So l bought one.
Where did you get the money
to pay for all this?
l mean liquor and the groceries
and the rent.
From a rich old man
who used to be my lover.
Hello, Eddie.
Hello, Charlie.
Come on in.
- That's my girl.
- Hello, Eddie's girl.
l looked all over for you.
- How did you find me?
- l asked around.
- Do you want me to go?
- No. Stick around.
- Can we get you a drink?
- l don't want to be no bother.
Don't play it small.
lt don't look good on you.
- How do you want me to play? l'm broke.
- So am l.
Sit down.
Would you get us a couple of drinks?
You walked out on me. No goodbye,
no nothing. Like a thief in the dark.
We were partners, more than partners.
He was like a....
- A son.
- Yes, like a son.
l've known him since he was 16.
The first time l saw him in Oakland, l said:
''This is a talented boy.
This is a smart boy.''
Talk to me.
l want you to come back
on the road with me.
l have no stomach
for that kind of life anymore.
What is your life like here? Playing the
small rooms, winning a few bucks a day.
l'll connect. l'll get your money back.
Do you intend to play Fats again at Ames?
ls that what's on your mind?
Never been out of it.
l'm going to beat that fat man...
...with that curly hair and
those diamond rings and that carnation.
This boy is crazy! They wiped the floor
with him and he wants to go back.
- What for? Another beating?
- You'll get your money back!
He thinks l care about the money.
l care about you.
Do you care about me, Eddie?
We were together a long time,
night and day.
So how do you say goodbye?
You give me the car and $100.
Do you think l care about the dough
or the car? l care about you.
This boy is the greatest pool hustler
you ever saw.
A high-class con man.
He can charm anybody into anything.
Did he tell you how well we did
on the road? We had everything.
We ate well, we slept late...
...we had money to burn.
Whiskey, dames.... Excuse me.
l tell you what, take her along.
And if you don't want to start right away,
we won't start right away.
We'll drive to Miami.
Get it all out of your system.
Have a few laughs, a few weeks in the sun.
- With what?
- Don't worry, l'll raise the money.
- Yeah? Where?
- What's the difference? l'll raise it.
Could l have another drink?
Did you hold out on me, Charlie?
How much?
My 25%. Approximately $1,500.
You crumb! With that much
l could have beat him! That's all l needed.
Give me the money!
- What for, to play Fats again?
- Yes, l'll play Fats again!
lf you want to come back on the road,
the money is yours...
...but not if you want to give it to Fats.
What do you say?
You still don't see, do you, Charlie?
You're nothing but a small-time Charlie.
You would love to keep me hustling,
wouldn't you?
ln a couple more years,
with me playing in those little towns...
...you might be able to buy a poolroom
in Oakland...
...six tables and a handbook on the side.
ls that when you say goodbye to me?
- ls that what you think?
- Yeah. That's what l think.
All right, that's what l want...
...a poolroom and a little handbook
on the side.
l'm getting old.
Lay down and die by yourself.
Don't take me with you.
- Just like that.
- Yes, just like that!
Thanks for the drink, Eddie's girl.
Give me another drink.
Boy.
Everybody wants a piece of me!
Won't you have one?
What did he have to come back here for,
anyway?
Come here.
- Are you going out?
- For a little while.
Are you okay?
What are you writing?
lt's a story. A story l'm making up.
Give it to me.
What is this supposed to mean?
Give it back to me!
What does this mean?
''We have a contract of depravity.
All we have to do is draw the blinds.''
Write yourself another story!
Well, what else have we got?
We never talk about anything.
We stay here in this room
and we drink and we make love.
We're strangers!
What happens when the liquor
and money run out, Eddie?
You told Charlie to lay down and die.
Will you say that to me, too?
What happens, Eddie?
- You find another rich old lover.
- That's right. And l'm sure you'll help me!
Are you waiting for me to cry?
You bum!
You poolroom bum!
- Give me a bottle of beer.
- Right.
- How did you make out?
- l made a few bucks.
- Poker game?
- Yeah.
ls it open?
lt's open.
- What will you have?
- Give me a beer.
- Okay?
- Sit down.
- What's the limit?
- Half and a dollar.
- Give me $10 worth of chips.
- $10.
- Make it $20.
- $20.
Cut.
Deal.
- Bourbon. J.T.S. Brown.
- Two.
l'm buying.
l thought you only drank milk.
- Only when l work.
- Yeah? Why?
l like it. lt's good for you.
lf you're gambling, whiskey gives you
an excuse for losing. You don't need that.
- How did you make out in the poker game?
- l lost $20.
Poker's not your game.
- What is?
- Pool.
Are you being cute?
No pool player shoots better pool
than you shot the other night at Ames.
- You have talent.
- So l have talent. So what beat me?
- Character.
- Yeah, sure.
You're damn right, l'm sure.
Everybody has talent. l have talent.
You think you can play big-money pool
or poker for 40 hours with only talent?
ls Fats the best in the country
just because he has talent? No.
He has more character in one finger
than you have in your body.
- l got drunk.
- He drank as much whiskey as you did.
- He knows how to drink.
- You bet he knows how.
You think that's a talent, too?
You think Fats was born
knowing how to drink?
Okay, what do l do now?
Lie down and bow from the ankles?
- What do l do, go home?
- That's your problem.
Or do l stay?
Stay until l hustle up
enough to play Fats again.
Maybe, by that time,
l'll have developed some character.
Maybe, by that time, you'll die of old age.
- How much will you need?
- $1,000.
At least $3,000.
He'll start at $500 a game,
and he'll beat the pants off you.
That's the way he plays against a man
who knows the way the game is.
He'll beat you five times or more,
depending on your nerves.
He might be scared of you. That could
change things, but don't count on it.
How do you know
when nobody knows that much?
Did you see that big car parked outside?
Well, that's mine. l like that car.
l get a new one every year, because l know
what guys like you and him will do.
l made enough off you the other night
to pay for it twice over.
ln that case, you owe me another drink.
Eddie?
- May l get personal?
- What have you been so far?
Eddie, you're a born loser.
What's that supposed to mean?
lt was the first time
l'd ever seen Fats hooked, really hooked.
- But you let him off.
- l got drunk.
Sure you did.
You have the best excuse for losing.
No trouble losing
when you have a good excuse.
But winning, that can be heavy
on your back, too, like a monkey.
You can drop that load with an excuse.
You have to learn to feel sorry for yourself.
lt's one of the best indoor sports, feeling
sorry for yourself, and enjoyed by all.
- Especially the born losers.
- Thanks for the drink.
- Wait. Maybe l can help you.
- To do what?
- Get the $3,000, play Fats again.
- Why?
Ten reasons, maybe fifteen.
Also there's something in it for me.
- l figured that. How much?
- 75%.
- For who?
- For me.
That's a big slice.
Who do you think you are, General Motors?
How much do you think
you are worth these days?
l'm supplying the money and time,
for that l get 75% return, if you win.
- You think l can lose?
- That's all l've seen.
- You saw me win $18,000.
- You want to hustle pool, don't you?
The game isn't like football.
Nobody pays you for yardage.
When you hustle,
you keep score real simple.
At the end of the game, you count
your money to find out who is best.
Why back me, then?
Back yourself, play poker and get rich.
l am already rich, but l like action.
That's one thing you're good for, action.
Besides, like l say, you've got talent.
You already told me that.
You cut that slice down to bite-size,
and maybe we can talk.
We don't talk. l don't make bad bets.
lt is 75%-25%.
- Kiss off.
- Wait.
- What'll you do about the money?
- There are places. l'll scuffle around.
The word's out on you, Eddie.
ln the wrong place, they'll eat you alive.
When did you adopt me?
l don't know when it was.
- Hi.
You lucky punk. l quit you!
Do you want in, friend?
- How much are you playing for?
- $1 on the five. $2 on the nine.
- l'll play a couple of games, just for kicks.
- Okay, friend.
That's it for me.
That does it for me, too.
- Are you quitting, too?
- You're a pretty good player.
- How much are you ahead?
- A couple of bucks.
- lt's just you and me.
- l guess it is, boy. Just you and me.
Do you want to raise the bet?
$2 on the five. $5 on the nine.
You know, kid,
l think maybe you're a hustler.
- Try me.
- Shoot.
Okay.
You sure you don't want to quit, friend?
Let's cut out the small stuff.
$100 freeze-out.
Ten games at $10 a game,
the winner takes all.
Then we'll see who quits.
Okay, friend, you're on.
- Call it.
- Heads.
You win.
You better not miss, friend.
l don't rattle, kid.
But just for that, l'm going to beat you flat!
That's one.
That's five.
That's six.
That's ten.
You two-bit punk, come on. Pay up, $100!
- You quitting, friend?
- Yes, l'm quitting.
Why, you're a pool shark, boy.
A real pool shark.
- So is he.
- You're better than he was. Much better.
There's your money, boy.
Pool shark!
Wait a minute.
Let's give this boy his money.
We always pay what we lose, boy.
We've got no use for pool sharks
around here!
- Who is it?
- lt's me, Eddie.
What happened?
l got beat up.
They broke my thumbs.
God!
Sarah, they broke my thumbs.
Broke my thumbs.
lt's all right.
l'm here.
You can read it if you want to.
Do you want to go out for a while?
To a movie?
No.
- Do you want a drink?
- No, do you?
What's it so hot in here for?
Please!
- Sarah, do you think l'm a loser?
- A loser?
Yeah.
l met this guy, Bert Gordon.
He said l was a born loser.
- Would he know?
- He knows a lot.
- Why did he tell you?
- l'm not sure.
He says there are people
who always look for an excuse to lose.
- What does this Bert Gordon do?
- He's a gambler.
- ls he a winner?
- He owns things.
- ls that what makes a winner?
- What else does?
- Does it bother you, what he said?
- Yeah.
lt bothers me a lot.
Because, you see, twice,
once at Ames with Fats...
...and then again at Arthur's....
That cheap, crummy poolroom.
Why did l do it, Sarah?
l could have beat that guy cold.
He never would've known.
l just had to show him.
l had to show those punks
how great the game can be when it's great.
You know, anything can be great, anything.
Bricklaying can be great if a guy knows.
lf he knows what he's doing and why,
and if he can make it come off.
Why, when l'm really going, l feel like a....
Like a jockey must feel sitting on his horse,
with all that speed and power underneath.
He's coming into the stretch,
the pressure's on and he knows.
He just feels when to let it go,
and how much.
He's got everything working for him.
Timing, touch.
lt's a great feeling.
A real great feeling,
when you're right and you know it.
Suddenly, there's oil in my arm.
The pool cue is part of me.
The pool cue has nerves in it.
lt's a piece of wood with nerves.
Feel the roll of those balls.
You don't have to look, you just know.
You make shots
that nobody's ever made before.
And you play that game
the way nobody's ever played it before.
You're not a loser, you're a winner.
Some men never feel that way
about anything.
l love you, Eddie.
Some day, Sarah, you'll settle down.
You'll marry a college professor.
You'll write a great book, maybe about me.
''Fast Eddie Felson, Hustler.''
l love you.
Do you need the words?
Yes, l need them very much.
lf you ever say them,
l'll never let you take them back.
You glad?
Yes, l'm glad.
Hello, Eddie.
Hi.
- How's business?
- Slow.
- Something wrong with your hand?
- l had an accident. A place called Arthur's.
You seem to do all right that way.
My game is about 20% off, maybe more.
- Did somebody step on your hand?
- A big creep broke my thumbs.
A man named Turk?
You know everybody, don't you?
Everybody who can hurt me or help me.
lt pays.
- You should give me lessons.
- Sign up.
Where do l sign?
The first match l have in mind
is in Louisville, Kentucky.
Name the place, boss, l'll be there.
- What happened?
- Like l told you, my thumbs.
l don't mean the thumbs.
You already told me.
- l've been thinking.
- Thinking about what?
Maybe l'm not such a great piece
of property right now.
A 25% slice of something big
is better than a 100% slice of nothing.
Give us a couple of drinks.
J.T.S. Brown.
- Good evening, sir.
- 'Evening.
- Give us a nice quiet table.
- Yes, sir, right this way.
Would you like a drink before dinner?
Okay?
Sherry, very old, very dry.
Two.
Sherry?
- lt's a nice joint. You look very pretty.
- l feel pretty.
- What's so funny?
- Your tie.
l've never seen you wear one before.
There's a first time for everything.
Yeah, that's great.
Excuse me.
To you, Eddie.
Thank you, sir.
What is it, Eddie?
Want another drink?
What do you want to tell me?
l'll be leaving town for a little while.
For how long?
- l don't know.
- A week, a year?
- More like a week. l'll be back.
- Sure.
Let's go home.
Taxi!
- No, l'll walk.
- Come here.
Better get some dry things on.
- Don't you want to know where l'm going?
- No.
Yes, l want to know what for,
but l don't want to ask.
l'm going to Kentucky,
to Louisville with a friend.
l'm going to try to make some money.
l need it.
l'll leave early in the morning.
- Leave now.
- Grow up.
Why should l?
l'm going there to play pool
with a guy named Findley.
l need the action and l need the money.
l told you l'd be back.
lf you were returning, you wouldn't
have taken me out or bought this dress.
You're hustling me.
You've never stopped hustling me.
No, l've never hustled you,
even when l thought l was, you know it.
Do you want me to sit and wait?
Faithful little Sarah.
Pull the shades down and sit.
When you feel like coming back,
you'll come back and love me.
And then you'll go away again.
ls that your idea of love?
l've got no idea of love.
Neither one of us would know what it was
if we saw it coming down the street.
l'd know it.
For God's sake, what are you doing to me?
l love you.
What's your idea of love, chains?
No.
l made you up, didn't l, Eddie?
You weren't real.
l made you up like everything else.
There was no car crash, Eddie.
When l was five l had polio.
l was never an actress.
The rich old man is my father.
He walked out on us when l was seven.
He sends a check every month
to buy his way out of my life.
The men l've known...
...after they'd left, l'd say,
''They weren't real, l made them up.''
But you, Eddie, l wanted you to be real.
l'm so scared!
l'm scared.
- Sarah Packard, Bert Gordon.
- How do you do?
That one of mine goes in Drawing Room A.
Thank you.
l got it.
- You sure you'll be comfortable, Miss....
- Packard. Sarah Packard.
lt takes me a while to memorize a name.
- Are you sure you don't want anything?
- No, l'm fine.
You ever been to Louisville for Derby week,
Miss Packard?
- l've never been to Louisville.
- Lots of action, lots of money, lots of class.
You see the best dressed,
most beautiful women in the world.
Knock your eyes out.
Findley is rich. His grandfather
left him 20% of a tobacco company.
What, and he hustles, too?
He's a gentleman, a gentleman gambler
who gets his kicks playing with hustlers.
He's got an old southern mansion,
with a pool table.
He drinks eight-year-old bourbon,
smokes cork-tipped cigarettes.
- How good is he?
- l don't know.
- l never saw him play. l hear he's great.
- l'm ready.
As soon as l've finished my coffee.
- You have great confidence in me.
- l don't.
- l've confidence in Findley.
- What's that supposed to mean?
lt means l'm confident he's a loser.
All the way a loser.
You are only about one half loser,
the other half winner.
- l'm finished.
- l got it.
No. When you play for me,
l pick up all the tabs.
Fats knew the game was in the clutch,
so he had to do something to stop you.
- He played it smart.
- l've played that game in my head, too.
Play it again. Learn something.
Fats went to the john.
He washed his face, cleaned his fingernails,
made his mind a blank...
...combed his hair,
and came back all ready to go.
You were through.
You saw how he looked,
clean, ready to start all over again.
Hold tight and push hard.
Do you know what you were doing?
You were waiting to get beat.
You were flattened out on your butt,
swimming in glory and whiskey...
...probably deciding how you could lose.
What makes you know so much?
How do you know what he was thinking?
l know.
Been there myself.
We've all been there, haven't we,
Miss Packard?
Got a match?
Doesn't your lighter work, Mr. Gordon?
l forgot all about it.
- How is your hand?
- Fine.
Good. l'd hate to put my money
on a cripple.
- Why did you say a thing like that?
- l'm sure Mr. Gordon meant no offense.
lt was a figure of speech.
- That's right, Miss Packard.
- A fact is a fact.
She's a smart girl, Eddie.
Right this way, Mr. Gordon.
Here you are, Mr. Gordon, Suite 56.
l wired ahead for two suites adjoining.
- l don't recall.
- l do! l want two suites.
l'm sorry, we're filled up,
this is Derby week.
You're wrong, you must've gotten my wire.
- Look through your reservations.
- l'll see what l can do.
Yes, you're right, Mr. Gordon.
l mislaid your wire. Two adjoining suites?
That's sweet music in there. You can
almost smell the action and the money.
l can feel it right down
in the bottom of my shoes.
- Eddie!
- Billy, how are you?
l didn't know you were here. Everyone's
here. lt's like a hustlers' convention!
West Stone Kid, Johnny Jumbo.
Come in, the guys will be glad to see you.
- What room are we in?
- 57.
l'll be up later.
Wait, Miss Packard.
We're neighbors, now. Call me Sarah.
l want to talk to you.
Do we need words?
l think so. We could cut each other up,
but that'd be bad for everybody...
...for me, for you,
and worst of all for Eddie.
You know what's good for him.
To win.
For whom and for what?
What makes the world go around?
For money and for glory.
Answer my first question. For whom?
Today for me, tomorrow for himself.
There is no tomorrow with you.
You own all the tomorrows,
because you buy them today, cheap.
Nobody has to sell.
- You bastard--
- Miss Ladybird!
You are here on a rain check, and l know it.
Hanging on by your nails.
You let that glory whistle blow for Eddie...
...and you're a wreck on the track,
a horse that finished last.
Don't make trouble, Miss Ladybird.
Live and let live!
While you can.
l'll make it up to you.
How?
You tell me.
Thanks.
There are three late scratches
in the following race:
Rosemary, Stroke of Luck, and L & R.
- Where's Bert?
- He went off somewhere.
That old loving horse paid $22.40!
With the $200 l won from that jockey
last night, and today at the track, l've $540.
- Here, you hold it.
- Why?
Just for luck.
- Findley's here.
- Where?
Over there by the bar.
- Aren't you going to talk to him?
- Sit tight. He'll be over here.
- You ready for another?
- Thank you.
No more for me.
Hello. l haven't seen you in a long time.
l haven't been here for a long time.
Miss Packard, Eddie Felson. James....
Findley.
- Glad to meet you.
- And l, you.
l think l've heard about you, Mr. Felson.
You play pocket billiards, don't you?
- Now and then. Why? Do you?
- A little, but l'm afraid l generally lose.
So does Eddie.
- l win sometimes.
- l bet you do, Mr. Felson. l just bet you do.
How much?
Bert?
l believe Mr. Felson
is making a proposition.
Could be.
Well, Mr. Felson...
...maybe you'd like to come to my place
sometime. We can play billiards.
When?
- You're very direct.
- That's right. When?
- Tonight?
- What time?
l'm having some people for drinks
right after the races.
Why don't you all come?
Then about 10:00 we can play.
- We'll be there.
- Good.
lf you don't mind,
l think l will stay at the hotel.
- What's the matter?
- l'm tired.
Come on, it'll be a lot of laughs.
Findley's parties are famous.
He invites everybody from high society
to every tramp in town.
Another way he gets his kicks.
lt excites him to be around
the criminal type. Some men are like that.
Some women, too.
- What's the matter?
- lt's all right. She drank too much.
Let her sleep it off.
Cut it out!
Do what he says, come on, upstairs.
Do you gentlemen care for a drink?
- None for me. Let's play.
- By all means.
Thought we came here to play pool?
l don't play pool, l play billiards.
lt's my house, my game.
You don't have to play if you don't want to.
- We won't.
- Bert, let me play him.
- How much?
- We'll start small. $100 a game?
- Did you ever play billiards before?
- Sure.
You hustling me?
l'm sure he knows what he's doing.
You can afford $100 to find out.
Deal the cards.
Beautiful shot!
You've played billiards before, Mr. Felson.
- Sure you wouldn't care for a drink?
- Nothing for me.
How do we stand?
- About even.
- When do l raise the bet?
- l don't know.
- lf that's his best game, l can beat him.
Level with me. Did you ever play billiards?
What's the difference?
There's a cue, balls on the table.
All you got to do is get the feel of it.
- Shall we raise the stakes?
- How much?
$500?
You think you can beat him?
Of course he does.
He wouldn't play me if he didn't.
l didn't ask him, can he beat you,
l already know he can.
l asked him, will he?
That's two different things.
l can beat him.
All right, $500.
Have you noticed, Bert, this fellow here
bears a striking resemblance to you?
lt seems you might have modeled
for the artist.
lt's possible.
Mark that one up, too, Bert.
l'll beat him the next game.
How are the hands?
Fine.
Rack up your cue, we're leaving.
- That's a shame. The night is young.
- The night is $2,000 old.
- Hey, Bert, wait.
- l said we're leaving.
l can beat him, Bert.
He suckered me, l didn't think he knew
how to hustle. l can outplay and beat him!
l don't believe you, Eddie.
l think you're still a loser.
l'll play him on my own money!
Be right back.
Okay, come on, let's play.
l'm broke.
- That's unfortunate, Mr. Felson.
- For whom, Mr. Findley?
Bert, he only beat me by a point.
- The bank is closed.
- Don't get off me, please!
l know when to quit. You don't.
Win or lose, you don't know!
What do you want me to do? Say it...
...and you've got it,
but don't get off me now.
Don't beg him.
- Go back to the hotel.
- Please, Eddie, don't beg him.
Go back to the hotel. Take a cab, go back!
Doesn't all this come through to you?
Doesn't it mean anything to you?
That man, this place, the people.
They wear masks, and under them
they're perverted, twisted, crippled!
- Shut up.
- Don't wear a mask. You don't have to.
That's Turk, who broke your thumbs!
He won't break your thumbs,
he'll break your heart, your guts...
...and for the same reason,
because he hates you for what you are.
- For what you have and he hasn't.
- Get off my back, once and for all!
Would you get off my back?
Play him, Eddie.
Play him for $1,000 a game.
Will you take a check?
Cash.
How much do l owe you?
$12,000.
Here.
lt's been an interesting evening.
lt sure has.
Charles, call a cab for these gentlemen,
please.
- l'd show you to the door, but--
- Yes, you're tired.
And beat.
Yeah.
You must come again.
Yeah, sure.
Here's your share: $3,000.
- The cab is waiting.
- Thanks.
- Eddie, let's go.
- l want to walk.
lt's a long walk.
l got time, Bert.
You want me to tell her for you?
Tell her what?
You got to be hard, Eddie.
When are you leaving?
ln a little while.
lt's what you want, isn't it?
lt's what Eddie wants.
He told me to give you some money.
Put it on the bed.
That's the way it's done, isn't it?
That's the way it's done.
The way you're looking at me...
...is that how you look
at a man you've just beaten?
As if you've just taken his money
and now you want his pride?
- All l want is the money.
- Sure.
Sure, the money and the aristocratic
pleasure of seeing him fall apart.
You're a Roman, Bert.
You have to win them all.
You got a drink?
Give me my key, please. Room 57.
Come on, give me my key.
Now, let's go over this again.
You say you were in the other room....
She closed the door, l told you,
she closed the door.
She closed the door, went in there,
maybe ten, five minutes or so.
Hey, let him come in.
Eddie....
Eddie?
She came in here, Eddie.
She asked me for a drink.
l gave her one.
We had a few more.
Eddie, she came in here!
l came to play pool, Fats.
- That's good. For how much?
- You name it.
$1,000 a game?
Let's make it $3,000 a game, Fats.
$3,000, that's my bankroll, my life savings.
What's the matter, Fats?
Beat me the first game,
and l'm on my way back to Oakland.
Let's go.
Get on me, Bert, l can't lose!
Willie?
- Call it.
- Heads.
How should l play that one, Bert?
Play it safe?
That's what you always told me,
play it safe, play the percentage.
Well, here we go, fast and loose.
One ball, corner pocket.
Percentage players die broke, too,
don't they, Bert?
How can l lose?
Twelve ball.
l mean, how can l lose?
Because you were right, Bert.
lt's not enough to have talent,
you've got to have character, too.
Four ball.
And l sure got character now.
l picked it up in a hotel room in Louisville.
Shoot pool, Fast Eddie.
l'm shooting pool, Fats.
When l miss, you can shoot.
Five ball.
Fourteen ball.
Four ball.
That's game.
Game!
Eight ball.
Thirteen ball.
l quit, Eddie.
l can't beat you.
Willie, give him the stake.
You got yourself a pool player.
Preacher, give me my coat.
Where do you think you're going?
Eddie?
You owe me money!
Just how do you figure that, Bert?
- What do you figure l owe you?
- Half!
- ln Louisville, it was 75%.
- Here, it's half.
What if l don't pay you?
You don't pay me?
You'll get your thumbs broken again.
And your fingers.
lf l want them to, they'll break
your right arm in three or four places.
You better pay him, Eddie.
You figure you're still my manager?
l'm a businessman, kid.
You've got a lot of games lined up for me?
We'll make lots of money together,
from now on.
50%?
lt don't have to be 50%.
lt can be 30%, 25%.
We really stuck the knife in her, didn't we?
We really gave it to her good.
lf it didn't happen in Louisville,
it would happen someplace else.
lf not now, six months from now.
That's the kind of dame she was.
Then we twisted it, didn't we, Bert?
lt doesn't stick in your throat because
you spit it out like everything else!
But it sticks in mine.
l loved her.
l traded her in on a pool game.
That wouldn't mean anything to you.
Who did you ever care about?
''Just win,'' you said.
That's the important thing.
You don't know what winning is.
You're a loser!
Because you're dead inside,
and you can't live...
...unless you make everything else
dead around you.
Too high, Bert.
Your price is too high.
lf l take it, she never lived. She never died.
We both know that's not true, don't we?
She lived. She died.
You better....
You tell your boys they better kill me.
They better go all the way with me...
...because if they just bust me up,
l'll put the pieces together...
...so help me God, Bert...
...l'll come back and l'll kill you.
Wait a minute.
All right.
Only...
...don't ever walk
into a big-time pool hall again.
Fat Man...
...you shoot a great game of pool.
So do you, Fast Eddie.