Flight 530 from San Francisco,
you're cleared for landing, Captain.
- Sorry, I don't speak Spanish.  - First time in Spain?
Yeah, first time in Spain. Where's my luggage?
Unfortunately, it's still in San Francisco.
Fantastic.
Sally, it's me.
Can you call the airline and tell them to leave my bags in San Francisco?
I'll be back before they get here, anyway. Thanks.
Will?
- Hey.  - Hey.
I was... I was expecting Josh.
He's asleep on the boat. Jet lag.
- Hit him all of a sudden. Good to see you.  - Good to see you.
How's the posting?
Best in a while.
Had a gospel quartet come through here for about six weeks,
and then a Picasso expert from Oregon State.
Why on earth would Spain want to hear from a Picasso expert from Oregon?
A different perspective.
Sorry, hold on.
Hello?
Look, could I call you back in a few hours?
- Okay, bye. Bye.  - Bye.
One call, Dad.
This vacation, it's just a real bad time for me to be away from the company.
Your mother's pretty happy about this vacation, Will.
Will?
Oh! Mmm!
- You look great, Mom.  -  Thanks for the groceries, hon.
How come you're so relaxed?
Well, that's 'cause we're all finally here.
How was your flight?
The plane went up, flew straight across, went down again.
Nothing a small bathtub of vino won't fix.
We can do better than that. Now, why don't you get that suit off?
It looks like an accordion on you. Where's your luggage?
Apparently it's still saying goodbye to the Golden Gate Bridge.
Oh! For heaven's sake. Uh...
Well, there's some clothes you left behind from last year's trip.
Why don't you put those on?
I'll have a nice glass of Rioja waiting for you when you're ready.
See what I mean?
When I got here, she was like, "Beer's in the fridge."
Mom always liked you best.
Oh, God.
Look who's here.
Dara, this is Will. The good brother.
The one who used to tell everybody he was an only child.
Only after Josh was born.
How was the ride with Godzilla?
No blood, no foul. Yeah.
Well, just take it nice and easy. It's only a week.
I think your dad's a sweetie.
She grew up in a Soviet orphanage.
Well, I gotta get changed.
That's not bad.
But it's a government job. You have to tolerate the bureaucracy.
You move when the government tells you to move, so not everybody likes it.
Yeah, I'm not sure I liked it.
Josh and I never got to have the same friends for more than two years in a row.
Not to mention we lived in 12 different countries over 18 years.
But the best thing is we learned about 15 weird local sports.
Excuse me, my man.
We both played basketball and ran track in the Comoros, remember?
Although no one in the school was over 5'3",
and Will was pretty much the all-star everywhere we went.
Wow! Well done.
Mmm. Got it?
Before we start, I just want to say how happy I am
that we're all finally together around a table again.
I didn't realize how much I'd missed this.
To family. Nice.
To family.
This looks fantastic.
My caveman caught it this morning.
You fish, Mr. Shaw?
Yeah, he fishes.
-  Oh, guys.  - He fishes. He fishes.
- No, guys, seriously, please.  - Come on! I want to hear this story.
-  Spear-fishing, actually, is his forte.  - Excuse me.
I got to take this. Important.
No more of those stories or I'll start telling some of yours.
Where are you sleeping tonight? You guys aren't sleeping together, are you?
Jesus, Dad.
If we work together on this, I'm sure it's going to be beneficial for both of us.
This Thursday?
I'm out of the country, so...
I understand.
Okay. Bye.
-  Quite dangerous.  - Yeah, in his case it was quite dangerous.
- Here he comes. Shh!  - Poor Will.
- Poor Will.  - It's just his little secret.
That story's going to stay in the family for a while.
It's not going anywhere.
Please, tell me. Come on.
Josh, that's enough.
- No, guys, seriously, please. Don't.  - Will is the fisherman.
All right, before they go off on any kind of fantastic story,
what really happened was that he took me out
when I'm 10 years old spear-fishing, ten years old,
and I spear my own flipper.
And everyone finds this hilarious.
- That's the story?  - That's the story.
He cried all night.
He could've speared his foot.  He cried himself to sleep.
Will would make this noise when he cried. Josh could tell you.
- It's like a little wuffling sound.  - Really funny. Really...
Actually, you know what? This is not the day for a joke.
- I don't know if I can stay the week.  - What?
I'm sorry, Mom.
I have just found out
my company is officially bankrupt.
What?
-  I'm sorry.  - What are you talking about?
Will?
I'm sorry I went off at you at dinner.
I'm sorry you're going through such a difficult time.
Thank you.
It'll be a good wind tomorrow.
Yeah.
Get ready to come about!
Will?
Will!
Tighter on that boom!
Tighter, Will!
I heard you the first time.
Josh, we'll anchor here!
Will?
Will!
When you get a minute.
Keep it into the wind.
Will! Into the wind!
Head it into the wind!
Dara!
Oh, my God, are you okay?
- Let me take a look.  - Yeah, I'm okay.
- Oh, my God!  - I'm okay. I'm okay.
Is she okay? You all right?
-  You'll be fine.  - Yeah, I'm fine.
- Damn phone!  - Hey! Are you kidding me?
- Will, have you lost your mind?  - No!
- Shut up!  - That's my career you threw away there!
- There is a girl on the deck of the boat...  - What the hell?
...with her head cut open!  Martin! Enough!
I'm okay! Seriously.
I'm going into town. Anybody need anything?
Try to find some antiseptic. The pharmacy should have some.
Okay, I'm gonna need some cash.
Hurry back, Will.
Gracias.
I love you.
- I got it. Be careful.  - Okay.
Hey. Did you see where that boat went?
Guys, any of you see a boat? Like, a sailboat? No?
Mom?
Please, you gotta help me. Something's happened to my family.
What?
Hey! Something's happened to my family!
My boat's been ripped to shit and they're gone!
- I'm Captain Pizarro. You are?  - I'm Will Shaw.
Where are you going?
Take me to the boat.
- Who the hell is that?  - Please, Mr. Shaw, relax.
Will. Can I call you Will?
How do you know my name?
Your mother told me.
- Where is she?  - I can take you to her.
And the rest of your family. Come on.
No, hey!
- Hey! Come on!  - No, no! Hey!
- Come on.  - Hey, let me go! Get off me!
Shit!
Will? Will? Let's go. Come on. Get up.
Are you okay, Will?
Head hurts. I just got the shit kicked out of me.
Where's Mom? Where's Josh?
I'm not sure where they are.
What?
I asked you, "Where's Mom? Where's Josh?" I left them with you.
Men came on the boat.
They put a gun to my head, and they took your mother and Josh and Dara.
- What the hell is happening?  - I'm sorry.
- Why are you sorry? What?  - I'm sorry.
Will, I don't book gospel quartets and Picasso experts.
It's not the job I do at the Embassy.
The only thing that's true is that I've worked for the government a long time.
So what do you do?
It's a branch of the Agency.
It's a special branch of the Agency.
- And Mom and Josh are gone.  - Not like you think.
- Just don't treat me like an idiot.  - I'm not.
- You are! Mom and Josh are gone.  - I'm not treating...
You're CIA and you don't know where they are?
I'm sorry.
Is it something you did?
It may be, yes.
I'm sorry, Will.
There's no way I could ever explain that to you.
But we're gonna get your mother back and Josh back and Dara back.
Try and get some rest.
- Hey.  - Marty, is that you?
- Yeah, it's me.  - What's going on?
- I'm on my way now.  - What's happening?
- Where are you?  - I'm at home. It's 3:00 in the morning.
I need to see you.
Yeah. Let's go. Come on.
I need you to drive.
Diego, I'm gonna meet Carrack. I need your help.
I'll call you later.
Does Mom know?
Yeah, she knows. She knows everything.
- She's my wife.  - How could you not tell me this?
There was no way to tell you. No way, Will.
It would have never been right to tell you what I do.
Who's that?
A friend.
Just sit tight.
You gonna be all right?
You're a great son.
Be back in a second.
- Are you okay?  - No.
What's going on? Are you hurt?
What did you do? You set me up?
- Did I set you up?  - Did you set me up?
- Marty, what are you talking about?  - They took Laurie and Josh off the boat.
Who did?
I can't help you if you don't talk to me, Marty.
Who took Laurie? Who did?
The guys we took the briefcase from. They want it back.
- Shit.  - Who are they, Jean?
They gave me 24 hours, or they're going to kill them.
Where's the briefcase?
The briefcase went straight up the line. It's gone.
Carrack, don't fuck with me right now.
- No?  - I'll try.
- No, that's it?  - I'll try.
- Okay, then I'm gonna go.  - Marty, I want to help you.
It went straight up the line. I don't have it anymore.
You need to fix this.
I'll do my best, Marty.
Dad?
God.
Deal with the body.
- Hello?  - What's the status?
- Someone's trying to kill me.  - Put Tom on the phone.
- Someone shot my father.  - Tell Tom he has less than 21 hours.
Who's Tom? Who the hell are you?
The guy who has your family.
Where do you have...
Hey! Hey, hey! No!
There's a guy who's trying to kill me!
Hold on, this guy's going to kill me! There's a guy trying to kill me!
Damn it!
Okay, I...
I'm American!
Can you help me?
There's no evidence of a Martin Shaw with any of our agencies in Spain.
He told us he was a cultural attache.
I thought you said that he wasn't.
My father is dead. Executed. Assassinated.
Mr. Shaw, there's a local warrant for your arrest.
- It claims you killed a police officer.  - Wait, hold it, hold it. No. No.
Look, the guy who shot my father was shooting at me halfway across the city.
We can assist you in securing legal counsel
and protecting your rights as an American citizen.
Look, I did not kill that cop.
But you know what? We don't have time for this.
My family doesn't have the time. Will you please help me? Please?
I suggest you accept our help getting you legal counsel.
- Is there someone else I can talk to?  - Just calm down.
All anyone ever says to me is calm down.
Tranquilo, tranquilo.
My family has been kidnapped,
and I am wanted for a murder I did not commit.
Yes?
Yes, ma'am.
Right now, in fact.
Someone needs to talk to you.
Come with us, Mr. Shaw.
Will? It's Jean.
Jean Carrack. I worked with your father.
You know, I bet if you raise your left hand, I will see a big white scar
running right across your palm.
You got that making me a martini when you were 10.
- Don't you remember?  - Hey, yeah. I remember you.
Look, your father has left your family in a tough spot.
I'd like to help.
Why don't you get in the car and we'll figure this out?
Okay, if you didn't kill him, who did?
I was there to help him.
I was trying to protect him, but he wouldn't listen to me.
He was not a great listener, your father.
I'll tell you everything I know when you get in the car.
Will. Come on.
Do you want to save your family? Because there's an expiration date on that.
Come on, Will.
So who was your father dealing with about your family?
Who was his contact?
I thought you said you were gonna do the talking.
If I'm going to help you, I have to figure out who I'm dealing with.
Did he call anyone? Did he meet anyone?
- Are you all right?  - I think I'm gonna be sick.
- Really?  - Really.
Pull over.
Better?
All right, kid, come on. Let's go.
Senor!
You little...
Forget him.
Come on, let's go. We'll just get the other one first.
Hey! Get away from there! Get away from there!
What?
Don't do this to me. Seriously.
Please. I'm...
Thank you.
Yes?
Hello? Are you... Hello?
Tell your son I want to speak to Tom.
-  Will?  - Mom!
Mom, are you okay?
Put your father on the phone. I need to speak to him now.
Mom,
you can't.
Just put him on the phone.
Mom, I can't put him on the phone.
Will, just do as I say.
Mom, I can't.
Where is he?
Mom, they've killed him.
No! No!
Hey! Hey! Calm down.
Tom and I had an agreement. My briefcase or your family's dead.
Listen, I don't know anything about your suitcase or briefcase or anything.
Just let my family go.
- This is not going to buy any more time.  - What?
Remind Tom what is at stake.
Look, my dad is dead and his name was Martin.
You've got the wrong guy.
Tell Tom. 6:00 PM. Puerta del Sol.
My briefcase or your family's dead.
Hello. Do you speak any English?
A little bit. How can I help you?
My name is Will Shaw. I'm just looking for Diego.
He was a friend of my father's.
Can you give me your address, please?
Yes.
Cruz Street.
34, Suite 502, Madrid.
Hi.
Hi, how are you?
What can I do for you?
- We spoke on the phone.  - Mmm-hmm.
You gave me the directions here.
Mmm-hmm.
Can I help you?
I need to speak to Diego Caldera.
Hey, Will. You feeling better now?
Whoa! Whoa!
Put the gun down! Put the gun down! Put the gun down!
I only speak goddamn English!
You want to kill my uncle!
Who the hell is your uncle?
Is Diego Caldera your uncle?
Yeah. This cabron comes in here with a gun
and tells me to sit down and shut up, waiting for my uncle to come in.
This guy's friends murdered my father this morning.
Your father was murdered?
That's why I'm here.
My dad called this office at least a dozen times looking for Diego.
- Where is your uncle then?  - What?
Look, okay? This guy,
his people came looking here for your uncle.
Where are they going to look next?
Do you really want to be here when his pals turn up?
Come on. We gotta find your uncle.
- It's open.  - Okay, okay, I've got it.
This kid is all over the damn news.
Why didn't you take care of him this morning?
Come on, Dixon, answer your phone.
Don't do it!
Hi, Will. Surprise.
Put the gun down, Will.
You're scared,
and scared people holding guns in my face, that scares me.
Well, this is going to be a nerve-wracking conversation.
May I sit down?
So,
what can I do for you?
Why did you kill him?
If our situations were reversed,
believe me, your father would've done the exact same thing.
Why did you kill him?
Your father wanted to give something back to our enemies
that's a matter of national security.
You mean the briefcase?
He was about to betray his country, Will.
And betray us, his team.
I don't believe you.
- Really?  - Honestly, kid,
we don't give a shit.
Maybe I knew him better than you did.
I want to see my family.
I don't have your family.
Who does?
I'm sorry to say that some terrorists do.
Will, you are the last person I want to get more involved in this right now.
But I need your help.
I need you to tell me who else he saw or spoke to about this.
You give me what I need,
I will pull out all the stops to help you get your family back.
You need to tell them that my father's dead and that I've got nothing to do with this.
I just want to save my family!
Right.
So, I certainly think we owe you something.
Wait, wait, wait. Sit down!
Go! Come on!
Go, go!
Come on!
God damn it!
Get out of the way!
Go! Go! Go!
We gotta find a way down!
There's no way down!
God!
- What are you doing?  - Get your arms up.
- Okay, hold that under your arm.  - No, no. Wait! Are you kidding me?
- Trust me. This is the only way down.  - No, no, no. No way!
This is the only way you're going to be safe.
No! Are you crazy?
- Lucia!  - No! No way!
Stand still and listen to me!
Are you ready for this?
Will! Don't drop me!
Oh, God!
Stop!
Will! Come on!
Come on!
I've been shot.
She's here!
Will!
No!
Lucky.
It's fine. It's fine.  No hospital.
- It's fine.  - No hospital.
It's not a hospital. My friend can help you here.
You gotta take me to Puerta del Sol. It's fine.
Are you okay?
What is this place?
Chris, please!
Lucia! What happened?
You gotta take me to Puerta del Sol. I need to find my family.
They killed my uncle!
This guy's wounded! You have to help me!
No, take him away. You'll get me into trouble!
You go to medical school, help him!
I'm a student, not a doctor.
Hey!
Cristiana! What's going on?
Habib, call Maximo, we need help!
He's losing lots of blood! I don't have anywhere to take him.
- When was he shot?  - An hour ago, I think.
Keep him awake.
Talk to me! Please, talk to me!
Where are they?
In the office.
Does she think this is a hospital?
I owe her uncle some favors
but she can't bring a bleeding guy into my club!
I don't have time for this shit!
What's going on, girls?
Maximo, please.
Maximo, Diego has been killed.
This guy saved my life!
His father's been killed too.
Maximo, hand me that vodka. I need to sterilize my hands.
Lucia, tell him this is going to hurt a lot.
I need to see if there's a bullet.
- What's she saying?  - She says not to worry.
You're gonna be fine.
Perfect! There's no bullet. Now I have to stop the bleeding.
There is no bullet. There is no bullet.
Please, please, please. Okay.
You need a drink, my friend? I do.
Guys, hold him tight!
- What's she doing? What's she doing?  - Okay, she's gonna stop the bleeding.
Well done. Well done, my friend.
Oh! I'm going to puke.
Why did they kill my uncle?
I don't know.
Probably because my father reached out to him.
I don't know. I'm sorry.
Why do you have a photo of Tom Keaton on your phone?
That's my father. That's Martin Shaw.
He's your father?
Yes.
- Is he dead? Are you sure he's dead?  - Yes.
Yes, I told you.
Did you know my father? Were you friends?
Friends before anything else.
All my life.
Oh, God. I can't stay here. I've gotta find my family.
Where do you need to go?
To Puerta del Sol.
So you called your father Martin?
I didn't call him that. That was his name.
Do you even know what he did?
What do you mean?
What he did for a living.
He said he was a business consultant.
Business consultant. That's rich.
What about you? What do you do?
I used to run a small company.
And what did your small company do?
Business consultants.
Like father, like son.
So you seem to know my father pretty well. How come?
Were you sleeping with him?
That's what you think?
I wasn't your...
I don't know what I'm supposed to think.
I wasn't your father's lover.
My mother was.
He was my father, too.
Did you know about his other family?
He was hardly around.
Sometimes I think the more a parent's absent,
the more you love them.
Next stop, Puerta del Sol.
So, you, too?
I was fine with it.
Sure you were.
And your mother?
What's she like?
My mother is dead.
I'm sorry.
Will! Wait!
Wait.
- Okay.  - I told you. I need to go alone.
If you need me, I'll be at the club.
That's all.
Thank you.
I hope you will get them back.
Keep your hands where I can see them.
Turn around and walk with me.
Where?
Follow me.
Where is your father?
Where's my family?
I've told you,
over and over.
My father is dead.
If you don't believe me,
then have your guy here really go to town on me.
Sure he'll feel better.
And I still won't know a goddamned thing.
Even if that's true, it's still your problem.
Do you know how we come to this, Will?
Two months ago, one of my men posed as a corrupt agent
willing to sell sensitive pieces of intel to terrorists.
The mission was to uncover a rogue CIA operative
we knew was making deals for his own interest.
So my agent arranged a rendezvous.
And guess who showed up?
Your father killed my agent
and stole a briefcase that held contents vital to my country.
And now you tell me he's dead?
Agent?
How about terrorist?
Terrorist?
My wife and son met a terrorist once, in a cafe in Tel Aviv.
In an instant,
they and 15 others
were turned to ash.
So the question becomes
who killed your father?
People from his own agency.
They killed his friend and they've been trying to kill me, too.
You mean Carrack?
Yeah.
You guys should really get together and chat about this.
I think you'd get on really...
Perhaps she wants to eliminate you as a witness,
along with the rest of your family.
Bottom line is that, wherever you go,
they'll be hunting you.
And that will suit our purposes fine.
- Will!  - Will!
- You're alive!  -  Guys!
- Has anyone hurt you?  -  Will, you're okay!
The irony is,
if your father's killers are trying to eliminate witnesses,
the only thing keeping your family alive right now is their captivity.
So here is the deal.
I need you out there to draw her to you.
We know that some potential buyers are in town.
So we feel that the sale is imminent.
If she really wants to kill you all,
I just need to stay close to you.
But just so we're clear, if I don't stop Carrack before it's sold,
I won't keep your family any longer.
I'll release them, and Carrack will kill them.
Understood?
Guys!
Will! Wait!
Just get off of me!
Hey! Get your hands off me! Get off me!
Let me go!
Hey, man.
I need to see Lucia.
Come. I'll take you.
Will.
I've seen them. They're alive.
I need to get her coming after me.
It shouldn't be hard, 'cause she's trying to track me down anyway.
She wants to kill anyone who knew anything about it.
And the Israeli said that the likely buyers are in town tonight.
So we gotta move, 'cause the deal could happen any time.
Hey.
- For you.  - Thank you.
How much did you hear?
Along with what Lucia told me before? Enough.
This bitch, Carrack,
she's the one who killed Diego, right?
So, how can I help?
They're spies, right? Eyes everywhere?
Phones, e-mail. Everything.
Let's start a tab. Then they'll find us.
Lucia, wait a second. Are you sure you're ready for this?
Say my name and you can say it with honor
She's not working tonight.
Gracias.
You don't understand me, but when you were in school,
you ever hear the story of Brer Rabbit? Huh?
- Is it sold?  - Is it sold?
Jesus Christ! You're dumber than your father.
What are you actually asking me, Will?
"Is it sold?" What's sold? The briefcase? Or is your family dead?
'Cause if it's sold, they're dead. Right?
The deal's gonna happen.
And the only way you'll know where is if you make me tell you.
But I ain't telling you shit.
No!
Get him up!
- Untie him! - He'll kill you, man.
Will!
Get off me! We'll do this!
- Get off me! Get off me!  - We'll do this!
Where's Carrack? Answer me!
Tell me! Where is she? Why isn't she here?
- Why isn't she here?  - Because!
She's a lady.
And ladies, unlike your little sister,
stay at home while the men go out...
Kick the shit out of him!
Don't worry. He'll talk.  Just tape him up. We've done enough.
I know that it's not easy to watch, but it will work.
- No, it won't.  - It will.
- I've got a plan.  - The duct tape won't hold.
We have to let him go. We need a car.
- I don't understand.  - Promise me you won't go in there.
I still don't understand.
He thinks I'm an idiot. Let me deliver on that.
Dad was no traitor. Carrack played him.
Played him and the Israelis.
- And the Israelis are out there?  - They better be.
There.
They are on the move.
Stay close to them. Call me if she shows up.
Ok.
He got away.
I'll deal with him later.
Let's hope for your sake he doesn't show up.
There. Pull over.
Be careful.
- Stay here, okay?  - Okay. What are you gonna do?
Wait for them.
I'm glad to see you brought what I was expecting.
Yeah, I ran into a little bit of trouble, but it's been dealt with.
Shh! Come with me.
- We're on your side.  - Okay.
So, gentlemen, if you're ready, we can do our business.
How can I be sure this is the real thing?
It came directly from a Mossad agent.
Sadly, no eyewitnesses.
You're not gonna find anything else like this one.
Shh!
Crawl back out of here.
We'll take over now.
No. Tell me where my family is or I'm not going anywhere.
Listen to me. Leave now or I'll have to drag you out.
- No!  - Leave now!
Catch.
Lucia! Calm down.
It's okay. It's okay.
You, Will?
Of all the people
who should've killed me.
Will! She's coming.
No! No! No!
You amateur!
Hurry up. Hurry up. Go, go, go!
Watch it!
Whoo!
- Come on!  - Please! No!
Jesus!
No, no, no! No!
God! Damn!
Where are they? Who?
The Israelis. Where are they?
Shit!
Where is she? Where is she?
She's there!
No, no, no! Wait, wait! Don't!
Come on!
Who's going to pay for my car now?
- Lucia! Get out. Come on, come on!  - What?
All right! That's it!
I'm getting sick of this. Come on.
She's coming! She's coming!
Come on!
God damn!
Carrack, you bitch!
Oh, Will.
What a mess.
Looks like you're gonna need some more stitches.
And your little dead friend, too.
Your mother's gonna freak out.
Aw! Is that your father's gun?
I'm sorry.
You looking for something like this?
Will!
My sister. She's hurt back there.
Relax. She's halfway to the hospital.
Your father, for all the hell he caused us,
would be proud of you.
What about my family?
Oh, my God!
You handled yourself pretty well out there for a kid who knows shit.
I have to tell you, I was impressed.
Thanks for helping us clean up our own mess.
Does this mean I can go home now?
Sure. Whatever.
But I think you should really consider another line of work.
You know, your father was an honest man.
I'm sorry he's gone.
Thank you.
Could I ask you something?
Shoot.
What the hell was in the briefcase?
There's only one way I can answer that.
I've gotta go see my family.
Hey.
Thank you.
You told her about me, right?
It didn't really seem important.
Thanks. Thanks a lot.
You should go and introduce yourself.
She is your sister.
She is my sister.