-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
-=THE LAST FANTASY=- Proudly Presents
How's it morning already?
Jarrod...
Jarrod, wake up.
It's okay.
What is that?
I do not know.
Ray!
Stay here.
What's wrong?
He is gone!
Jarrod!
I can't decide.
Elaine, you pick the last one.
Jay-rock... T-money?
Well, we do had a bad time, we were bad.
You haven't changed a bit.
Neither is Terry...
You'll see.
- He is a real deal. - Can't wait.
Well you should have thought about that before you shout a piece of shit.
What are you doing here so early?
- It's a beautiful day. - Well I know it.
They gonna call about the robotic but...
Tell 'em to handle it...
No business on my birthday.
- Hi. - God. She always have to be here?
She is working.
Showbiz, baby.
You're sweatie...
- Elaine, are you feeling alright? - Yeah.
Yeah, I'm fine...
Here, let me get that for you.
Here you go.
- Thank you. - No problem.
That's you my hero.
Yeah, that's us.
Oh, you got to be kidding me!
- You better not get use to this. - Who? Me?
Penthouse.
Alright, come on.
How is the second most talented guy I know?
I don't know. How are you?
I'm good.
Happy Birthday!
Oh, You must be Elaine.
- God. - Welcome.
This is amazing.
Automatic living at its finest.
My personal place in clouds.
The view is incredible.
Elaine, let me ask you a question.
How do you keep my boy Elaine?
Don't answer that.
It is a full-time job.
Well, what ever he is paying you, I'll double it.
Oh well! Its like coaching is full already.
I like it, yeah.
That's your room right there.
You guys want it to the pool?
Absolutely.
Baby!
Pool time!
- Baby, get me a Cosmo. - Absolutely, hold this.
Hey, the bar is this way.
You really did it man.
I mean, just like everybody knew you would but...
Hi guys!
Hello...
I kind of not done it without you.
What I do? Decorated the walls?
- You do look nice. - They do look nice.
Happy Birthday, Terry.
Yeah, happy birthday to me!
I can't live in that place man.
And I don't know what I should be gettng as your gift.
I got some ideas on that.
Come on.
I see everyone getting along famously.
- Baby! - Yeah.
Where is my cosmo?
Oh my bad.
Denise, get me a drink.
- Anyone else? - No.
Hey, this definitely beats Brooklyn in December.
I don't know... I kinda like having four seasons.
You got one group down block.
Tomorrow we gonna hit the high sea
and we take it hell out of my sun seeker.
67 footer, my starter yacht
Homeland security...They must be here because they know
that our party tonight gonna be the bomb!
Cheers.
Happy Birthday, Terry!
- Hi mate, how is it going man? - Alright.
There is somebody I want you to meet. Ray!
Hold on.
Happy birthday man.
Thank You.
How is "The Robot Fight" coming along?
Dude its sucks! But the director loves it, so... you know!
- Hey, this is the Boy Wonder? - Yeah.
And his lovely lady. Yeah!
Hey, it's good to meet you, man.
I'm excited you gonna join the crew.
Uh... I mean I...
You find a place to live yet?
I'm tellin' you, Venice is where is at...
I live there, so I can show you around. - Thank you.
- I have to go to this little girls room. - Alright.
No... babe... Elaine!
She is smokin', nice job dude. Excellent.
- Way to go! - Way to go!
Whats going on ladies?
- Sorry. - What is that about?
- Jeez us! - Okay, look.
Ok, its obviously out of the bag...
I'm thinking uh... You should move to LA.
What am I gonna do in here? I'm barely surviving back home.
I can use you.
Oh, I don't need your charity, alright?
Ok fine!
I need you.
I don't know anything about effects man.
- That's bullshit, come on! - That's not bullshit.
You got the eye and you know it. Alright! The computer is just a tool.
I don't know, I've never saw myself out here.
Where do you see yourself?
You got a fine A-B plan I do not know about?
It is not about the money, okay?
It's always about the money.
What about Elaine?
I can't handle everything. You got to take care of that yourself.
Terry, there is a call for you upstairs.
You think about it.
Elaine.
Alright, come on.
We suppose to be having fun, what's the problem?
Just forget it, alright!
Look...
Terry sprung this whole California thing on me today, alright.
I had no idea...
I'm "late"...
What do you mean you "late"?
"Late"!
Oh, sorry.
Since when?
I don't know.
I've been feeling sick all weeks, so I took a test and...
Why didn't you tell me?
I wanted to...
Believe me... I just I don't want to ruin your trip.
You thought.
Shit!
Is that all you have to say?
What would you want me to say?
- I don't think I'm ready for this. - You not ready, Jarrod?
What about me?
It's not... Hey will you kid...!
Isn't that what we've look forward to?
Elaine...
Wa... wa... wait... we got it... we got it take a look at that one.
We have a winner! That what I'm talking about!
Pardon me ma'am, but...
...we received a few noise complaints.
From who?
The building is half empty.
I understand that but, the other half is trying to sleep...
...so if you don't mind ...just
Fine.
Another one for the books... Oh yeah.
Well, well, well. - I call the couch.
Oh come on, there is plenty room for both of us.
I like more space.
Wow, alright. Maybe can be excuses.
Good night.
Earthquake?
Probably just a Tremor.
Turn off the lights.
Ray.
What are you doing?
Ray!
Stay here.
- What wrong? - He is gone!
Jarrod, no! Jarrod, no!
- What the hell is going on? - Terry, please, you got to hurry!
What's got you man?
Jarrod!
Please... What's happening?
Jarrod! Oh my God!
What's wrong with him?
Where is Ray?
- Where is Ray? - No, no, no, no...
Where is he?
- He is gone! - What do you mean he is gone?
I mean he is gone.
- Did he fall? - No!
- Did he jump? - I don't know! I don't know!
Please, please...
He went outside, to the light.
And then, he just disappeared... I don't know.
Terry, please!
Jarrod, look at me.
What did you see huh? What did you see?
What happened?
Jarrod, what happened?
I don't know.
I was being pulled to...towards this light.
- Open the blinds! - No!
God!
There is something down there.
What?
Jarrod, check this out.
I don't see anything.
There, people on the roof.
What are they doing?
I don't know.
We should check it out.
You don't know what's out there.
- Everything Okay. - Alright.
I'm calling the police.
- I'll get some pictures. - You can't go out there.
I can't let Terry alone.
It just keep ringing.
A gun?
Really?
Just check the news and find out what the hell is going on.
Terry!
We will be right back!
- Jarrod. - Look at me.
Let's go.
Hurry back.
The stairs are this way.
God dammit...
What's going on?
I'm going to check it out.
What are you doing with a gun?
Go back to your apartment. Go!
And keep it down.
Are you sure about this?
There is been nothing news since 4 a.m.
Denise, check the TV.
Its calm.
Dammit, Jarrod.
You didn't tell me to hold it open.
I tought it was common sense.
I'm sorry.
Get down.
What now?
Let's get a better look.
Hi. This is Jackie. Please leave a message.
Mom, its me.
Something happened uh...
Pick up.
Please, just...
...call me back as soon as you get this.
Holy shit!
- I can't see it. - Is that what I think it is?
Oh my god!
- Just run. - What is it?
Run! Just run! Go!
Come on, push.
Back off! Back off!
Come on!
Elaine, no!
- Move, Move! - Okay.
Baby, are you okay?
I feel like I'm in fire now.
Give me that, give it to me!
It will stop immediately. I promise.
Its alright.
You look too.
How?
Oh my god!
All those people.
What do they want with them?
I'm not looking to find out.
God, I can't believe this...
I mean how?
Once you look at the light...
...it grabs hold.
- It's like... - It controls you.
I mean who wouldn't stare at something so beautiful?
It's kind of brilliant actually.
Enough with this shit.
I got an idea.
Where are you going?
- Walt's. - What for?
- Don't worry about it. - Everything is under control.
Are you okay?
Yes. Its not matter.
Let me see.
I said its not...
- Alright. - I uhh...
Walt?
Yo. Walt?
Are you in here?
- What the hell are you doing? - Hiding.
I saw the people, in the sky.
With the god damn raptor.
Come on!
I take you in the car and get the hell out of here. Let's go!
I'm not going out there.
Get down! Get down!
Shut the dog! Shut the dog!
No!
Walt!
Did you hear that?
What's up? Talk to me!
We get on my boat and get out at here.
What happened?
They took Walt.
What are you talking about?
This one was different. It came in the building and just snatch 'em.
Then we should just go!
Hold on a sec.
Am I the only one who saw these photos?
That's all happening right outside Right now! They are everywhere.
No, they are not everywhere.
- They are not over the water. - He's right.
Yeah, well it didn't take 'em very long to find you on the roof.
We can drive there in two minutes.
You have no idea what their capable of.
I know you're scared... okay We're all scared...
But I'm not burying my head...
in the sand and open this cause away
- I'm not saying that. - Hey, look. Just take it easy, man.
- There is no easy about this. - I understand that.
They're in the fucking building. - Terry?
It's the timer.
Oh my god...
Shit!
Hide! Go! Go! Go!
You're disgusting!
What the hell is the matter with you?
- We talk about that later. - Yeah, we will talk about that.
Still want to stay?
I don't want any of this, they don't see us or hear us
so if we stay here and stay quiet...
For how long?
They're picking people out there. Plain and simple.
The further we can out of this city, the better off we are.
He's right.
Jarrod.
If we get to the boat we have a chance!
- Yes, but if we don't... - We have to!
We have to try.
Get your stuff.
Get food and water.
Let's do this.
Let's go.
Alright, come on.
Look, the sooner I get there, The sooner the boat ready to go.
Terry...
Hey! - Come on, let's go.
What are you doing?
Driving, I know the way!
- Just take your slut. - Candice.
Candice!
Get in the car!
Terry, I'm sorry.
- Hurry up. - What do you think I'm doing?
Hey, slow down.
No.
Stop.
You need any help?
- No, just go, we're fine. - Yeah, but maybe...
Enough, alright! I said we are fine.
Terry, get off!
Terry!
I got you!
Jarrod! Get your ass back at here now!
Drive! Drive now!
What are you doing?
Come on!
Open!
Oh shit! Come on!
- Open! - Come on.
Open you piece of shit!
Back off! Back off! Back off! Go!
No! Oh my god!
Oh my god! Go!
Go! This way!
Are you alright?
Yeah I'm okay.
Oh my god!
Miss, we got to go.
No, we...
He is alive!
Colin!
Help me!
Come on! Let's go!
Go!
Make for the back door.
Run!
Move! Move!
Come on!
Don't stop!
Open the door!
Get off me!
Back off! Open it!
Come on!
All the way to the top is the safest place that I can think of.
What if they're there?
And if you like being here with that, be my guest!
Let's go.
Come on! Quickly! Quickly! Quickly!
I should have helped him.
Hey! Come help me with this.
It's better than nothing, right?
Yeah, if you say so.
What are you doing huh?
Like it or not this is happening.
You got to be strong.
Is everybody okay?
Are you hurt?
No... I'm okay.
- What now? - We stay here...
We keep watch, and we pray that someone comes.
He's right.
Someone is gonna come.
It isn't come out forever.
Right?
Sweetie, it is best if we stay together.
I can't.
The smoke...
Giving this circumstances, I think smoke is more than reasonable.
Candice...
I'm pregnant, alright?
And I just thought that...and with all the stress...
It's okay.
I never have the guts to tell my mom.
Come on boss. Let the girls get some sleep. You and I keep watching.
Both of us?
If they're trying that light stuff, We got each other back.
I hate LA.
I haven't seen a soul all night.
Maybe the worse is over.
Maybe not.
What do you think these things really are?
I don't know.
Is that even matter?
It's just doesn't seem real.
Well it is real.
You better wake up.
What's that suppose to mean?
This city hasn't a blink of life.
We need to survive.
There is gonna be not many of us live.
What do you see?
Somebody is fighting back.
- What are you doing? - I want to see what's out there.
Turn that off!
It's too bright!
No! - We can't risk it!
Oh my god.
Did you sleep at all?
Was it getting worst?
What?
The marks on your skin.
You know when I looked to the light, I couldn't stand for 10 minutes.
Who knows what it did to us.
To our bodies.
You remember the first moment when you saw it?
When it completely took over.
It's kind of uh, use to feel...
...down to the floor.
And I still do.
Why don't you take a seat, relax.
Alright, I'll bite.
What's your plan boss? Because I know you're dying to tell me.
Nothing to say?
We are sitting on the marina, for Christ sake.
Yes, I notice that.
And there are hundreds of boats right across the street.
We've been through all this.
Remind us how we've failed that last time.
We go quietly this time.
And search every boat until we find the key?
If we have to...
Great plan, Jarrod.
I can't believe you even suggested that after what happened.
It wasn't my fault.
I was frenetically begging...
...but you wouldn't listen.
And you think Terry would've listened to me?
All right...
Let say we make it out of the building.
Accros the marina, down the dock
we even find a boat, and everything never mind...
- And then we get out the hell of here. - Where to?
Carolina, down the Coast?
- Anywhere is better than here! - How do you know?
We are here!
We are alive!
What was that?
What do you see?
Hallelujah.
Come on! Come on!
Everybody get down!
Elaine?
It worked.
I can not believe it! Is it over?
May I?
All this yours, boss.
You think there are more planes where they came from?
Yes.
Now they know what to do.
They will be sending help at no time.
What?
What is it?
They're not dead.
They are just really... really pissed off.
Something is happening.
We have to cover these windows.
Come help me with this.
Come back over here!
I'll find something!
Here.
Jarrod, what are you doing?
Something you can't!
What's this really about huh??
These things are coming for us.
You think that I haven't notice that mess under your shirt.
We will stay here, and hold up, for good!
I agree.
Well, I guest I decide everything.
We have no water. No power.
Yeah, but you saw what's out there.
Yeah.
And I will rather make a run for it...
...than stay in a 20 storey building.
Between those things and the radiation
...we are done up here.
Get off me!
- What the hell are you thinking? - We have to let 'em know we're here.
- To hell everything you know! - You've been saying to wait for help.
The help is here!
Does that look like a rescue chopper to you?
Don't you get it?
We're at war!
Where are they going?
Those choppers will coming back for them. We have to go.
Come on!
We'll go to the roof. Get them to pick us up.
What if they not come back? Look what happened to those planes.
- Look all those helicopters? - We have to take a chance!
A chance?
They just nuked the city.
And you want to wave hello?
Seriously You need to back off!
You have to...
Oh shit!
You just gonna stand there?
What happens when the rest of the blinds fall?
We don't have enough bed sheets.
- Come on! - How can you be so sure?
Let's go!
You have no condition to decide anything.
Who knows whose side you are.
I'm warning you.
Stop it! Both of you!
Look at his face.
He is sick.
- Do not make me hurt you! - Oh don't worry.
I'm not leaving without my family.
And there is nothing that...you can do to stop us.
Elaine, you have to trust me.
It's me.
I'm still... me.
I know.
We have to go.
He is gonna get her killed.
Come on.
Alright, let's go.
Did you see them?
They're right there.
- Help Us! - Don't move!
- Don't shoot! - No, no, wait!
- Remain where you are! - We need help, please.
Go there now.
No!
We have two civilians, we got to way them out.
I got it, we have visual on the two, get down right now.
No!
Come on.
Get it off me! God!
Go! Go! Go!
The scaffolding.
It's the only way down. Go, go!
Come on!
Elaine, run!
Vaya con dios, son of a bitch!
Help me!
Jarrod.
Look at me.
Look at me, Jarrod.
Get up, come on!
Elaine, please.
You have to go.
I'm not going anywhere without you.
Jarrod!
No!
My baby!
Jarrod...