Previously on AMC's
The Walking Dead...
Beth!
Where is Beth!?
Maggie...
I miss Maggie, and my dad.
Being afraid is what's
kept us alive.
No. It's how we kept breathing.
I know Glenn got out
and I know which way he went.
I'm gonna go get him and
I'm gonna come back for you.
Look, "Sanctuary for all.
Community for all.
Those who arrive, survive".
♪ pack your things ♪
♪ leave somehow ♪
♪ Blackbird's song ♪
♪ is over now... ♪
♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ mouths are dry... ♪
♪ river runs ♪
♪ hands are tied ♪
♪ preacher's sons ♪
♪ pack your things ♪
♪ leave somehow ♪
♪ Blackbird's song ♪
♪ is over now ♪
♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ don't be scared ♪
♪ I'm still here ♪
♪ no more time... ♪
♪ for crying tears... ♪
- You got point?
- Yeah, I got it.
Hi.
Hello.
Just you out here?
Yeah.
How long's it been
like that for?
I don't know.
I was with one group
and another one after that.
They didn't make it?
Neither one of them?
What's your name?
Bob Stookey.
You people have a camp?
How many walkers
have you killed?
Haven't kept count.
A couple dozen.
How many people you kill?
Only one.
Why?
She asked me to.
Want to come with us?
Yes.
You got any questions for us?
No.
It doesn't matter who you are.
Really?
Yeah.
It doesn't matter.
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com
Bob!
Maggie!
Let go of her!
No! No!
Bob.
It's okay.
He got me right on the bandage.
Ow.
Ow! Ow! Ow!
I didn't say stop.
I just said ow.
- Are we close?
- Almost done.
How do you know?
The signs are all there.
Just got to know
how to read 'em.
What are we tracking?
You tell me.
You're the one
who wanted to learn.
Well, something
came through here.
The pattern
is all zig-zaggy.
It's a walker.
Maybe it's a drunk.
I'm getting good at this.
Pretty soon I won't
need you at all.
Yeah, keep on tracking.
It's got a gun.
Can you move it?
Yeah.
You ready?
We should wait
till the fog clears.
We've been waiting a while.
You see all this?
We got lucky.
We need visibility.
We've got six bullets left.
She's right.
We've been doing good
following the plan.
No need to get sloppy now.
What is it?
It's broken.
We don't need it.
Sun comes up in the
east, sets in the west.
We'll keep an eye
on it in between.
We'll be fine.
Can we--
can we hold up a sec?
You all right?
I just need to sit down.
All right.
Hold up.
Hop on.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
This is a serious piggyback.
Jump up.
You're heavier than you look.
Maybe there are people there.
Yeah, if there are,
I'll handle them.
There are still
good people, Daryl.
I don't think
the good ones survive.
_
What's that?
Terminus.
When we were out on the run
to the veterinary college,
we heard a message
about this on the radio.
- They were broadcasting?
- What did it say?
Couldn't make it out.
I only know because
I'm seeing it now.
"Those who arrive survive."
We should go.
I thought we were
looking for Glenn.
If he saw one of these,
he would go looking for me
looking for him.
Look at this map.
All these tracks
from different directions
leading to the same place.
It's far.
And we don't know
if there are other signs.
You don't think
this is the only one.
This is the best lead
we've had so far.
It says sanctuary. That's
just another reason to try.
Others from the prison
could be there. Tyreese.
If it sounds too good
to be true...
Maybe if Glenn saw one of these,
maybe he felt the same way.
He wouldn't.
He'd believe, I know.
What do you want to do, Sasha?
Keep making these
circles from the bus?
Or are you talking about us
starting to do something else?
We're not splitting up.
That can't happen.
You want to take
a vote or something?
We don't need to vote.
_
Give it a minute.
It's so clean.
Yeah.
Someone's been tending to it.
May still be around.
Let's get that ankle wrapped.
Looks like somebody ran
out of dolls to dress up.
It's beautiful.
Whoever did this cared.
They wanted these people
to get a funeral.
They remembered
these things were people
before all this.
They didn't let it
change them in the end.
Don't you think
that's beautiful?
Come on.
- Where's Maggie?
- Getting more firewood.
Still bleeding?
Barely.
- So tell me...
- Tell you what?
You think we should stop.
Yeah.
Tell me why.
To not die.
You, Maggie, me.
- Yeah, that's not it.
- What?
I don't think you know
why you want to stop.
Bob, what happened
this morning,
we get warnings.
We did fine.
We get warnings.
And the next time it's on us.
Odds are Glenn is dead.
Odds are we will be, too.
That's the reality.
We got six bullets
and you're still bleeding.
Those tracks,
they run through towns.
The first one we see,
we find a building,
some higher ground
to set up in.
All of us.
That's what we need to do.
That's what we're gonna do.
If we can talk her into it.
Just think about it.
Dang.
You find anything?
Whoa.
Peanut butter and jelly,
diet soda, and pig's feet.
That's a white trash
brunch right there.
It all looks good to me.
No, hold up.
Ain't a speck of dust on this.
So?
That means somebody
just put it here.
This is someone's stash.
Maybe they're still alive.
All right, we'll take some of it and
we'll leave the rest, all right?
I knew it.
Knew what?
It's like I said.
There are still good people.
- Mm.
- Gross.
Hey, those pig's feet are mine.
♪ pine for summer ♪
♪ then we'll buy ♪
♪ a beer to shotgun ♪
♪ we'll lay on our lawn ♪
♪ and we'll be good... ♪
The place is nailed up tight.
The only way in
is through the front door.
What are you doing?
This is the comfiest bed
I've had in years.
- Really?
- I ain't kidding.
Why don't you go ahead
and play some more?
Keep singing.
I thought my singing
annoyed you.
There ain't no jukebox, so...
♪ and we'll buy... ♪
♪ a beer to shotgun ♪
♪ we'll lay on the lawn ♪
♪ and we'll be good ♪
♪ now I'm laughing
at my boredom ♪
♪ and my string
of failed attempts... ♪
Bob?
_
Bob.
Come on. She's got to
follow the tracks.
We can still catch up to her.
Sasha, we can still
catch up to her.
You have been grinning since we
left the prison in one piece.
If you're so happy to be alive,
then why are we walking
into the heart of darkness?
It's not about me being alive.
Do you even know
why you're smiling?
Oh, yeah.
I'm not alone.
That's how it happened
when I lost my first group.
And my second group.
I broke that streak.
You'd be smiling, too.
Self-awareness
is a beautiful thing.
You should try it sometime.
- Oh, you're not going to take the bait?
- Nope.
You're just as bullheaded
as she is sometimes.
You know that?
_
Yeah.
Going as fast as I can.
Forget that.
Here you go.
Whew.
All right.
Let's eat.
Stay.
It's just a damn dog.
Hi.
Come here, boy.
He wouldn't come in?
I told you to stay back.
Yeah, but, Daryl,
you said there was a dog.
Maybe he'll come
back around. Come on.
I'm awake.
So am I.
Can you see it?
No.
Been that way for an hour.
Might be stuck on something.
There's a lot
of noise at night.
Cicadas, owls.
I think sometimes
they go in circles.
Still, when I was
out here by myself,
I didn't sleep much.
You're not sleeping much now.
You've got to heal.
You need to sleep.
I can try.
I tried.
Bob, what the hell
are we doing out here?
Why do you think
Tyreese is dead?
- What? - If Tyreese were
alive, he'd go for Terminus.
I know you know that.
So why do you think he's dead?
Or are you just too afraid
to find out if he is or not?
Hmm.
Up until now, I thought you were
the toughest person I ever met.
Which is kind of weird,
'cause you were
the sweetest, too.
Just saying.
I'm gonna leave
a thank-you note.
Why?
For when they come back.
If they come back.
Even if they're not coming back,
I still want to say thanks.
Maybe you don't
have to leave that.
Maybe we stick around
here for a while.
They come back,
we'll just make it work.
They may be nuts,
but maybe it'll be all right.
So you do think there are
still good people around.
What changed your mind?
You know.
What?
I don't know.
Don't...
What changed your mind?
Oh.
I'm gonna give that mutt
one more chance.
Beth! Beth!
Run!
Beth, pry open a window.
Get your shit.
I'm not gonna leave you.
Go out. Go up the road.
I'll meet you there.
Go!
This way.
Beth! Beth!
Beth!
She's keeping to the tracks.
If we pick up the pace,
we'll catch her.
_
Bob, right there.
Secure and high up.
See if we can set up
something to catch the rain.
See if we could move from the
rooftops to look for food.
Maybe even try to grow
some up there.
Sasha, I'm not stopping.
We are.
I'm not.
She's out there alone.
She didn't want us to come.
She made her choice for her.
I don't care.
She's alone.
When I got to the prison,
I thought to myself,
"How long?
The clock's ticking.
How long until everyone else
is dead and I'm on my own?"
Bad things happened
'cause I was scared.
They didn't need to.
I didn't need to be afraid.
Now we get to Terminus
and Tyreese isn't there,
it doesn't mean he's dead.
- You don't need to be afraid.
- I am not afraid.
So this is it?
It doesn't have to be.
That's right.
I'm gonna try something here.
Well, okay.
You don't have to do it.
You don't have
to be alone again.
I won't be.
Maggie?
Oh, shit.
Where's Bob?
Out looking for you.
Why are you here?
I was looking
for another walker.
Found more than I wanted.
You know, I was lying there
and I remembered--
I heard what you said
back at the camp.
I heard you say
you thought we should
be in a town.
What else did you hear me say?
That odds are Glenn is dead.
And we should stop.
But you're wrong.
So why are you here?
'Cause I was waiting for you.
I'm not giving up.
But I need your help.
'Cause I can't do it by myself.
And even if I catch up to Bob,
we can't do it alone.
I thought that I couldn't
ask you to risk your life.
But I can.
'Cause I know what
you'd be risking it for.
And it isn't just Glenn.
I get that you're afraid.
I am.
I am afraid.
We could get there.
I know.
So let's go get Bob...
and let's get there.
Well, lookit here.
Damn it, hold up!
I'm claiming the vest.
I like them wings.
Hold up.
A bowman.
I respect that.
See, a man with a rifle, he could
have been some kind of photographer
or soccer coach
back in the day.
But a bowman's a bowman
through and through.
What you got there,
150-pound draw weight?
I'll be donkey-licked if that don't
fire at least 300 feet per second.
I've been looking
for a weapon like that.
Of course, I'd want one
with a bit more ammo
and minus the oblongata stains.
Get yourself in some
trouble, partner?
You pull that trigger,
these boys are gonna
drop you several times over.
That what you want?
Come on, fella,
suicide is stupid.
Why hurt yourself when you
can hurt other people?
Name's Joe.
Daryl.
♪ no more time ♪
♪ for crying tears... ♪
Bob.
♪ oh... ♪
♪ ooh ooh ooh ♪
♪ oh oh oh ♪
Sync and corrections by n17t01
www.addic7ed.com