1
00:00:45,290 --> 00:00:59,600
我立大地根基的時候 你在哪裡呢？
那時晨星一同歌唱 神的眾子也都在歡呼
舊約——約伯記38章 第4、7節

2
00:01:16,140 --> 00:01:18,640
兄弟
Brother...

3
00:01:23,640 --> 00:01:26,140
母親
Mother...

4
00:01:31,030 --> 00:01:33,590
他們把我帶到了你的門口
It was they who led me to your door.

5
00:02:03,900 --> 00:02:06,990
人類心靈通過兩種方式去感觸生命
A man's heart has heard two ways through life.

6
00:02:08,970 --> 00:02:10,560
歸於自然
The way of nature.

7
00:02:11,670 --> 00:02:13,200
以及--感恩
And the way of grace.

8
00:02:15,010 --> 00:02:17,710
你一生中將選擇你感觸生命的方式
You have to choose which one you'll follow.

9
00:02:30,260 --> 00:02:32,450
感恩的意義並非只是單純的感恩
Grace doesn't try to please itself.

10
00:02:35,160 --> 00:02:39,430
而是對一切蔑視、遺忘、厭惡等等劣性的寬恕
It accepts being slighted, forgotten, disliked...

11
00:02:43,870 --> 00:02:46,770
甚至寬恕侮辱和傷害
It accepts insults and injuries.

12
00:03:05,230 --> 00:03:07,790
而自然的意義卻在於其自在隨性之本源
Nature only wants to please itself.

13
00:03:08,600 --> 00:03:10,570
感謝我主賜予我們食物...
Bless our lord this food...

14
00:03:10,700 --> 00:03:12,630
並使其它人與自然之物也能夠感受這種博大的本源
Get others to please it too.

15
00:03:12,870 --> 00:03:14,360
...你忠貞不渝的僕人...
...Loving and faithful service...

16
00:03:14,500 --> 00:03:16,470
它統管世間一切
It likes to lord it over them.

17
00:03:16,670 --> 00:03:18,300
...祝福孩子們...
...Bless these boys...

18
00:03:18,710 --> 00:03:20,500
用它自己的方式.
To have its own way.

19
00:03:25,280 --> 00:03:27,710
即使全世界都沐浴在陽光之下
It finds reasons to be unhappy.

20
00:03:27,980 --> 00:03:30,780
真愛環繞著世間萬物
When all the world is shining around it.

21
00:03:32,290 --> 00:03:35,190
它也能清楚的知曉不幸從何而來
And love is smiling through all things.

22
00:03:50,440 --> 00:03:53,930
他們教導我說, 懷有感恩之心的世人
They taught us, that no one
who loves the way of grace,

23
00:03:54,310 --> 00:03:56,680
總會好人有好報的
ever comes to a bad end.

24
00:04:04,650 --> 00:04:06,590
無論發生任何事
I will be true to you.

25
00:04:08,860 --> 00:04:10,620
我都將對你真誠以待
Whatever comes...

26
00:06:31,870 --> 00:06:33,100
我的孩子啊.
My son.

27
00:06:42,480 --> 00:06:45,340
我真想跟他一起死了算了.
I just want to die. To be with him.

28
00:07:26,860 --> 00:07:29,150
他現在正在我主手中.
He's in God's hands now.

29
00:07:35,900 --> 00:07:38,230
他一直都在我主手中.
He was in God's hands the whole time.

30
00:07:41,240 --> 00:07:42,530
不是麼？
Wasn't he?

31
00:07:47,180 --> 00:07:48,610
我的家啊
My home.

32
00:07:54,080 --> 00:07:55,640
我的神啊
My God.

33
00:08:02,220 --> 00:08:04,280
我不會恐懼的
I shall fear no evil.

34
00:08:05,790 --> 00:08:08,660
因你在我身旁，我才不會恐懼
Fear no evil, for you are with me.

35
00:08:08,830 --> 00:08:10,630
你現在又如何了呢？
What did you gain?

36
00:08:10,830 --> 00:08:13,600
求你不要遠離我，我快撐不住了
Be not far from me, for trouble is near.

37
00:08:13,770 --> 00:08:15,530
走吧，沒事兒了
Go on now, we're alright.

38
00:08:18,010 --> 00:08:19,500
沒事兒了
We're alright.

39
00:08:28,980 --> 00:08:30,580
謝謝
Thank you.

40
00:08:36,890 --> 00:08:38,760
別再想他了...
Shouldn't have your memories of him, ...

41
00:08:40,160 --> 00:08:42,220
你得堅強起來啊, 並且...
You have to be strong now, and...

42
00:08:45,530 --> 00:08:49,370
我知道，痛苦將...總將會過去的
I know, the pain will, it will pass in time.

43
00:08:50,140 --> 00:08:52,200
你知道...也許會...
You know, it might seem,

44
00:08:52,370 --> 00:08:54,770
比較難熬，但說真的，總會過去的。
hard, my saying that, but it's true.

45
00:08:54,940 --> 00:08:56,930
...我也不想這樣啊...
I don't want it to.

46
00:08:59,350 --> 00:09:01,080
逝者已逝
Life goes on.

47
00:09:03,250 --> 00:09:05,120
生活還得繼續啊
People pass along.

48
00:09:06,960 --> 00:09:08,750
雖然一切都在變化之中
Nothing stays the same.

49
00:09:12,560 --> 00:09:14,590
你還有其它兩個孩子啊
You still got the other two.

50
00:09:21,470 --> 00:09:24,500
主會賜予，也會帶走
The Lord gives and the Lord takes away.

51
00:09:26,140 --> 00:09:27,670
這就是他的方式
That's the way he is.

52
00:09:34,050 --> 00:09:38,380
所以，有些時候主也會在傷口撒鹽
He sends flies to wounds...that he should heal.

53
00:09:55,670 --> 00:09:59,470
我再也沒機會對他說對不起了
I never got a chance to tell him how sorry I was.

54
00:10:04,850 --> 00:10:06,840
我甚至...
I even...

55
00:10:08,880 --> 00:10:12,650
...不分青紅皂白的打過他
...punched himself in the face for no reason.

56
00:10:20,300 --> 00:10:24,790
你緊挨我坐在鋼琴前
我罵他琴譜翻錯頁了
You sit next to me at the piano
and I criticized where he'd turned the pages.

57
00:10:42,750 --> 00:10:45,240
我甚至感到羞愧難當
I might even feel ashamed.

58
00:10:46,520 --> 00:10:48,510
為何羞愧？
Why shame?

59
00:10:54,300 --> 00:10:57,230
可憐的孩子啊，可憐的孩子啊
Poor boy. Poor boy.

60
00:11:27,800 --> 00:11:29,890
你是如何來到我身邊的呢？
How did you come to me?

61
00:11:36,910 --> 00:11:38,870
什麼模樣？
In what shape?

62
00:11:43,510 --> 00:11:45,270
什麼角色？
What disguise?

63
00:13:09,200 --> 00:13:11,460
我看到了我的童年時光
I see the child I was.

64
00:13:20,680 --> 00:13:23,110
看到了我的兄弟們
I see my brother.

65
00:13:26,410 --> 00:13:27,940
真誠
True.

66
00:13:30,720 --> 00:13:32,120
善良
Kind.

67
00:13:38,790 --> 00:13:41,460
他去世時只有19歲
He died when he was 19.

68
00:14:14,200 --> 00:14:17,190
檢查一下，這個對應這個
Just check, this one against this.

69
00:14:17,400 --> 00:14:19,390
她要一起回來
She wants to get back together.

70
00:14:19,870 --> 00:14:22,630
但是，木已成舟
But, the chapter's closed, the story's been told.

71
00:14:24,740 --> 00:14:26,070
你怎麼辦？
What are you gonna do?

72
00:14:27,540 --> 00:14:29,030
試試吧
Experiment.

73
00:14:33,180 --> 00:14:35,670
你還年輕，這都是為了你的前程
When you're young, it's all about your career.

74
00:14:46,300 --> 00:14:50,400
我只是感覺，我...撞到牆了...
I just feel like I'm...bumping into walls...

75
00:15:07,220 --> 00:15:11,450
整個世界一團糟，人心壞了，越來越貪婪
The world's gone to the dogs,
people are greedy and keep getting worse.

76
00:15:15,860 --> 00:15:18,550
我想要阻止這一切
I try to get into their hands.

77
00:15:26,300 --> 00:15:30,860
嗨，爸，我為我說過的話感到對不起，我...
Hey dad, I'm sorry I said what I said, I'm...

78
00:15:36,910 --> 00:15:40,780
是的，我每天都在想他
真的對不起，我真的不該說...
Yea, I think about him every day.
I just shouldn't have said what I did, I'm sorry.

79
00:15:51,760 --> 00:15:54,280
你想什麼呢？
我知道，我知道你作的...
What are you thinking?
I know, I know what you did...

80
00:15:56,300 --> 00:15:59,960
客戶只拒絕了它們中的兩個...
And only two of those were turned down by client...

81
00:16:20,660 --> 00:16:22,780
我如何失去的你？
How did I lose you?

82
00:16:29,960 --> 00:16:31,990
迷惘
Wandered.

83
00:16:36,240 --> 00:16:38,170
忘卻你
Forgot you.

84
00:17:37,900 --> 00:17:39,390
找到我
Find me.

85
00:18:04,430 --> 00:18:06,390
她怎麼能受得了
How did she bear it?

86
00:18:16,100 --> 00:18:17,570
媽媽
Mother.

87
00:18:55,380 --> 00:18:57,540
我做錯了什麼嗎？
Was I false to you?

88
00:19:44,290 --> 00:19:46,060
主啊...
Lord...

89
00:19:53,330 --> 00:19:54,670
為什麼？
Why?

90
00:20:02,680 --> 00:20:04,580
你在哪兒啊？
Where were you?

91
00:21:06,210 --> 00:21:07,870
你知道麼？
Did you know?

92
00:21:24,230 --> 00:21:26,490
對你來說，我們是誰呢？
Who are we to you?

93
00:21:45,910 --> 00:21:47,440
回答我啊
Answer me.

94
00:25:58,970 --> 00:26:01,030
我們對你哭泣
We cry to you.

95
00:26:07,370 --> 00:26:08,860
我的心靈
My soul.

96
00:26:18,050 --> 00:26:19,640
我的孩子
My son.

97
00:26:28,000 --> 00:26:29,720
聽我們說
Hear us.

98
00:34:34,110 --> 00:34:36,140
點亮我的生活
Light up my life.

99
00:34:39,620 --> 00:34:41,420
我在找尋你
I search for you.

100
00:34:46,390 --> 00:34:47,520
我的家園
My home.

101
00:34:58,510 --> 00:35:00,000
我的孩子
My child.

102
00:36:19,990 --> 00:36:22,180
你通過她對我說
You spoke to me through her.

103
00:36:26,030 --> 00:36:28,430
你的聲音從天上傳來
You spoke with me from the sky.

104
00:36:30,500 --> 00:36:32,190
從樹林中傳來
The trees.

105
00:36:37,140 --> 00:36:39,130
在我感到愛你之前...
Before I knew I loved you ...

106
00:36:41,910 --> 00:36:43,600
信仰你之前
Believed in you.

107
00:37:02,200 --> 00:37:05,130
你是何時第一次觸動了我的心扉啊
When did you first touch my heart?

108
00:39:39,820 --> 00:39:44,090
...並且在他的旗幟指引下，
像個男人一樣對抗邪惡、世界和魔鬼...
...And manfully to fight under His banner
against sin, the world, and the devil...

109
00:40:25,430 --> 00:40:29,700
我們和麥克曼德先生一起吃晚餐
獲得了兩個投標權
We're having Mr. McMander over for dinner.
This is a double bidder right on in.

110
00:42:11,040 --> 00:42:12,830
這是什麼啊？
What's this?

111
00:42:13,040 --> 00:42:15,870
兩隻鱷魚
對，兩隻鱷魚
Two alligators.
Two alligators.

112
00:42:21,510 --> 00:42:24,180
袋鼠
袋鼠
Kangaroo.
Kangaroo.

113
00:42:28,860 --> 00:42:36,260
跳啊，跳啊，跳啊，跳啊
Jump. Jump. Jump. Jump.

114
00:43:42,260 --> 00:43:43,420
寶貝
Sweetheart.

115
00:43:46,170 --> 00:43:47,460
別介啊
Please.

116
00:43:50,140 --> 00:43:51,300
我知道了
I know.

117
00:43:51,340 --> 00:43:53,530
不行，不行
No! No!

118
00:44:18,840 --> 00:44:20,740
是我的
It's mine!

119
00:44:24,440 --> 00:44:26,170
哦，你找到我啦，呵呵
You found me!

120
00:45:02,210 --> 00:45:05,200
你將和小樹一起成長
You'll be grown before that tree is tall.

121
00:45:10,020 --> 00:45:12,080
藍色的遠方
Blue far.

122
00:45:14,590 --> 00:45:15,680
你
You.

123
00:45:29,140 --> 00:45:30,660
害怕嗎？
Are you afraid?

124
00:45:32,810 --> 00:45:34,070
過來
Come here.

125
00:46:27,760 --> 00:46:31,960
過來，沒事兒，到這兒來
離那兒遠點兒，那是斯賓塞的院子，好不好？
Come here. Alright, now come back here son,
stay out of there. That's Spencer's yard, okay?

126
00:46:32,670 --> 00:46:34,220
看見這條線了麼？
You see this line?

127
00:46:34,600 --> 00:46:36,530
不能越過它，明白麼？
Let's not cross it, you understand?

128
00:46:37,640 --> 00:46:39,000
明白了麼？
Do you understand?

129
00:46:40,070 --> 00:46:42,040
看見這條線了麼？看這兒，看這兒。
Do you see this line? Look it here. Look here.

130
00:46:44,740 --> 00:46:47,410
快回來，回來
Okay, now come back here son. Come on back.

131
00:46:54,690 --> 00:46:56,380
離那兒遠點兒
Let's stay out of there.

132
00:47:12,940 --> 00:47:15,910
"親愛的"兔子奶奶一天早上說
"Now, my dears" said old Mrs. Rabbit one morning,

133
00:47:16,440 --> 00:47:19,410
"你可以去田野或小巷"
"You may go into the fields or down the lane"

134
00:47:19,950 --> 00:47:22,610
"但是別去麥格雷戈先生的花園"
"Don't go into Mr. Mcgregor's garden"

135
00:47:23,380 --> 00:47:25,540
"你父親就是在那兒發生的意外"
"Your father had an accident there"

136
00:47:31,390 --> 00:47:33,820
主就生活在那兒
That's where God lives.

137
00:48:01,650 --> 00:48:05,520
晚安，五年後再見
Goodnight, we'll see you in 5 years.

138
00:49:02,140 --> 00:49:03,640
吃蚱蜢麼？
Want to eat a grasshopper?

139
00:49:04,820 --> 00:49:06,410
我找到了，我找到骨頭了
I found it! I found this old bone!

140
00:50:18,990 --> 00:50:21,620
感謝賜予我們食物
Bless this food to our use.

141
00:50:21,630 --> 00:50:24,350
你忠貞不渝的僕人
As to your loving and faithful service.

142
00:50:24,530 --> 00:50:27,160
讓我們牢記那些需要幫助的人.
Make us remindful of those who are in need.

143
00:50:27,530 --> 00:50:28,500
阿門.
Amen.

144
00:50:36,380 --> 00:50:38,540
幫我把黃油拿過來好麼？
Can you pass the butter, please?

145
00:50:39,450 --> 00:50:41,470
幫我把黃油拿過來好麼？先生？
Can you pass the butter please sir.

146
00:50:41,610 --> 00:50:42,810
先生
Sir.

147
00:50:44,050 --> 00:50:47,580
今天幹什麼你？
上學了
What did you do today?
We went to school.

148
00:50:48,120 --> 00:50:49,850
然後呢？
After that.

149
00:50:50,620 --> 00:50:52,250
在院子裡呢？
What about the yard?

150
00:50:52,660 --> 00:50:54,650
照我說的把東西都放到該放的地方了麼？
Did you put the runners in like I asked?

151
00:50:56,300 --> 00:50:57,420
是的
Yes.

152
00:50:58,230 --> 00:50:59,660
是的，先生
Yes, sir.

153
00:51:01,130 --> 00:51:02,690
是麼？好像沒有吧？
Well, it didn't look like it.

154
00:51:19,590 --> 00:51:20,680
好的
Yes.

155
00:51:34,300 --> 00:51:36,140
裡斯先生喜歡傑克的讀後感
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report.

156
00:51:36,140 --> 00:51:38,800
親愛的，沒人關心
Nobody's asked sweetheart.

157
00:51:39,770 --> 00:51:41,260
你知道的
You know this.

158
00:52:05,160 --> 00:52:07,260
孩子們
先生
Son.
Sir.

159
00:52:09,300 --> 00:52:11,360
把打火機拿過來
Reach me my lighter.

160
00:52:18,910 --> 00:52:21,140
忘了點兒什麼麼？
Haven't you forgotten something?

161
00:52:46,040 --> 00:52:47,600
你愛你父親麼？
Do you love your father?

162
00:52:49,210 --> 00:52:50,440
是的，先生
Yes, sir.

163
00:52:55,390 --> 00:52:58,940
...然後他們去尋找岩石蟒蛇卡亞
...and they went off to look for Kaa the Rock Python.

164
00:53:01,850 --> 00:53:05,150
他們發現，在正午的陽光下，他躺在一個溫暖的窗台下
They found him stretched out
on a warm ledge in the afternoon sun.

165
00:53:06,560 --> 00:53:08,930
欣賞著他那美麗的新上衣
Admiring his beautiful new coat.

166
00:53:18,770 --> 00:53:20,800
你最愛誰
Who do you love most?

167
00:53:26,610 --> 00:53:28,710
你們三個我一樣愛
I love you all three the same.

168
00:53:30,350 --> 00:53:33,720
給我們講一個以前講過的故事吧？
Tell us a story from before we can remember.

169
00:53:37,420 --> 00:53:39,860
他有一次乘飛機飛行.
He went for a ride in a plane once.

170
00:53:43,060 --> 00:53:44,960
那是個畢業禮物.
It was a graduation present.

171
00:54:00,710 --> 00:54:01,770
媽媽...
Mother...

172
00:54:11,090 --> 00:54:12,520
我好不好？
Am I any good?

173
00:54:20,530 --> 00:54:21,900
勇敢麼？
Brave.

174
00:57:21,380 --> 00:57:23,210
每個人都會這樣麼？
Can it happen to anyone?

175
00:57:30,360 --> 00:57:32,190
沒人談起它
Nobody talks about it.

176
00:57:37,000 --> 00:57:39,490
幫幫我，讓我別跟我爸頂嘴
Help me not to sass my dad.

177
00:57:41,240 --> 00:57:44,810
幫幫我，別讓狗打架了
Help me not to get dogs in fights.

178
00:57:58,640 --> 00:58:01,640
幫幫我，感恩於所有所得
Help me be thankful for everything I've got.

179
00:58:03,690 --> 00:58:05,660
你住在哪兒啊？
Where do you live?

180
00:58:07,090 --> 00:58:09,580
幫幫我，別讓我撒謊了
Help me not to tell lies.

181
00:58:16,340 --> 00:58:18,330
你在看著我麼？
Are you watching me?

182
00:58:28,810 --> 00:58:30,870
我想知道你是什麼樣的？
I want to know what you are.

183
00:58:37,460 --> 00:58:39,820
我想看到你所見的
I want to see what you see.

184
00:59:36,150 --> 00:59:37,480
過來
Come here.

185
00:59:48,460 --> 00:59:52,090
站在那兒，把門安靜的關上50次
You're going to stand there and
you're going to close this door quietly, 50 times.

186
00:59:53,100 --> 00:59:54,400
大聲的數出數兒來
Count it out.

187
00:59:56,030 --> 00:59:59,370
3, 4, 5,
3, 4, 5,

188
01:00:00,370 --> 01:00:03,430
6, 7, 8
6, 7, 8

189
01:00:04,610 --> 01:00:08,380
得連根兒拔起，不能只拔上面兒的
You can't just take off the top.
You got to get them by the roots.

190
01:00:16,620 --> 01:00:18,110
你母親是天真的
Your mother's naive.

191
01:00:18,290 --> 01:00:20,620
要想出人頭地，必須處處拔尖
It takes fierce will to get ahead in this world.

192
01:00:22,790 --> 01:00:25,320
如果你夠優秀，別人都會用你
If you're good, people take advantage of you.

193
01:00:31,740 --> 01:00:35,100
這些高管們，你知道他們都是怎麼坐上這個位置的麼？
Every one of these top executives,
you know how they got where they are?

194
01:00:35,310 --> 01:00:37,570
一鼓作氣，想做就做
Floated right down the middle of the river.

195
01:00:40,110 --> 01:00:43,280
沒有什麼是做不到的
Don't let anyone tell you
there's anything you can't do.

196
01:00:45,420 --> 01:00:48,320
千萬別跟我學
Don't do like I did, promise me that.

197
01:00:50,660 --> 01:00:52,820
夢想當個音樂家
Dreamed of being a great musician.

198
01:00:53,490 --> 01:00:55,860
可我卻沒有堅持到底
I let myself get sidetracked.

199
01:00:57,060 --> 01:01:01,150
如果你有夢想，就一定要堅持到底，
要讓你的生命沒有遺憾
If you're looking for something to happen,
that was it. Life, lived it.

200
01:01:18,350 --> 01:01:21,650
約伯認為住在高處就可躲避災難，但是非難依舊
（牧師口中的故事出自《舊約.聖經》之約伯記）
Job imagined he might build his nest on high.

201
01:01:22,690 --> 01:01:27,060
他認為他為人正直，本不應遭受諸多非難
That the integrity of his behavior
would protect him against misfortune.

202
01:01:27,430 --> 01:01:30,450
但是約伯的朋友們卻不這麼認為
And his friends thought mistakenly

203
01:01:30,600 --> 01:01:34,330
他們認為，上帝懲罰約伯，
一定是因為約伯私下裡幹了什麼見不得人的勾當
That the Lord could only have punished him
because secretly he had done something wrong.

204
01:01:36,000 --> 01:01:37,230
但是事實並非如此
But no.

205
01:01:37,540 --> 01:01:39,560
禍兮福所倚，福兮禍所伏
Misfortune befalls the good as well.

206
01:01:41,210 --> 01:01:43,540
我們不可能永遠遠離災禍
We can't protect ourselves against it.

207
01:01:43,740 --> 01:01:45,730
我們的孩子也不可能絕對一世平安
We can't protect our children.

208
01:01:45,910 --> 01:01:48,780
不幸之時，我們要雪中送炭
We can't say to ourselves,
even if I'm not happy,

209
01:01:48,950 --> 01:01:51,810
而不能雪上加霜
I'm going to make sure they are.

210
01:01:52,050 --> 01:01:55,950
吾以為風可載我而行
We run before the wind, we
think that it will carry us forever.

211
01:01:56,790 --> 01:01:58,260
然非也
It will not.

212
01:01:58,420 --> 01:02:02,550
人生消散如浮雲，逝去如落葉
We vanish as a cloud,
we whither as the autumn grass.

213
01:02:02,690 --> 01:02:05,290
然而新的生命又有如新枝抽芽一般生機勃勃
And like a tree, are rooted up.

214
01:02:08,030 --> 01:02:11,260
這般紛亂，是因萬能的宇宙出錯了麼？
Is there some fraud in the scheme of the universe?

215
01:02:11,400 --> 01:02:13,700
又有什麼可以永生不滅麼？
Is there nothing which is deathless?

216
01:02:13,840 --> 01:02:16,670
答案是沒有，沒有什麼是不朽的
Nothing, which does not pass away?

217
01:02:18,840 --> 01:02:21,210
我們不能停滯不前
We cannot stay where we are.

218
01:02:21,380 --> 01:02:23,470
我們要不斷進取
We must journey forth.

219
01:02:23,650 --> 01:02:27,380
找尋那比財富更重要的人生目標
We must find that which is
greater than fortune or fate.

220
01:02:28,950 --> 01:02:31,860
人生除此別無他求
Nothing can bring us peace, but that.

221
01:02:33,290 --> 01:02:37,460
勇者和智者也是血肉之軀
Is the body of the wise man or
the just, exempt from any pain?

222
01:02:38,700 --> 01:02:43,290
美貌終究會枯萎
From any disquietude, from the deformity
that might blight its beauty

223
01:02:43,440 --> 01:02:47,060
健康終究抵不過頑疾
from the weakness, that might destroy its health.

224
01:02:48,870 --> 01:02:54,170
你信上帝麼？約伯相信上帝，
所以他離上帝很近
Do you trust in God? Job too,
was close to the Lord.

225
01:02:55,550 --> 01:02:58,570
沒有什麼苟且可以瞞天過海
Are your friends and children, your security?

226
01:03:00,050 --> 01:03:04,180
世間也沒有任何角落，可以躲過宿難
There is no hiding place in all
the world where trouble may not find you.

227
01:03:04,490 --> 01:03:09,150
約伯為躲避危難煞費苦心，最終仍卻躲不過
所以說，世間之事，該來的總會來，躲也躲不過
No one knows when sorrow might
visit his house, any more than Job did.

228
01:03:10,560 --> 01:03:13,120
約伯曾經一無所有
At the very moment
everything was taken away from Job.

229
01:03:13,270 --> 01:03:16,670
他知道是神拿走了他的一切
He knew it was the
Lord who had taken it away

230
01:03:19,240 --> 01:03:24,930
回顧過去，久久他才頓悟何為永恆
Return from the passing shows of time
He saught that which is eternal.

231
01:03:26,140 --> 01:03:29,310
當上帝將手指向約伯，
約伯在上帝手中看到了神曾給予他的一切
As he alone see God's hand, who sees that he gives.

232
01:03:30,650 --> 01:03:35,910
同時約伯也看到了上帝從他那裡帶走的一切
Or does not also the one see
God's hand, who sees that he takes away.

233
01:03:37,190 --> 01:03:42,420
當上帝轉身面對約伯時
Or does he alone see God,
who sees God turn his face towards him?

234
01:03:43,700 --> 01:03:48,530
上帝也正在背對約伯
（說明任何事物都具有兩面性）
Does not also he see God,
who sees God turn his back.

235
01:03:48,700 --> 01:03:50,170
那是我的一個朋友
He's a friend of mine.

236
01:03:50,300 --> 01:03:52,030
在鎮上作房地產生意
The one who's after real estate in town.

237
01:03:53,510 --> 01:03:55,170
弗蘭克約翰遜
Frank Johnson.

238
01:03:56,210 --> 01:03:58,200
理髮師出身
Started out as a barber.

239
01:03:59,950 --> 01:04:02,210
現在專門建造大型建築
He built something, big.

240
01:04:03,980 --> 01:04:06,920
他比神有錢多了.
Now you'd think he was the
fourth person of the Holy Trinity.

241
01:04:09,250 --> 01:04:11,250
但卻從不和別人談自己多有錢
They never talk about their money.

242
01:04:14,790 --> 01:04:16,850
有時候，一步錯
Wrong people go hungry.

243
01:04:18,200 --> 01:04:19,790
步步錯
Die.

244
01:04:22,000 --> 01:04:23,800
有時候卻贏一步，勝全局
Wrong people get loved.

245
01:04:26,840 --> 01:04:28,900
世界就是這麼變化莫測
The world lives by a trigger.

246
01:04:31,640 --> 01:04:34,440
所以說，有時候也不一定非得特別優秀才能成功
（就是說，天時、地利、人和，以及運氣對於成功來說也很重要）
You want to succeed? You can't be too good.

247
01:04:42,150 --> 01:04:44,990
嘿嘿，小伙子，嘗嘗哥的玉米餅啊
Hey there young fella, try my cornbread.

248
01:04:46,190 --> 01:04:48,250
來吧，再給你加點兒黃油
Do y'all want some butter, do you?

249
01:04:50,260 --> 01:04:52,200
來點兒麵包吧
How about a pound of bread.

250
01:05:19,560 --> 01:05:22,850
你感興趣，對麼？來吧
You'll like this right? Okay? Come on.

251
01:05:23,090 --> 01:05:25,860
假裝你現在遇到麻煩了
假裝你示弱了，假裝不想打架
Act like you're in trouble,
you don't want to fight, you don't want any trouble.

252
01:05:26,000 --> 01:05:28,020
然而，就趁他一不留神的時候，一擊即中，將他打到
The minute you see him blink, crack him!

253
01:05:28,170 --> 01:05:29,390
好嗎?
Okay?

254
01:05:29,570 --> 01:05:32,400
好，來吧，第三局開始嘍
防守，你正在防守，對麼？
Okay, come on, three quarters.
Cover, you're going to cover, right?

255
01:05:32,570 --> 01:05:36,970
好的，來吧，好的，再使點兒勁兒
右手打的不錯，現在再從左邊打過來
Okay, here. Come on, nice, harder, nice.
That's a good right, let's see your left.

256
01:05:37,610 --> 01:05:42,170
讓我告訴你訣竅是什麼
這樣，你從這邊兒打過來，同時保持警惕
This is the most important thing.
Okay? You come in this way, keep your gaurd up.

257
01:05:43,110 --> 01:05:45,410
揍我，快點兒，揍我啊，快，傑克？揍我啊
Hit me, come on, hit me. Come on, Jack? Hit me.

258
01:05:45,550 --> 01:05:47,280
揍我啊，快來啊，快點兒
Hit me, come on, come on!

259
01:05:47,420 --> 01:05:49,280
好吧，來吧，快來揍我吧
Okay, here it is, hit me!

260
01:05:49,420 --> 01:05:50,750
來啊，兒子，來啊
Come on, son, come on!

261
01:05:50,920 --> 01:05:53,080
你他媽干屁呢？
What are you doing?

262
01:05:56,630 --> 01:05:58,860
自己把身上弄乾淨了
Wipe yourself off.

263
01:06:00,030 --> 01:06:03,020
左直拳，把嘴閉上，保持警惕
Left! Don't leave your tongue out,
you're going to lose it!

264
01:06:03,170 --> 01:06:06,660
左直拳，左直拳，右直拳，右直拳
Left. Left. Right. Right.

265
01:06:07,540 --> 01:06:09,100
左直拳，使勁兒啊
Left harder.

266
01:06:09,270 --> 01:06:11,830
使勁兒，使勁兒啊
Harder. Harder!

267
01:06:12,440 --> 01:06:15,000
來揍我，揍我，快，兒子，揍我
Hit me, hit me. Come on son, hit.

268
01:06:15,150 --> 01:06:17,610
然我見識見識你有多厲害，使出你的渾身解數來啊
Give me something, show me what you got.

269
01:06:19,180 --> 01:06:21,050
來吧，繼續
Come on, go on.

270
01:06:27,490 --> 01:06:28,860
好好吃飯
One meal.

271
01:06:44,380 --> 01:06:46,070
滾蛋
Leave the table.

272
01:06:52,280 --> 01:06:53,750
你也藐視我麼？
You too?

273
01:06:55,690 --> 01:06:57,780
跟你弟弟一樣藐視我麼？
沒有，先生
You going to continue to defy me?
No, sir.

274
01:06:57,960 --> 01:07:00,650
我還沒吃完，你倆就跟我鬧？你們打擾我吃飯了
You're interrupting me, I wasn't done yet.

275
01:07:03,830 --> 01:07:05,600
我吃完了麼？
Am I finished?

276
01:07:06,560 --> 01:07:09,870
沒有麼？
是的，沒有
No?
Yea

277
01:07:09,870 --> 01:07:11,960
謝謝你，陛下
Thank you, your majesty.

278
01:08:08,490 --> 01:08:10,190
編故事
Makes up stories.

279
01:08:13,670 --> 01:08:15,720
說好聽的.
Fortunate words.

280
01:08:24,040 --> 01:08:27,100
他總說別把胳臂肘放到桌子上
He says don't put your elbows on the table.

281
01:08:28,480 --> 01:08:29,970
但他卻不這麼作
He does.

282
01:08:33,920 --> 01:08:36,180
侮辱人
Insults people.

283
01:08:37,660 --> 01:08:39,250
漠視人
Doesn't care.

284
01:08:39,690 --> 01:08:41,120
我記得你剛出生的時候
I remember when you were born.

285
01:08:46,760 --> 01:08:48,250
他們不讓我回家
They wouldn't let me come home.

286
01:08:50,270 --> 01:08:55,140
海軍規定軍官不能擅離職守
Navy said an officer must be
present for the laying of the cue.

287
01:08:56,370 --> 01:08:58,040
但我必須回來
I had to launch.

288
01:09:42,090 --> 01:09:43,880
下一個單詞是volcano.
The next word is volcano.

289
01:09:54,630 --> 01:09:56,730
下一個單詞是socket.
Next word is socket.

290
01:10:03,040 --> 01:10:06,740
請將答卷給同桌，並互相打分
Please pass your answers to each other.
We're going to grade each others' papers now.

291
01:10:13,050 --> 01:10:14,680
別鬧了，行不行
No interruptions, please.

292
01:10:16,490 --> 01:10:19,890
別把鉛筆放嘴裡
Come on, get your pencil out.

293
01:11:39,870 --> 01:11:42,070
寶貝，我的神啊，寶貝啊
Sweetheart!, Oh God, sweetheart!

294
01:11:43,440 --> 01:11:44,870
親愛的
Honey!

295
01:13:14,300 --> 01:13:15,890
很糟糕麼？
Was it bad?

296
01:13:25,440 --> 01:13:28,070
你也會死麼？
Will you die too?

297
01:13:30,450 --> 01:13:32,510
你還沒老呢媽媽
You're not that old yet mom.

298
01:13:50,870 --> 01:13:52,560
你在哪兒
Where were you?

299
01:14:04,850 --> 01:14:06,540
你的一個孩子死了
You had a boy die.

300
01:14:14,160 --> 01:14:16,250
發生了什麼事情？
Would anything happen?

301
01:14:29,310 --> 01:14:32,140
我看不見了
我看不見了
I can't see!
I can't see!

302
01:14:37,050 --> 01:14:39,280
如果你不幸
Why should I be good?

303
01:14:42,450 --> 01:14:44,320
我也不會開心
If you aren't.

304
01:15:33,940 --> 01:15:35,430
謝謝你
Thank you.

305
01:15:50,550 --> 01:15:52,950
我們快完事兒了
We're close.

306
01:15:55,130 --> 01:15:56,890
這兒怎麼禿了？
Why's this bare here?

307
01:15:57,730 --> 01:15:59,660
樹下面就是不長草的
The grass wont grow under the tree.

308
01:15:59,660 --> 01:16:02,620
這兒不是金布爾斯，他們可以雇園丁
It does at Kimbles.
They have a gardener.

309
01:16:02,970 --> 01:16:04,460
他們有錢
They have money.

310
01:16:04,840 --> 01:16:06,830
當然，是繼承來的錢
Of course he inherited it.

311
01:16:08,370 --> 01:16:12,740
可那不是我們家，在咱家，如果活兒沒幹完就不要抱怨
I don't want to hear one more
word out of you, not until this is finished.

312
01:16:52,650 --> 01:16:54,380
你種的太密了
You're cropping that too close.

313
01:16:54,790 --> 01:16:56,950
記得按時澆水
You're going to have to keep that water.

314
01:17:23,750 --> 01:17:25,050
托斯卡尼尼
Toskanini.

315
01:17:25,750 --> 01:17:29,080
有一次錄一個片段錄了65次才滿意，
你知道他錄完後說了什麼麼？
Once recorded a piece 65 times.
You know what he said when he finished?

316
01:17:30,150 --> 01:17:32,050
還不夠好
It could be better.

317
01:17:34,130 --> 01:17:35,560
想想吧
Think about it.

318
01:17:37,930 --> 01:17:41,020
你老爸有27項專利
27 patents, your father has.

319
01:17:42,400 --> 01:17:44,990
那是一種所有權，對創意的所有權
It means ownership, ownership of ideas.

320
01:17:46,540 --> 01:17:50,440
你得讓別人服你
You gotta sew them up.
Get them by the nuts if you pardon my French.

321
01:17:52,510 --> 01:17:54,100
發財
Be rich.

322
01:17:56,550 --> 01:17:58,780
自己的路自己走
You make yourself what you are.

323
01:18:02,720 --> 01:18:04,450
命運由自己掌控
You have control of your own destiny.

324
01:18:08,290 --> 01:18:09,950
永遠不說「不行」
Can't say I can't.

325
01:18:11,530 --> 01:18:13,430
我現在雖然有麻煩
You see I'm having trouble.

326
01:18:14,800 --> 01:18:19,360
但事情沒結束，我就永遠不會說我解決不了
I'm not done yet. Can't say I can't.

327
01:18:54,710 --> 01:18:56,700
他為什麼總傷害我們
Why's he hurt us?

328
01:18:59,010 --> 01:19:01,070
我們的父親？
Our father?

329
01:19:07,080 --> 01:19:10,610
快來文斯，來啊，接住，接住啊
Come on Vince!, come on. Get it, get it!

330
01:19:24,670 --> 01:19:26,570
親親爸爸
Give your father a kiss.

331
01:20:06,310 --> 01:20:09,250
撒謊
Lies.

332
01:20:11,220 --> 01:20:12,910
不，我不能
幫我個忙好麼？
I can't.
Will you do something for me?

333
01:20:13,350 --> 01:20:14,410
保證能做好麼？
Do you promise you'll do it?

334
01:20:14,750 --> 01:20:18,190
只要是爸爸吩咐你去做的，就不管什麼都會去做麼？
Without having to ask what it is? Just have the
confidence in what your father asks of you is right?

335
01:20:18,520 --> 01:20:19,920
是的，先生
Yes sir.

336
01:20:20,460 --> 01:20:24,150
從現在開始半個小時裡能一句話都別說麼？
除非有什麼特別重要的事兒
In the next half hour, will you not speak
unless you have something important to say?

337
01:20:30,830 --> 01:20:32,800
我最好的朋友，你今天都幹啥了?
What did you do today, my fine feathered friend?

338
01:20:35,270 --> 01:20:37,000
往前坐點兒
Sit on the front of your chair.

339
01:20:37,580 --> 01:20:40,740
這會有益於你養成良好的坐姿
我從報紙上看到的
It's better for your posture.
I read that in the paper.

340
01:20:44,620 --> 01:20:46,980
這真是你從萊德貝特先生那兒買的麼？
Did you actually buy this from Mr. Ledbetter?

341
01:20:48,090 --> 01:20:50,320
別解釋，就點頭就行，是還不是？
Don't explain, just nod, yes or no?

342
01:20:56,530 --> 01:20:58,550
安靜
Be quiet.

343
01:21:00,060 --> 01:21:01,930
你說什麼？
What did you say?

344
01:21:05,200 --> 01:21:06,460
不要
Please.

345
01:21:07,140 --> 01:21:08,200
放開他
Leave him alone.

346
01:21:12,080 --> 01:21:13,440
放開他
Leave him alone!

347
01:21:17,880 --> 01:21:19,750
你給我過來，過來
Come here! Come here!

348
01:21:24,590 --> 01:21:25,990
滾蛋
Get up there!

349
01:22:22,750 --> 01:22:24,540
你讓我親兒子跟我對著干
You turn my own kids against me.

350
01:22:26,220 --> 01:22:28,240
你毀了我所做的一切
You undermine everything I do.

351
01:22:37,830 --> 01:22:39,590
你想怎麼樣
How do you like it?

352
01:22:41,430 --> 01:22:42,560
住手
Stop it!

353
01:22:43,600 --> 01:22:50,030
給我住手
Stop.

354
01:23:01,150 --> 01:23:02,520
住手
Stop.

355
01:25:00,770 --> 01:25:04,170
爸爸呢？
出差了
Where's Dad?
He's gone on a trip.

356
01:25:47,220 --> 01:25:49,780
抓住她，抓住她
Get her! Get her!

357
01:25:49,950 --> 01:25:51,850
互幫互助
Help each other.

358
01:25:54,120 --> 01:25:56,750
別關紗窗門
Do not slam that screen door!

359
01:25:57,830 --> 01:25:59,760
愛每個人
Love everyone.

360
01:26:02,570 --> 01:26:04,120
每片樹葉
Every leaf.

361
01:26:05,900 --> 01:26:08,060
每一縷陽光
Every ray of light.

362
01:26:15,810 --> 01:26:18,410
都是我們的禮物
Our gift.

363
01:26:57,690 --> 01:26:58,920
閉嘴
Shut up!

364
01:27:56,550 --> 01:27:58,740
小心，小心，快跑，快跑
Watch out! Watch out! Go, go!

365
01:28:17,870 --> 01:28:19,390
打碎了算了
I say let's bust them.

366
01:28:32,580 --> 01:28:33,610
好
Yea!

367
01:28:43,730 --> 01:28:45,090
好
Yea!

368
01:28:45,900 --> 01:28:48,020
這兒有只蛤蟆
Found a frog!

369
01:28:48,730 --> 01:28:50,200
給丫綁火箭上
Lets go set it off in a sky rocket!

370
01:28:50,570 --> 01:28:52,030
別讓丫跑了
He's getting away!

371
01:28:54,400 --> 01:28:55,890
躲開，躲開
Get back! Get back!

372
01:29:03,180 --> 01:29:04,880
丫到月球了吧
Did he go to the moon?

373
01:29:07,980 --> 01:29:12,550
丫跟哪兒呢？
這兒呢
Where is he?
There he is.

374
01:29:13,820 --> 01:29:15,590
這是個試驗
It was an experiment!

375
01:29:19,600 --> 01:29:20,820
為什麼
Why?

376
01:29:22,770 --> 01:29:24,790
以後別那樣了
Never do it again.

377
01:29:25,600 --> 01:29:27,330
保證麼？
Promise?

378
01:29:30,340 --> 01:29:32,370
你要告訴老爸麼？
You want to tell dad?

379
01:29:33,510 --> 01:29:36,840
他們就是為了嚇唬你
They're just trying to scare you.

380
01:29:38,850 --> 01:29:40,540
對準耳朵
Keep your ear there.

381
01:29:45,120 --> 01:29:47,020
她所不知的是
Things she got to learn.

382
01:29:50,530 --> 01:29:53,550
我正在不斷探索未知
I gotta know stuff too.

383
01:30:10,610 --> 01:30:14,520
大人們命令你不能幹的事兒，他們卻總干！
They say you can't try stuff? They did!

384
01:30:19,090 --> 01:30:21,080
你怕啥？
What do you need be afraid of?

385
01:30:24,290 --> 01:30:27,920
我看出來你怕了
You're afraid. I see it.

386
01:30:28,700 --> 01:30:30,720
這兒，這兒
Right here! Right here!

387
01:35:56,190 --> 01:35:57,990
我不想說話
I can't talk to you.

388
01:36:07,200 --> 01:36:08,900
別看我
Don't look at me.

389
01:36:57,390 --> 01:36:59,480
再見吧故事
Au revoir story.

390
01:37:03,430 --> 01:37:06,880
再見吧黃昏
Au revoir dawn.

391
01:37:35,390 --> 01:37:36,820
放這兒
Put it in there.

392
01:38:16,270 --> 01:38:17,860
我相信你
I trust you.

393
01:38:34,080 --> 01:38:37,520
你累了？
我根本不累
You tired?
No. I never get tired.

394
01:38:38,520 --> 01:38:41,320
你早上確實累了
沒有，我裝的
You did this morning.
No, I was just pretending.

395
01:38:41,890 --> 01:38:43,790
你說我是騙子？
沒有
You call me a liar?
No.

396
01:38:44,290 --> 01:38:47,990
我不想打架
怕了？
I don't want to fight.
Afraid to?

397
01:38:48,560 --> 01:38:50,400
不是，只是不想
No, I just don't want to.

398
01:38:51,830 --> 01:38:55,330
要是我之前說你害怕了
你還說我是騙子麼？
不
If I was to say you're scared,
would you call me a liar?
No.

399
01:38:57,140 --> 01:39:00,170
你怕了，對不對
You're scared, aren't you?

400
01:39:10,450 --> 01:39:11,890
算了吧
Quit it.

401
01:40:00,140 --> 01:40:01,470
過來
Come here!

402
01:40:03,640 --> 01:40:05,640
不
NO!

403
01:40:09,010 --> 01:40:10,950
我不想你命令我
I don't want to do anything you tell me to.

404
01:40:12,350 --> 01:40:14,510
我想幹什麼就幹什麼
I want to do what I want.

405
01:40:18,650 --> 01:40:21,180
你懂個屁，你對他惟命是從
What do you know? You let him run all over you.

406
01:41:11,810 --> 01:41:13,940
我怎麼回去？
How do I get back?

407
01:41:19,420 --> 01:41:21,280
他們在哪兒
Where they are.

408
01:41:55,890 --> 01:41:57,940
這個太重了，兩隻手拿
This one is heavy,
you're going to need two hands.

409
01:42:08,330 --> 01:42:11,320
小心點兒，知道這是什麼嗎？
中國貨？
Careful now, you know what that is?
Chinese?

410
01:42:12,070 --> 01:42:14,060
對，中國貨，很棒吧
That's Chinese, that's very good, yes it is.

411
01:42:15,470 --> 01:42:18,410
你老爸周遊全球，一路直到中國
Your father went all around the world.
All the way to China.

412
01:42:19,240 --> 01:42:22,540
這是泛美航空
你老爸就是坐的這個飛機
That's Pan Am Airlines,
that's what your father flew on.

413
01:42:22,980 --> 01:42:26,420
整個洗手間都是不銹鋼的，連洗臉盆也是
The entire bathroom was stainless steel.
Even the wash basin.

414
01:42:26,780 --> 01:42:29,010
我對這筆交易很有信心
I feel confident the deal is going through.

415
01:42:29,520 --> 01:42:31,280
沒啥，別管它，讓莫利見鬼去吧
Nothing, forget it. I'll tell Molly to go to hell.

416
01:42:32,120 --> 01:42:34,720
那是德國的
That's from Germany.

417
01:42:35,020 --> 01:42:36,180
看到了麼？
See that?

418
01:42:39,460 --> 01:42:41,190
放下，兒子
Put that down, son.

419
01:42:41,600 --> 01:42:42,860
泰勒能來麼？?
Can Taylor come over?

420
01:42:43,530 --> 01:42:45,300
家裡對你還不夠好麼?
Was your family not good enough for you?

421
01:42:52,680 --> 01:42:55,580
別像上次一樣讓我等那麼久好麼？
It's not going to take as long as last time?

422
01:42:56,050 --> 01:42:57,710
有嚼勁
Al dente.

423
01:43:00,780 --> 01:43:03,510
這是個主觀意見，知道有什麼不同麼？
It's a subjective point, you know the difference?

424
01:43:03,820 --> 01:43:06,650
主觀的意思就是說是你自己想出來的，
別人無法證實的
Subjective means it comes from your mind.
It can't be proven by other people.

425
01:43:15,000 --> 01:43:17,970
很高興再見到你，走吧孩子們
It's good to see you again. Let's go boys.

426
01:43:22,240 --> 01:43:23,900
有些事兒你們不能幹
There are things you can't do.

427
01:43:24,240 --> 01:43:26,230
而且有些事兒我也不能幹
But there are things I can't do either.

428
01:43:27,640 --> 01:43:30,010
別叫我老爸，得叫我父親
You're not to call me dad, you will call me father.

429
01:43:30,350 --> 01:43:31,610
但是...
別插嘴
But...
Do not interrupt!

430
01:43:31,980 --> 01:43:33,810
但是你...
叫你別插嘴
But you did...
Don't interrupt!

431
01:43:39,560 --> 01:43:40,780
這是你家
It's your house.

432
01:43:41,160 --> 01:43:43,560
只要你願意，你就可以讓我滾蛋
You can kick me out whenever you want to.

433
01:43:48,700 --> 01:43:51,260
或者更想弄死我算了
You'd like to kill me.

434
01:44:10,250 --> 01:44:11,580
爸
Dad.

435
01:44:16,530 --> 01:44:19,120
為什麼他會出現在這個世界上
Why was he born?

436
01:45:43,910 --> 01:45:45,540
謝謝上帝，弄死他得了
Please God, kill him.

437
01:45:50,690 --> 01:45:52,090
弄死他
Let him die.

438
01:45:57,260 --> 01:45:59,190
讓他消失也行
Get him out of here.

439
01:46:20,150 --> 01:46:22,880
她只愛我
She only loves me!

440
01:46:34,140 --> 01:46:40,840
神啊，用你神聖的恩典繼續保護這些孩子們吧
這也許會使他們永遠信仰你
Defend O'Lord this thy child with thy heavenly grace.
That he may continue thine forever

441
01:46:41,570 --> 01:46:45,540
每天賜予他多一些聖靈
And daily increase in thy Holy Spirit more and more

442
01:46:45,540 --> 01:46:50,740
直到他去到你那永恆的國度
阿門
Until he come unto thy everlasting kingdom
Amen.

443
01:47:32,120 --> 01:47:34,180
看到啥了...
See something...

444
01:48:24,710 --> 01:48:26,140
把手放上
Put your finger over it.

445
01:48:28,480 --> 01:48:29,770
這兒
There.

446
01:48:31,280 --> 01:48:32,910
快
Come on.

447
01:49:30,810 --> 01:49:33,330
我不能做我想做的事兒
What I want to do I can't do.

448
01:49:38,910 --> 01:49:41,410
卻總做著我厭惡的事兒
I do what I hate.

449
01:50:42,340 --> 01:50:43,900
你想打我就打吧
You can hit me if you want.

450
01:51:02,160 --> 01:51:03,360
對不起
I'm sorry.

451
01:51:06,700 --> 01:51:08,730
我們是兄弟
You're my brother.

452
01:51:52,920 --> 01:51:55,150
你想展現給我的是什麼？
What was it you showed me?

453
01:52:03,630 --> 01:52:06,890
我知道不能怪你
I didn't know how to name you sin.

454
01:52:11,500 --> 01:52:14,400
但我想說確實是你
But I'll say it was you.

455
01:52:19,370 --> 01:52:22,170
是你一直在召喚我
Always you were calling me.

456
01:54:10,890 --> 01:54:13,980
我自認為偉大，所以就應該被愛
I wanted to be loved because I was great.

457
01:54:16,860 --> 01:54:18,290
我是大人物？
A big man.

458
01:54:20,430 --> 01:54:22,620
還是一無是處？
I am nothing.

459
01:54:27,040 --> 01:54:29,800
人們沐浴在幸福的榮光之下
Look, the glory around us.

460
01:54:33,210 --> 01:54:35,400
樹林與小鳥相映成趣
Trees and birds.

461
01:54:38,710 --> 01:54:41,650
而我卻倍感慚愧
I lived in shame.

462
01:54:44,220 --> 01:54:46,950
我卻無視所有美好與幸福
I dishonored it all and didn't notice the glory.

463
01:54:53,700 --> 01:54:55,530
太傻了
A foolish man.

464
01:55:00,670 --> 01:55:02,190
工廠倒閉了
They're closing the plant.

465
01:55:06,010 --> 01:55:07,870
而我的選擇是
They gave me a choice.

466
01:55:11,410 --> 01:55:12,740
失業
No job.

467
01:55:15,880 --> 01:55:19,220
或者去幹髒活累活
Or transfer to a job nobody wants.

468
01:55:28,460 --> 01:55:29,730
父親
Father.

469
01:55:32,770 --> 01:55:34,830
我從未缺勤
I never missed a day of work.

470
01:55:35,670 --> 01:55:37,540
母親
Mother.

471
01:55:38,140 --> 01:55:40,570
甚至星期天也加班
Tithe every Sunday.

472
01:55:44,010 --> 01:55:47,280
你們永遠在我心中
Always you wrestle inside me.

473
01:55:51,790 --> 01:55:53,810
永遠
Always you will.

474
01:55:55,160 --> 01:55:57,520
裡斯先生喜歡傑克的讀後感
Mr. Reese liked Jack's book report.

475
01:55:59,560 --> 01:56:04,290
變得強壯
快快長大，能快點獨立
Make you strong and,
grow up and be your own boss.

476
01:56:08,270 --> 01:56:10,000
也許，我對你太嚴格了
Maybe I've been tough on you.

477
01:56:12,470 --> 01:56:13,940
是我做錯了
I'm not proud of that.

478
01:56:15,910 --> 01:56:18,310
彼此彼此
I'm as bad as you are.

479
01:56:21,720 --> 01:56:23,710
其實我愛你勝過愛媽媽
I'm more like you than her.

480
01:56:32,590 --> 01:56:36,800
我的一生只為了能夠教育好你們
其它的都不重要
It was about all I've done in life,
otherwise I've drawn zilch.

481
01:56:44,570 --> 01:56:47,640
你是我的所有
You're all I have, you're all I want to have.

482
01:56:55,050 --> 01:56:56,310
親愛的孩子
My sweet boy.

483
01:59:03,010 --> 01:59:05,410
別傻站在那兒
Are you just going to stand
there like a bump on a log?

484
02:00:17,890 --> 02:00:20,220
有愛才會幸福
The only way to be happy is to love.

485
02:00:24,890 --> 02:00:26,690
去愛吧
Unless you love,

486
02:00:28,800 --> 02:00:30,990
否則一生轉瞬即逝
your life will flash by.

487
02:00:41,980 --> 02:00:43,600
多行善舉
Do good to them.

488
02:00:48,680 --> 02:00:49,980
保持好奇之心
Wonder.

489
02:00:54,720 --> 02:00:56,210
永遠不失去希望
Hope.

490
02:01:48,610 --> 02:01:50,080
如兄弟般團結
Brother.

491
02:02:39,560 --> 02:02:42,220
別丟下我們
Keep us.

492
02:02:50,510 --> 02:02:52,630
指引我們
Guide us.

493
02:03:01,780 --> 02:03:03,940
直到永遠
To the end of time.

494
02:03:46,330 --> 02:03:48,160
跟隨我
Follow me.

495
02:10:53,090 --> 02:10:54,990
我將他歸還於你
I give him to you.

496
02:11:00,230 --> 02:11:01,890
將我兒歸還於你
I give you my son.

