¦ÄOh,I come from a land
From a faraway place
¦ÄWhere the caravan camels roam
¦ÄWhere it's flat and immense
And the heat is intense
¦ÄIt's barbaric but hey, it's home
¦ÄWhen the wind's from the east
And the sun's from the west
¦ÄAnd the sand in the glass is right
¦ÄCome on down, stop on by
Hop a carpet and fly
¦ÄTo another Arabian night
¦ÄArabian nights
¦ÄLike Arabian days
¦ÄMore often than not
Are hotter than hot
¦ÄIn a lot of good ways
¦ÄArabian nights
¦Ä'Neath Arabian moons
¦ÄA fool off his guard
Could fall and fall hard
¦ÄOut there on the dunes ¦Ä
[camel panting]
Ah, salaam, and good evening
to you, worthy friend.
Please, please, come closer.
Too close. A little too close.
There.
Welcome to Agrabah,
city of mystery,
of enchantment,
and the finest merchandise this side
of the river Jordan, on sale today.
Look at this. Yes.
Combination hookah and coffeemaker.
Also makes julienne fries.
Will not break. Will not...
It broke.
Ohh! Look at this.
I have never seen
one of these intact before.
This is the famous
Dead Sea Tupperware.
Listen. Ah, still good.
Wait. Don't go.
I can see that you're only interested
in the exceptionally rare.
I think, then, you would be
most rewarded to consider this.
Do not be fooled
by its commonplace appearance.
Like so many things,
it is not what is outside,
but what is inside that counts.
This is no ordinary lamp.
It once changed the course
of a young man's life.
A young man who, like this lamp,
was more than what he seemed.
The diamond in the rough.
Perhaps you would
like to hear the tale?
It begins on a dark night...
where a dark man waits
with a dark purpose.
[horse nickers]
You are late.
A thousand apologies, O Patient One.
You have it then?
I had to slit a few throats,
but I got it.
Ah-ah-ahhh.
The treasure.
Ow!
Trust me, my pungent friend.
- You'll get what's coming to you.
- What's coming to you. Awk!
Quickly! Follow the trail.
Faster.
[horse neighs]
[wind howling]
[Jafar] At last, after all
my years of searching...
the Cave of Wonders.
Awk. Cave of Wonders.
By Allah.
Now, remember.
Bring me the lamp.
The rest of the treasure
is yours, but the lamp is mine.
- [chuckles]
- [lago] Awk, the lamp. Awk, the lamp.
Jeez, where'd ya dig
this bozo up?
Shh.
[echoing rumble]
- Who disturbs my slumber?
- [thief gasps]
It is I, Gazeem,
a humble thief.
Know this.
Only one may enter here,
one whose worth lies far within.
A diamond in the rough.
What are you waiting for? Go on.
[beast sighing]
- [roaring]
- [screaming]
No!
Seek thee out
the diamond in the rough.
[coughing]
I can't believe it.
I just don't believe it.
We're never gonna get
a hold of that stupid lamp.
Just forget it.
Look at this.
I'm so ticked off that I'm molting.
Patience, lago. Patience.
Gazeem was obviously less than worthy.
Oh, there's a big surprise.
I think I'm gonna have a heart attack
and die from that surprise.
What are we gonna do?
We got a big problem here, a big...
Yes.
Only one may enter.
I must find this one, this...
diamond in the rough.
[man] Stop! Thief!
I'll have your hands
for a trophy, street rat.
All this for a loaf of bread?
Whoa!
[screaming]
- [guard] There he is!
- You won't get away so easy!
You think that was easy?
[giggling]
You two, over that way,
and you, follow me.
- We'll find him.
- Morning, ladies.
Getting into trouble a little early
today, aren't we, Aladdin?
Trouble? No way. You're only
in trouble if you get caught.
- Gotcha.
- I'm in trouble.
And this time...
[monkey squeaking]
Perfect timing, Abu, as usual.
- Abu.
- Come on. Let's get outta here.
¦Ä Gotta keep one jump
Ahead of the bread line
¦Ä One swing ahead of the sword
¦Ä I steal only what I can't afford
That's everything.
¦Ä One jump ahead of the lawmen
¦Ä That's all and that's no joke
¦Ä These guys don't appreciate I'm broke
- Riffraff.
- [both] Street rat.
- [guard] Scoundrel.
- [man] Take that.
¦Ä Just a little snack, guys
¦Ä Rip him open
Take it back, guys
¦Ä I can take a hint
Gotta face the facts
- ¦Ä You're my only friend, Abu
- [women] Who?
¦Ä Oh, it's sad Aladdin's hit the bottom
¦Ä He's become a one-man rise in crime
¦Ä I'd blame parents
Except he hasn't got 'em
¦Ä Gotta eat to live
Gotta steal to eat
¦Ä Tell you all about it
When I got the time
¦Ä One jump ahead of the slowpokes
One skip ahead of my doom
¦Ä Next time gonna use a nom de plume
There he is.
¦Ä One jump ahead of the hit men
One hit ahead of the flock
¦Ä I think I'll take a stroll
Around the block
- [man] Stop, thief.
- Vandal.
- Abu!
- Scandal.
¦Ä Let's not be too hasty
¦Ä Still I think he's rather tasty
¦Ä Gotta eat to live
Gotta steal to eat
¦Ä Otherwise we'd get along
[guards] Wrong.
[main guard] Get him!
He's got a sword!
You idiots.
We've all got swords.
[groaning]
- ¦Ä One jump ahead of the hoofbeats
- Vandal!
- ¦Ä One hop ahead of the hump
- Street rat!
- ¦Ä One trick ahead of disaster
- Scoundrel!
¦Ä They're quick, but I'm much faster
¦Ä Here goes, better throw my hand in
¦Ä Wish me happy landin'
All I gotta do is jump ¦Ä
[screaming]
[guards] Yuck! Oy!
And now, esteemed effendi, we feast.
All right.
[Abu] Yum, yum!
Uh-oh.
[sighs]
Here. Go on. Take it.
[giggling]
[groans]
Ah, don't. Huh?
On his way to the palace, I suppose.
Another suitor for the princess.
- [giggling]
- [woman screams]
- [whinnying]
- Out of my way, you filthy brats.
Hey!
If I were as rich as you,
I could afford some manners.
Oh. I'll teach you some manners.
[men laugh]
[grimacing]
Look at that, Abu.
It's not every day you see
a horse with two rear ends.
[crowd] Ooh!
You are a worthless street rat.
You were born a street rat,
you'll die a street rat,
and only your fleas will mourn you.
I'm not worthless.
And I don't have fleas.
[sighs] Come on, Abu.
Let's go home.
¦Ä Riffraff, street rat
¦Ä I don't buy that
¦Ä If only they'd look closer
¦Ä Would they see a poor boy
¦Ä No, siree
¦Ä They'd find out
¦Ä There's so much more
¦Ä To me ¦Ä
[sighs]
Some day, Abu,
things are gonna change.
We'll be rich, live in a palace,
and never have any problems at all.
[roosters crowing]
I've never been so insulted.
Oh, Prince Achmed.
You're not leaving so soon, are you?
Good luck marrying her off.
Oh! Jasmine.
[Sultan] Jasmine!
Jasmine!
- Jasmine!
- [snarling]
Confound it, Rajah.
So, this is why Prince Achmed
stormed out.
Oh, Father.
Rajah was just playing with him.
Weren't you, Rajah?
You were just playing
with that overdressed,
self-absorbed Prince Achmed,
weren't you?
[both laughing]
[clears throat]
Dearest, you've got to stop rejecting
every suitor who comes to call.
The law says
you must be married to a prince...
by your next birthday.
The law is wrong.
You've only got three more days.
Father, I hate being forced into this.
If I do marry,
I want it to be for love.
Jasmine...
it's not only this law.
I'm not going to be around forever,
and, well, I...
I just want to make sure
you're taken care of.
Provided for.
Please try to understand.
I've never done a thing on my own.
I've never had any real friends.
[grumbles]
Except you, Rajah.
I've never even been
outside the palace walls.
But, Jasmine, you're a princess.
Then maybe I don't want
to be a princess anymore.
Oooh! I... I...
Allah forbid you should
have any daughters.
Hmm?
I don't know where she gets it from.
Her mother wasn't nearly so picky.
Oh! Ah, Jafar.
My most trusted advisor.
I am in desperate need of your wisdom.
My life is but to serve you, my lord.
It's this suitor business.
Jasmine refuses
to choose a husband.
- I'm at my wit's end.
- Awk! Wit's end!
[laughing] Oh!
- Have a cracker, pretty Polly.
- [Jafar laughs]
Your Majesty certainly
has a way with dumb animals.
[grumbles]
Now, then,
perhaps I can divine a solution
to this thorny problem.
If anyone can help, it's you.
But it would require the use
of the mystic blue diamond.
Oh. Uh, my ring?
But it's been in the family for years.
It is necessary to find
the princess a suitor.
Don't worry.
Everything will be fine.
Everything will be... fine.
The diamond.
Here, Jafar.
Whatever you need will be fine.
You are most gracious, my liege.
Now, run along and play
with your little toys, hmm?
Yes. That will be pretty good.
[spits, coughs]
I can't take it anymore!
If I gotta choke down on one more
of those moldy, disgusting crackers...
Bam! Whack!
Calm yourself, lago.
Then I'd grab him around the head.
Whack!
Soon I will be sultan,
not that addle-pated twit.
And then I stuff the crackers
down his throat.
Ha, ha!
[whining]
Oh, I'm sorry, Rajah.
But I can't stay here
and have my life lived for me.
I'll miss you.
[whimpers]
Goodbye.
[vendors calling out]
Okay, Abu. Go.
Try this. Your taste buds
will dance and sing.
[squeaking]
- Get your paws off that.
- [taunting]
Why, you...
Get away from here,
you cursed, filthy ape!
Goodbye.
- Nice going, Abu.
- [cooing]
Breakfast is served.
Pretty lady, buy a pot.
No finer pot in brass or silver.
Sugar dates.
Sugar dates and figs.
Sugar dates and pistachios.
Would the lady like a necklace?
A pretty necklace for a pretty lady.
Fresh fish!
We catch 'em, you buy 'em!
Oh, no. I don't think so.
- Oh!
- [gulping]
- Excuse me.
- [gulps]
[belches]
I'm really very sorry.
Wow.
Uh-oh.
Hello? Hello?
Oh, you must be hungry.
Here you go.
You'd better be able to pay for that.
Pay?
No one steals from my cart.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
I don't have any money.
- Thief!
- Please...
If you let me go to the palace,
I can get some from the Sultan.
Do you know what
the penalty is for stealing?
No! No, please!
Thank you, kind sir.
I'm so glad you found her.
I've been looking all over for you.
- What are you doing?
- Just play along.
You, uh, know this girl?
Sadly, yes. She is my sister.
She's a little crazy.
She said she knew the Sultan.
She thinks the monkey is the Sultan.
O wise Sultan, how may I serve you?
[gibberish]
Tragic, isn't it?
But no harm done.
Now, come along, sis.
Time to go see the doctor.
Oh, hello, Doctor.
How are you?
- No, no, no. Not that one.
- Come on, Sultan.
[gibbering, gasping]
Huh? What?
Come back here, you little thieves!
[explosion]
With all due respect,
Your Rottenness,
couldn't we just wait
for a real storm?
Save your breath, lago. Faster.
Yes, O mighty Evil One.
[panting]
Part, sands of time.
Reveal to me the one
who can enter the cave.
Yes! Yes!
There he is.
My diamond in the rough.
That's him? That's the clown
we've been waitin' for?
Let's have the guards extend him
an invitation to the palace, shall we?
Swell.
[coughs]
[sinister laughter]
Almost there.
I want to thank you
for stopping that man.
Uh, forget it.
So, this is your first time
in the marketplace, huh?
Is it that obvious?
Well, you do kind of stand out.
I mean, uh, you don't seem to know
how dangerous Agrabah can be.
Hmm. I'm a fast learner.
Wow.
[chuckling] Hey.
Come on. This way.
Whoa. Watch your head there.
Be careful.
Is this where you live?
Yep. Just me and Abu.
Come and go as we please.
That sounds fabulous.
Well, it's not much,
but it's got a great view.
Wow. The palace looks
pretty amazing, huh?
Oh, it's wonderful.
I wonder what it would
be like to live there,
and have servants and valets.
Oh, sure. People who tell you
where to go and how to dress.
It's better than here.
You're always scraping for food
and ducking the guards.
You're not free to make
your own choices.
- Sometimes you feel so...
- You're just...
[both]...trapped.
[clears throat]
So, where are you from?
What does it matter?
I ran away
and I am not going back.
Really? How come?
Why, you...
My father's forcing me
to get married.
That's... that's awful.
- [Aladdin] Abu!
- [angry squeaking]
What?
Abu says, uh...
that's not fair.
What?
- Oh, did he?
- Yeah, of course.
And does Abu
have anything else to say?
Well, uh, he wishes there was
something he could do to help.
Oh, boy.
Hmm.
Tell him that's very sweet.
Here you are.
- [both] They're after me! After You?
- My father must have sent them...
- Do you trust me?
- What?
- Yes...
Then jump!
We just keep running into each other,
don't we, street rat?
Run! Go! Get out of here!
Get this thing off of me!
- It's the dungeon for you, boy.
- Get me off
Let him go.
- Looky here, men. A street mouse.
- [guards laugh]
Unhand him,
by order of the princess.
Princess Jasmine.
- The princess?
- [Abu] Princess?
What are you doing outside the palace?
And with this street rat.
That's not your concern.
Do as I command. Release him.
I would, Princess,
except my orders come from Jafar.
- You'll have to take it up with him.
- Believe me, I will.
Jafar?
Oh, Princess.
Awk! Jafar, I'm stuck.
How may I be of service to you?
The guards just took a boy
from the market, on your orders.
Your father has charged me
with keeping peace in Agrabah.
- The boy was a criminal.
- What was his crime?
I can't breathe, Jafar.
Why, kidnapping the princess,
of course.
If you could just...
Aah! That hurt!
He didn't kidnap me.
I ran away.
Oh, dear.
Oh, how frightfully upsetting.
Had I but known...
What do you mean?
Sadly, the boy's sentence
has already been carried out.
What sentence?
- Death.
- [gasping]
- By beheading.
- No.
I am exceedingly sorry, Princess.
How could you?
[weeping]
[coughing]
[coughing, gasping]
So, how did it go?
I think she took it... rather well.
[Jasmine crying]
It's all my fault, Rajah.
- I didn't even know his name.
- [Rajah murmuring]
She was the princess.
I can't believe it.
I must have sounded
so stupid to her.
[Abu] Yoo-hoo! Aladdin!
Hello!
Abu. Down here.
[squeaking]
Come on, help me out of these.
[scolding]
Hey, she was in trouble.
Ah, she was worth it.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Don't worry.
I'll never see her again.
I'm a street rat, remember?
And there's a law.
She's gotta marry a prince.
- She deserves a prince.
- Ta-da!
I'm a, I'm a fool.
[man] You're only a fool
if you give up, boy.
Who are you?
A lowly prisoner, like yourself.
But together,
perhaps we can be more.
I'm listening.
There is a cave, boy,
a Cave of Wonders,
filled with treasures
beyond your wildest dreams.
Ooh!
Treasure enough to impress even
your princess, I'd wager.
Jafar, can you hurry up?
I'm dyin' in here.
- [squawking]
- But the law says only a prince can...
You've heard of the golden rule,
haven't you?
Whoever has the gold
makes the rules.
[wheezing laugh]
Why would you share all of this
wonderful treasure with me?
I need a young pair of legs and
a strong back to go in after it.
Uh, one problem.
It's out there.
We're in here.
Uh-uh. Things aren't always
what they seem.
So...
do we have a deal?
Oh, I don't know.
[thunder crashing]
Who disturbs my slumber?
Uh, it is l, Aladdin.
Proceed.
Touch nothing but the lamp.
Remember, boy,
first fetch me the lamp,
and then you shall
have your reward.
Come on, Abu.
[squeaking]
- Would you look at that!
- [whimpering]
Just a handful of this stuff
would make me richer than the Sultan.
Abu!
[whines]
Don't... touch... anything.
We gotta find that lamp.
[grumbles]
Huh?
- Aladdin!
- Abu, will you knock it off?
[screeches]
Abu, what are you, crazy?
A magic carpet.
Come on. Come on out.
We're not gonna hurt you.
[screeches]
Hey, take it easy, Abu.
He's not gonna bite.
Thanks.
[squeaking]
Wait a minute. Don't go.
Maybe you can help us.
Hey! Whoa!
You see, we're trying
to find this lamp.
- I think he knows where it is.
- [squeaks excitedly]
[echoes]
[whispers] Wait here.
[moaning]
Oh!
This is it?
This is what we came
all the way down here to...
Abu! No!
- [cave] lnfidels!
- Uh-oh.
[cave] You have touched
the forbidden treasure!
Now you will never again
see the light of day!
Whoa!
Help! Help! Help!
Gotcha!
Carpet, let's move.
Abu!
Abu, this is no time to panic.
Start panicking.
[both] Whoa!
[Abu panting]
[thunder cracks]
[roaring]
- Help me out.
- Throw me the lamp.
I can't hold on.
Give me your hand.
First give me the lamp.
[maniacal laughter]
Yes!
At last!
- [wicked laughter]
- [Aladdin struggles]
What are you doing?
Giving you your reward.
Your eternal reward.
[screaming]
[yelling]
[roaring]
[chuckling]
It's mine.
It's all mine.
I... where is it?
No.
No!
Jasmine?
[Sultan] Oh, dearest.
What's wrong?
[sniffling]
Jafar has...
done something terrible.
There, there, my dear.
We'll set it right.
Now, tell me everything.
Oh.
Aladdin. Wake up.
Aladdin.
Oh! My head.
We're trapped.
That two-faced son of a jackal!
[snarling]
Whoever he was,
he's long gone with that lamp.
Aha!
[chuckling] Why, you hairy little thief.
Looks like such a beat-up,
worthless piece of junk.
Hey, I think there's
something written here,
but it's hard to make out.
Aaaaahhhhh!
Oy!
1 0,000 years will give you
such a crick in the neck.
Hang on a second.
Whoa! Whoa!
Does it feel good
to be outta there.
Nice to be back,
ladies and gentlemen.
Hi. Where you from?
What's your name?
Uh... Uh, Aladdin.
Aladdin. Hello, Aladdin.
Nice to have you on the show.
Can we call you "Al"?
Or maybe just "Din."
How about "Laddie"?
Sounds like, "Here, boy. C'mon, Laddie."
I must have hit my head
harder than I thought.
Do you smoke? Mind if I do?
[giggling]
Oh, sorry, Cheetah.
Hope I didn't singe the fur.
Yo, Rugman. Haven't seen you
in a few millennia.
Give me some tass-el.
Yeah. Yo, yo.
Say, you're a lot smaller
than my last master.
That or I'm gettin' bigger.
Look from the side. Do I look different to you?
Wait a minute.
I'm your master?
That's right. He can be taught.
What would you wish of me?
The ever impressive,
the long contained,
often imitated,
but never duplicated...
[echoing] Duplicated, duplicated...
Genie...
of the Lamp!
Right here direct from the lamp,
right here for your
very much wish fulfillment.
[Genie] Thank you.
Whoa. Wish fulfillment?
Three wishes to be exact.
And ix-nay on the wishing
for more wishes.
That's it. Three.
Uno, dos, tres.
No substitutions,
exchanges or refunds.
Now I know I'm dreaming.
Master, I don't think you quite realize
what you've got here.
So why don't you just ruminate
whilst I illuminate
the possibilities.
¦Ä Well, Ali Baba had them 40 thieves
¦Ä Scheherazade had a thousand tales
¦Ä But, master, you're in luck
'Cause up your sleeves
¦Ä You got a brand of magic never fails
¦Ä You got some power in your corner now
¦Ä Some heavy ammunition in your camp
¦Ä You got some punch pizzazz
Yahoo and how
¦Ä See, all you gotta do
Is rub that lamp and I'll say
¦Ä Mr. Aladdin, sir,
What will your pleasure be
¦Ä Let me take your order
Jot it down
¦Ä You ain't never had a friend like me
¦Ä Life is your restaurant
And I'm your maitre d'
¦Ä Come on, whisper what it is you want
¦Ä You ain't never had a friend like me
¦Ä Yes, sir
We pride ourselves on service
¦Ä You're the boss, the king, the shah
¦Ä Say what you wish
It's yours, true dish
¦Ä How 'bout a little more baklava?
¦Ä Have some of column A
Try all of column B
¦Ä I'm in the mood to help you, dude
¦Ä You ain't never had a friend like me
¦Ä Oh, my
¦Ä No, no
¦Ä My, my
[scatting]
¦Ä Can your friends do this
¦Ä Can your friends do that
¦Ä Can your friends pull this
¦Ä Out their little hat
¦Ä Can your friends go poof
Hey, looky here. Ha ha!
¦Ä Can your friends go
Abracadabra, let her rip
¦Ä And then make the sucker disappear
¦Ä So don't you sit there
Slack-jawed, buggy-eyed
¦Ä I'm here to answer
All your midnight prayers
¦Ä You got me bona fide certified
¦Ä You got a genie
For your charge d'affaires
¦Ä I got a powerful urge to help you out
¦Ä So what's your wish
I really wanna know
¦Ä You got a list
That's three miles long, no doubt
¦Ä All you gotta do is rub like so
¦Ä Mr. Aladdin, sir
Have a wish or two or three
¦Ä I'm on the job, you big nabob
¦Ä You ain't never had a friend
Never had a friend
¦Ä You ain't never
¦Ä Had a
¦Ä Friend
¦Ä Like
¦Ä Me
Ah ha ha!
- Wah ha ha!
- [greedy laugh]
¦Ä You ain't never had a friend like me ¦Ä
- [buzzing]
- [weak applause]
[chattering] Huh?
- [groans]
- So, what'll it be, Master?
You're gonna grant me
any three wishes I want, right?
Ah, almost.
There are a few provisos,
a couple of quid pro quos.
Like?
Ah, rule number one:.
I can't kill anybody.
So don't ask.
Rule number two.
I can't make anybody
fall in love with anybody else.
You little punim there.
Rule number three. I can't bring
people back from the dead.
It's not a pretty picture.
I don't like doing it.
Other than that, you got it.
- Hmm.
- Oh!
Provisos?
You mean limitations?
On wishes?
Some all-powerful genie.
Can't even bring people
back from the dead.
I don't know, Abu. He probably
can't even get us out of this cave.
Looks like we're gonna have to
find a way out.
Excuse me?
Are you lookin' at me?
Did you rub my lamp?
Did you wake me up?
Did you bring me here?
And all of a sudden
you're walking out on me?
I don't think so,
not right now.
You're gettin' your wishes,
so sit down!
- [Abu screeches]
- In case of emergency,
the exits are here, here,
here, here, anywhere.
Keep your hands and arms
inside the carpet.
We're...
outta here!
[Sultan] Jafar, this is an outrage.
If it weren't for all your years
of loyal service...
From now on, you are to discuss
sentencing of prisoners with me,
before they are beheaded.
I assure you, Your Highness,
it won't happen again.
Jasmine...
Jafar. Let's put this whole
messy business behind us.
Please.
My most abject and humblest apologies
to you as well, Princess.
At least some good will come
of my being forced to marry.
When I am queen, I will have
the power to get rid of you.
[chuckles nervously]
That's nice.
All settled, then.
Now, Jasmine, getting back to
this suitor business... Jasmine?
Jasmine!
[growls]
If only I had gotten that lamp.
"l will have the power
to get rid of you."
[growling] To think
we gotta keep kissing up
to that chump
and his chump daughter
- for the rest of our lives...
- No, lago.
Only until she finds
a chump husband.
Then she'll have us banished.
Or beheaded.
[both] Eww!
Oh. Wait a minute.
Jafar. What ifyou were
the chump husband?
What?
Okay, you marry
the princess, all right?
And, uh, then you
become the sultan.
Oh.
Marry the shrew.
I become the sultan.
- The idea has merit.
- Yes, merit. Yes.
And then we drop papa-in-law
and the little woman off a cliff.
Yaaah!
Kersplat!
[wicked laughter]
I love the way
your foul little mind works.
[both laugh sinisterly]
Thank you for choosing Magic Carpet
for all your travel needs.
Don't stand until the rug
has come to a complete stop.
Thank you.
Goodbye now. Good-ye.
Thank you.Good-ye.
Well, how about that,
Mr. Doubting Mustafa?
Oh, you sure showed me.
Now, about my three wishes.
Dost mine ears deceive me?
Three? You are down by one, boy.
Ah, no. I never actually wished
to get out of the cave.
You did that on your own.
Well, I feel sheepish.
All right, you baaad boy,
but no more freebies.
Fair deal.
So, three wishes.
I want them to be good.
What would you wish for?
Me?
No one's ever asked me that before.
Well, in my case...
Ah, forget it.
- What?
- No, I can't. I...
Come on. Tell me.
Freedom.
You're a prisoner?
It's all part and parcel
of the whole genie gig.
Phenomenal cosmic powers...
Itty bitty living space.
Genie, that's terrible.
But, oh, to be free.
Not have to go,
"Poof. What do you need?
Poof. What do you need?
Poof. What do you need?"
To be my own master.
Such a thing would be
greater than all the magic
and all the treasures
in all the world.
But what am I talking about?
Let's get real here.
It's not gonna happen.
Genie, wake up and smell the hummus.
Why not?
The only way I get outta this
is if my master wishes me out.
So you can guess how often
that's happened.
I'll do it. I'll set you free.
- Uh-huh, yeah, right.
- No, really, I promise.
After I make my first two wishes,
I'll use my third wish
to set you free.
Well, here's hopin'.
All right.
Let's make some magic.
So how 'bout it?
What is it you want most?
Well, there's this girl.
Wrong.
I can't make anybody
fall in love, remember?
Oh, but, Genie,
she's smart and fun and...
- Pretty?
- Beautiful.
She's got these eyes that just...
and this hair. Wow.
And her smile... [sighs]
Ami.
C'est l'amour.
But she's the princess.
To even have a chance,
I'd have to be...
Hey, can you make me a prince?
Let's see here.
Chicken a la king? Nope.
Alaskan king crab.
Ow. I hate it when they do that.
Caesar salad. Ah!
Et tu, Brute? No.
Aha. "To make a prince."
Is that an official wish?
Say the magic words.
Genie, I wish for you
to make me a prince.
All right!
Yo, yo! Woof! Woof!
First, that fez-and-vest combo
is much too third century.
These patches.
What are we trying to say, beggar?
No. Let's work with me here.
Ooh. I like it. Muy macho.
Now, it still needs something.
What does it say to me?
It says mode of transportation.
Excuse me, monkey boy.
Aqui. Over here.
- Uh-oh.
- [Genie] Here he comes.
What better way to make your
entrance on the streets of Agrabah
than riding your very own
brand-new camel.
Watch out. They spit.
Mmm. Not enough.
Still not enough.
Let's see.
What do you need?
Yes!
Esalalumbo shimin Dumbo.
- Whoa!
- [trumpets]
Talk about your trunk space.
Check this action out.
[trumpets]
[frightened monkey noises]
Abu, you look good.
[Genie] He's got the outfit.
He's got the elephant.
But we're not through yet.
Hang on to your turban, kid.
We're gonna make you a star.
[door opens]
Sire, I've found a solution
to the problem with your daughter.
Awk. The problem with your daughter.
Oh, really?
Right here.
"lf the princess has not chosen
a husband by the appointed time,
then the sultan shall
choose for her."'
But Jasmine hated
all those suitors.
How could I choose
someone she hates?
Not to worry, my liege.
There is more.
"lf in the event
a suitable prince cannot be found,"
Jerk.
"a princess must then be wed to..."'
Hmm. Interesting.
What? Who?
The royal vizier.
Why, that would be... me.
But I thought the law says
that only a prince
can marry a princess.
I'm quite sure that...
Desperate times call for
desperate measures, my lord.
Yes. Desperate measures.
You will order
the princess to marry me.
I will order...
the princess...
to...
But you're so old.
The princess will marry me.
The princess will marry...
- [trumpet fanfare]
- What? What is that?
That music.
[chuckling]
Jafar, you must come
and see this.
¦Ä Make way for Prince Ali
¦Ä Say hey
¦Ä It's Prince Ali
¦Ä Hey, clear the way in the old bazaar
¦Ä Hey you, let us through
It's a bright new star
¦Ä Oh come, be the first on your block
To meet his eye
¦Ä Make way, here he comes
Ring bells, bang the drums
¦Ä You're gonna love this guy
¦Ä Prince Ali, fabulous he
Ali Ababwa
¦Ä Genuflect, show some respect
Down on one knee
¦Ä Now, try your best to stay calm
¦Ä Brush up your Sunday salaam
¦Ä Then come and meet
His spectacular coterie
¦Ä Prince Ali, mighty is he,
Ali Ababwa
¦Ä Strong as ten regular men definitely
¦Ä He faced the galloping hordes
¦Ä A hundred bad guys with swords
¦Ä Who sent those goons to their lords
Why, Prince Ali
¦Ä He's got 75 golden camels
Don't they look lovely, June?
¦Ä Purple peacocks, he's got 53
Fabulous, Harry.
I love the feathers.
¦Ä When it comes to exotic-type mammals
¦Ä Has he got a zoo
I'm telling you
¦Ä It's a world-class menagerie
¦Ä Prince Ali, handsome is he
Ali Ababwa
¦Ä That physique, how can I speak
Weak at the knee
¦Ä Well, get on out in that square
¦Ä Adjust your veil and prepare
¦Ä To gawk and grovel and stare
At Prince Ali
- ¦Ä He's got 95 white Persian monkeys
- ¦Ä He's got the monkeys
- ¦Ä Let's see the monkeys
- ¦Ä And to view them he charges no fee
¦Ä He's got slaves
He's got servants and flunkies
¦Ä Proud to work for him
They bow to his whim, love serving him
¦Ä They're just lousy with loyalty to Ali
¦Ä Prince Ali
¦Ä Prince Ali, Amorous he
Ali Ababwa
¦Ä Heard your princess
Was a sight lovely to see
¦Ä And that, good people, is why
¦Ä He got dolled up and dropped by
¦Ä With 60 elephants, llamas galore
¦Ä With bears and lions,
A brass band and more
¦Ä With his 40 fakirs,
His cooks, his bakers
¦Ä His birds that warble on key
¦Ä Make way
¦Ä For Prince Ali ¦Ä
[clapping] Splendid.
Absolutely marvelous.
[clears throat]
Your Majesty,
I have journeyed from afar
to seek your daughter's hand.
Prince Ali Ababwa.
Of course.
I'm delighted to meet you.
This is my royal vizier, Jafar.
He's delighted, too.
Ecstatic.
- I'm afraid, Prince Abooboo...
- Ababwa.
Whatever.
You cannot just parade in here
uninvited and expect to...
By Allah, this is quite
a remarkable device.
Ooh.
I don't suppose I might...
Why, certainly, Your Majesty.
Allow me.
Sire, I must advise against this.
Oh, button up, Jafar.
Learn to have a little fun.
Ow, ow, ow.
Ahh! Whoa!
Just where did you say
you were from?
Oh, much farther than
you've traveled, I'm sure.
- Try me.
- [Sultan] Look out, Polly.
Hey, watch it.
Watch it with the dumb rug.
Aah!
Whew!
Out of the way.
I'm coming in to land.
Jafar, watch this.
- Spectacular, Your Highness.
- That was lovely.
Yes, I do seem
to have a knack for it.
This is a very impressive youth.
And a prince besides.
[whispers] If we're lucky, you won't
have to marry Jasmine after all.
- I don't trust him, Sire.
- Nonsense.
One thing I pride myself on, Jafar,
I'm an excellent judge of character.
Oh, excellent judge.
Yeah, sure. Not!
[Sultan] Jasmine will like this one.
And I'm pretty sure
I'll like Princess Jasmine.
Your Highness, no.
I must intercede on Jasmine's behalf.
This boy is no different
from the others.
What makes him think
he is worthy of the princess?
Your Majesty,
I am Prince Ali Ababwa.
Just let her meet me.
I will win your daughter.
How dare you.
All of you. Standing around
deciding my future?
I am not a prize to be won.
Oh, dear.
Don't worry, Prince Ali.
Just give Jasmine time
to cool down.
I think it's time to say good-bye
to Prince Abooboo.
[Aladdin sighs] What am I gonna do?
Jasmine won't even
let me talk to her.
I should've known I couldn't pull off
this stupid prince wish.
[growling]
So move.
Hey.
That's a good move.
I can't believe it.
I'm losing to a rug.
Genie, I need help.
All right, Sparky,
here's the deal.
If you wanna court
the little lady,
you gotta be
a straight shooter.
- Do you got it?
- What?
Tell her the...
-...truth!
- No way.
If Jasmine found out I was really
some crummy street rat,
she'd laugh at me.
A woman appreciates a man
who can make her laugh.
Al, all joking aside,
you really ought to be yourself.
Hey, that's the last thing I wanna be.
Okay, I'm gonna go see her.
I just... I gotta be smooth,
cool, confident.
How do I look?
Like a prince.
[sighs]
- [Aladdin] Princess Jasmine?
- [growling]
- Who's there?
- It's me, Prince Ali.
Ahem. Uh, Prince Ali Ababwa.
I do not want to see you.
No, no, please, Princess.
Give me a chance.
- [Jasmine] Just leave me alone.
- Down, kitty.
So, how's our little beau doing?
- Good kitty, take off.
- [Rajah growling]
Down, kitty.
Wait. Wait.
Do I know you?
Uh, no. No.
You remind me of someone
I met in the marketplace.
The marketplace?
I have servants who go
to the marketplace for me.
Why, I even have servants who go to
the marketplace for my servants.
It couldn't have been me you met.
No. I guess not.
[Genie] Enough about you, Casanova.
Talk about her.
She's smart, fun,
the hair, the eyes.
Anything. Pick a feature.
Ahem. Uh, Princess Jasmine?
You're very...
- Wonderful, magnificent, punctual.
-...punctual.
- Punctual?
- Sorry.
- Uh, beautiful.
- Nice recovery.
Hmm.
I'm rich, too, you know.
- Yeah.
- The daughter of a sultan.
I know.
A fine prize
for any prince to marry.
Uh, right. Right.
A prince like me.
Warning! Warning!
Right. A prince like you.
And every other stuffed shirt,
swaggering peacock I've met.
Mayday! Mayday!
[Jasmine] Just go jump off
a balcony!
- What?
- Stop her. Stop her!
- Want me to sting her?
- Buzz off.
Okay, fine.
But remember, "bee" yourself.
- Yeah, right.
- What?
Uh... Uh, you're right.
[sighs] You aren't just
some prize to be won.
[Aladdin] You should be free
to make your own choice.
I'll go now.
- No!
- What? What?
How...
How are you doing that?
- It's a magic carpet.
- It's lovely.
- [kisses]
- You, uh...
You don't want to go
for a ride, do you?
We could get out of the palace,
see the world.
- Is it safe?
- Sure. Do you trust me?
- What?
- Do you trust me?
Yes.
¦Ä I can show you the world
¦Ä Shining, shimmering, splendid
¦Ä Tell me, Princess
¦Ä Now, when did you last
Let your heart decide
¦Ä I can open your eyes
¦Ä Take you wonder by wonder
¦Ä Over, sideways and under
¦Ä On a magic carpet ride
¦Ä A whole new world
¦Ä A new fantastic point of view
¦Ä No one to tell us no
Or where to go
¦Ä Or say we're only dreaming
¦Ä A whole new world
¦Ä A dazzling place
I never knew
¦Ä But when I'm way up here
It's crystal clear
¦Ä That now I'm in
A whole new world with you
[Aladdin] ¦Ä Now I'm in
[Jasmine] ¦Ä Unbelievable sights
¦Ä Indescribable feeling
¦Ä Soaring, tumbling, freewheeling
¦Ä Through an endless diamond sky
- ¦Ä A whole new world
- ¦Ä Don't you dare close your eyes
- ¦Ä A hundred thousand things to see
- ¦Ä Hold your breath, it gets better
¦Ä I'm like a shooting star
I've come so far
¦Ä I can't go back to where I used to be
- ¦Ä A whole new world
- ¦Ä Every turn a surprise
- ¦Ä With new horizons to pursue
- ¦Ä Every moment, red-letter
¦Ä I'll chase them anywhere
There's time to spare
[both] ¦Ä Let me share
This whole new world with you
- ¦Ä A whole new world
- ¦Ä That's where we'll be
- ¦Ä A thrilling chase
- ¦Ä A wondrous place
¦Ä For you and me ¦Ä
- It's all so magical.
- Yeah.
It's a shame
Abu had to miss this.
Nah. He hates fireworks.
[Aladdin]
He doesn't like flying, either.
Uh, that is, um...
Oh, no.
You are the boy from the market.
I knew it.
- Why did you lie?
- Jasmine, I'm sorry.
- Did you think I was stupid?
- No.
- That I wouldn't figure it out?
I mean, I hoped you wouldn't.
No, that's not what I meant.
Who are you?
Tell me the truth.
The truth?
The truth. Um...
The truth is...
I sometimes dress as a commoner, um...
to escape the pressures
of palace life.
But I really am a prince.
Why didn't you just tell me?
Well, you know...
royalty going out
into the city in disguise,
it sounds a little strange,
don't you think?
Hmm.
Not that strange.
Good night, my handsome prince.
Sleep well, Princess.
[sighs]
Yes!
For the first time in my life,
things are starting to go right.
[yelling, struggling]
[muffled] Abu. Abu.
Hold him.
I'm afraid you've worn out
your welcome, Prince Abooboo.
[muffled] Why, you...
Make sure he's never found.
[laughing]
Never fails. Get in the bath
and there's a rub at the lamp.
Hello? Al?
[gasping] Al! Kid, snap out of it.
You can't cheat on this one.
I can't help unless you make a wish.
You have to say, "Genie,
I want you to save my life."' Got it?
Come on, Aladdin!
I'll take that as a yes.
[imitating alarm]
Up scope.
[babbling in German]
[coughing]
Don't you scare me like that.
Genie, I, uh...
I...
- Thanks, Genie.
- Oh, Al.
I'm gettin' kind of fond of you, kid.
Not that I wanna pick out
curtains or anything.
[humming]
[Sultan] Jasmine.
Oh, Father, I just had
the most wonderful time.
- [Jasmine] I'm so happy.
- You should be, Jasmine.
I have chosen a husband for you.
- What?
- You will wed Jafar.
- [gasping]
- You're speechless, I see.
A fine quality in a wife.
I will never marry you.
- Father, I choose Prince Ali.
- Prince Ali left.
Better check your
crystal ball again, Jafar.
- Prince Ali!
- [gasping]
How in the... uh. Awk!
Tell them the truth, Jafar.
You tried to have me killed.
What? Ridiculous nonsense,
Your Highness.
He is obviously lying.
Obviously lying.
Father, what's wrong with you?
I know what's wrong.
Oh, my!
Jafar's been controlling you with this.
[stammering] What? Jafar?
You, you traitor!
Your Majesty,
all this can be explained.
Guards! Guards!
Well, that's it.
We're dead. Forget it.
Just dig a grave for both of us.
We're dead.
- [Sultan] Arrest Jafar at once.
- [struggling]
This is not done yet, boy.
- [laughing]
- [coughing]
[Sultan] Find him!
- [Sultan] Search everywhere!
- Jasmine, are you all right?
Yes.
Jafar, my most trusted counselor,
plotting against me all this time.
This is horrible, just horrible.
How will I ever...
Huh?
Can this be true?
My daughter has finally
chosen a suitor?
Ha, ha! Praise Allah!
You brilliant boy,
I could kiss you.
I won't.
I'll leave that to my...
But you two will be wed at once.
Yes, yes. And you'll be happy
and prosperous,
and then you, my boy,
will become sultan.
- Sultan?
- [Sultan] Yes.
A fine upstanding youth
such as yourself,
a person of your
unimpeachable moral character
is exactly what this kingdom needs.
[lago] We gotta get outta here.
I gotta start packing.
Only essentials.
We gotta travel light.
Bring the guns, the weapons,
and how about this picture?
I think I'm making a weird face in it.
[laughing maniacally]
Oh, boy. He's cracked.
He's gone nuts.
Jafar! Jafar!
Get a grip!
Good grip.
Prince Ali is nothing more than
that ragged urchin, Aladdin.
- He has the lamp, lago.
- Why, that miserable...
But you are going
to relieve him of it.
Me?
Sultan?
They want me to be Sultan?
Huzzah!
¦Ä Hail the conquering hero
[¦Ä Stars and Stripes Forever plays]
Aladdin, you've just won
the heart of the princess.
What are you gonna do next?
[sighs deeply]
[whispering] Psst. Your line is,
"I'm going to free the genie."'
Anytime.
- Genie. I can't.
- Sure you can.
You just go,
"Genie, I wish you free."'
I'm serious.
Look, I'm sorry. I really am.
But they wanna make me sultan.
No. They wanna make
Prince Ali sultan.
Without you,
I'm just Aladdin.
- Al, you won.
- Because of you.
The only reason anyone thinks
I'm worth anything is because of you.
What if they find out
I'm not really a prince?
What if Jasmine finds out?
I'd lose her.
Genie, I can't
keep this up on my own.
I can't wish you free.
Fine. I understand.
You've lied to everyone else.
Hey, I was beginning to feel left out.
Now, if you'll excuse me, Master.
[sighing]
Genie, I'm really sorry.
[raspberry]
Well, fine.
Then just stay in there.
What are you guys looking at?
[whimpering, sniffling]
[Aladdin] Look, I... I'm sorry.
Abu, I'm sorry. I didn't...
Wait. Come on.
[sighing]
What am I doing?
[sighs] Genie's right.
I gotta tell Jasmine the truth.
[Jasmine] Ali. Oh, Ali.
Will you come here?
[sighing] Well, here goes.
Jasmine?
Where are you?
[imitates Jasmine]
Out in the menagerie. Hurry.
- I'm coming.
- [panting]
[wicked laughter]
- [goofy chuckle]
- You got a problem, Pinky?
Jerk.
[gleeful cackling]
Boy, Jafar's gonna be happy to see you.
- [imitates Jafar] Excellent work, lago.
- Ah, go on.
No, really. On a scale of
one to ten, you are an eleven.
Oh, Jafar, you're too kind.
I'm embarrassed.
I'm blushing.
People of Agrabah,
my daughter has finally
chosen a suitor.
- [crowd cheering]
- [Aladdin] Jasmine.
Ali, where have you been?
Jasmine, there's something
I got to tell you.
The whole kingdom's turned out
for Father's announcement.
No. But, Jasmine, listen to me, please.
- You don't understand...
- Good luck.
- [Sultan]...Ali Ababwa!
- [cheering]
Oh, boy.
[cheering]
Look at them,
cheering that little pipsqueak.
Let them cheer.
You know, Al, I'm getting really...
I don't think you're him.
Tonight, the part of Al
will be played by a tall, dark
and sinister ugly man.
- I am your master now.
- I was afraid of that.
Genie, grant me my first wish.
I wish to rule on high as sultan.
- Whoa!
- Bless my soul.
What is this?
What's going on?
Oh, my goodness, what's happening?
Father.
[cackling]
Jafar, you vile betrayer.
That's Sultan Vile Betrayer to you.
Oh, yeah?
We'll just see about that.
- [gasps] The lamp.
- [Jafar laughs]
Finders keepers, Abooboo.
[whistles]
[people screaming]
Genie, no!
Sorry, kid.
I got a new master now.
Jafar, I order you to stop.
Ah, but there's a new order now.
My order.
Finally, you will bow to me.
We will never bow to you.
Why am I not surprised?
If you won't bow before a sultan,
then you will cower
before a sorcerer!
Genie, my second wish...
I wish to be the most powerful sorcerer
in the world!
- [Jafar laughs maniacally]
- Genie, stop!
Ladies and gentlemen,
a warm Agrabah welcome
for Sorcerer Jafar!
Now, where were we?
Ah, yes. Abject humiliation.
- Down, boy.
- [meows]
Oh, Princess.
There's someone I'm dying
to introduce you to.
Jafar. Get your hands off her.
¦Ä Prince Ali
Yes, it is he
¦Ä But not as you know him
¦Ä Read my lips
And come to grips with reality
¦Ä Yes, meet a blast from your past
¦Ä Whose lies were too good to last
¦Ä Say hello
To your precious Prince Ali
Or should we say Aladdin?
Ali?
Jasmine, I tried to tell you.
I'm just...
¦Ä So Ali turns out to be
Merely Aladdin
¦Ä Just a con, need I go on
¦Ä Take it from me
¦Ä His personality flaws
¦Ä Give me adequate cause
¦Ä To send him packing
On a one-way trip
¦Ä So his prospects
Take a terminal dip
¦Ä His assets frozen, the venue chosen
Is the ends of the earth, whoopee!
- So long!
- Good-bye, see ya.
¦Ä Ex-Prince Ali ¦Ä
[laughing maniacally]
[wind howling]
[shivering]
Abu.
Abu!
[Abu whimpering]
Oh, this is all my fault.
I should have freed the genie
when I had the chance. Abu.
- Are you okay?
- [teeth chattering] Mm-hmm.
I'm sorry, Abu.
I made a mess of everything.
Somehow... I gotta go back
and set things right.
Carpet.
- [Abu chitters]
- [Aladdin strains]
Abu, start digging.
[frantic panting]
That's it.
Yeah! All right!
[whines]
Now, back to Agrabah.
Let's go.
- [lago] Puppet ruler want a cracker?
- [Sultan moaning]
Here's your cracker.
Shoved all the way down your throat.
Here. Have lots.
Stop it.
Jafar, leave him alone.
[growling]
It pains me to see you
reduced to this, Jasmine.
A beautiful desert bloom
such as yourself
should be on the arm of the most
powerful man in the world.
What do you say, my dear?
Why, with you as my queen...
- Never.
- [enraged growl]
I'll teach you some respect.
[gasping]
No. Genie.
I have decided
to make my final wish.
I wish for Princess Jasmine
to fall desperately
in love with me.
Ah, Master, there are a few addendas,
some quid pro quo...
Don't talk back to me,
you big blue lout.
[Jafar] You will do what
I order you to do, slave.
[Jasmine] Jafar.
I never realized how...
incredibly handsome you are.
Mmm. That's better.
Now, pussycat...
tell me more about myself.
You're tall...
dark...
well dressed...
Al. Al, little buddy.
Shh.
Al, I can't help you.
I work for Senor Psychopath now.
What are you gonna do?
Hey, I'm a street rat, remember?
I'll improvise.
[Jasmine]...cute little gaps
between your teeth.
Go on.
And your beard...
is so... twisted.
- You've stolen my heart.
- [gasping] Jaf...!
- [lago mumbling]
- And the street rat?
What street rat?
- [clattering]
- [gasping]
[gasping]
[both] Yech!
That was...
You!
How many times
do I have to kill you, boy?
Get the lamp.
No!
Ah, ah, ah, Princess.
Your time is up.
[growling]
Jasmine.
Oh, nice shot, Jaf...
Don't toy with me.
Abu!
[Jafar] Things are unraveling
fast now, boy.
[Jafar laughing]
Get the point?
[laughing]
[straining]
I'm just getting warmed up.
Are you afraid to fight me yourself,
you cowardly snake?
A snake, am l?
Perhaps you'd like to see
how snakelike I can be.
[screaming]
¦Ä Rick 'em, rack 'em, rock 'em, rake
Stick that sword into that snake
You stay out of this.
Jafar, Jafar, he's our man.
If he can't do it... great!
[Jasmine] Aladdin.
[screams]
Jasmine, hang on.
[laughing] You little fool.
You thought you could defeat
the most powerful being on Earth.
Squeeze him, Jafar.
Squeeze him like a... Awk!
Without the genie, boy,
you're nothing.
The genie. The genie.
The genie has more power
than you'll ever have.
What?
He gave you your power.
He can take it away.
Al, what are you doing?
Why are you bringing me into this?
Face it, Jafar.
You're still just second best.
You're right.
His power does exceed my own.
But not for long.
The boy is crazy.
He's a little punch-drunk.
One too many hits with the snake.
Slave, I make my third wish.
I wish to be
an all-powerful genie!
All right, your wish is my command.
Way to go, Al.
Yes.
Yes!
The power.
- [Jafar laughs]
- [Jasmine coughs]
The absolute power!
- What have you done?
- Trust me.
The universe is mine to command,
to control!
Not so fast, Jafar.
Aren't you forgetting something?
- Huh?
- You wanted to be a genie...
you got it.
What?
And everything that goes with it.
- No! No!
- I'm gettin' out of here.
[Aladdin] Phenomenal cosmic powers...
You're the genie. I don't want...
Itty bitty living space.
Al, you little genius, you.
- Ahh!
- [meow]
[Jafar] Get your blasted beak
out of my face.
- [lago] Oh, shut up, you moron.
- Don't tell me to shut up.
Allow me.
10,000 years in a Cave ofWonders
ought to chill him out.
- [lago yelling, indistinct]
- [Jafar] Shut up!
Jasmine...
I'm sorry I lied to you
about being a prince.
I know why you did.
Well, I guess...
this is good-bye?
Oh, that stupid law.
This isn't fair.
I love you.
[sniffles] Al, no problem.
You've still got one wish left.
Just say the word
and you're a prince again.
But, Genie,
what about your freedom?
Hey, it's only
an eternity of servitude.
This is love.
Al, you're not gonna find another girl
like her in a million years.
Believe me, I know.
I've looked.
Jasmine, I do love you,
but I got to stop pretending
to be something I'm not.
I understand.
Genie, I wish for your freedom.
One bona fide
prince pedigree coming up.
- What?
- Genie, you're free.
I'm free. I'm free.
Quick. Quick.
Wish for something outrageous.
Say, "l want the Nile."' Try that.
- Uh, I wish for the Nile.
- No way!
[laughing gleefully]
Oh, does that feel good! Oh!
I'm free! I'm free at last!
I'm hittin' the road.
I'm off to see the world.
I'm...
Genie, I'm...
I'm gonna miss you.
Me, too, Al.
[sniffles]
No matter
what anybody says,
you'll always be a prince to me.
That's right.
You've certainly proven your worth
as far as I'm concerned.
It's that law
that's the problem.
- Father?
- Well, am I Sultan or am I Sultan?
From this day forth,
the princess shall marry
whomever she deems worthy.
Him. I choose...
I choose you, Aladdin.
Call me Al.
Oh, all of ya, come over here.
Big group hug.
Group hug.
Mind if I kiss the monkey?
Ooh, hairball.
Well, I can't do any more damage
around this Popsicle stand.
I'm outta here!
Bye-bye, you two crazy lovebirds!
Hey, Rugman, ciao.
I'm history.
No, I'm mythology.
I don't care what I am. I'm free!
¦Ä A whole new world
¦Ä A whole new life
¦Ä Foryou and me
¦Ä A whole new world ¦Ä
[laughing]
Made you look.