Starting...
ALEX CROSS
Enjoy!
Would you like to die?
Hold it.
Drop it.
Stand still.
Wait a minute, guys.
It's not safe.
Thank you.
- You're very welcome.
It is good.
You're safe now.
How is she?
- She's alive. More so than the others.
Monica, what about that shot
in the kneecap?
It's like working with sixth graders
with you two. I'll see you later.
You have ten minutes.
Now look there.
The sky is lit.
There are many stars outside the prison.
Sit down then we make our game off.
You know I know you
two people who did not kill.
You need inspected.
But you look after me.
I've killed.
Properly.
17 years old.
Never convicted.
Pop Pop, something's not right.
- Because I was smart. I always came away with.
You're smart, but your uncle Daramus,
that guy is really smart.
Long criminal record. If he for two murders
was condemned, he was there.
He is not here, do you?
- No, you do.
Do you think it is noble what you do?
- Is that a hypothetical question?
Yes, that is noble.
You can not save everyone, Dr. Cross.
- I'm not trying to save everyone.
Only you.
It is very good,
but at that piece ...
if you're doing like
Stevie Wonder ...
Let's hear it.
Janelle, have you done your homework?
No, I'm just some math
and history do.
That's what you do so after dinner?
I do not think so.
Go upstairs and do your homework.
Chain gang.
Is there something wrong with you?
Ms?
- Take your foot off my couch.
Honey, can you help me?
Mary, you enter to something.
What is it?
Top shelf. I can not reach.
The only thing to be married to you
to be is that they are small.
What is going on?
Look around and tell what's new.
- A game?
What's in it for me?
- Your pride.
Properly.
But if I win and get it right?
- We'll see.
Where do you start?
With the front door?
Or the screen door you made.
No more squeak.
You have coffee with someone
before you went home.
A Latte.
There is some foam on your blouse.
You stopped when you did your job.
You have the car washed.
Had tanked and did some disinfectant.
- Go on.
Changes the lipstick.
Red wine is gone.
Creams and Fog.
Not bad.
But that's all insignificant.
You obviously need a clue.
I need a clue.
It was very close.
- Very close. Look.
I do not know what that might be.
Perhaps the echo in the printer?
Who told you that?
Is that for us?
- That's our child.
You're pregnant. We're having a baby.
- Are you okay?
How far have you been?
- Eight weeks pass.
It's our secret until I'm 12 weeks away.
Can you do that for as long as you keep it?
I'm not pregnant
by talking.
I think we have him or her,
Alex should call.
This can for both.
Really?
Food in 20 minutes.
That looks good.
You look like the cat that
ate the canary.
You do not know everything.
Put me down.
- No.
I'm just happy.
Very, very happy.
I'm at the line.
The transfer is diverted.
You know where to find her.
All.
Do you understand that?
You are the manager.
- On good days.
We want to bet.
- Who?
"The Butcher of Slygo '.
- The fight here.
You look at him.
We have a car.
We do not run.
10000 The Butcher and 1,000 for you.
I do not get much for a day's work.
The locker room is above on the right.
That's what I mean.
Look at him.
We do a special impromptu game.
With my husband,
a heavyweight champion ...
Dinant Stansi.
Get him, champ.
Easy earned this.
That guy can not weigh more than ...
than 58 pounds.
He must have a death wish.
Give him applause, but I do not know
why he does this.
The Butcher or Slygo.
I want a nice fair fight.
Understood?
Are you ready to be beaten up?
Do not hit me in my face,
otherwise you never fight.
Apart.
In your corner.
Ready to fight?
Come on.
Come, let me show you my favorite part
of the house.
You have powerful enemies?
He's clean.
You have a statue of Guan Yu.
The god of war.
War is a passionate company
of strategy and willpower.
Just like sex.
It therefore belongs to the bed stand.
The war was declared.
And now my favorite part.
Unconditional surrender.
Take off your panties and give them to me.
Do you like it?
Say it again.
- I like it.
I can not have.
No.
Sorry, boss. What is going on?
- There are four shot.
Four shot? Where?
414 Lake Shore Drive.
- Our district.
I give this to you and Tommy Kane.
Important.
Alex, this you must prepare.
A woman is tortured to death.
Understood?
Let's see who it is.
It's Alex.
I need this record.
Come on, Tommy. Record.
- What is it?
There are four shot and tortured.
Where are you?
I'm in a card game.
I'm winning.
You are on the cards and you win.
Redeem your money and tell me
where I can pick up.
You can pick me up at the corner
Saint Albin and Mac.
I'll see you there soon.
There is a multiple murder.
I gotta go.
Are you worried?
- No. Why?
You're pretty pissed your pants on.
I'm such an open book?
- To me you will.
What do you think I am for him?
From early on we are already best friends.
If I'm lying to him, he knows that.
We have been careful.
Caution?
Do you think we can take him in the leg?
This guy can tell you scrambled eggs
've had for breakfast from 90 feet away.
I lie way not like him.
Confess it up.
Tell him what he already knows.
That's not good for your future
and your career.
I know.
But I'm good at my job.
And Alex knows that.
- Yes, Alex knows the rules too.
And this is what we do ...
that should not go.
- But so it is.
And we are here.
- And it's only two months.
We must give some time to make sure
to be that this is real.
And if that's ...
we have difficult decisions
ahead.
You're the guy that my father said
that I had to avoid like the plague.
I like to watch you and I hate it
to you in the middle of the night to see leave.
One day you look at me ...
I like my donuts suds and slurp my coffee ...
and then beg you to me to be saved.
- The easy Irish charm. Forget it.
I thought how very way you've changed
since high school. Guess what?
I know what you're talking about and where you
worry about. It's just one thing.
Do not tell me I do not have to worry.
Briana was one thing, Skyler was one thing ...
Monica is not a thing that is dangerous.
I assume you're not a fool.
So simple is not it.
- Why do you say that to me?
I feel something for her.
Maybe I'm in love with her.
I'll make it easier for you
in case you do not understand.
You and her team brings us, me, you
and my family in danger.
I do not want to take that risk.
You need to stop, or someone must leave.
- I got it.
You're gonna do?
- What did you do today?
You do have more on your mind
than my sex life?
I get a job with the FBI, man.
Really?
- I get paid more ...
and I can spend more time with Maria
and my three kids.
Did you have three children?
Do not say ...
- The detective on duty.
Number three.
I am very happy with it.
That is great news.
Congratulations.
But an office job with the FBI,
terrible news. You can not take that job.
Tommy, I love you very much.
- Of course I love you too.
But I'd rather take advice
a ham sandwich.
Now you insult me ??really.
Let me explain something to you.
You play the game,
the game plays you.
I am determined.
It's happening.
This is what you obviously already discussed with Mary?
I knew it.
After you have discussed it with Mary ...
then you decided.
Thank you.
- How are you?
Good morning, sir.
- Good morning, boss.
You're early.
I had a prayer breakfast
the Baptist church ...
Lafayette Park.
It is a help for needy program.
You act on this?
Course.
Crime in this neighborhood ...
You do not want and it's bad for business.
Solve it.
He runs away.
- Absolutely.
That's what me here.
You want to know what Gandalf
and I have to say?
You're the magician.
What should I say.
We have another one, right?
Is this some kind of gang war?
Here at least
required for two or three.
No.
This is a guy.
- A guy who killed all three of them?
A.
Would you explain that?
What a sick guys.
It's a guy.
- Some guy.
I have a driving license.
There is at: Fan Yau Lee ...
she has $ 8,000 in cash.
The only other object, this elegant
but blank card swap.
Prints on the glass. There was
a laptop. That he has taken.
Maybe he came for.
- I do not know.
I do not think a guy this
all did.
He knew her.
Tied her up,
has had sex with her.
Then it goes wrong. She did not scream
else were her bodyguards have come.
He drugged her
with a "date rape drug.
We do a blood test.
But me get this straight.
How does he get a gun
past the guards?
They frisked him before
him alone with her.
You would think.
That down there have a .380, it seems.
A small pistol, woman model.
This has happened.
There's a guy here and shoot him.
Touches the guard twice.
If it's a guy,
we are talking about a professional.
A true professional, because
Asian man who comes through the door ...
he let him squirm, goes to his car
and takes his tools and comes back.
And he shoots him between the eyes.
And goes up for the encore.
I'm going to ask you a question.
And you get ...
nine chances to say the correct answer.
It hurts, does not it?
I am fascinated by pain.
But I can make it stop.
Tell me what the password
of your laptop.
He had a password.
I understand that.
There he not all ten fingers
required.
Those other nine were for fun.
So, he's here, cuts her fingers
off and sit here.
He draws.
Look at this.
A killer thinks he Picasso.
Charcoal.
That takes a while.
I leave the lab researching.
Maybe he's a unique type.
He does have schooling.
That's pretty good.
Let's find out too.
That is four times our salaries.
- If they did, there's more.
Safe.
- There is a safe.
What you got?
- Seems to fingerprint reading.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking?
- I always think what you think.
It's your honor.
- No, go ahead.
Do it.
- No.
You do it.
- You're the doctor.
Here we go.
Jackpot.
Slim girl.
She had a backup of its hard disk.
Looks like Picasso not always thinking.
I would like to you was wrong.
This is very annoying.
Here's the coffee you asked.
- Thank you.
I have information about Fan Yau. Not much.
- What you got?
28 Years. Taiwanese nationality.
No family here but I still look after.
She goes to the Fudan University
in Shanghai, where she graduates.
Then she won a scholarship to Oxford.
But stops after three months.
Then no trace.
If you think about the house, the jewels
and the car. That money must come from somewhere.
The chances are that there is a boy.
- Are women only as to money?
That is the easiest way for a woman.
It's about a lot of money.
Stick to the matter.
What does the coroner?
It was not death by shock.
Her heart just kept on with it.
But this is interesting.
There was a scar from a subcutaneous injection
in her neck.
Blood test results are
Of course not.
Who are always behind. Let them get along.
That is important. What have you there?
The BIOS looks strange
In English.
We have her email account through.
In her e-mails were two names for.
Jao Mercier and Erich Nunemacher.
- Mercier, who has money.
Number four on the Fortune 500.
- Here it is.
Moutish Corporation. They are here in Detroit.
The Aqua building.
As I said, a lot of money.
Did you now Erich Nunemacher?
Here are a 'E and N'.
He gives us his next target. Come on.
You're coming with us. KLEB, go ahead
and let them know we're coming.
You got it.
We come to Erich Nunemacher.
- I'm sorry, detectives ...
we said already, without a warrant
go no further.
Tell me what this is about and I
tomorrow it will pass.
He's a target.
Tomorrow morning he is dead.
A murderer does not go beyond you.
We are all former German agents.
This company is our responsibility.
The water pressure drops.
Very quickly.
Has that ever happened before?
- No.
He has been in the building. Hurry up.
- Follow me.
What is this?
- Mr. Nunemacher your life is in danger.
You must leave.
- Nonsense, this building can not income.
Tell them. And you, sterilize your hands
before you touch my furniture.
Sir, Fan Yau's killer
perhaps in the building.
Go after them himself and throw these people
to the outside.
Guard him.
Is there a door to this office
I do not see?
Idiot, this whole floor
is my office.
Sit down if you do not want
you shot.
Do not touch me. You have dirty hands.
- Sit down.
I'm not an amateur.
- What do you think you're doing?
That door should now open.
Open it.
I can not. If it is closed,
can only monitor outside open it.
Remember anything else.
Then get someone who can make him open.
- Listen, you do not, you idiot?
If it is closed, we can do nothing.
Let me see your hands.
Put the gun down.
Put the gun down now.
Would you do this when you die?
Put the gun down.
Do it now.
Put your hands behind your back.
Put your hands behind your back now.
Now do you open that door
or I'll kill you myself.
Go out and foster but suicide.
Is it?
Look at me.
I think I killed him.
He is no longer alive.
Is it?
You'll see.
You think you know.
The eyes are deeper and the bridge
the nose is stronger. Pronounced.
And he's older.
He crows feet around his eyes.
Ladies and gentlemen, that had worse outcome.
Alex, you and your team were close
but that is not enough.
I almost had him.
There's blood in the bathroom so we have DNA.
What have we got?
The charcoal pencils are unbranded
as well as the paper.
They are sold everywhere everyday.
The drawing gives us nothing.
- Witnesses?
This is Detroit.
No one says anything.
I just talked Nunemacher.
He and Mercier are trapped in the house.
With our agents and monitoring of Mercier.
Go ahead along.
Mercier who is a good guy.
A Frenchman. Very first name.
Has a million fund established to
the new town to life.
We have rich French guy
and a professional assassin ...
a multinational. What's the connection?
Fan Yau, Chief Financial Officer,
Nunemacher, chief general manager ...
He works upward.
Perhaps, when Mercier self.
- He does indeed.
We need Mercier morning visit.
- Listen to me.
I have this whole thing under control.
I have things to continue.
And so far ...
did you not tell me anything.
What do we know about the killer?
Give my team a chance.
This guy is a killer.
There is no ready profile for him.
Should I tell you what I know?
He is an ex-soldier.
Someone. I do not know who.
But he feels bad.
Restless looking for a sociopathic narcissist.
Trying to hurt someone.
Will someone pay.
Would that he suffers.
I do not know who.
Maybe his mother,
his father or himself.
The world.
Who knows.
We have good look at him,
He also gave us a good look.
Is there a chance that we
on his list?
No, it will not work.
That guy, I'm telling you, he's very focused.
Fan Yau, $ 500,000 dollars in jewelry?
He did not care about. He is focused.
He has a clear path.
He goes down the list.
He will not depart.
- I'll tell you what.
We are dealing with a psychopathic
murderer, with a clear focus.
This enables the inhabitants do not hesitate.
This is a beautiful cottage.
- You could say that.
Hello. I'm Peramita Megawatti.
The assistant to Mr. Mercier.
He expects you so, please ...
sit down and I will say that you are there.
Can I offer you anything because
we have everything?
Would you like something to eat? I can also coffee
worry because I can still use now.
I do nothing.
- Something to eat, coffee?
No. We just McDonalds on.
That's funny.
That must be strong coffee that they give.
- That was no coffee. Have you seen her eyes?
Is she stoned?
- Yeah, she's been up all night.
Nobody looks like at eight o'clock in the morning.
- I remember your undercover work.
That was a special occasion.
- Gentlemen. Good to see you.
Under normal conditions.
- I did the same thing to say to you.
Detective Ash.
I'm not expecting you.
It was very sexy to be saved
by a beautiful woman.
With such a versierzin I had him you must
to murder. I'm kidding.
Thank you, Dr.. Cross.
Leon Mercier.
I'm so sorry. My ring.
My only weakness, 14 karat.
I got it from the king of Cambodia.
Thank you all for your courage on behalf of Eric.
He and Cloche are both like family to me.
Working for you is very dangerous
lately apparently.
Can I speak with you, Dr.. Cross?
Moutish Corporation presents
a new vision for Detroit.
What do you think?
Are you like everyone Dr. Cross?
You see only death and destruction?
Sir, you want me to question
draw, I'm a cop.
This town is reborn.
A global center
for production and innovation.
But this time hydrogenation.
Nanotechnology.
Mini reactors the future.
Mr. Mercier, you and I both know
your employees are not the goal. You are that.
Any idea why?
You have done your homework.
Please sit down.
You know, there are many reasons why.
- I understand that. I do not judge.
I'm just looking for clues.
Whoever last night
Fan Yau killed ...
Erich also tried last night to murder.
I'm sure I'm his ultimate goal.
- Any idea who it could be?
I really have no idea.
But ...
I do not want to die.
Forgive me.
The pressure is enormous.
Do you like nature, Dr. Cross?
- Human nature.
Cognac?
- No.
Yes you service. But this is Louis XIII.
- Mr. Mercier, we can continue with the case?
You'll find it disgusting to
people like me to protect.
Someone who is rich and spoiled.
- Go there but not from.
I'm just looking for a villain.
You know, if I did not call
, I had called you.
Of course you would do. To me one hour
to run and nothing to tell.
No. So with my own
eyes could see ...
or you might be able to handle it
the killer.
If I was not fit, would
Erich Nunemacher no longer live, right?
No. I think you
a very good detective, you Dr. Cross.
Make no mistake. I think you
the man, I hope you are.
If I have something else in
shoot let me know.
I have another appointment
So excuse me.
Cloche please,
accompanies Dr. detective. Cross to his car to.
It is long ago that we together without
the kids are off.
And here we are with this bum.
I will not pay for his food today.
I want you to know that he has a job
to look.
Like his father, who has two, right?
The FBI's profiles, 35 percent
more money. 35 percent.
Good health,
good dental insurance.
Normal hours, not as unpredictable as this.
Come on baby, this is good.
I get it.
But on the other hand ...
I also have a career and that is here in Detroit.
- I know.
The children like school. And I
do not know how public education in DC.
And how do you explain that your mother
that you leave from Detroit?
With the National Guard and a drink.
These are the questions that need answering
before we 'for sale' sign.
I understand, really.
- We have to go through this together.
Okay, together.
Let them toast, come on.
It's bad luck to water
to toast. We do not.
That is superstition, come on.
- Okay, a toast. On the bum.
Try not to take.
Baby if I could do FBI profiles
I did this probably is not.
We're not done yet.
- I know, wait a minute.
Monica this may very well be better.
Monica?
- This is not Monica.
Do you know who this is?
Are you surprised to hear from me?
What do you want?
- Your what to send.
It now comes your way.
There are so many interesting things
you can do with fire, and water.
Dr.. Cross, are you there?
Come on.
You can do better than that.
This is your only chance for me to analyze.
Why do not you give me a few questions?
I want you to ask me a few sets.
Did you have fun?
- Come on.
Or I have fun?
Yes, I think so.
But I think you get my hobby boring.
- So your hobby is inflicting pain?
No, that is not just simply a hobby.
The infliction of pain is an important
part of my true vocation.
So it fascinates you?
In the beginning it was difficult to determine
with the guilt to go.
So where have you started? A pet
of the neighbors? Or was it from yourself?
You are disrespectful. Very disrespectful.
And that's not nice. Not at all.
I am a professional.
We're just two professionals
a conversation, right?
Your table is ready.
Would you follow me please?
I consider you as a professional.
You're not a professional.
Why not?
And last night then?
You have my instructions and drawings found.
There you have my appreciation.
Monica told me, under duress ...
the rest just happen on time.
They may have some pain, right?
You're a sick bastard impaired.
Do you?
Dr.. Cross, you take it personally.
Yes, but as personal as you out of that building
ran with your tail between your legs.
I can handle another day to finish.
Failure must be difficult
for a man like you.
So how have you punished yourself?
Wire under your nails?
Have you getazerd testicles?
That's psychology from the handbook, Dr. Cross.
Really.
A handbook.
And besides, how can I believe you when you
who wears blue tie?
Besides you have a very beautiful woman.
Just sits there ...
to decide what they will eat tonight.
She looks great.
Honey ...
Somebody call 911.
Baby look at me.
No, it's good.
I was wrong, man.
I was wrong
and see what happened.
Thank you.
What do you Tommy?
It was the lab. They have
traces of the drug ...
that bastard used. The
has a 24 hour half-life.
It's called TTX Tatras and something else.
That means he's someone
from the neighborhood. Someone knows him.
Someone has it in his hands.
It paralyzes the victim
and let him fully conscious.
That means she was awake.
She could do nothing but ...
she could feel everything happening to her.
We must find him and off.
You need to calm down,
You must stay with me, you ...
You do not understand.
- Please, Tommy. We need to figure this out.
Janelle sits in her room crying.
She is alone.
She needs you, son.
Can I?
You can not sit on your own.
We are all worried about you.
Nobody goes through this alone.
I want my mommy back, I want her back.
- I know.
I want her back.
You know, before you were born ...
I had to buy that piano of your mother.
I hate the piano, I hate it. I hate everything.
I never play anymore.
Janelle, look at me.
When I was your age ...
my father died.
And then my mom and she said ...
all things
I'm trying to tell you, honey.
But she also said that my father loved me.
And I know your mother loved you, baby.
She loved me and your brother.
And if a person is gone,
love is not gone, it stays.
Do you understand me?
It remains.
So we continue to love her mind.
Thank you baby, big girl.
Good afternoon detective.
Call this a bad time?
That depends on whether you me
tell where you are so ...
I can chase like a dog
a rabbit chase.
That's all right.
I can feel it.
I mean you looked so stunned by
at the funeral today.
But now the pain starts to really flow,
or not?
Here is another emotion for you.
That was fun.
The pleasure that I will if I have your soul
from your body see oozing, maggot.
Confucius said that if the path
of revenge enters, dig two graves.
As long as you're there but in lies.
- I?
Why me?
I mean, you let me do.
It's all your fault.
I had you in my sights, fixed.
You had so smart.
You had me irritated.
All your psychological spouting drivel.
I had decided that death too easily
to you. No, you must suffer.
Really suffering. Therefore, I
your wife away instead of you.
And now you take this knowledge to the grave.
If you just had kept your mouth shut ...
you had no pain.
I saw the way
how you and Tommy looked at each other.
I know what you're planning.
I loved her.
As if she were my own daughter.
That I do not tell you.
Look at yourself sometimes.
Self-appointed, judge, jury and executioner.
Mama, if you step aside or go up the stairs
but you're in my way.
You've lost your wife
but you're still here.
Your soul is alive in your body.
You can not lose.
I lose nothing.
I'm gonna deliver justice.
Liar.
Try me for the fool.
If you leave, you will be killed.
That's not gonna happen.
- Then grab it, do it.
You go home, is on the following day
and then what?
I need to figure out how I another day
can live without Mary.
Do not go away.
If you do run away tonight,
how do you then earn income?
If your children in the eye,
what will you tell them?
I know what's in your heart,
but you can not do this.
He does not stop.
I've seen his face.
I heard his voice.
I will always be a threat to
forms him, do not you see?
I'd rather meet his soul
the gates of hell, before I ...
him a different person from me
lets steal that I love.
Look at me.
These men take you and my children
them to a safe place.
Go with them.
And do not fuss.
There it is.
Alex Cross. How's my girl Pop Pop?
Not bad for someone
that your bill.
Now I know how those rumors started.
Why do you visit her so much?
- To see if they do not like you is.
Her some hope.
- What are you, Doctor? I have a wide range.
Do you want to replace that car which you drive?
Want a flat screen for your two little ones?
Would you kitchen appliances for your mother?
Do not talk about my children,
Not a word, understand?
What have you for my wife?
I'm sorry.
That was downright cruel.
I hope you do not think
I had something to do with it.
Should you clowns are so close?
Maybe you know something
you do not know you know.
Everyone says that, Dr. Cross.
- I am looking for a pharmacist.
Is your wife injected?
- The killer used a pharmacist.
A. And you? You know them all.
The guy I'm looking for is a very bad
judgment. He must be crazy for money.
He loves exotic stuff. Who is it?
- Why would I help a policeman?
I'm not a policeman.
- No, you're a real gangster.
Well, this top gangster,
in a real gangster car.
Do you know what this is?
A .38 with Pop Pop's fingerprints on it.
I found it when I was her arrested.
You and I both know that they trigger
not persuaded.
So I make you a deal.
Give me the pharmacist and I give you the gun.
You are definitely off the track hit.
But you're not crazy.
There was more than one there.
What is this?
There's your answer.
If a lawyer to appeal
going, you know what happens?
Then the prosecutor what evidentiary problems.
Case closed. Give me a name.
- She goes free.
Give me a name.
I want to call my lawyer.
- I'm your lawyer.
Do you TTX?
- I do not know what you're talking about.
The woman he loves is dead and
mine too. Talk to me.
Do you TTX?
- What are you talking about?
You have no lawyer but a priest.
For we hold you responsible.
Throw him.
I want a name.
I know his name.
I do not know who he is.
And those security cameras then, eh?
Maybe there was not black?
That's him.
Go back.
Slower.
Sucks, I'm not wearing my glasses.
- I got it. TD860.
Homicide.
We have a Cadillac.
- Thomas, David, eight, six, zero.
Thomas, David, eight, six, zero.
-  Wait.
No, listen to me. ANSTAR.
Call them, they can of
close distance. Let's go Tommy.
Thanks for your help.
ANSTAR says that they can not communicate
with the equipment. He has it disabled.
No, it must be traced.
Give him only the sender and receiver
the GPS.
Compare it with the chassis number
then you know where he is.
Wait a minute. You need a car chassis number
trace. I will give you the number.
0828201141308, yes.
Yes, you can send it to my screen.
Perfect, thanks.
It worked, he's in town.
He goes to ...
He's headed West Canfield Street.
- In the city, where is that?
Please tell me Mercier in town
and that we do not know.
Mercier gives a presentation this afternoon
to the city planning commission.
It's about 30 minutes to happen.
The federal courthouse.
Call Brook Well and let him know that ...
millions of baby it is
and are likely to civilian mastery.
If he federal courthouse
now shut.
That's far enough.
Close everything.
I want to be sure
everyone follow my instructions.
Anyone who has the command, she says,
and tell them that they work according to my scenario.
Mine and not theirs. Understood?
- Yes, sir.
The EOD is.
This whole block must have ...
15 minutes wiped his.
Ongoing.
It's a carpark.
Where do you play tonight, mate?
- Looks very artistically.
Do you need groupies or something?
Where do you play tonight?
Maybe we.
What do you have in the other pocket, your panties?
Panties husband. We talk to you.
That's right, just go away, bitch.
EOD, what do we have?
- It's not safe.
We can all these vehicles
impossible within ten minutes check.
One of them
can blow up the whole block.
Beautiful. So we're in the middle of Baghdad.
Max, I connect the signals.
I want you to block the signal. In a radius
of at least 20 blocks in all directions.
Close off Madison Avenue.
Lockdown within a radius of one kilometer.
They say he stopped at the corner of ...
We lost her.
- EOD, they block all signals.
On the side.
What are you doing with the train, man?
- Hey, we're talking to you. Are you deaf?
That's a terrorist, take him out.
No, please, God, no.
Please, man. I'm not dead.
Alex, I hope you have similar,
otherwise we have an expensive exercise.
Do not worry about politics
and be for once a policeman, please.
Do me a favor.
- This is not just a crazy, Will.
It does not matter what he is.
Do not you see?
If you look around you see
that everything is shielded.
There is no scenario where you
have thought that he had not picked it.
Do not you understand what I'm saying? The only thing here
must be done to stop Mercier ...
20 Blocks are closed.
This stops today.
In fact, stop it now.
Just in time for the six o'clock news, right?
- That's great.
You are both suspended,
pdf here. Your home.
Frenzy comes just.
Okay, think like him. You have in his head.
Where could he be?
Come on. Go into his head. Walk through it.
Where would you sit?
I want to personally assure
that it is closed. Completely safe.
The train.
Watch out.
Please, I will not tell anyone.
Can you hear me?
Where's the car? Go ...
- The car is at Bagley and Grand River.
That is the old Michigan Theater.
- This is converted to parking.
That must be his escape.
Talk to me, man.
Is it?
Tell me that all is well with you.
- With me it's good.
Remember that we have talked about
two graves, detective?
I am above.
You think this is good?
I'm ...
enjoy here.
I created you.
Hold on.
I got you.
Come on guys, come on.
Hold on, they're coming.
Good.
Hurry up. On three.
One, two, three.
It's over, right?
No.
It's not over, Tommy.
Cross here.
- We now come together.
Thank you, Chief.
- Wait a minute.
Who is this?
- I think you know that.
It looks like I've underestimated you.
Doctor Detective Cross.
How did you find me?
- By yours only vanity.
Your 14 carat gold ring
the king of Cambodia.
You did not get to the courthouse.
But we both knew that you were not.
It was Cloche.
You sent him inside
to attack for you to do.
An attack that you doubt yourself
have settled.
I have the line mapped.
- The transfer is diverted.
You know where to find her.
Everything. Do you understand that?
My financial problems in Germany were
is too large.
Everything is in ruins.
- Yes, 2008 was not a good year for you.
I was forced to do something drastic.
I could not afford to lose.
So you darkened the Detroit of your fund?
Nunemacher and Fan Yau were involved
to help you escape ...
so you had from them.
They had information.
So I had no choice.
And that psycho? Who is he?
- I never knew where he was.
I made contact with him on the open market.
He was highly recommended.
You let that monster loose and thought him
could check? You're an arrogant ass.
Your wife never made
part of the issue.
I'm really sorry.
- I think you should look out the window.
What is this? You have nothing against me.
There is no extradition treaty here.
- I do not want extradition.
You're in the perfect place.
- But you have no evidence, no case.
I'm clean.
- That was you, but your assistant Paramita ...
is an addict. And I knew
it is only a matter of time ...
before she was caught as they
used or sold or something.
She has overflowed.
If you specified for immunity.
But I have nothing to do with the drugs.
I know nothing since.
Why are there two kilos of cocaine,
in the box next to your favorite sofa?
Do you have any idea what the punishment is
for drug smuggling, where you are now?
That is death by firing squad.
- You tricked me.
They are lies. All filthy lies.
- My wife is dead because of you.
And you will soon be dead because of me.
I think you underestimate the days of
of people over, Monsieur Mercier.
Lies. No, help me. Let me go.
We got him.
- Yeah, we got him pretty good.
If you anticipate here tonight,
how do you then earn income?
If your children in the eye,
what will you tell them?
Well, I guess this is it.
- Yes, I think so.
Here, you can save me the stamps.
What is this?
- My obligation to the FBI.
This looks like a place up.
What do you think?
I think you let your shoot
if I'm not there. So watch out.
Very funny.
I was really worried about you.
Like the time I had to intervene before
Charlie McClinch would kick your ass.
And that was the first day in kindergarten.
Set the tone for our relationships.
- Do I remind you of the Winston brothers?
Two against one, I persisted
and you came to the end up.
I sat behind a tree to enjoy
you was beaten.
Thank you mate.
- No, man, thank you.
See you in DC.
- Of course.
The movers are so
and get paid by the hour.
You do not ...
You do not want to leave you love.