ARE YOU SURE YOU WANT TO DELETE?
DELETING FILES
ACCESS DENIED USER ID REVOKED,
FILES TEMPORARILY FROZEN
They could well say I'm a monster
for what I've done
maybe they're right .
I always thought that I'd have more time.
Dad.
I'm sorry
Peter?
He likes to sleep with the lights on.
Mary, lets go.
Dad.
Be good
I have found a safe place for the night
, at Lake Geneva.
Are you uploading it?
Yes, to Roosevelt.
In case we...
It'll be fine, Mary.
Did you see his face?
He ​​will never understand.
Mary we've been through this
Our life as we know it is over.
We will spend every day from now on
looking over our shoulders...
never feeling safe.
We can't do that to him.
He's just a little boy. I know.
It's going to be alright.
It's gonna be alright.
No rest for the weary.
No, I'm afraid not.
Occupational hazard I guess.
What is it you're working on?
Just planning ahead.
Do you think I could speak to the pilot?
Is there anything you need?
Perhaps I can help.
I'd just like to radio ahead, and make sure
everything's in order for when we land.
I think We both know that's not an option
, Dr. Parker.
They say you're a genius.
Not if you think you can escape.
It's okay.
I got you. Are you okay?
I'm going to make you safe.
It's done. Breathe.. Mary.
- Roosevelt.
- What? Roosevelt.
He goes again.
It"ll be alright okay.
Listen... to me.
UPLOAD COMPLETE
What you got for me today,
New York?
Reporting live from the New
York born chopper.
An Oscorp truck carrying plutonium
has been hijacked.
A Police chase is in
Alright lets get to work.
Say hello to, Aleksei Sytsevich.
Spider-Man. Hello, pedestrians.
Mr. criminal?
Hey My name is Spider-Man, you can call me
'webhead, you can call me amazing.
Just don't call me late for
dinner You get it?? okay!
No handshake? Are you a hugger?
I'm a murderer.
WARNING. Plutonium-238 is a radioactive
material and is highly explosive.
Excuse me.
There's room over on the sidewalk.
I design here.
Can anyone help me? Please.
Are you having problems with your gun?
Let me help you out with that.
All my work.
This is bad
I'm gonna be right back.
Look out. Wooo!
Okay There you go. Are you okay?
You alright - You're Spider-Man.
My costume gives me? Look
This is pretty important, Max.
How do you know my name?
Its written on your badge.
I'm a nobody. Hey! You're not
a nobody, you're a somebody.
Lick that. Listen to me.
The world needs you. You're
my eyes and ears, out here.
Alright! Alright
I see you out there.
Warning: Violation of protocol </
i>
Hands up..
Gotcha, gotcha
No, I got you, too.
No your not going anywhere.
Come here, come to daddy.
Get out of the way.
Got it, got it. Woo.
Ohhh come on.
Hey wait, come back.
Heel. Gotcha.
Hey I'm Sorry, I'm running a bit
late, I got stuck in some traffic.
Just tell me I know I'm sorry
Where are you?
First on Broadway second on Broadway third
on Broadway, Ah Five minutes, ten pops.
Are those sirens?...No.
Peter, No!, peter, No sirens.
Peter, what's going on
Peter.
Hello.
I'll be right there. Promise.
This years fellow victorian please
welcome, Gwen Stacy.
Good morning, esteemed faculty,
and families of my fellow graduates.
It's an honor to be standing up
here today.
Hello... I told you,
I am running a bit late.
I saw the Spider
I know that we all think we're immortal
.
We're supposed to feel.
That way, We've graduated.
Like our three, four years
years in high school...
what makes life valuable, is
that it doesn't last forever.
What makes the passage is that it ends.
We know that now more than ever.
And I say it...
today of all days
. = =
To remind us that time is luck.
So don't waste it, living someone elses
life.
Make yours count for something.
Fight for what matters to you,
no matter what.
And even if we fall short...
what better way is there to live?
Alright
I'll take that Thats my room.
This is not over, Spider
Peter Parker
I think I know that guy.
Peter Parker.
Sorry.
Wait, do it again.
I was so happy myself.
I'd like to have seen that.
No, no, no
I am so proud of you.
Were you?...I'm so proud of you
I know the first thing Uncle Ben
would say... I know to.
"You got to hurry up the party's over.
You gotta go out and get a job."
And then he would say: "Don't just
follow the path. Make your own trail."
"Ralph Waldo Emerson... no?"
He said he'd made it up.
You really did learn something here.
I wish your uncle could have been here.
Yeh me too. And my folks.
Yeh, yeh.
Alright, you can go.
Guys, come together.
Alright 'Cheese'...Cheese.
Yeh Just gimme two seconds.
Don't go too far away.
Good to see you. Alright.
Did your traffic jam have anything
to do with the Russian mob...
and machine guns?
Why don't you just tell me?
When you going to give a speech.
Gwen. Honey, family photos. Okay
are you coming to dim sum?
You can't keep me away.
Its at eight o'clock. Don't be late.
I'm hungry.
I am going to domesticate you.
Alright I want to hear it all night long.
Over and over again, all night long.
That was pretty good.
Peter, join us.
I have to find my aunt, I gotta find my
aunt. But I may catch up later. Thank you.
You will make enemies.
People will get hurt.
You have to promise me something kid </
i>
Leave Gwen out of this.
Promise me that.
Peter's outside.
Peter.
What is it?
Whats wrong? Are you alright?
I don't know what I'm doing.
Its my my father, right?
Yes, I see him everywhere I go
I don't know what to do.
I can't get him out of my head.
I thought We'd talked about this.
Yeah, I know...
It's not his choice.
I promised him that I would
keep away from you.
And now I'm gonnna come
and eat dinner with your family.
How can I do this?
What does this make me?
I don't know I've got No idea.
It makes me not able to
live with myself.
I thought that it would make you love me?
I do love you.
I love you.
Then why isn't that enough? Hmm.
What if something happens to you, just
like it happened to him, because of me?
No, wait.
I cannot let that happen.
You are Spider-Man...
and I like that.
But I love Peter Parker more.
Thats worth it to me.
I cannot lose you too.
Because you do not want,
we can't be together?
Why are we here?
I can't. I'm sorry, Gwen.
You have done this to me...
Again, again... Peter
I can't live like that.
I break up with you.
I broke up with you.
Good morning, New Yorkers.
We find a beautiful day here in the city
.
The city increases in sightings of
Spider-Man, spark a national debate...
over the role of vigilantes
in American crime fighting .
Spider-Man, Last night on
manhatten he saved a dozen lives.
We want to hear your calls.
Without Spider-Man
there is no hope for this town .
Who pays the bill for all damages he leaves
behind? Its you and me the taxpayer.
Did you make this?
This is a wind turbine.
Did you make this? No way!!
This is amazing.
Good as new. I'll walk you home.
- Whats yours?
- Jorge.
Jorge, I'm Spider-Man.
I feel like my kids are
safe, with him out there
keep out of the way,
and let the police do their job.
Some folks think that there
might be than one Spider-man.
What do you think.
One guy or many
I'd love to know who's behind that mask.
- Nice outfit.
- Thanks.
We have a caller on the line called named
Max, who claims he knows Spider-Man.
Listen I'm upset.. Spider-Man
to me is being misunderstood.
He's a very, very good person,
He's protecting us.
Not only that He saved my life, onetime,
and we sure became best friends.
How much?..your that Spider guy.
I'm Spider-Bad.
This Spider-Man guy, he's not
the police, he's not a fireman.
What gives him the right,
to get involved in other people's business
Peter, Honey, can I come in?
NO!!
Peter the final starts at nine honey.
And you said you'd take my car
into the shop, remember?
Gimme a second Aunt May, I'm gonna
get the door, just gimme a second.
Please just Let me alright.
The exam is at 9 am,
you my first car...
No you can't come in stay outside
I'm still naked.
You said you're gonna take my car
into the shop because...
- Are you alright?
- Yeh. You okay
I'm just, I'm very naked
Aunt May.
Whats happened to your face, its dirty?
It is?...Yes.
Ohh yeh yeh I was cleaning
the chimney.
- We have no chimney.
- What?
- You're late.
- I know, I'm late.
Downstairs... NOW
alright I'm leaving?
I am naked here.
Morning. I love you.
I love you too. Hurry up.
MAX AND SPIDER-MAN SAVE NEW YORK
say something look who's here?
Spider-Man.
How was your morning?
As always, Max.
I was trying to save the world
to protect humanity.
Is not it someone's birthday today?
Thats why you're here.
You remembered my birthday.
All the crime fightin, you've been doing and
still have time to visit little old me Max.
It's amazing.
Course. Why wouldn't you visit?
We're best friends.
What are you doing?
Did you make a cake?
People do not see the little
things that you do for others.
I know what they say about you in the
press, but it doesn't matter to me.
Because I know the real you.
Because You're amazing.
That's what the press needs.
They should call you the
amazing Spider-Man '.
You like this, Spidey?
I like it a lot, Max.
Good... Because today is going
to be amazing.
Circuit break
I'm not late.
I'll be there in fifteen minutes.
I just wanna know if you can find another
waitress to replace me.
Because I start my training, up at
the hospital.
But don't mention this to Peter.
Because he worries.
Yeh.yeh, Okay you got it. Double
shift on Thursday. Okay bye.
- Who was that?
- Harvey.
- A double shift huh?
- Sometimes.
I have nothing else to do
I like the girls.
I miss Ben, give me a little
extra, in my cookie jar.
I have some, another couple of photos
from the bugle so that outa help.
It would really help if that guy
would give me a fair wage
Jameson pays me a fair wage,
as it was in 1961.
HEY, HEY, wait. Where you
going? What are you going?
I'm doing my laundry.
No, I do the laundry.
Its my job, I've been doing your
laundry since you were six years old.
I'm in college now, its time I took
care of my own dirty underwear.
The last time you did the laundry,
you turned everything blue and red.
That was a mistake.
I was washing the American flag.
No one washes the flag.
I do, I wont anymore fine
It's just underwear.
This is my laundry, my home
my machine. Eat your breakfast.
Alright laundry sheriff.
I'll do it later.
I'll do it. Give it.
No, I'll do it another time.
- Excuse me.
- Idiot.
I do not get it.
Lock slot. Come on, come on.
Watch it, buddy.
Oscorp Industries proudly announce... </
i>
world's first electromagnetic
power plant .
By converting aging power stations
into hydro electric towers...
we're generating clean,
green, sustainable energy...
that the city can provide
and finally the rest of the world...
Dillon, you're late. The
trains were so slow.
Do not you realise that Oscorp is not
responsible for the entire city?
The designs for the power grid,
and they use a lot of them.
Those power grids were
designed by me.
You designed them? Sure you did.
I'm Spider-Man.
You're not Spider-Man.
Talk to me about him,
and I'll rip your head off.
Now get to work.
Which floor - 74.
Thank you ..
Hold that.
I got it.
Thanks, you're a gentleman.
Most would left the door closed. Well
people don't notice other people.
Which floor - 63...
Let me. What?
- 63
63, please - Thank you..
Thanks.
My name is Max Dillon.
I'm Gwen. Nice to meet You.
Likewise.
Is it your birthday?
Oh yeh, this flyer.
The birthday party is in big club.
Many celebrities.
I would like to invite you
but the guest list is closed.
I understand that.
But thanks anyway. Sounds exciting.
It must be cool that the whole world is
watching.
You know Spider-Man saved my life once.
Of all the people in the whole
city he saved me.
He said he needed me.
That must be a wonderful feeling.
Floor 63.
Nice to meet you, Max.
Wait, she remembered my name.
Welcome home.
It's dark in here.
Your eyes will adjust.
It's better this way.
Pa.
This is not how I imagined
I'd die.
Looking at my son,
and seeing a stranger.
You had such potential, Harry.
Such intelligence,
and you've thrown it all away.
You threw me away.
You sent me to boarding
when I was eleven.
On my 16th birthday...
you sent me Scotch.
Or one of your assistants did.
I'm pretty sure, there
was the card: In it.
With compliments. Norman Osborn.
I don't. Expect forgiveness
from you
I don't believe in miracles.
How could you possibly
understand...
that your childhood
had to be sacrificed...
for something greater?
Not just for me. For you.
Are your hands starting to twitch yet?
When you lay awake...
Hiding under your skin...
waiting to show itself.
To show you who you really are.
Retroviral hyperplasia.
I never told you...
But its genetic.
Our disease.
The Osborn curse.
When it began at your age.
Let me see it.
Your hand, give it to me.
The greatest inheritance
I can give you
is not money.
Told you about my work.
Perhaps you can succeed...
where I failed.
BEST MR JAMESON NEW PHOTOS ADDED
MAYBE IT IS POSSIBLE THAT
SPIDER-MAN JUST WANT HELP
Sincerely PETER PARKER.
WRONG
Norman Osborn, the legendary founder
and CEO of Oscorp Industries has died.
The Osborn estate has confirmed </
i>
He is survived by his only son, Harry
Osborn, who is the sole heir...
of the Oscorp corporate empire..
Osborn fundamentaly changed the medical
professions approach to human healing...
And affected the lives of millions
.
I started Oscorp because I looked at
the world around me and I thought.
"We can do better.
We should do better. ".
Einstein said the world can not be changed,
without changing our thinking.
But change isn't just a slogan.
It begins with hard work. Change begins
with persistence and commitment.
Mr. Osborn changed the world.
Now its up to each of us to ensure that
his hopes and dreams remain alive.
But not today.
- Today...
- Hello?
I speaking with Gwen Stacy
Yeah, who's calling?
I'm calling from the Oxford college
program we have some exiting news
Dillon, you stay here.
Theres a current flow problem in genomics
lab.Why don't you go take a Look at that.
It's my birthday. Everybody else
is leaving, Why do I haveto stay?
Because you're special. Smythe...
I mean Mr Smythe.
Happy birthday.
Bio electrogenesis.
Production of electricity by
living organisms...
Hi guys.
Someone loves a party.
You're just a little queasy.
I got your medicine.
And on my birthday.
After all I've done for this company.
Warning.
Error in sector 5A
It's just reflux...
Did you know my birthday, Kari? Get
you to sing "Happy Birthday" for me?
Then I'll just have to sing
it to myself.
Gilbert, its Max. Can you shut
down power in sector 32, please?
Forget it I'm out the door.. What
do you mean Henderson? Hello!
Sorry, Max
I'll do it myself.
And I'll sing to myself.
Happy Birthday... To me.
Happy Birthday.
To me.
System restored Have a nice day.
Harry, Oscorps are under intense public scrutiny,
in the wake of Dr. Connors recent breach of trust.
You mean, people are pisssed off because he
tried to turn everyone into giant lizards?
Given that...
all the animals hybrids programs he
was involved in were destroyed...
to restore investor confidence.
That is, the Osborn way.
If somethings inconvenient round
here just get rid of it, right?
Much of that statemen may fall on
you now.
You sell a plausible deniability as
your best option... Sure, sure.
A twenty-year-old kid.
A 200 billion dollar company.
What was Dad thinking?
I mean You're all lawyers...
Right!
Surely someone must have questioned his
sanity in the end.
Someone must have thought about having
him declared legally incompetent.
It would have made this conversation,
a lot easier... Harry...
It's Mr. Osborn.
We're not friends.
Hii.
You were his assistant, right?
What is your name?
Felicia... Felicia.
From now on, everybody at this table
will? Felicia.
Because Felicia works for me.
Would anybody like to speak up??
Well good. Then you can all
keep your jobs, for a while.
Sir... There's Peter Parker
that you would like to speak to you
Felicia, I want to see every
file on this list.
Every single one.
Peter Parker.
It's like seeing a ghost.
Hi, Harry.
So random.
- Its ten years.
- Eight.
Close.
So, how you doing kid.
I heard about your Dad and I wanted
to... Come and..
To check it out, To see how you're doing.
I'm with some people.
I'm in a meeting.
Sorry I didn't want to intrude,
I know it's been a long time.
I know exactly what you're going through.
.
And you were so there for me when my
parents...
Thats why I'm here.
Thank you.
It was good to see you man.
Very good.
Sorry about your Dad.
You've got your braces on.
Now it is all your focus back on your
one eyebrow.
There it is.
Does someone dry your
hair every morning?
One of my main servants
hold the hair dryer...
But I work the comb.
Okay, so at least I'm not completely
helpless.
After graduation I went
to Brazil and Singapore.
- And then Europe.
- I saw you.
What do you mean? You saw.
I saw you in some magazine with some French
supermodel, You know what I'm talking about?
The whole model thing is
so exhausting. I know.
What?
Do you have a girl?
Thats a question.
No, I'm not a girl.
I don't know.
It's complicated.
Yeh I don't do complicated.
So What's her name? Who is she?
Her name is Gwen. Gwen Stacy.
- Gwen Stacy?
- She works for you.
Really?
She's an intern Oscorp.
Is she a model employee?
When my father sent away me I tried to
forget everything about this place..
I guess that kind of
includes you.
You don't have to explain to me.
Bro.
We both got dumped.
Did you ever figure out why your parents
bailed?
My Dad left a briefcase.
Thats all I got a briefcase full of junk.
I try not to think about it.
Hows that working out for you?
Perfect.
What a throw.
Its just the wrist.Its just all in the
wrist buddy.
You can do it with some strength.
Things have gottne crazy around here man.
Giant lizards, and...
Spider-Guy.
There's just one guy,
just one Spider-Man.
Or woman.
We don't know for sure.
He ​wears spandex to rescues kittens from
trees.
Very impressive.
I think he just gives people hope.
For what?
That eventually everything gonna
be alright.
I wish I had time for eventually.
Who was he? Maxwell Dillon,
electrical engineer.
No associates or friends to speak of.
He ​​submitted specs for the grid,
that we... appropriated.
He was invisible.
Wall Street's nervous enough that
child having taken over the company.
We've got to find a way to get him out.
In the meantime the press gets hold of this
accident. Our stock will?
So make sure that this Mr. Dillon
still remains invisible.
This could prove useful for us
in the future.
Hi.
Move.
Hey!
You look amazing.
I'm sorry for the spontaneous...
Spontaneous is...
Its how I feel.
I just figured it was time.
Time we try to be friends.
Friends, yeah, that's...
awesome.
I don't want this to be complicated.
I hate complicated.
Keep it simple.
Okay great. Yeh, yeh. But...
I mean.
Look If we're friends,
we gotta establish some ground rules.
Basic Rules?
- Like that.
- Like what?
That laugh.
This should not.
You must annoying laugh.
That's still adorable.
That was not adorable.
Okay I've got one.
What? What is it.
Don't tell me that I look amazing..
With your big brown doe eyes.
I really mean it.
No..No... What
I've just figured out the next
ground rule.
Do more of this.
The nose rub.
What am I supposed to do?
It's allergy season.
I can not stand. I'm gone.
Come on.
First we get ice cream,
and then I'm out.
I have done it.
And as I completely addicted to this
place that has Korean meatballs.
Are you going to eat?
It's great.
On 6th Street. I know
You will love it there.
How do you know?
How do you know I love it there?
Cos hmm.
You told me.
It just opened last month.
Did you follow me?
I knew it. How often?
Just once a day. Sometimes.
Sometimes more.
Why?
To watch me? ...Yeh.
And because its the closest
I could get to you.
I'm moving to England.
What?...Yeh.
I have a scholarship at Oxford.
In molecular medicine.
It's between me and this other kid.and
there's this oral exam... We need to do
and he's like a freshman
in college, but he's 14 years.
He can possibly be,
but I can be.
And then I have to move to England.
I'm really excited.
That's...
England?
I need reinforcements.
Send patrol cars to the southend
corner of Duffy Square.
Everyone get out the way please.
Get out the way.
Remove your hands from the cables.
Get your hands away
from the cables.
Let me see your hands.
Stay right where you are.
Do not move.
Freeze. Get down, on the ground.
Get down on the ground now.
- Stop.
- On the floor.
It's not my fault. Stop.
Please...
My goodness.
They see me standing. They see me.
They see me.
No... Stop. Don't do that.
Please.
Wait, it's not my fault.
It's not my fault.
I said, stop.
I'm glad your not one of those
cops that rides a horse.
Team members... Hold your fire and wait for
my call.
Hold your fire, I repeat hold
your fire. And stay down.
Stop. Stop it well, Sparkle.
Hey..How are you doing?
It's You. Well I know its me,
Who are you?
You don't remember me?
No, should I?
I walked into the street, the car
almost hit me. You swung me up.
You saved me.
You said you needed me.
The guy, you're the guy with the
Blue-prints... Yes, Blue-prints
I remember you, course I remember
you, your my eyes and ears.
What's your name again?
How could you forget me?
I do, I know. I know it, don't tell me...
It's Max. Is it Max?
Yes
I'm sorry, I didn't recognize you with...
You look different.
How are you?
I don't know what's going on
with me... I believe you.
Its strange.
I have so much strength.
I have so much anger.
I can see that, you don't want
to be here You're scared.
You don't know whats happening, to you, I can
see that you don't want to hurt anybody.
You'll be alright. I've got a clear shot.
Standing by.
They're not going to shooy you.
Guys, this is my buddy Max.
I told you about Max.
No one shoots at Max.
It's just between you and me talkin. Whoahh...
Stay right there, stay right there.
Be careful with the grid
and the electricity.
I just wanted them to all see me.
If he makes a move,
take that shot.
Come with me, somewhere we'll talk
away from all these people... Okay.
NO... Stop.
Spidey.
You..Queer.
Electric idiot.
He lied to me, he shot me...
Shut up.
You're so selfish.
Stay with me Max.
You set me up.
No..I didn't set you up.
You lied to me. No, I'm trying
to help you, let me help you.
It's my birthday.
And now Its time for me to light up
candles.
Can anyone see Spider-Man?
That's enough.
Mike. Big John.
Nice work fella's. It was a
pleasure doing business with you.
Spider-Man...
England?
Really?
That's hot.
Our coverage of a breaking story begins
with Jessica Abo, at the scene.
We're staying here with two eyewitnesses,
who are going to tell what they just saw.
So tell us How did the Spider-Man
do it. How did he beat this creature.
Its got to be rubberised, Spideys suit
thats why he didn't get electrocuted.
Probably neoprene.
Thank you very much, the two of you
so many questions remain unanswered..
WHAT IS ROOSEVELT?
DO I HAVE TO LOSE YOU TOO????
Online polls show a sudden upset of public
sentiment in favourof the wall-crawler.
Tonight it would seem the city owes him
a debt of gratitude.
Next generation of
military body armor.
Features include enhanced
mobility, battlefield injury repair.
Nervous system interface.
So the common household spider,
and merged human cells.
Have contained the power
to self heal...
From severe infection, tissue damage.
We used a radioactive isotope
with compatible human DNA..
Welcome to, Dr. Jallings science
investigator.
Today we're going to be talking about
electricity. Very interesting.
Batteries, insulators,
electromagnetic current.
Batteries can withstand
a lot of incoming current.
The more powerful the battery, the
bigger the current it can withstand.
If the incoming charge,
exeeds the outgoing charge.
The battery might explode.
EXPLODE.!!!
Doing experiments like this,
always wear protective gear.
We need a bigger power.
Hello? Pete its me.
Hello, Harry. What time is it?
Late. I dunno.
I've been up all night.
I need to see you.
You alright...?
Not really Pete.
I'm dying... But I think you can help
save my life.
Your looking at the world's first
Human-Spider hybrid.
In the hope is to extract the venom
from their glands.
Turn that into a cure, an agent
That heals diseased cells.
And If I can be cured...
Imagine what this could do for other
diseases like Alzheimer's even cancer..
They never made it to
human trials.
14 years of research, and nothing
to show for it.
Except maybe this.
- Spider-Man.
- What about him?
He was bitten by one of
those things and it worked.
I don't know how and I
don't know why... But
he can do everything else a spider can..
Including Self heal.
I need to find him.
I need his blood.
You drink Spider-Man's blood?
It will save my life.
It may not Harry.
It's not that simple.
Look what happened to Curt Connors.
Connors was weak.
This is me Peter.
Why do not you put it in the newspaper,
help him donate?
I'm sure he's sensitive to people shoving
needles...
Sensitive?
Well then you could just sensitive me,
tell me where he is.
And I will go ask him myself...
No.
You took his picture.
So you know him.
I took a picture from a long way away,
it was a long lens. I don't know him.
Together you said at the river.
How he gives people hope.
Come on.
DATABASE BY START SEARCH
SEARCH USER
NAME NOT FOUND
SEARCH BLOCKED
Just say yes.
Don't turn your back on me.
I do not want to end up like my father.
Peter.
Please.
Peter, please.
I will try and find Spider-Man.
What does the security here?
Wait. Miss Stacy.
What are you doing here?
She's not here.
Look on another floor.
You in trouble?? Who's that man?
There was an accident,
they are trying to cover it up.
When I found out, that guy
from Times Square Last week...
I met him, he was and an
electrical engineer..
He would Spider-Man love it.
Because I got the feeling,
that he wanted to kill me.
How it feels to love you.
I visited him in the computer,
but everything was cleared about him.
Totally glossed over.
Typically Oscorp.
Why are you here?
Harry, he's dying.
- What do you mean?
- He's dying.
And He thinks Spider-Man's blood can save
his life. My blood and Spider-mans blood.
As far as I know, if I give it to
him, it could kill him.
Or worse.
This is a maintenance closet.
Gwen!
The most? Hiding place
you could have chosen.
I'm... sorry.
This hiding place could
take us to the Bahamas.
We need to talk about England,
because I do not want...
You kissed me. I'm sorry,
I couldn't help it.
How did you like it?
- It felt a bit rushed.
- I know.
This is the plan. Get the elevator,
while I distract him.
I'm sorry... I'm all thumbs today
Gwen Stacy
I'm Harry... Yeh
I'm an old friend of Peters.
Yeah, I know who you are. Sorry.
I was funny rushing...
I'm sorry he never mentioned.
I thought you two had broken up.
Yeh, yeh, we have but it's...
Complicated.
Everythings always
complicated with Peter.
That's right. But
that's why he needs you.
Right?
To help him make his choices
clear.
Nice meeting you. Yeh
It was a pleasure.
RAVENSCROFT INSTITUTE
You've had a terrible accident.
I'm Dr. Kafka.
I'm here to help you.
Of course, Doctor.
Thats why you prepared
military grade, Biostim electrodes.
High intensity capacitors.
The kind they make at Oscorp.
All this because you're trying to help me.
You are correct.
I'm here to study you.
To understand what you are, and why
.
I will get results.
I always do.
Do you realize you'll lock me in a
prison...
powered by electricity?
I feel it in the walls.
In my veins.
What you do. You can't contain.
It's a force of nature. Like me.
Want to know how powerful I am?
Yes.
Well so do I..
GOOD, ,,GOOD
I'm dying to know.
You'd better make damn sure that you
kill me. Because if you don't..
I'm gonnna kill the light.
Everyone in this city, will discover
how it feels, to live in my world.
A world without power.
A world without mercy.
A world without Spider-Man.
And everyone will see me
who or what.
Who are you?
Don't you know? I am Electro.
Warning . Electrical capacity reaches
escape.
Initiate lockdown
procedure, immmediately.
Very impressive, Electro.
Lockdown began.
Aunt May?
What are you doing?
When did you do this?
There's something your not
telling me, Aunt May.
Every time I mention my parents,
your eyes go down.
I know you're not telling me something.
You're lying to me.
I know you love me... I don't. I
know you love me..But you do.
Tell me. It's my father.
Yes, he was your father...
but that didn't seem to stop him
from leaving you.
I need the truth.
The truth is that your parents left you
here, on our door-step.
This little boy whose world was turned
upside down with no explanation.
We did the best, we could.
You Uncle Ben, he and I.
Who else was going to care for you and
protect you? And worries about you.
Your father? No.
I was the one who wiped your nose,
who made you brush your teeth...
and do your homework. And washed
your dirty underwear. ME!!
You stupid, nonscientific aunt, who
doesn't know how to make ends meet...
who has to take nursing classes, with 22 year old
kids, so I can pay for you to go to college.
And I don't know how to do
this without Ben. I don't know how.
And you're dreaming about your perfect
father...
Who was never here. NO!
No I wont tell you.
You're my boy.
As far as I'm concerned, you're my boy.
And I wont hurt you
I'm your boy.
You're my everything.
You're more than enough.
That's not what this is about.
- I love you so much.
- I know.
It's okay.
Aunt May...
I need to know.
Alright.
I'll tell you everything I know.
But It will hurt you. Okay.
A few days after the funeral...
The government men.
Came to see us.
They said, the genetic research...
That your father was doing with
Norman Osborn, was very valuable.
And that people would pay a lot for it.
And thats why he ran off with it.
They said he was a traitor.
I couldn't believe it.
They told us he betrayed his best
friend for, all of us, for the money.
I don't understand..
Yes, I know.
I didn't believe it.
This doesn't make any sense..
Peter... I don't know how.
For so long. I would play it over and over in
my head, what had I missed. What had I missed.
He was just a normal unasuming guy. He wore
the same ratty lab coat for 20 years...
He took the D train to work,
at seven every morning...
came home at 6 every night.
I don't know.
Maybe everyone has a part of
themself, to hide...
Even from the people they love.
Mr. Osborn.
Look up.
You were looking for me.
I do not believe my eyes.
Spider-Man.
Just the man I wanted to see.
You ah, talked to Peter? ...Yep
I want to help you, Mr. Osborn.
I really, really do.
I can't give you my blood.
Not right now.
- Pardon?
- It's too dangerous.
If our blood is not compatible,
you could die.
I'm already dying.
Your blood can give me time.
But it could do something worse.
Okay.
Alright How much?
- What?
- How much do you want?
A boat or plane? Or
Money? How much do you want?
I don't want your money.
Everybody wants my money
I don't.
I thought you saved people.
I thought thats what you do.
Is you save peoples lives.
You just gonna let me die.
I'm trying to protect you.
Right now.
You're trying to protect yourself.
Look..We just need
a bit more time...
I have no time. Get out
I'm sorry.
You're a fraud, Spider-Man.
Can I to talk to you for a second.
I'm running late. Right now.
It only takes a minute.
Give me some time.
One thing. Then I'm gone.
It's a mess.
My Dad my mum,
everything my father done lies.
Lies. Lies, lies
Nothings as it seems.
So here we are? I went to see Harry Of
course I want to save him. You know.
He's my best pal.
What if my blood works? But what if it
doesn't? I don't know. I got no idea
I have nothing.
The only thing I keep coming back to...
Gwen Is.
Miss Stacy, shall I take you
upstairs?
Yes, I'm so sorry.
I'm so sorry..I'm already late...
Can I have just one moment?
Thank-you.
Where are we?
This is my last interview for Oxford.
I don't know.
I'm sorry to bother you.
But who am I? I am John Hopkins.
I'm one of the young professors at Harvard,
and I'm trying to get her to be in my...
Part of my team. For a while now.
And she is the best person I know,
and a scientific genius.
Anyway, "God save the Queen, ' I'm
sorry that I made things... Peter!!"
Peter What do you want to say to me?
Whats the one thing?
I have to leave for a year.
Its important to me.
Maybe we are moving in
the opposite direction.
I don't know.
We were just going different ways.
I gotta go. I gotta go
Gwen.
Good luck.
'Secret Roosevelt station.
Track 61 secret underground detour...
line D towards Pershing Square.
Here President Franklin Roosevelt
could be transported quickly...
"to keep his polio secret
for the American people."
Mr Osborn.
You alright? Is there anything I can
get you?
No, unless you can bring
those Spiders back, to life.
Spiders?
The ones that they destroyed.
"To restore investors confidence."
Go home, Felicia.
Take the day off.
Harry!
I think there may be another way,
to get what you're looking for...
I overheard Menken talking
with one of our security.
Before they destroyed the spiders
they had the venom extracted.
What are you saying?
That way they could comply with the lawsuits, and
still keep the data for when it became useful.
Where is it?
Somewhere in the building.
An unregistered department
called "Special Projects".
Special Projects.
Last entry: 1 hour ago
'Approved by Harry Osborn...
Access Ravenscroft archive.
And I'll turn off the light.
So that everyone in this city will discover
what its like to live in my world.
A world without power.
A world without Spider-Man.
Warning. Your user
access has been revoked.
You can not enter. He's busy.
What did you do? A more relevant
question is what did you do?
An employee is killed, and in your
first act as CEO you cover it up.
No, you covered it up, and then you
buried him in the madhouse using my name.
Ravenscroft is a time institution
devoted to mental improvement.
You are experimenting on people in there.
Progress has its stepping stones.
Now in light of your deceptive
criminal actions, you'll be happy.
How do I say this gently...
sacked.
You are not going to bury me.
It looks to me like you're
halfway in the ground already.
It's only a matter of time.
You're going to die a horrible death.
Like your father.
The difference is,
no one is going to miss you.
- Get him out of here.
- Wait.
I know the way out.
My name is Richard Parker.
Whatever lies will be told about me,
I would like the world to know the truth.
Oscorp was already a leader
in genetic research...
When Norman Osborn made a deal with
a foreign military organization.
To continue funding my research..
I found out what they were going to
it for.
Weapons.. Biological weapons, of course.
So I refused.
Now to get me out of the picture..
Norman Osborn, has
falseified evidence against me...
In order to take control,
of my work.
Can I help you?
Yeh you can open the gate.
I'm Harry Osborn.
Theres a patient, that I specially
would like to see.
Joe, this is Mr. Osborn Oscorp.
Sorry, Sir, without a yellow badge,
you can't come in here.
It doesn't matter, because there is
something else that Norman doesn't know.
The Human DNA, that I implanted in
the spiders...
was my own.
Which means that without me
without my bloodline...
Oscorp can never replicate or
continue my experiments.
With Electro integrated.
400 milligrams of sodium
and phenobarbital.
I've destroyed as much as possible
from the archives...
but I didn't have time
to kill all the spiders.
As a scientist, my choice is very clear
now.
I have to disappear. I have to get
as Far away from here, as I can.
But as a father...
It Means, I may not see my boy
again..
Nothing is as important to me,
as my son, Peter.
Nothing in this world.
But I have a responsibility to protect
the world, from what I've created.
And protect him from what
I know Osborn, is capable of.
People will say I'm a monster...
for what I've done.
Maybe they're right.
I always thought that I'd have more time.
DAD!!...DAD!... I'm sorry.
Anesthesia... off
I'm gonna get you out,
But we haven't much time.
Who are you? - I'm Harry Osborn.
I want to make you a deal.
- I should kill you.
- Come on.
Think, Max.
I'm not the one you want.
You want Spider-Man.
And I can give him to you.
But... I need something first..
I need you to get me to Oscorp.
Get you Inside? You own it.
Not anymore.
Oscorp betrayed us both.
So I can't get in there without you, And
you can't get out of here without me.
What's happening? Someone triggered
an alarm in the iso unit..
Get a containment team in there now..
You can't possibly know what I want.
You improved the design to the grid, and
they stole it, and now you want it back.
You just wanna take what's
yours.
All the power is in the city, Max,
and its right at your fingertips.
Once you have completed the
electricity network...
Spider-Man will come to you, bleed
him.
Break the glass.
Max, we don't have much time.
Go... go... go.
One reason why I should I trust you?
Because I need you.
- You need me?
- Yeah, I need you.
You are my only chance, that
I have of surviving.
- You need me?
- Yes, I need you.
I need you. Please.
I know what its like to be thrown away..
Please!!! MAX!!
I need you. I need you.
You will you be my friend?
I thought we were already?
I had a friend once.
It didn't work out.
Yeah, me too.
Let us go catch a spider.
You have one new voice message.
Hi, Peter, Its me.
I got in to Oxford. Woo-hoo.
Very exciting
I came by your house, a little bit
ago And I..You weren't there. And so
I'm on my way to the airport...
Right now.
Because there's a summer
conferance, I had read about
and I thought that it would
somehow.
Be easier, I guess, this way.
I think that maybe its time to,
let us go...
And thats not because I don't love you,
but its actually because I do.
Goodbye..
We have to move now.
Why... Whats happened?
Remember me?
Ohhh, my oh my, how the tables have
turned.
I know it's hard to admit... But ahh
spectacular.
Move into this..Am I right?
Right thats right.
So... Dear godfather..
It's time to create me a wish.
I want in to special
...- How dare you come back here?
You, unworthy, defective.
Ohh..Sorry, that's not the answer
what we were looking for.
"Clear."
Welome back to the bonus round.
Let's take a walk. Shall we...
The grid is all yours.
Spider-Man. Give it to me.
- What is this?
- The future.
Rope one on..
It won't work.
We're in heavy diagnostic test.
Apart from human trials. You've
actually already run human trials...
you're just too stupid to know it.
Do it. Now.
You've had all this time.
CRITICAL INJURY DETECTED
HEALING PROTOCOL ACTIVATED
It's Spider-Man.
Stop the cab.
Wait I aint even moving...
I LOVE YOU
Did you get my message?
What message?
The message from above.
Wow-that was you?
Don't go. Let the world get off.
It says that 'I love you'.
Because I love you.
No offense, but you're wrong.
You're my path, you're my path.
You and I will always be togetherl.
I know there are a million reasons
why we shouldn't be together.
But I'm tired.
I'm tired of everything.
Of having to make a choice.
And I choose you.
So...
heres my thought.
England.
Both of us.
I'm following you now.
I'm just going to follow you everywhere..
I'm just going to follow you
the rest of my life..
They got crime there. In England..
Apparently They have tons of crime.
Yeh I know... Jack the Ripper.
They haven't caught Jack the Ripper, he's
still in London..
What the hell is that?
Is that Max?
He ​might just cut power to the city
I need tech-ops up here right now.
Phone lines are down. Someone
go down and grab. Tech-ops...
Hey... write down what you remember,
people.
There's gotta be some sort
of a backup plan, right?
There is an emergency generator.
The transmission lines
they're never gonna get the backup.
How can I stop him?
Every time I get close, to him
he fries my webshoots.
Have you tried to stop him?
Yes, rubber, plastic...
Did you try to magnetizing him?
I didn't... Try magnetizing him.
Okay well, remember eighth grade?
Final class...
If you magnetizes him now
with a battery...
You cause an electric short.
Yes...
Approach, this is Pan National 273
on approach..
How do you hear?
Approach, do you copy
radio's working its not us..
There is no reason to panic.
Go back to your vehicle.
Go back to your car and stay calm.
Everyone go back to your vehicles.
- Agent.
- Spider-Man.
My father was superintendent George Stacy. Yeh
I know who he was. What can we do for you?
Jumper cables, Jumper cables!! Yes
and copper wire.
Am I talking louder than I
usually talk right now - Yes.
You'll get over.
Try. Move.
Okay It works now. And why you
were number two in school.
- I have to go.
- I'm with you.
You're not coming with me. Yes I know
Sorry... It's too dangerous.
I'm with you
and I know how to reset the system.
I'm coming with you.
You know that you need me.
Then go with it.
Close the bonnet.
Sorry, I love you.
Don't hate me.
We still have no spare units.
Take the technicians.
I need a respirator right now I'll
get the battery operated. Hang on!
Can you see me now, Spider-Man?
It is time to meet our
destinies.
We're experiencing electrical disturbance.
Instruments are going haywire radar is down.
We're flying blind out here
do you copy?
Tower We are standing by
What is happening?
Aircraft, on intersecting path.
Time to impact?
Four and a half minutes.
Clock it... Clock it right now Now.
You're late, Spider-Man.
I've designed this power grid.
Now I'm gonna take back what,
what is rightfully mine.
I want control of everything.
And I will be like a God for his.
A God named "Sparkles?"
Not this time. Is that all you've got?
Come on!!!
Come on.
You ready to give up?
Ohh Thank-You, Gwen Stacy.
Shake it off. It's your bones,
muscles and your organs.
Ohh boy
I hate this song.
Spider-Man, bet you never
saw this coming..
Are you serious?
You wire me to a car,
What are you a caveman.
You tie me up, to go off to war
I outa help you.
I know the grid down.
I can reset the system.
You can't be here right now I'm not messing
around. You can't be here right now.
Nobody makes my decisions.
For me, alright... Nobody..
This is my choice okay...
My choice, mine...
Now how do we stop him?
He is like a battery. So What happens
when you overcharge a battery?
It explodes... Right..So We
use his power against him. Perfect.
Okay I need to re-connect power,
I need you to reset the system.
Okay when I say you turn that power on, you turn
it on. No matter what. Peter, no matter what.
Go!! Go!
60 seconds to impact.
Now, Gwen. Do it nowwww.
OVERLOAD
Unit 687.
This is La guardia tower.turn
immediately, heading 280.
Incoming traffic, I repeat 280.
Get back to work, lets
land these planes.
I'll be back.
We're back in the air. Back
to work everybody lets go.
Hello are you still making a fight.
Gwen, stay there.
Peter.
When you said: Spider-Man, said no
you meant "you" said "no"
Harry, what did you just do?
What you made me do.
You were my friend and you betrayed me.
No, I was trying to protect you.
Look at me. Harry. Its gonna be Okay.
Its gonna be alright..
You give people no hope.
You take it away.
No, Harry. And now I'm going
to take away yours...
Gwen... Run...
Harry, put her down.
Harry, Stop this right now.
Harry put her down, this is
not you, Harry Put her down.
Harry's dead.
Harry This is between you and me.
You wanna fight?
Fight me, let her go.
You're okay?
I got you. I put you down now.
Breathe..
You'll be fine.
Stay with me. Stay with me
Gwen
Gwen... please.
Please.
I can't do without you.
Leave us.
Have you made progress?
I've examined some worthy
candidates.
Now that Spider-Man's gone...
this city will never be the same.
Ohh..I'm counting on that.
Speaking of progress,
you're looking better.
It comes and goes.
Tell me more.
How many men did you have in mind?
I want to keep it small.
Everything you need is already at Oscorp.
Access granted.
Welcome, Mr. Fiers.
Who is the first volunteer?
Aleksei Sytsevich.
Apparently serving a
life sentence.
He was eager to join us.
Good.
Start with him.
Russian Aleksei Sytsevich was broken. Out of a
classified penetentiary known simply as 'The Vault'..
By an unknown team of men.
Its yet Another example of
increased criminal activity.
Since the disappearance of Spider-Man
5 months months ago..
The webslingers absence has
left a hole in the heart of our city.
Believe it or not even the New York city Police
Department has joined the chorus of New Yorkers...
In hoping for the return of webslinger...
The entire world seems to be asking
the same question:
Where is Spider-Man.
Its wrong that spider-guy.
Since he's disappeared seems like,
everybody really needs him.
Where you going?
- I'm not sure.
- Peter...
Where are you going?
I don't know.
It's not funny...
I've been trying to clean up
around here, get organised...
Clean some of Bens stuff.
In boxes..
Funny the heavier the box gets,
the lighter I feel.
You throwing his stuff away?
I couldn't. Do that
It's a part of me.
It's just... Finding...
a better place for them.
I'm gonna take one last look...
and put them away where they belong.
Gwen's speech.
It is easy feel hopeful
on a beautiful day like today.
But there will be Dark days ahead of us
to.
And there will be days when you
feel all alone.
Thats when hope is needed
most...
no matter how heavy it gets..
Or how lost you feel, you must promise me..
That you will hope on.
Keep it alive.
We have to be greater
than what we suffer..
I wish for you that you become
hope.
People need that.
And even if we fail, what better way
is there to live..
As we look around here today.
And all of the people who help to
make us who we are..
I know it feels like we're
saying 'goodbye'
But we carry a piece of each other into
everything that we do next..
To remind us, of who we are...
and if we were meant to be..
I had a great 4 years with
you, I'll miss you all very much.
Move out of the way.
I'm here live on Park Avenue and 56th
Street where there is complete chaos...
A man in some sort of weaponised
armoured suit, is wreaking havoc on
I'm Rhino.
I told you I would be back.
Hold your fire.
Everybody hold your fire.
Boy, you have to...
Look, New York.
Spider-Man is back.
That's my son.
Brave boy. Huh.
Does Aleksei Makes scare you, little
boy?
Hey, Spider-Man.
I knew you'd come back. Thanks
for stepping up for me.
You are the bravest kid
I've ever seen.
I'm gonna take care of him, so you
can take care of your mom... Okay...
Alright get out of here your gone.
Do you want to fight with.
You will fight me now?
On Behalf of the fine people of New
York city and real rhinos everywhere...
I ask you to turn your mechanised
palms in the air.
Never. I crush you and
kill you and destroy.
You're gonna have to come down here
so you can kill me? Yes...
I'll be right there..There's
No place like home.
Synced by THIWANKA