- Si. Bueno. - Family is everything.
No?
Now, do you love your son?
Si.
Now do you understand?
You have a $ 10 million insurance policy. I know that.
Georgina!
Obey me, I will loveyou. Come on.
That's how it works, huh?
- Simple. - That's right.
Mwah.
She got a sister?
How's business?
The Japanese are here in a big way.
Cheap labor, factory space.
But they feel a lot safer living over the border in El Paso.
I ferry them back and forth. They think I'm John Wayne.
- Ah. - Come on.
- I live like a king down here. - Yes, you do.
- You been workin'? - Yeah. No.
Nah. Been movin' around, you know.
Colombia, couple of places I can't name. Nothing catches my fancy.
Oh.
You think God will forgive us forwhat we've done?
- No. - You don't?
Me either.
- How long you staying? - I don't know. I just you know.
I wanted to see you, Ray, see how you're doin'.
You know, I came by on impulse.
Well, I could do with some impulse.
What happened?
Family paid the ransom
then they sent the kid home after a couple of days
minus an ear, of course.
Now every mother in Mexico City with a little bit of moneywants bigger and better bodyguards
my own wife included.
I hate to break it to you, but she's right. She's right.
Look, Sammy, all my clients have, uh, kidnap and ransom insurance.
I have a policy. A.I.G. My dad gave it to me.
Yeah, I know. I got it for your dad.
But what are you gonna do in 60 days whenyou can't renew it?
- You can't because you don't have a bodyguard. - I had to let Emilio go.
You gotta please Lisa. I mean, hey, ass like that's hard to find.
Look, a bodyguard's like anything else.
You get whatyou pay for, okay?
You could do this. You get one that's got a decent resume.
We're not looking for goddamn Superman here, right?
Get someone cheap till you renew the policy
and then, uh then fire the prick forwhatever. Incompetence.
All kidding aside, the most important thing is thatyour daughter goes back to school
and thatyourwife gets to save face.
This way, you won't be the only unprotected family in the neighborhood.
That's right. A bodyguard. YourSpanish is good enough.
- You're crazy. - You even look the part.
I n my state, I couldn't guard a corpse.
It's rich guys flashing their cash. It's all forshow.
- Nothing's gonna happen. - Yeah? You think they'd hire a drunk, a has- been?
You have to keep it under control.
What if there was, you know, say, a kidnapping attempt? What do I do then?
You do your best. They're not gonna be payingyou enough to perform miracles.
- I don't know. - It's not exactly a scam, Crease.
- Even at half speed, you're pretty damn good. - Yeah.
Bodyguard's gotta be close to people though.
He gotta talk all the time, and I'm no good at that.
You'll be the silent type. People are gonna appreciate that.
Bodyguard. So who's the guy?
Samuel Ramos. He's a young guy.
He owns one ofthe plants inJuarez.
Yeah?
The Jap car industry is in the toilet.
He's trying to persuade Ford to partnerwith him.
I think he's in trouble. His family lives in Mexico City.
He asked me if l knew anybody he could trust.
- And you thought of me. - Yeah.
Take a job, Crease. Breathe some air.
Then decide if you want to stick around or not.
Besides, I'm glad to see you. I got nobody to talk to down here.
Listen, my wife wants someone presentable and polite.
You'll be the fifth candidate she sees this week.
Your resume's quite impressive.
Sixteen years of military experience, extensive counterterrorism work.
I'm surprised anybody could afford you. What's the catch?
I drink.
How does that affect you?
Well
coordination, reaction time.
If top professionals try to kidnap your daughter, I'll do the best I can
but the service will be on parwith the pay.
What ifamateurs tried?
I'd probably kill 'em. Is that likely?
No.
No one is to know aboutyour drinking. That includes mywife.
Lisa!
My wife, Lisa. And this is John Creasy.
- You're an American. - So are you.
It's all in there.
Would you like a drink?
Yes, uh,Jack and water'd be good.
- Haveyou done much ofthis kindofwork before? - No, ma'am.
But he has a lot of experience in related fields.
- You have a family, Mr. Creasy? - No.
Pita.
- Thankyou. - Yes, Mom?
Honey, this is, uh, Mr. Creasy.
In English, honey.
Um, do you wanna show Mr. Creasy to his room?
- This way, Mr. Creasy. - Okay.
Thankyou.
Just like that?
I think it's nice
that he's an American.
I think it's terrific. You sure?
Thankyou.
I feel better now.
- !Hola, Bruno!- !Buenas tardes!
That's Bruno, the gardener.
And, um, that's Maria, the cook.
- !Hola, Maria! - Hola, Pita.
We fixed the room up two weeks ago. It's nicer than before.
You've got a TV and C.D. player. What kind ofmusic do you like, Mr. Creasy?
I don't know.
- You don't know? - I don't know.
That's Bird.
Emilio forgot to take him when he left.
Emilio was my last bodyguard.
Have you protected a lot of children before, Mr. Creasy?
Creasy. You can call me Creasy. And no, you're the first.
Creasy.
Bye, Creasy.
So long.
Bye, Bird.
Ow.
- School tomorrow, peeps. - Does that mean we can get a dog?
Dad promised me one when I went back to school.
Yeah, we'll see.
If you get a dog, will you give up your bear?
You're getting too old for him.
- How'd you like Mr. Creasy? - Creasy.
He said to call him just Creasy.
- Uh- huh. - That isn't disrespectful, is it?
No, not if he asked you.
Here. There you go.
- He's like a bear too. - Yeah?
A big, sad bear.
- Is he sad? - I think. Or something.
- Good night, honey. - Night.
- Oh, can you get me some floss in the morning? - Floss?
- Yeah, the strawberry kind. - Oh, sure.
Good night, Bear.
Creasy Bear.
What's that one for?
La Virgin de Guadalupe.
Business. For T oyota, for Ford.
If one dies, maybe she can resurrect the other one.
I don't know.
She likes him.
- What are you talking about? - Creasy.
Pita likes him.
Pita loves school.
Pita wouldlove Count Dracula ifhe took herback there, honey.
Okay?
- Hey. Are you okay? - I don't know.
I don't know, Lisa.
I 'm trying.
Come on, Bird.
That's right. That's right. Come on.
All right. Home to Emilio.
You're home free, baby.
- Where are you from, Creasy? - The U.S.
- I know, but which state? - No state in particular.
You can drive and talk at the same time.
No, I can't, Pita, so, please, let me just do myjob.
Are you going to stay?
My last bodyguard left.
Somebody gave him more money than we could.
I guess that makes me a bargain then, huh?
Being black is that a positive or negative for a bodyguard in Mexico?
Time will tell.
There were 24 kidnappings in Mexico City in the last six days.
- Four a day. - Yeah?
- Twenty- four? - Twenty- four. What do you think about that, Creasy?
- I think thatyou know entirely more than you should. - Well, thankyou.
Hola, Miguel.
- See you later. - You have to sign.
- What? - You have to sign in, show them your I.D.
Buenos dias. Come on.
Right there.
- Hola, Manuel. - Hola, Pita.
- Hola, Pita!- Hola!
Pita! It's so good to have you back.
Sister Anna, this is my new bodyguard, Creasy.
Sister Anna, the headmistress.
Senor Creasy.
Hurry. Class is about to begin.
- Go, go. - Bye, Creasy.
- Madre. - You must look after our Pita.
It is not good that she's late today.
I'm very sorry. I, uh I'll have to get used to the rules. It won't happen again.
No offense, but I regret thatyour profession needs to exist.
So do I, Madre. So do I.
Do you ever see the hand of God in what you do?
No, not for a long time.
The Bible says, "Be not overcome of evil, but overcome"
"Overcome evil with good."
I'm the sheep that got lost, Madre.
When you were a kid, Creasy, did you like school?
- I don't remember. - You don't remember?
No, I don't remember. It, uh Nah, I didn't like it.
Why not?
Because it wasn't a school likeyours.
There was no, uh no Sister Anna.
Wereyou unhappy?
Being unhappy, Pita, that's a state of mind. I really don't remember.
What happened to your hand?
- It's a birth defect. - No, it's not.
Look, no more questions, okay?
- It really wasn't a question. - It sounded like a question.
Look, I got a job to do. Hey!
No. Gracias. Gracias. No. No.
Listen to me. I'm being paid to protect you, okay?
No, no, no. I'm being paid to be your bodyguard.
Look at me. I'm not beingpaid to beyourfriend.
I'm beingpaid to protectyou, so no more questions. That's it. Period.
- You hear me? - Yes.
- And no crying. - I 'm not crying.
Well, don't start.
You gotta understand, this is a job.
In order for me to do
In order for Wait a minute.
Yeah, come in.
Mr. Creasy.
I just wanted to make sure you have everything you need.
I'm fine, thanks.
Is the food all right? 'Cause, uh, Maria told meyou didn't eat.
Uh yeah, the food is great.
I just wasn't that hungry tonight.
Soyou, uh, read the Bible?
Yeah, sometimes.
- Does it help? - Yeah, sometimes.
- Can I talk to you for a minute? - Sure.
How are you doing with Pita?
Fine. Fine.
Soon as she figures out that I'm not her new toy, we'll be fine.
- Yeah, she told me about that. - Okay.
- You don't have children, do you? - I told you I didn't.
Well, they can be tenacious when theywant something.
- And Pita just wants to be friends. - Okay.
Butyou're paying me to protect her, right? Not to be her friend.
Right?
So, uh
Iook, maybe this isn't gonna work out.
Maybe your husband should find somebodywho's a little more sociable.
No, you're right.
You're being paid to protect her
and I'm confident thatyou'll do that.
I'll be coming with you tomorrow. I hope that's all right.
You think God will forgive us for what we've done?
I'm tired ofkillin ', Ray.
You think God will forgive us for what we 've done?
In my state, I couldn 't I couldn 't guard a corpse.
Talk all the time.
You know, I'm no good at that.
You know how they say
a bullet always tells the truth?
Yeah.
- Hey. - Crease.
What's wrong?
Hey, listen, you- you ever have a
a nine- millimeter round that didn't go off?
Well, yeah. Failure to fire.
I know. Failure to fire and- and- and, uh
You know, I pulled the trigger and and and
click, nothing.
You're talking about a bad primer.
Yeah, I Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
But I You know, right, dimple. Dimple on the primer.
That may be.
Well, like we used to say
a bullet always tells the truth.
Crease?
- You all right? - Yeah.
What wereyou shooting at?
Yeah, I'm sorry, Ray. I'm sorry I wokeyou.
No, i- it's okay. Nothin'. I was watchin' TV.
Okay.
All right.
Pita, you have a pencil?
Thankyou.
It's hard to get used to the traffic down here.
Yeah. I'm very sorry.
- See you, baby. - All right. See you later.
- Hey. Don't forget your towel. - Oh, thankyou.
Bye. Buenas dias.
- You're a strong swimmer. - I neverwin.
Thanks.
- So what do I do? - What do you think you should do?
You're the fastest one in the water, the slowest one off the blocks.
- What do you think that means? What do you gotta do? - Get faster off the blocks.
Get faster offthe blocks.
- Our big swim meet is in three weeks. - Yeah?
- I was gonna enter the 1 50 freestyle. - Yeah,you'll be fine.
You'll be okay.
- I'll still be slow. - You're not slow.
I never finish better than third.
All right. Maybe you are slow then.
Vamos, Bird!
Vamos!
How do you think he got out?
- I let him go. - It's better to be free, right?
It's better for him.
Actually, he was driving me crazy.
Good night.
- See you in a couple of days. I love you. - All right. Love you.
Be good. Come on, Lise.
- All right, sweetheart. We'll call you from Detroit. - Okay.
- I love you. - Love you.
- Okay. Bye, honey. - Senora.
- Bye. - Oh. Gracias.
- Okay. Bye, honey! - Bye.
- I love you. - Love you.
I hate leaving her.
Concentratin'?
Eyes are closed?
What happened?
- I flinched. - You flinched? The gunshot holds no fear.
- Say it. - The gunshot holds no fear.
The gunshot holds no fear! Say it.
- The gunshot holds no fear. - Louder!
- The gunshot holds no fear! - Louder!
- The gunshot holds no fear! - That's good.
You welcome the sound.
In fact, it's the sound that sets you free.
You are a prisoner on this block until that sound sets you free.
- Areyou ready? Areyou ready? - Yes. Yes.
- Areyou set? - Uh- huh.
- Creasy? - Hmm?
- What's a concubine? - Why do you ask?
It's in my history book.
- Oh. - It's like a wife, right?
Yeah. Yes, uh Can I see that?
- Kind of a wife. - Right there.
But the emperor ofChina had 1,000 ofthem.
Um
Okay, like nowadays in- in the West, they have one husband for one wife.
But in the olden time cultures, they had, uh
you know, different uh, different rules.
- Why, you feel sorry for the husband? - Yeah.
Can you imagine my mom multiplied by a thousand?
Creasy. You're smiling.
- What? - You were smiling.
- No, I'm not. No, I was not. - You were.
- You're not now, but you were. - You were smiling. I wasn't.
- You were. - When?
- Like five seconds ago. - I'm not smiling.
A second ago you were. - You said five seconds ago. Now that's six.
Six seconds ago I wasn't smiling. - Ten seconds ago.
Ten seconds ago I was smiling. Okay, in the next 10 seconds, let's see who smiles first.
- You smiled already. See? You did. - Mmm!
- No, that wasn't a That was a smirk. - Yeah, you
That's not a smile. A smirk is different.
They both start with "S," but they're not the same Do your homework.
You were.
Bang!
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop. Come back, come back.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop, stop. Come here.
Hurry up, hurry up. Set.
Bang!
You don't flinch when you hear the gunshot, understand?
You listen for the sound. You don't anticipate.
Concentrate on the sound. You understand me?
They're gaining on you! Go, go, go, go, go, go! Stop! Stop!
Come on, get out. Let's go again. Let's go again.
- Gracias. Come here, girl! - Daddy!
Oh, I missed you so much.
- I missed you too. - How are you doing? I got a surprise for you.
- You do? - Ready?
- Huh? - You got me a dog! You finally got me a dog!
- What do you think? - Oh, my gosh.
- Just what I wanted. What's his name? - Sam, like Dad.
Great! Come on, Sam! Come on, Sam!
- State. - Mm- hmm.
Bhutan. It's a Himalayan kingdom.
Theywere havingsomeproblems with theirroyal familynot that long ago.
- Mm- hmm. - Okay.
Any more questions?
- Do you have a girlfriend? - What?
- Do you have a girlfriend? - No.
What kind ofquestion is that? You're supposed to be studying history.
- That is history. Creasy history. - No, that's ancient history.
- No more questions. - Who was your very first girlfriend?
Nonya. Nonya business. That's who.
- Okay? - Hi.
Tomorrow afteryou drop off Pita, could you take me to get my hair done?
- Yes, ma'am. - All right.
Well, um, I'll leave you two to your history.
- Good night. - Goodnight, honey.
- Okay, now ask me. - Ask you what?
bang!
Go, Pita, go. Go! Go, go, go, go!
Go, go, go, go, go.
- Bravo! Muy bien!
- 10.99. - Yes!
Whoo!
- I'm tough, Creasy. - No such thing as tough.
There's trained, then there's untrained.
- Now, which are you? - Trained.
Trained. Okay. Let's go again.
- Here. - Stand here near the finish line.
Okay. Hey.
I'm a prisoner in the block until the gunshot sets me free.
- Don't smile, don't fool around if you want to win. - Okay.
- You want to win? Trained or untrained? - Trained.
Go.
- SenorCreasy, nice to See you. - Oh, good to see you, Madre.
Pita's parents are away on business in Juarez. I was
Todayyou are her father.
Pita Ramos!
I won! Creasy! I won!
- Okay. - I won!
- Once upon a time, when we were young - When I was young.
Well, when we were young and he was younger
all heads turned ourway.
We made a deal to take the world together.
Yeah, then one day I got a call, and he said
I'm in love! I'm in love!
And I'm moving to Mexico. "
AndI said
What happened to the plan? What happened to it?
I said, "The plan's right here."
Yeah. Yeah. And what'd I do?
I hung up, then I met Alicia
and then I went, "Oh, now I gotyou! I gotyou."
I got it. Can I kiss her? Is that
Absolutely! Hey, what are you doing?
- You got me. - Okay, I think now is a good a time as any.
I bought it with my own money.
Open it.
It's St.Jude, patron saint oflost causes.
Wow.
Well deserved.
Thankyou, Pita. It's beautiful.
You're welcome.
- Dad. - Yes, sweetie?
Can I talk to you?
Yes.
I don't want to play piano. I want to swim.
It's not open for discussion, honey, okay?
Mr. Lozzi's a very, very famous teacher, and ifhe accepts you as his student
you're gonna play the piano.
Whatever.
Baby.
- I love you. - I love you.
- I just want what's best for you, you know that? - Okay.
Okay, honey.
if you broke all my fingers, then taped them back together
I wouldn't be able to play piano, but I could still swim.
Sam, get back.
Don't be a crybaby. You're tougher than that.
Sit, sit, sit, sit, sit, sit.
- Remember the dayyou wanted the pencil? - Yeah.
I know why.
- Yeah? - You wanted the license number off ofthat car.
I wrote it down in my notebook.
I got it all but the last number.
I'll get it from you lat Can you belch?
Burp. Can you burp?
That's good. That's very good.
- I just had a Coke. - All right. Listen.
Now, this teacher, this famous teacher
He teaches a lot of rich kids and plays for the symphonies, right?
- Right. - You belch every few minutes while you're practicing.
- Okay. - You apologize to him, butyou keep belching.
- You'll offend every sensibility he has. - Okay.
Very good. You'll be back in the pool in 24 hours, I guarantee you.
Right, Sam?
- Hola. - Lupita Ramos?
Foryou, Creasy.
Thankyou.
- How does this look? - Good.
- Good. - Hmm?
- Hola, Pita. - Hola.
- Bye. - Bye.
Gracias.
Pita.
Pita!
Run!
Creasy!
Creasy. Creasy.
I can't
Come on!
John W. Creasyis underarrest forthe murder oftwo police officers
oftheJudicial Police.
Creasy!
Also involved in the kidnapping of
Excuse me.
Everybody relax, okay? Relax, Sammy.
I know she's your little girl.
When I tell you everything's gonna be all right, everything's gonna be all right.
SenorRamos.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
Victor Fuentes, Anti- Kidnapping Division, PoliciaJudicial.
Excuse me. I'm Jordan Kalfus. I'm the family attorney.
Speak slower, please. My Russian is better than my English.
Well, I'm conducting the negotiations, and we neither need norwant police assistance.
We're gonna We're gonna handle this thing ourselves.
SenorRamos, two police officers were killed
duringyour daughter's abduction.
I have a written order from Ministerio Publico
authorizing our participation ex- officio.
if you want to speak to Attorney General Diaz, it's on me.
No. Okay.
The kidnapperwill tell you to deliver the money alone.
Porfavor, don't do that
oryou will find yourself in a real Mexican hell.
No mariachi. No tequila and no Pita.
Crease.
When I heardit was this hospital, I was so pleased.
There is a pastry shop nearby.
Delgado's. They have the best pastries in Mexico.
Oh, Miguel Manzano
director of the A.F.I .
and a former director oflnterpol in Rome.
- And you are? - Friend ofhis. Rayburn.
Rayburn?
Hola.
Do you love your daughter, Senor Ramos?
Yes. Yes.
- Do you want to see her again? - Yes, I do.
Senor, if your daughter's life
is as important to you as it is to me
you will do as I say.
- Yes? - Okay. Yes.
- Crease. Can you hear me? - Hmm.
You got four of them. All dead.
- Pita. - It's, uh
It's been two days. They're negotiating a ransom.
These things take time, Mr. Creasy.
Crease.
Don't fuck with me, all right?
Do you have the 10 million? Do you have the money?
- Yes, we have the money. - Now if you do as I say
the girl will be returned exactly as she was taken.
But if you deviate from the process in any way
I swear, you will never see her again.
I understand. Listen, I- I too worship la Virgin de Guadalupe.
I ask you if you understand.
Hello, sir. This is, uh, Mr. Ramos's attorney.
He's going through a very difficult time here, but he understands.
Do you understand? Repeat the drop instructions.
Okay, the money, 10 million, U.S., will be divided into
two 1 5- gallon black canvas bags, each containing five million
which will be checked at the bank by the K. R. agent
then driven to the house in an armored car where it will be transferred to the delivery car.
You got a flat tire here.
This is for you.
Hel lo. Yeah.
Listen, I need a driver to drive Samuel.
No. Why?
He's got a bad ticker. He's got a heart condition.
Look, he's a nervous kid who doesn't respond well to stress.
All right. But the carwill not be powerful.
Remove the trunk lid. Use the maid's Valiant Acapulco.
You willarrive at La Diana Fountain at 1:00 a.m.
You will drive around the circle two times.
Samuel will remove his shirt and hold it out the window
to I. D. the car.
There is a payphone on the southeast corner.
The phone will ring. He will answer and wait for instructions.
There is a map on the top ofthe phone. Follow it.
Perfecto.
- What are you doi ng? He said no phones! - Relax. Relax.
- I 'm just trying to protect your daughter.- J ust get me there, please.
- What's going on? - Hospitals can be very dangerous places.
Especiallywhen you have killed two corrupt cops.
Leave the money in the trunk ofthe white car.
Then return to your car.
Do not look back.
Remember, I'm a professional.
if you keep your word, I will keep mine.
- Hel lo. - Mr. Ramos.
You betrayed me. You killed my nephew.
You took my money.
Senor Ramos
All right. Get out of here, all ofyou. Get the fuck out of my house!
Okay, this is Lisa.
I'm Pita's mother.
And I'm very sorry forwhatever happened to your nephew, but I beg you
This conversation is not being recorded.
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry. I wish we had talked sooner, senora.
I'm really sorry.
Now it is too late.
Fuck off!. Get the fuck out of my fucking house now!
Get out! Get out!
Hey.
Hey, Ray.
- Where am I? - Well, it looks like a dog hospital.
Manzano was afraid the cops were gonna kill you.
How ya doin', Doc?
What's the matter?
She's de dead, Crease.
It's a mess.
Somebody hijacked the drop, and, uh
the kidnapper's nephew was killed
so he k he killed Pita.
No.
Did you recognize any of these men?
No. Does that make me a suspect?
No.
It would be convenient, but no.
Um, maybeyou should show me some pictures of some Mexican cops.
- Maybe we'll get somewhere then. - Those were all policemen.
Bad judicial cops.
Protected by a brotherhood.
Brotherhood?
A brotherhood called La Hermandad.
You all set?
- Hmm? - Right arm. Here.
- Okay? - Yeah. I'm all right.
Let's go.
- Somebody's on us. - Yeah. Lois Lane.
- Who? - Mariana something, works for Reforma.
Newspaperjournalist.
Maybe she thinks you're a scoop.
I 'll get you up to the border.
A friend of mine will take you to San Diego, drop you right at the naval hospital.
- I'm not going, Ray. - What are you gonna do?
Let's take a ride by the crime scene. She can follow us.
Buenos dias.
Mr. Creasy?
A lot of people are looking for you.
I'm Mariana Garcia Guerrero.
Reporter for Reforma.
- Nice to meet you. - I found this across the street.
Open it.
It's Santa Muerte. Death worship.
- They've put a curse onyou. - Ha. They're a little late.
- What are you going to do? - I'm gonna get in my truck and leave.
I can help you.
There's a brotherhood called La Hermandad.
It protects high- ranking government officials, corrupt police
and organized crime at a level that is too difficult for me to reach.
Okay.
And I think thatyou and Lupita Ramos are victims ofthis organization.
I want to expose them. Talk to me, give meyour story, then I can helpyou.
Please.
Help me do what?
You're gonna help me do what?
You're a stranger here, no?
That's right.
You're going to need friends that know theirway around.
Okay.
Okay, friend that's gonna help me.
A pleasure to meetyou. Tell your driver to keep his distance next time.
All right, friend?
Si.
You'll be stateside by supper time.
I'm gonna need some help first though, Ray.
if you don'tstop bleeding, you won't last a daythe shapeyou're in.
- Is that a yes or is that a no? - Yeah.
But I'm done killing. I told you that.
- Okay. - Anything else is yours.
- You're talking about war. - Exactlywhat I'm talking about.
Can you help me?
- Yeah. - Good.
Creasy.
- What are you doing here? - Oh.
Came to get my stuff.
Couldn't find my Bible. I thought it might be in here.
- I borrowed it. - Okay.
It's crazy, huh?
One weekwe're figuring out which nightclub to go to
and the next thing I'm reading the Bible.
It's a good thing. You hold on to it.
I keep thinking, if onlywe hadn't
It's like, um
mywhole life, all I've everthought about
was what I could get for myself.
Even with my own baby.
She needed me so much, and sometimes
I felt like I had nothing to give her.
Just, um, I don't know what to do.
- What are you gonna do? - What I do best.
I'm gonna kill 'em.
Anyone who was involved. Anybodywho profited from it.
Anybodywho opens their eyes at me.
You kill 'em all.
Yla Browning.
Hola.
Yeah, it's me.
- Mr. Creasy. - Okay. I need the license
Well, no, excuse me.
I need the name and address of someone whose license number is C- 5- T- K- 8.
That's C- 5- T- K- 8.
I got everything but the last digit, so I need 10 possible matches.
And when do I find out which ofthe 10 it is?
- Eventually. - Well, where do I reach you?
I'll call you.
Jordan, Angola, Lebanon. Yes, I know all ofthat.
He's an assassin. And you want to help him identify the owner ofa car for him?
- Mariana. - Si.
Gracias.
Ciao.
Now,Jorge Gonzales.
Okay.
What are you gonna do? What are you gonna do?
What I do best.
Anyone who was involved. Anybody who profited from it.
Anybody who opens their eyes at me, I'm gonna kill 'em.
Oh, God!
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey.
Okay? Ahora.
Huh? You know who I am?
Correct?
Correct.
Okay.
Hey, hey, hey.
No se nada.
Hmm?
La Voice.
Okay.
Okay. Well.
Wait, wait, wait.
Give me one cigarette, please.
- Si. - Okay.
Okay, my friend. It's off to the next life for you.
I guarantee you, you won't be lonely.
Revenge is a meal best served cold.
- La nina. - No.
No? Vamos.
No?
Hmm?
I heard you speaking Spanish. You're American, right?
- And so are you. - Yeah.
- Get out of here. Where are you from? - I'm from NewJersey.
- You from New Jersey? - Yeah.
I'm from New Jersey. All right, listen to me.
All right. Everything is done up by cellphone.
You just wait around for calls, and we don't even have a fucking number.
Who pays you?
We got an A.T.M. card. We take out 200 fucking measly dollars every two weeks.
- Two hundred dollars? - Yeah.
- What's the PI N number? - The what?
The PI N number. Code number.
- 4747 - 4747
- Yeah. - Good. You wouldn't lie to me, right?
- I'm not lying, man. - Did you kill her? You didn't kill her, did you?
No.
Don't lie to me. Don't lie to me! Did you kill her?
Oh, man, you're making me fucking nervous.
- Did you kill her? - Noway. The fucking boss did, or his brother.
- We never see his face. - You're not lying to me, are you?
No. Goddamn it! I'm telling you the truth!
Tell me, who? You never see whose face?
Well, we were in the otherroom
andhe wasyellin'at the girl 'cause his nephew got killed
and the money got stolen.
Wait, wait. Wh- What? Somebody stole what money?
- The ransom money at the drop. - Who? Who stole it?
- He said some fuckin' crooked cop took it. - Who?
- Fuentes. - Fuentes?
Yeah, that's right.
All right? Huh?Jerseyboy?
Yeah. Now.
- This Fuentes guy? - Yeah.
He's a lieutenant for the Anti- Kidnapping Division.
Fuentes is. What'd you do?
- Oh, man. - Tell me about the girl. What'd you do?
- Huh? What'dyou do? - I just do what they told me.
- You do what they tell you to do? - Yeah.
Did you say good- bye to her? Answer my question.
- Did you say good- bye to her? - No!
- You didn't? Here's your chance. Say good- bye. - Oh, shit!
Say good- bye to her. Say good- bye to her.
Fucking let me go!
Rico?
Okay. Okay.
- No? - No.
Si.
- Si, Guerrero. - Listen, it's me.
Yeah, it's me. You know anything about a young girl being kidnapped recently?
- She's about 1 2 years old? - Yes, that's last night.
- Do you know something? - What's her name?
Uh, Camilla. Camilla Valencias.
?Camilla? ?Se llama Camilla?
- Si. - Okay. I got her.
Where are you?
- Creasy, what happened? - It's okay.
Sit down. Relax.
She's okay. She's okay. You got banking connections?
Yes, I have connections.
Okay. The PI N number's 47 47.
I wanna find out who's putting money in that account.
What do you know about a cop named Fuentes?
He's with the Anti- Kidnapping Division.
He's the one who drove Samuel Ramos to the drop.
- Fuentes? - Si.
- Who is she? - You can ask herlater. She'll tellyou anything.
What do you know about him? About Fuentes?
Three years ago they caught him with $50,000 and a dead body in the trunk ofhis car.
- Huh. - Never charged.
Arresting officer couldn't testify 'cause he was dead.
- Is he La Hermandad? - Mm- hmm.
- You know where he lives? - He lives in a judicial compound.
He travels by motorcade.
Creasy, he's betterprotected than the president ofMexico.
He's gonna need it. You gonna take care of her?
- Yes. Well, how can I find you? - I'll find you.
This is my jurisdiction.
I want this man as much as Creasy does.
He'll deliver more justice in a weekend than 10 years ofyour courts and tribunals.
- Just stay out ofhis way. - I plan to.
I will even help him, if l can.
But, uh, I would like to understand him.
Give me that.
Pita Ramos
that's a numberto you.
You know, one more dead, but a number.
What was she to Creasy then?
She showed him it was all right to live again.
And the kidnappers took that away, huh?
And they're gonna wish they never touched a hair on her head.
A man can be an artist
in anything food, whatever.
It depends on how good he is at it.
Creasy's art is death.
He's about to paint his masterpiece.
I don't have anything else to say.
Forgiveness is between them and God.
It's my job to arrange the meeting.
Don't move. Put your hands down. Put 'em down.
SenorJohn W. Creasy
is underarrest for the murder oftwo officers oftheJudicial Police.
He's suspected ofpossible involvement
ofpossible involvement in the kidnapping ofLupita Ramos.
Can you hear me? H uh?
Know where we are?
We're under the bridge where the deal went bad.
The ransom got stolen. You wanna tell me what happened?
- Haveyou heard of La Hermandad? - Yes, I have.
- Do you know what it is? - Yes.
- You're the president? - Yes.
The president? Wow.
Look at me.
Oh, you can't. I'm sorry.
How's that?
Let me show you what I got here.
See this? This is a charger. It's used by convicts to hide money and drugs.
They stick it in their body. They tuck it up their rectum.
You familiarwith that? This Look at me.
Pencil detonator.
Timer, used as a receiver- transmitter.
C- 4. Highly explosive.
You put 'em all together, you got a bomb.
Not very sophisticated, but very powerful.
That's whatyou have in your ass right now.
Don't move. Don't move. Don't move.
Cheap watch. Pagerwatch.
Used to send a page to the receiver that's upyour behind right now.
So, I'm gonna send you a page
which you will receive
in five minutes.
Now.
You got less than five minutes to tell me what went down between your men and the kidnapper.
I have nothing to do with the kidnapper.
- Four minutes and 30 seconds. - Nothing. I don't know him.
You don't know? Fourminutes and 25 seconds.
Four minutes and 20 seconds. Are you sure?
Okay.
I got all the time in the world. You don't, but I do.
- Hey, relax, relax, buddy. - I'm relaxed.
You got three minutes, 59 seconds.
I saw the opportunity, and I got lucky.
And?
And I had my men ready as we got instructions where to go.
You had your men ready to steal the drop.
You had your men readyto kill one of the kidnappers,yeah?
You've done this manytimes.
- One of the nephews of the head kidnapper - Bingo. Bingo. Bingo.
- Bingo, yeah. You've done this many times, huh? - Many times, yeah.
- Yeah. Killed many victims too, haven't you? - Come on, sir.
- We just make out as best we can. - "As best we could"?
2:47
Two minutes, 47 seconds.
Wait- Wait a minute. Come on.
- I have a little gift for you. - Forme?
- Yeah. Come on. Come on. - What do you got?
There was no $10 million. There was one halfin the bags.
The ransom was $10 million? They put it in two bags.
- Five million in each bag, right? - Two bags, true.
But one has halfpaper
the other onlypaper.
Maybe your men stole it.
Whoever did it took it before the exchange.
Okay. At the Ramos house
before the exchange, who put the bags in the car?
- Guess what. - What?
Ramos lawyer,Jordan Kalfus.
- Jordan Kalfus? - Yeah.
Pedro.
Sir? Please.
I- I'm sorry. I'm really sorry for the girl.
It was just business. You know, I'm a professional.
That's what everybody keeps saying. "I'm just a professional."
Everybody keeps saying that to me. "I'm just a professional. I'm just a professional."
I'm getting sick and tired ofhearing that. You understand me?
What are you going to do now?
What am I gonna do? I'm gonna leave. I gotta go.
- Yeah. I got - Come on. Come on. What about me, huh?
- What about you? You got 40 seconds. - Come on.
- Thirty- five. - A last wish, please. Please.
Last wish? I wish you had more time.
Hey! Hey, hey!
Hola.
- Mariana, it's me. - Creasy, where are you?
Listen, I got something that looks like banking codes from BankCoast in the Cayman Islands.
- I need it translated as fast as you can. - Whose account is it?
Jordan Kalfus, andit looks like U.S. deposits and withdrawals.
Give me the same thing on Samuel Ramos.
Samuel Ramos. That's it?
- That's it. - Okay.
Gracias.
- Creasy. - Samuel.
Honey?
What's going on?
That's what I wanna know. What is going on?
Huh, Sam?
I'm gonna ask your wife a couple of questions, okay?
You move
you make one sound
I'll snatch the life right outta you, you understand?
What happened, Lisa, hmm?
Were you in on this?
- Orwas it justyour husband, huh? - Am I in on what?
You know what I'm talking about Pita's kidnapping, her death. Wereyou a part ofit?
- Pita got killed because the ransom got stolen. - Shut up!
Yeah, the moneywas stolen. You're right. He's right.
The moneywas stolen byVictor Fuentes. How much was stolen though, huh?
- $2.5 million, right? - What are you talking about?
He knows what I'm talking about. $2.5 million. That's whatVictor got, isn't it?
- What are you talking about? - 2.5 million.
2.5 million to yourlawyer Jordan Kalfus
that he put in an account in the Cayman Islands, but he won't get a chance to spend it.
What happened to the other five, Sam?
Huh? That's 2.5, 2.5. What is five from 10?
That's five. What happened to the other five, Sam? Tell yourwife.
It's your chance to talk. What happened to the otherfive?
- You got a wife, Creasy? - No, I don't have a wife.
Then you'll never know how hard it could be to tell your wife the truth.
No, you have a wife! You tell me what happened!
It was in this room that my father prayed.
- I don't give a fuck about your fucking father! - My father prayed.
He prayed that his gambling debts and his infidelities would be forgiven right in this room.
- Sam uel! I love you! - What, Lisa?
- Tell me the truth. - I didn't i nherit a ki ngdom! That's the truth!
You wanna know the truth? I inherited his debt and his mess.
- I inherited his lawyerJordan - You tell me what happened to my baby!
Say it! Say it! Say it!
Say it! Say it! Be a fucking man!
Jordan told me she'd sit in a room
and watch cartoons all day
and she'd eat ice cream and we'd have her back in two days.
He lied to me!
That's why he's fucking dead! I did it!
I did it, Lisa!
I agreed to the kidnapping.
I did it for us for the three of us.
I'm so sorry, Lisa.
You kill him.
You kill him or I will.
Huh. You know, they say a, um
a bullet always tells the truth.
It never lies.
It didn't work for me, Samuel, but maybe
maybe it'll work for you.
I'll prayfor you.
Gracias.
- Hola? - Hola.
- Mr. Creasy? - Yeah, it's me.
- I traced the PIN for you and I have an address. - Yeah?
The cardholder is Reina Rosas Sanchez, the wife of"The Voice.
She lives in Los Arcos, apartment 26D, Via Appia.
- Good. - And another thing.
Pick up today's paper andyou'll have a picture of"The Voice.
Good. Thank you.
Shh, shh, shh.
Jose? Que te pasa?
Si.
Okay.
Hmm?
Si.
- Si? - Si.
Aurelio Rosas Sanchez. Okay.
Okay.
Si.
Huh?
Hola, Daniel.
Senor Creasy.
Yeah. Yeah, I got your family here.
Yourbrother doesn't look too good.
Yeah, Reina, she's what, about eight months?
Huh? You wanna negotiate?
The most important thing in life is family.
Do you agree?
I agree.
And there you are. You have my family.
Well, most of my family.
My wife and I are separated. You knowhow that is.
Now, tell me seriously, h- how much do you want?
Ah.
Your brotherwants to speak to you. Yeah, hold on.
I'm gonna take your family apart piece by piece. You understand me?
Piece by piece. Shut up!
I don't want your money!
Do you understand me? You understand me? I want you.
I'm listening.
I'm listening, Daniel. I'm listening.
All right, I will give you a life for a life.
Whose life? What are you talking about?
Whose life, Daniel? I want you.
And in exchange, I will get my life back.
- What life? Whose life? - The girl's. Pita's.
- Pita's dead. - Creasy!
I'm a businessman. A girl dead is worth nothing. She's alive.
All right.
I want proof of life. You hear me?
I want proof of life. I want I want
I want the name of her bear. What does she call her bear?
You tell herto tellyou
to tell me what she calls her bear.
- Yeah? - Creasy.
She calls the bear Creasy Bear.
Okay.
O- Okay.
I give you your brother, you give me the girl.
- All right. - Where?
Hello?
Lisa, listen to me. Don't hang up.
I think Pita's alive.
I can't take this anymore.
Take the road to Puebla.
Get offjunction 34, south side.
I'll meetyou there in two hours.
So where is she?
She's right over there. You see those two cars out there?
Pita's kidnapper, Daniel
this is his brother.
Here.
I'm goin' up on the bridge to get Pita.
Ifanythinggoes wrong, youput it to his head.
You pull the trigger, all right?
You understand?
You don't
Iet him loose until she's with you.
You got it?
And you don't wait for me, okay?
Yeah.
- You'll be all right. You okay? - Yeah.
Creasy!
- You all right? - Yeah.
They didn't hurt you?
Hi.
Your mother's waitin' for you. She's right down there at the end ofthe bridge.
- Okay? You go home. - Okay.
- All right. - Where are you goin'?
I'm goin' home too.
I'm goin' to Blue Bayou.
Oh, Hey.
I got something for you.
I got the last number too.
I loveyou, Creasy.
And you love me, don'tyou?
Yes, I do.
With all my heart. Pita, go.
- Go. Run. - Bye.
Vamos!
- Pita! Baby, come here. It's okay. - Mom!
- Mom! - Come on! Okay, I'll let you go now.
Mom!