You really will
have to rethink
your lifestyle, you know?
What lifestyle are you
talking about, Mum?
Wine only on Fridays.
And try to think about
dark green vegetables.
So really,
that's the same as saying
we'll never see
each other again.
Well, it is.
It just is.
How can I do
anything if I don't know
what you want?
She was
so upset about it,
and I said to her, "Look,"
I said, "you've got boobs.
They're there. Look."
Staying in is pathetic
when she could be out
having a good time...
I've gotta
go back in. No.
I'm sorry.
I love you.
Racial hate.
That's bullying.
Just tell the teacher.
Yes, being too friendly,
it's the same as bullying.
Yes, it is,
so just tell the teacher.
What do you want?
I'm trying to get
something for tea.
Andy? Andy!
Is he one of yours?
Oi, Mate!
Mate, you can't park here!
You've gotta get back.
Don't knock it
till you've tried it.
This is magic
in a small plastic cup.
I've got
a fucking great big truck
parked right outside...
We're told
by Scotland Yard that
this is a major incident.
The emergency is
a major incident.
Still only being said
that there are several
people injured...
As we
go to air, Central London
is in chaos tonight...
40 minutes
into it, there was
a lot of confusion...
They do know now
that terrorism should be
the number one option...
Our priorities
have changed.
But it's
important for all of them
to be together on this...
Armed police!
Stay where you are!
Get your hands in the air!
Get on your knees!
Hands behind your back!
All we know so far is
that police have
arrested a man
after a dawn raid.
This man, Farroukh Erdogan,
of Turkish origin,
is rumored to be
the ringleader
of the group responsible
for the Borough bombing.
Mr. Erdogan's wife and child
were also taken into custody.
Police forensic teams are
examining a lock-up nearby.
...determination
of investigators
to track down
those responsible.
So,
what does the government
have to say about it?
They will not change
our way of life.
Defense
Barrister Simon Fellowes
refused to comment
on the Erdogan case
on his way into
the preliminary hearing.
This is going to be
a secret trial, isn't it?
In cases of terrorism,
there are circumstances
where to reveal
evidence in open court
would be highly
damaging to present
and future operations.
But crucial
prosecution evidence
will be concealed
from the defense.
If that was happening
in any other country,
you'd say it was
a rigged trial.
The accused will be
fully represented.
But not by
his own barrister.
In the open hearing,
in front of the jury,
he will be represented
by his own barrister.
In the closed hearing,
his interests will be
represented by
a special advocate.
But the fact is,
we're told this is
the trial of the century,
and yet we are not
being allowed to see
the full picture.
So questions
have to be asked.
The judicial process
in this country is
and will remain
fair and transparent.
Attorney General,
thank you.
Martin Rose.
And so today,
we mourn Simon.
And we ask,
as he took his own life,
was he alone?
For as any of us may find,
it's in this
solitary confinement
of the soul, as it were,
that we succumb to despair.
And in Simon,
a successful lawyer,
a popular man,
we see that none
of us is immune,
and that each of us
needs God.
Now let us pray.
Martin, are you going
to the house for drinks?
No, I have to
get back to London
and see my son.
Of course.
Terrible... Simon.
Yes.
I hear you're
stepping into his shoes
on the Borough bomb case.
Quite a challenge.
You know how it is.
But you're all right,
are you?
Sorry?
I mean, you're well?
Oh, I see. In my mind.
It's a good question.
What with the nasty divorce
and bitter custody battle
and all that.
Personal matter, I appreciate,
really none of my business.
Am I emotionally unstable?
I wouldn't
phrase it like that.
You ought to.
The very last thing
you want to see
is another neurotic
defense barrister
selfishly topping himself
before the curtain goes up.
How embarrassing
would that be?
Well?
You may rely on me.
Yeah, I needed
a cigarette.
Patches don't work for me.
My skin's too thick.
Comes from working
with bastards like you.
Okay, Devlin, our friend
the Borough Market bomber.
Oh. Another wonderful
human being.
Tell me about him.
Well, he's born in
a three-goat town
on the Turkey-Iraq border.
No birth certificate.
No papers.
1996, he gets
guest worker status
in Germany...
Without papers?
He's arrested for
possession in Berlin.
Explosives?
Heroin.
Arrives in London, 1998.
Gets married, has a kid.
They stay with
a sister-in-law,
one Mine Kemmal.
They stay with her
for three months
till she gets fed up
and chucks them out.
He bunks off back
to Germany to drive
a taxi in Düsseldorf.
2009, returns to London.
2012, bang.
So what's he been
doing for three years?
Becoming radicalized,
most likely.
The prosecution
will propose that
Erdogan is
the leader of the cell.
Of course, they will.
Two died in the bombing,
one resisting arrest.
Our client is
the last man standing,
therefore the evil genius.
There is a certain
convenience to it.
Could you find out
if it's too late for us
to change
the special advocate?
She was Simon's choice,
not mine.
Why would we want to change
the special advocate?
It's Claudia Simmons-Howe.
I'm not sure she's any good.
Happy birthday, My Lord.
My birthday
was a week ago.
Why are you
really here?
I'd like your advice.
Yes?
I think I should
resign as special advocate
for Farroukh Erdogan.
Why would you do that?
Well, there's a new
defense barrister.
Martin Rose.
Yes.
And I was appointed
by his predecessor,
so I think it's just cause
for an entirely new team.
Highly disruptive
to the defense.
But better in the long run.
Not what your father
would have done, Claudia.
Oh, that's hardly fair.
He would have
regarded the defendant's
interests as paramount.
As I do.
In the biggest,
most high-profile
murder case
in British history.
Still,
perhaps you're right.
What?
Perhaps you
should be replaced.
No.
It's not that
I should be "replaced."
Especially as Mr. Rose
has himself expressed
a similar opinion.
He has?
So I'm told.
I'm not going to resign.
But the rules
are very clear.
The defense barrister,
that's me,
must have no contact
with the special advocate
once you've seen
the classified evidence.
Furthermore,
close social
or personal relationship
will be seen as
compromising the secrecy
of the closed evidence
which is not allowed.
Martin.
And then we'd both be
looking for a new job.
I am the special advocate.
Nobody is going
to take my place.
If that makes your
position untenable,
so be it.
Well, if you prefer,
we could just tell
the judge that
we had an affair.
So, when we're asked
if there are any
moral impediments to us
fulfilling our duties,
technically,
we'll have to lie.
Look, I'm fine with it.
I'm an arrogant,
unprincipled prick,
as you so succinctly told me
the last time we met.
I'm not lying on oath.
Once the classified
material has been served,
you must not meet,
nor communicate
nor share information
in any way,
nor may you be
seen to do so.
Your remit,
Miss Simmons-Howe,
is to solely address me
on the secret evidence,
which we will evaluate
in closed session.
Mr. Rose, you will
not see this material
unless I decide
it is relevant
and must be disclosed.
Do we understand
the rules?
Mr. Rose, do you know
of any reason related
to yourself or your
personal circumstances
which would
prejudice your ability
to carry out this case
or which might,
in any way, embarrass
the Lord Chancellor?
No, My Lord.
Miss Simmons-Howe,
do you know of any reason
related to yourself or your
personal circumstances
which would
prejudice your ability
to carry out this case,
or which might in any way
embarrass
the Lord Chancellor?
Miss Simmons-Howe?
No, My Lord,
I know of no reason.
There's no need to sulk.
I have an aversion
to wasted journeys.
Is that right?
You don't even know
what you're looking for.
Inspiration, Mr. Devlin.
I told you.
Nothing to see.
Nothing to look at,
which is different.
So, November 30th, 10:43.
Bright, sunny day.
Innocent people.
Truck approaches
from the west entrance.
Shouldn't be parked there.
Someone must
have noticed it,
but there's no time,
is there?
No time to do
anything about it.
10:44.
10:45, and then...
Later that day,
an anonymous phone call
tips off the police.
"Suspicious behavior"
by men at a lock-up
garage in West London.
The lock-up
rented to our client.
Our client knows nothing.
Yeah, because
he sublets the place
for cash to
a certain Mr. Asif, who,
sadly, is no longer with us
since he blew himself up
at the wheel of a truck.
Erdogan had no idea
what was being stored there.
Simon's line of defense.
As dictated
by the defendant.
So why does Erdogan
make 27 phone calls
to Asif in the 12 days
before the explosion?
Chasing rent
on the lock-up.
Very weak.
I want to see
every document
in this case.
Everything is
exactly as Simon left it.
And I've written
an inventory.
Ah.
Claudia Simmons-Howe.
Nazrul Sharma.
Home Office.
Call me Naz.
I brought you your safe
and your laptop.
This safe will be
securely installed here.
It is to be the sole
designated location
in which you are
permitted to store
the secret materials
in the case of
The Crown v. Erdogan,
which will be
delivered to you
prior to the hearing.
Um, this laptop must be used
for the creation and storage
of all documents
relating to the case.
No copies to be made.
Return to us upon
delivery of a verdict.
There's also this
code for the safe.
I'm supposed to get you
to memorize it and then
we burn it together,
but I think I can
trust you to do that.
You've done this
all before, haven't you?
You broke into my chambers.
It was open.
After you unlocked it,
I'm sure it was.
I think you're mistaken.
You're not from Home Office.
You're from Secret Service.
Secret Service?
One of the new intake,
I'd say. Post-July 2005.
Careers in Ml5.
"What can you do
for your country?"
The vetting seems to go on
forever, doesn't it?
But then one day,
you get your ticket
to the fast track
and you never look back.
Goes to your head,
of course.
Makes you think
you can do whatever
you want.
Like breaking into
a barrister's chambers.
I'm supposed to ask you
if there's anywhere else
you might take
the secret material.
Go on, then.
It's sort of personal
questions, isn't it?
I'd rather not, to be honest.
Whether anyone
lives with you.
Or whether there
might be anyone?
A special friend, perhaps,
who regularly or irregularly
spends the night,
that's the way
they put it.
You can leave now.
That's my number.
I know it's a very
complicated case,
so if you ever wanna
talk anything over,
you can give me a call.
What, though
I'm legally obliged,
quite specifically,
not to discuss it
with anyone.
There are people
who really want
a conviction here.
So if you're ever feeling,
uh, bullied or intimidated...
Oh, I can cope
with that, thank you.
Or threatened.
Threatened?
And what do you
mean by that exactly?
You can give me a call.
And what will you do?
Whatever needs
to be done, Claudia.
That is all.
Good evening.
Where's Mike?
He's done his back in,
hasn't he.
Too much sitting around,
I'd say.
I want him back by 3:00.
Oh, listen, Elizabeth,
I thought I'd
take him to Kingston.
Can we make it more like...
5:00?
Mum says I have to
wear a life jacket.
Of course.
Miss Simmons-Howe.
Mr. Devlin.
How are you?
Very well, thank you. You?
Devlin.
What is she doing here?
Ask her yourself.
She and I are not
allowed to communicate.
An exception can be made
for the common courtesies.
Though evidently not,
in this case.
Until the delivery of
the closed material,
I am permitted
to communicate
with Mr. Rose.
Whether or not
I choose to do so
is another matter.
As I'm beginning
to understand.
So would you please
inform this gentleman
that I am here
to see Mr. Devlin?
She and I are going
to visit Erdogan,
as I told you
earlier today.
Thank you for reminding me.
I am the client's solicitor.
It's a matter of routine
that I'm present
at any interview
with the client.
I know that.
But would you please
inform the lady opposite
that I have first call
upon your services
and expertise?
Perhaps in
all the excitement,
Mr. Rose has forgotten
that there is a special
advocate on this case
and that we're both
representing the defendant.
I want to eat my lunch.
I was here first.
Terrorist scum!
Do you
want us to stay?
No. But could you
take the vomit with you?
There'll be
an eye in the hole.
Are you the doctor?
No. I have been appointed
by the Attorney General
to be your special advocate.
I told them I'm sick.
Has anyone explained to you
what a special advocate does?
No.
Nobody explained
anything to me. I'm sick.
So fuck you.
Mmm.
Mr. Erdogan, you are
accused of master-minding
a suicide bomb attack.
"Master-minding."
There is some
evidence against you,
which the prosecution
believes should be kept
secret from the public
and from you
in the interests of
national security.
What evidence?
I don't know yet,
I haven't been given it,
but when I am,
I need to understand
as much as I can about you
and why you say
you're innocent.
The secret evidence
will be assessed
in closed session.
The courtroom will be locked,
and there will be just myself,
the judge, the prosecutor
and a representative
of the security services.
I bet you all know
each other.
I'm on your side.
It's my job to
convince the judge
that you need to see
the secret evidence.
But I can't
do that on my own.
I need your help.
Where are you getting
the heroin, Farroukh?
Prison heroin is very impure,
that's why you're throwing up.
You should ask to be put on
their dependency program.
In Berlin,
you were arrested for
possession of heroin,
but you were released.
Why did they release you
without a custodial sentence?
I didn't stick around.
I got on a plane.
But how did you
get leave to remain
if you had a conviction
for possession?
May I ask you again?
How did you get
leave to remain
if you had a conviction?
I don't need
a whatever-the-fuck-you-are.
I need
a fucking doctor. Okay?
I wonder if Mr. Erdogan
is a little tired.
It's a long day for a man
in a place like this.
Then they
sent me back and said,
"No. Now you have to
take off your shoes."
And I mean, I'm wearing
stilettos, right?
What, do I have tiny,
little explosives?
You should try
being Asian.
I get stopped and searched
every couple of weeks.
I wouldn't say no.
Handsome, young policeman?
Martin.
You never come.
Are you drunk?
Not yet.
Does everyone know
Martin Rose?
Can I sit between two people
who hate each other?
I like to come as a relief.
Yeah, you can sit
next to me if you like.
But I should warn you,
I'm just a boring,
old civil servant.
Oh, that's hardly
fair, Melissa.
The work of
the Department of Transport
is vital to the nation.
You're doing me no favors.
What else can I say?
Traffic flow projections.
Flexible approaches to
variable speed limits
during peak hours...
I think
we can stop there.
You see, Mr. Rose,
I'm as good as my word.
Martin, may I
introduce Joanna?
Hello, Joanna.
I'm going through
a vicious divorce
at the moment
and will soon be
penniless, so,
from your point of view,
what would be the point?
Joanna, he's famously awful.
Hi. Just getting some air.
You're defending one of
the Borough Market bombers
at the Old Bailey.
Yes.
And you're a journalist.
In fact,
you're Joanna Reece.
Thirty-two.
Deputy Bureau Chief
on the London desk of
The New York Times.
You called Simon Fellowes
seven times on his
office number.
Three times at home.
He obeyed the rules
and filed a report.
You also left your card
on my windscreen
at his funeral.
Sort of distasteful
thing to do, if you ask me.
Anyway, you hoped
I'd make contact,
which I didn't.
So you cooked things up
with a mutual acquaintance
and came here tonight,
in the hope that
I might get drunk
and you and I
could have a nice
off-the-record
chat about the case.
I don't
speak to journalists
at the best of times,
especially not about trials
relating to matters
of national security.
No matter how drunk.
If you knew that
I was here,
why did you come?
Curiosity.
I want to know
what your angle is.
Well,
are you sure
Simon Fellowes' death
was a suicide?
Middle Temple.
I will be told
some secret evidence.
If I'm going to
challenge that,
I need to know everything.
If your dad is convicted,
he will spend the rest
of his life in prison...
Actually,
I'll jump out here.
Devlin.
I just hailed the same
cab twice in one night.
In fact, three times
in the last two days.
Different part of town.
Different driver. Same cab.
How do you know
it was the same one?
Because I remember
the license number.
4-2-1-9-1.
Devlin, for some reason,
we're being managed.
You wanna
look at the forensic
report on the car,
or have you
memorized it already?
Memorized it.
TATP on the upholstery
on the front passenger seat,
the rear seat
and the boot as well.
May I remind you
that the client
has already determined
his line of defense.
And Simon Fellowes
was gonna follow
that line, was he?
That Erdogan gave Asif
a lift from the airport
to the station,
and the TATP on
the seats came from Asif?
If I was that stupid,
I would jump
off a roof myself.
Oh, you're such
a heartless fucker.
But, actually,
I don't think Simon
was that stupid.
I think he was
on to something.
I think he picked up
on the same thing I did.
Which is?
That it's a very,
very expensive car.
Where did they
find this car?
Chinatown.
Jade Temple restaurant.
Newport Street.
Excellent. Then I'll
go there for dinner.
Want something to drink?
Just a water, thanks.
Self-selection.
You must be Erdogan's
heroin dealer.
I know Mr. Erdogan came here
because his car was found
clamped outside.
I already
spoke to the police.
I'm not a policeman.
I just have some
simple questions for you
with one word answers.
20 pounds a word.
When he bought heroin,
was it pure or cut?
Pure.
He asked you
the same questions
I just did, correct?
Morning, Claudia.
All set?
Oh, I'm supposed
to blindfold you.
Do you want to do that?
This room is bugged.
Not like you
to be suspicious.
I'm just saying.
It's routine around here.
Confidential conversations
are transcribed
and filed away.
Better be careful
what I say, then.
Yeah, or at least
speak clearly.
For the sake
of the typist.
The existence
of these premises
is covered by
the Official Secrets Act.
Any attempt to disclose
the existence or location
hereof will result
in prosecution.
Be gentle. She's fragile,
and he's a very sensitive boy.
Mrs. Erdogan,
I'd like to ask you
some questions.
Farroukh...
Why did you come back
to London from Berlin
in March 2009?
She says she don't
know why he came back.
Can you ask her
if he ever talked about
his time in Germany?
I just found myself
on a plane.
I was out of my head
most of the time so...
How often did he attend
the Lime Street mosque?
I don't know where he went.
Would you please
ask your mother?
She don't know.
I don't know how
often I called Asif.
I called him
all the time
to get the rent.
He was always
late with the rent.
That's why I called him.
But I've told all of this
to the queer guy before you.
Emir...
Would you please
tell your mother
that I'm on her
husband's side.
When I go into the court,
I will be told
some secret evidence.
If I'm going to
challenge that,
I need to know everything.
If your dad is convicted,
he will spend the rest
of his life in prison.
I used to do that.
What?
Play Medal of Honor?
No, I used to get angry.
Rather than
help people who were
trying to help me,
I'd just say nothing
as a way of
getting my own back,
even though the
only person I was really
hurting was myself.
You didn't know what
was in the lock-up?
You never went inside,
you just took the rent?
Yeah.
And the long calls to Asif
were an accident,
and all the money
you made were from
small-time drug deals?
Yeah.
Are you any good at it?
Medal of Honor, I mean.
I want her
out of here, now!
Don't wanna talk
to her no more!
I want her out!
Everything all right?
Mmm-hmm.
I don't have any
further questions.
Not yet.
So what was in
that note to Erdogan?
Give me a cigarette.
So what was
all that about, then?
Hmm?
When Erdogan came
to London from Germany,
he got immigration papers
within three months,
in spite of his
criminal record.
ILR usually
takes three years,
even if you're clean.
Within six months,
he's driving
a brand new Mercedes.
He's spending
two grand a week.
He lied about
dealing drugs.
Before I went in there,
I suspected, now I'm sure.
Erdogan was
being run by Ml5.
No wonder
they're all so upset.
They must have thought
he had the cell
under control,
but either he
double-crossed his handlers
or the cell used him
to pass bad information.
Either way, Ml5 fucked up.
The arrest was a mistake.
But the telephone tip-off?
Would have gone
to the local police who
tipped off Scotland Yard.
Erdogan would have
been under arrest
before Ml5 could do
anything about it.
So now they're fucked.
This means that
Farroukh Erdogan,
who's on trial for murder,
almost certainly
paid for the explosives
that killed 120
innocent people
with taxpayers' money.
When Simon
got this far, of course,
they threw him off a roof.
Mussi Kartal.
It's actually quite convenient
to be under surveillance.
What's that?
Well, normally
getting a taxi can be quite
difficult this time of night.
I see you're using
more than one taxi now.
That's a good idea.
What did you say?
It's okay.
Apparently I'm paranoid.
- In here?
- Yes. You can go in.
Thank you.
Just passing?
I was visiting a friend.
Oh, that's nice.
How about you?
I hurt my neck.
I'm sorry. Accident?
You tell me.
Believe me,
I sincerely hope that it was.
I'm waiting for an X-ray.
If there's no fracture,
I can take this off
and go home.
Isn't that good news?
That is good news.
Look, Martin, I can imagine
what you're thinking.
How this looks to you.
I've made no allegation.
But if we accept that they,
that someone,
then we have to accept
all sorts of things which
are simply unacceptable.
And I will not accept that.
You really know
how to clarify
a situation, don't you?
I'm not even here.
Then thank you
for your support,
Mr. Attorney.
There is
a temptation, Martin,
for any barrister
in a case like this
to stray.
To dig into.
What?
All right,
let me do it for you.
"Perhaps, Martin,
one should see this
as a cautionary event.
"Not so much a warning,
"merely a suggestion to remain
on the straight and narrow."
Am I right?
Intuitive.
But incomplete.
You neglect to mention
your previous relationship
with Miss Simmons-Howe.
I wonder why.
Perhaps because,
and, please,
let me do it for you,
it's a weakness.
A weakness that could end
both your careers.
Am I right?
And perhaps that weakness
is the very reason
you were chosen for this job.
Goodbye, Martin.
Claudia Simmons-Howe,
this is the closed
material in relation
to the case of
The Crown v. Erdogan,
disclosure of
which will damage
national security.
It must be kept,
by you, at all times
in a secure location
until such a time
as a verdict is given.
Et cetera,
et cetera, et cetera.
And if you wouldn't mind,
let's keep the
pen-pushers happy,
shall we?
Would you like me to
place them in the safe?
I'll be reading them
right away.
Of course. Fine.
You can leave now.
Oh.
Lock's changed.
Ingersoll. Very nice.
It's the choice
of professionals.
I'm being watched.
You always were.
That couple over there,
perhaps.
Probably.
Shall we?
You first.
Erdogan was
working for Ml5.
Very good.
But Erdogan's
not his real name.
It's Mussi Kartal.
In 2008, there was a bomb at
a US Air Force base in Munich
which killed 20 servicemen.
Mussi Kartal was part
of the terrorist cell
that was aleg... allegedly
responsible for it.
Kartal was arrested,
but he cut a deal with
the prosecutors in
exchange for his freedom.
Ml5 liked the idea of a man
who was already compromised.
They brought him
in to be recruited by
a local terrorist cell,
the idea being
that he would help
plan a major attack
but ultimately betray
his fellow conspirators.
At the last moment.
And that's where
it all went wrong.
That's why
the secret is lethal.
Is that your headline?
Huh. No headline
without proof.
You've obviously never read
a British newspaper.
Why don't they
just kill Erdogan?
Then there
would be no trial.
There'd be no verdict.
No one to blame.
So we think
he has a deal, do we?
He keeps his mouth shut,
plays along.
Doesn't mind
being found guilty,
and in return, he's safe.
Right.
But defense barristers
who ask the wrong
sorts of questions,
in this situation, well,
they're sort of expendable.
Aren't they?
Stay off
the rooftops, Martin.
Can I have a phone, please?
Pay as you go.
Any kind you like.
Oh, sorry.
Excuse me,
can you take a photo of us?
Can I search your bag?
Ladies and gentlemen, Wembley,
please welcome the teams.
This better be good.
Farroukh Erdogan
was working for Ml5.
What?
Hold on. You have
evidence of this?
No. I'll handle it.
Trust me.
Martin, if that's
our client's defense...
It's not our client's defense.
Then we need to
establish that.
We need to prove that
he was actually
working for the state.
You can't expose this.
Our client is pursuing
a simple line of defense.
He won't challenge
the findings
but portrays himself as
an unfortunate bystander.
"Yes, My Lord,
there was half a ton
"of nitrate in my lock-up,
but it wasn't mine."
Let me handle it
in open session.
He will be
wrongly convicted.
It will constitute
a grave miscarriage
of justice,
as you now know, Martin.
The client's instructions...
Were what?
"Send me to jail for
the rest of my life"?
The informant.
The anonymous informant.
Leave it, Claudia.
Don't go anywhere near it.
The informant must know.
That's what
they're trying to hide.
Let me handle it in
open session tomorrow.
I will act in our
client's best interest,
but not stand aside
while the state
perpetrates murder.
Another murder is what
I'm trying to prevent.
They make it
look like suicide.
Or an accident.
They got Simon
and they nearly got me.
Oh, for goodness sake,
Martin.
I don't want them to have
a reason to get to you.
Anything else?
No.
This morning
is all about secret evidence.
Evidence
the defense want disclosed,
but which the prosecution say
must be withheld
to protect our country's
security interests.
The defense will
present their case,
and the judge will decide
which evidence can be
put in front of a jury.
As such, rumor has it,
some quite
senior members of Ml5
will be facing questions
from Mr. Erdogan's
special advocate,
Claudia Simmons-Howe.
All rise.
We are listed for both
a closed and open session
to review the evidence
in Mr. Erdogan's case.
He's charged with murder,
conspiracy to murder,
conspiracy to cause explosions
and possession of explosives.
Before we begin,
we need to establish
the order of
today's proceedings.
I would suggest, My Lord,
that we begin with
the open material.
And the prosecution?
I have no preference,
My Lord.
But I always believe
these matters are best left
to the wisdom
and discretion
of the bench.
We will begin with
the closed material.
My Lord...
Prepare the court
for a closed session.
Mr. Rose.
Wigs off.
We are now in closed.
The Crown argue
that this evidence
should not be disclosed
to the defense
in the interests of
national security.
It will be
presented for the benefit
of the Special Advocate.
Miss Simmons-Howe,
I understand that you wish
to cross-examine
the Security Service witness
whom we will call Witness X.
I do, My Lord.
Witness X, you are
the Security Service
Chief of Operations
in the Erdogan case?
I am.
You all right?
Taking it personally,
are you now?
You mustn't.
Nobody listens
to me, either.
That's life.
I just get on with it.
Think happy thoughts.
Will you confirm to
the Special Advocate
the identity of the informant?
The informant is
Mr. Erdogan's
14-year-old son, Emir.
Could you tell
the court why you believe
it would harm
national security
to reveal his identity
in open court?
Following
Mr. Erdogan's arrest,
we discovered that Emir
had been hacking
his father's computer
for nearly three years.
He has detailed knowledge
of communications
between his father
and significant people,
known and unknown,
in Istanbul,
Berlin and in Pakistan.
More importantly, he knows
many of the passwords
his father used.
But why do you not
want the boy's role
in the arrest of his father
to be revealed
in open session?
Because he's asked
for absolute assurances
that he will not be called
to give evidence in court.
So he has expressly
requested anonymity?
And until this court
confirms that he will
remain anonymous,
he's refusing to reveal
key pieces of information
that he's gathered from
his father's computer files.
Are we sure
he's telling the truth?
Small amounts of information
he's already given
have proven sound
and extremely valuable.
And, presumably,
if it were to be
revealed in open court
that Emir informed
on his father and worse,
that he's now in
a position to provide
the Security Services
with invaluable
information,
there is a strong
probability that his life
would be in danger?
Good game?
What?
Last night.
Looked like great goals.
Yeah, yeah.
That's more like it.
- Excuse me a moment.
- Witness X...
I have some questions.
This is an important case
for Ml5, would you say?
It involves national security.
Of course.
And I must say that
importance has been made
very clear to me,
both professionally
and even personally.
Your agents work very hard.
I'll be sure to pass on
your appreciation.
Miss Simmons-Howe.
Does all the information
on Farroukh Erdogan's
activities
come from his son?
Yes.
And prior to the bombing,
there was no contact between
Ml5 and the defendant?
That's an odd question.
Nevertheless,
it has been asked.
We had no reason
to link Mr. Erdogan to a plan
to blow up Borough Market.
What about MI6?
Not as far as I'm aware,
and I'm sure I would be,
if they did.
Isn't it the truth
that you don't want
Emir Erdogan's identity
to be disclosed
because you're afraid
of what he might reveal
about his father,
afraid that he
might reveal something
of his father's history?
What history?
Why did Erdogan
return to London
from Germany?
You spoke to him.
But he wouldn't
answer my questions.
Who paid for his ticket,
for example?
Perhaps you asked
the wrong questions.
Or perhaps he had
been told not to answer.
Wait. What do you mean?
You are claiming
that Farroukh Erdogan
was what was known
as a "clean skin"?
Yes.
That he was not considered
to be a person of interest?
No.
You had
no surveillance on him?
He was not
on your radar?
No.
You were not handling him
as an Ml5 agent?
Are you familiar with
the name Mussi Kartal?
That name is new to me.
Miss Simmons-Howe,
where is this line of
questioning leading?
My Lord, to answer that,
I need an adjournment.
A what?
I wish to question the boy,
Emir Erdogan, here in court.
That boy holds the key
to unlock information
that may save lives.
I believe he will
support the case
that Farroukh Erdogan
was known to Ml5,
that he was
working with Ml5,
and that, in fact,
he was working for Ml5
at the time of the bombing.
I believe Emir Erdogan
has evidence that will
support that claim.
I believe his testimony
will expose the malpractice
and incompetence of
the Security Service,
and demonstrate that
his father was nothing
more than a pawn
in the hands of Ml5,
who used him to snare
genuine terrorists
in an operation
that went tragically
and murderously wrong
for 120 people on that day.
Evidence?
I believe so.
Just five seconds
of your time, sir.
Mr. Rose,
can I ask you a question?
Five seconds of your time.
Mr. Altman,
the Crown will arrange
to bring Emir Erdogan
to court.
I will question him myself.
10:00 a.m. Tomorrow.
My Lord...
Tomorrow, 10:00 a.m.
Miss Simmons-Howe,
where is she?
You just missed her, sir.
Nothing but
a civil servant, right?
I don't know what
just happened in there,
but whatever did...
Please wait.
Claudia was just
trying to do her job.
We're simply trying
to defend our client.
Your client is a guilty man.
And you know this because
he worked for you.
He was inside the cell.
He didn't tell
you what happened,
and you assume
that this means that
he deliberately duped you.
But they could have
crossed him as well.
There is doubt.
You lawyers, you like your
fucking doubt, don't you?
Well, I can't use doubt.
I can only use certainty.
I need certain knowledge
in order to do my job.
To save lives.
You people,
you're all the same.
You want
the freedom to attack me,
but without me,
you wouldn't have
much freedom at all.
Your girlfriend should have
kept her mouth shut.
Ladies and gentlemen,
at this time of
heightened security,
it is important...
Claudia, it's me.
Turn off your phone,
dump your bag,
dump everything
and meet me at
the first place
I took you to.
The first place
The accused, Farroukh Erdogan,
appeared briefly
in court number one
and pleaded not guilty to
all the charges against him.
They want you.
In court.
To give evidence.
Are you okay
with that, Emir?
I saw you. With my father.
There's a lot of blokes
look like me.
...what information
should be kept secret
in the interest of
national security
and what information
should be disclosed...
We leave at 9:00.
I'll drive you
there myself.
...what seems increasingly
a crucial question.
We don't know who appeared,
we don't know what was said,
we don't know
what's being considered.
The case will
continue tomorrow.
She don't know...
Emir, would you...
New message.
Hi, Claudia,
this is Sophie from Chambers.
Just calling and hope that
we can reschedule our
meeting for next week
from Monday to Thursday...
Claudia, if you're at home,
get out of there.
Please meet me
at the first place
I took you to.
Come on!
It's been so long.
Listen, I need your help.
Don't.
You're hurt.
I said, "Don't."
You're bleeding.
Yeah. Well,
it's not my blood.
Claudia, what happened?
Well?
You're safe now.
The informant
is his son, Emir.
Emir?
But he's just a child.
He knows something, Martin.
They're clearly scared of him.
They've put him
in a safe house.
He has evidence.
Of his father's
links to Ml5.
I wanted to see
how they would react.
Yeah, well, now you know.
If you even begin to say,
"I told you so."
No, Claudia, I...
Because I...
All I care about is...
We're not strong enough
to fight them, are we?
No.
There's no good way
out of this, is there?
There's no...
There is no right
way out of this.
No.
Sorry, Claudia.
Hmm.
So how do we do it?
I'll call them and tell them
that we'll do as we're told.
It's that simple?
Yes.
That simple.
What?
Nothing.
I hate that they hurt you.
I don't want to be here
when you make the call.
I don't want to
hear you do it.
It's Martin Rose.
I need to talk to
Melissa Fairbright
or whoever it is that uses
that pseudonym, please.
Yes?
Melissa,
it's Martin Rose.
I'm calling to
make a deal.
Never mind
your fucking deal.
Where's the boy?
What?
Emir's gone.
He's broken out
of the safe house.
We don't have long.
They'll trace my line.
If they find him,
they'll kill him.
They will kill him.
Well, then
we have to stop them.
How?
We get him to court.
If we get him to court,
his evidence will protect him.
His old flat.
He's not stupid.
He'll know
they're watching him.
Where would a boy
that age go?
He could be out
on the streets,
could be anywhere.
Claudia.
I sent to my aunt.
"I sent to my aunt."
That's what he said.
Yes?
Right.
Well, keep looking.
Mrs. Kemmal,
we've learned that
your nephew has escaped.
Has run away from
the place where he was
being looked after.
Has he sent you
anything recently?
I have not heard from him.
Or seen him?
No.
Mrs. Kemmal,
we want to help Emir.
But it's more than that.
I think that he could be
in great danger.
We want to protect him.
I made a mistake.
We've all made mistakes.
Here's the evidence.
Everything you need
from Dad's hard drive.
It's them.
Oi!
You have every advantage
our society can offer.
But will you defend it?
No, you leave
that to someone else.
So I fight a war
against men who'd
see you wrapped up
in a mask the moment
you look like a woman.
Come on.
Let's get out of here.
Are you all right?
They didn't get me.
Hello.
Listen, we've got the boy.
Who? What are you
talking about?
Emir Erdogan.
They were going to kill him.
Jesus, Martin.
What the hell have you
got yourself into?
I need you to meet me.
He's not safe with us.
I need you to
look after him.
Make sure that
he gets to the court
by 10:00 tomorrow.
Can you do that for me?
All right.
All right, bring him here.
No, I'll meet you at
the back of King's Cross
in an hour from now.
Okay.
Back of King's Cross tunnel.
At 3:30.
I'll be there.
And, Martin...
You be careful.
You know what?
It's a bit
bloody late for that.
Do you think it'll work?
It'll buy us a few hours.
He'll see you.
No, he won't.
Because he's not coming.
If he was,
he'd be here by now.
He doesn't
trust you, Devlin.
And you assured us
you could control him,
steer him in
the right direction.
Sorry.
I have to make
a decision now.
Do you understand?
Devlin.
I'd never have thought.
Only two people knew
I was at the football.
You and Ml5.
The moment he asked
about the game, I knew.
Your son's?
Yes.
How old is he now?
Old enough
to know how much
I fucked up his life.
In so many ways,
you were the worst thing
that ever happened to me.
Oh.
You were
undoubtedly the worst thing
that ever happened to me.
They'll be waiting for us.
I know.
What if they stop us
before we get to court?
Well, at least we tried.
This is
a security announcement.
If you see anything suspicious
or anyone acting suspiciously,
please report it immediately
to a member of staff
or the police.
Hello, yeah?
Okay.
You know the plan.
Mr. Rose...
Will justice be
served in court today?
Mr. Altman,
are we ready to proceed?
My Lord,
I call Emir Erdogan
to answer any questions
that the court or
Miss Simmons-Howe may have.
I swear by Allah
that the evidence
I shall give
shall be the truth,
the whole truth
and nothing but the truth.
How's the neck?
Much better.
That is good news.
I wondered
if you and I might...
We could go for breakfast.
You and I?
Yes. Wouldn't that be nice?
Emir, I have
some questions for you.
Do you recognize this?
That's my memory stick.
My Lord, might this
be exhibit number one.
There are a number
of files that are
of potential relevance
and which I would
now like to examine.
I expect he's in
full flow by now.
Don't you think? The boy.
As I understand it,
his evidence could cause
a mighty furore.
Well, well...
But I wouldn't want
this trial to be the end
of your career, Martin.
Which it would be,
if all the facts
were to be revealed.
Facts?
About how you
and the Special Advocate
were in frequent
communication.
Indeed, that you went
so far as to meet up.
Quite contrary to the terms
of your binding oath.
My advice...
My heartfelt,
sincere advice as a...
Well, my advice is to
let it go, all of it.
You see...
What am I?
Government senior
law officer.
Advisor to the
Prime Minister.
It means nothing.
There are powers at play
that neither you nor I,
nor the Prime Minister,
for that matter,
may even hope to control.
I mean, not entirely.
Not at the very
essence of the term.
So there is,
you see,
a certain
inevitability about it,
wouldn't you say?
About what?
- The collapse of the case.
- What else?
I just have this feeling,
don't you?
Who's to say? Perhaps
it's better that way.
Erdogan.
Safe until he isn't, right?
As I say,
it's just a feeling.
A premonition.
Call it what you will.
A calamity for justice,
of course.
Now, we can fret about it,
become indignant,
write an angry letter
to the newspapers
or our Members of Parliament.
Won't make any difference.
Emir's evidence
is being heard
in closed session
and that is
where it will remain.
It will be presented
in accordance with the law,
then the evidence
will be placed in a box.
The box will then be closed
and it will never
be opened again.
Of course, there'll be
the inevitable
government inquiry,
which will take
a number of years
and will fail to
reach any conclusions.
But if no one misbehaves,
no one larks around at
the back of the class,
Emir and Ilkay Erdogan
will not be deported to
somewhere unpleasant.
They will be
allowed to live here.
You try not to
forget that, Martin.
That is your part
of the bargain.
Responding to
news of the collapse
of the case this morning,
the Attorney General
made the following statement.
This is a major
disappointment.
With the eyes of
the world upon us,
it saddens me hugely that
we weren't able to show
the great strength
of our legal process
and judicial system.
I will, of course...
You never
answer your phone.
I never know
what to say.
Emir and his mother
have been allowed to stay.
But I guess you
already knew that.
You blame yourself.
Mostly.
Well, that's good.
The old Martin Rose
would never have accepted
the blame for anything.
I only said, "Mostly."
Well, that's even better
'cause that means
the old Martin Rose
has not entirely gone.
But no longer practicing.
Please ask the stenographer
to put that on the record.
See, I know
where this is going.
And the answer is "no."
It will be just like
being here, doing this.
I get it.
And for the next bit,
you tell me that
the law needs
men of integrity.
Yeah, it does.
But that doesn't mean that
there's also a place
for someone like you.
Usually after I...
There's a place
not far from here.
It's not very good.
It's a bit over-priced.
I can't honestly
recommend it.
But um, you're welcome
to join me.
In fact, I'd be
very happy if you did.
Order!
Order! Order!
Would the Attorney General
care to comment on
the rumors of a cover-up
in the collapse of the
Farroukh Erdogan case?
And does he still
consider our legal system
to be fair and transparent?
I am certain that
as I stand here today,
our justice system stands out
as a beacon of clarity...
Stands out as a beacon
of clarity, of equality
and, above all, of integrity.
- Resign! Resign!
- Order!