WOMAN:
Okay, here we go.
Oh, wow.
Oh, my God, you guys.
Oh, my God, Rachel, you suck.
BOUNCER: It's a private party.
- It's okay, they're kind of expecting me.
[LIL WENDY'S "SHAKE IT"
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
- Shake it, shake it
- Let me hear you now
Shake it, shake it, shake it
- Shake it, shake it
- Let me hear you now
Hello?
[MUSIC STOPS]
ALL:
Surprise!
[ALL CHEERING]
[UPBEAT DANCE MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]
I know you told me not to,
but I just had to.
I just had to.
- You're not mad, are you?
- No, it's sweet.
And are you surprised?
Was I surprised?
- You were?
- Ugh. Was I?
She was surprised!
You don't want this.
I knew it, I knew it, I knew it. We did it!
[ALL CHEERING]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- No! Oh, no, sorry, somebody's in here.
- Ow!
It's me.
- Ow. Not afraid to put your back into it.
- What are you doing in the ladies' room?
What? I saw you come in here,
looking all tragic.
So I'm here to check for razor blades.
You were not coming in here for me.
You're dodging Claire.
See what happens when you sleep
with people you don't love?
- That's insulting.
- Why don't you talk to her?
Rachel, she's crazy.
[CROWD CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY]
CLAIRE: There you are.
- Good God.
CLAIRE: Hi.
- Hi.
Where have you been all night, mister?
Mr. Magoo. Ha-ha-ha.
Just hiding. Yeah.
Hiding. Ha-ha-ha.
- It's so, like, chaotic in here.
- Yep.
Do you wanna...? Do you wanna go
someplace more, like, um, intimate or...?
No. Party. So I think I'll stay here.
- Me neither. I don't want to either.
- Yep. Awesome.
- Oh, my God.
- What is it?
I want you to see me drop it like it's hot.
One second.
- This is awesome.
- [WHISPERING] Talk to her.
DARCY:
When she walked in... Aah!
Hey!
- That was very nice of you.
- What?
Pretending to be surprised.
- Please don't tell her. She'll be heartbroken.
- I won't.
[MIMICS THUD]
What's going on, Dex?
How you doing? You gonna introduce me
to the birthday girl?
Rachel, this is Marcus.
Old family friend. Just moved into town.
What up, birthday girl?
Please stop saying that.
Don't worry. The capacity to be pleasured
only increases with age.
- Trust me.
- Wow.
What's up? What's your name?
You got a boyfriend?
RACHEL: Wow.
- Yeah. I'm sorry.
DARCY:
Hello.
I'm gonna say something.
And I know everybody wants to hear it.
Center of attention. That's weird.
All right, well, as most of you know,
I'm getting married in 61 days.
[ALL CHEER]
And, Dex, honey,
I have a confession to make.
This won't be my first marriage.
[SALT-N-PEPA'S "SHOOP" PLAYING
ON STEREO]
I wanna shoop, baby
Yep. Rachel and I have been soul mates
since the beginning.
Like two peas in a pod,
we did everything together.
Like re-enacting Dirty Dancing.
And our infamous dance routine
to Salt-N-Pepa's "Push lt."
We basically shared everything.
Including Ethan.
Oh, shit. Why am I in this?
DARCY:
Our date to the sixth grade dance.
And through all the years,
Rachel and I were inseparable.
It was us against the world.
And after we graduated Indiana,
she ditched my ass for stupid law school...
...despite the fact
that I selflessly rejected...
...my acceptance to Notre Dame...
...because she wasn't let in.
But whatever.
It all worked out in the end,
because she went to NYU Law...
...and met my future husband,
and introduced us.
[CROWD CHEERING]
I'll never forget, when Dex proposed...
...all I could think about
when he was down on one knee...
...was that I wish Rachel was here...
...watching me in this moment.
[WHISPERING]
Sorry. Who are we celebrating?
I mean, to say you are my best friend
is the understatement of the century.
You're the sister I never had.
You're sometimes the mother
I often need.
The reason why I can stumble
so fearlessly into adventure...
...is because she's always there.
She is always, always there.
I love you, Rachel.
[WHISPERING]
I love you too.
Happy 30th!
I'm so happy it's not me yet!
All right. Come on, let's get this
party going. Come on, come on.
[CROWD CHEERING AND UPBEAT
DANCE MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO]
And shake it, shake it.
[CHUCKLING]
Wow.
So are you two, like, uh...?
A couple? Nope.
- No?
- Nope.
You guys ever...?
- No. No.
- No?
WOMAN:
Shake it, Darcy!
You know what, sweetheart?
I think it's time that you came down.
[UPBEAT HIP-HOP MUSIC PLAYING]
Rachel, tell him to let me stay.
Come on, I did the party.
I'm the one who did it.
- Honey, I love you so much.
- I love you.
- Did you like it? Did you like your party?
- I did. I loved it.
[DARCY LAUGHING]
Oh, my God, remind me to buy you
new shoes. I just hate your shoes so much.
Okay, yep, time to go home.
- I hate them.
- You know what? She'll call you tomorrow.
I don't understand why you think,
"I'm gonna buy that pair of shoes."
- Happy birthday.
- Hey, thank you.
[WHISTLES]
Never helps, but I do it anyway.
There's an old maid in the window.
Let's get her a cat.
Okay, you're not old.
You're just a lawyer. It's different.
I'm serious, Ethan.
Thirty's young, but it's not that young.
- Okay. Ten-second pity party. Go.
- Ethan.
I'm past my prime child-bearing years.
Wow. Okay.
I didn't know we were going dark.
I basically wasted my entire 20s.
And I hate my job.
Okay, two things? You went way over.
And, secondly, you didn't waste your 20s.
You just grew up.
Why won't you marry me?
Because I like you too much.
Ah! Perfect timing.
RACHEL:
Dex.
- Hey, what's going on?
- Darcy forgot her purse.
RACHEL: Her new Chanel?
- Not the new Chanel! Let's go.
- Come on.
- Oh. I'm gonna go help him find it.
Are you serious?
It's like a $2000 handbag.
Dudes aren't supposed to know that.
In or out, asshole?
You need a hug, buddy.
Oh! And voilà.
- Oh!
- Ha-ha-ha.
- You all right?
- Mm-hm.
- You sure?
Thank you. Come on. I'll get you a taxi.
So did you have a good time tonight?
Yeah, I did.
[SCOFFS]
I did!
Hey. Let's get one more drink.
Oh, no, that's okay. You don't have to.
Come on. I want to.
DEX:
Two Heinekens, please.
RACHEL: Darcy.
DARCY: It'll be fun. Come on.
DEX:
Are you always this obnoxious?
DARCY: Ha-ha-ha.
Yes, I am. Does that surprise you?
Wow. You really don't notice
the way women look at you.
You're funny.
I'm not that funny.
You're right. You were much funnier
in law school.
[CHUCKLES]
[GROANS]
God, if we could do anything, anything,
wake up tomorrow and do anything...
...be anything, what would you do?
- What would you be?
- Rap superstar.
Come on, seriously.
I'd be a teacher.
- Really?
- Yeah.
Yeah, I always wanted to teach.
You know, maybe start with high school.
Coach the soccer team.
So why aren't we?
Doing what we really wanna do?
Well, I don't know about you...
...but doing what I wanna do
has never been much of a factor.
It's more like what I'm expected to do.
Yes.
Exactly.
Wow. We're really flipping her out.
She can't imagine
what you're doing here with me.
Hot people are supposed to be
with hot people.
- Excuse me.
RACHEL: Dex. Shh!
You're making
my girlfriend uncomfortable.
- Dex. Stop it.
- What?
Oh, my God. Ha-ha-ha.
Oh. Now I remember why I had
such a crush on you in law school.
No, you didn't.
Course I did.
Oh, come on. You knew.
Two stops. Tenth and Second,
then down to Tribeca.
I'm sorry.
I don't know why I...
I was just a...
Yeah, all right.
I'm thinking more like one stop.
DARCY [ON MACHINE]:
Rach? Rachel?
Rach.
Rachel, pick up.
Pick up, pick up, pick up.
Oh, my God.
DARCY: Rachel. Rach.
- Oh, my God. What did I do?
DARCY: I'm panicking.
Dex never came home.
Oh, no.
DARCY: Listen to me.
Dex never came home and I don't...
[TELEPHONE BEEPS]
Fourteen missed calls.
Oh, my God! Wait! Don't be naked!
What...?
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
- Should I answer it?
- What? No! No, no. Don't...
Oh, shit!
- Pants. What?
- I should answer.
DARCY: Why isn't anyone answering?
- Don't answer the phone.
RACHEL: I'll just say...
DARCY: Pick up the phone!
- What?
DARCY: Rach.
I don't know.
DARCY: It's an emergency,
and I think Dex is cheating on me.
And I know it sounds so crazy, but,
hot people, they get cheated on sometimes.
- What do we do?
DEX: Rachel.
It'll be okay. It's gonna be okay.
We'll figure it out.
[GROANS]
I'll tell her I was with Marcus.
[WHISPERING]
God, I'm such a terrible person.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
What did I do?
I mean, not just to her, but to you.
Rachel, stop. It wasn't just you.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Rachel, I...
I better go.
- Hello?
- Rach, where the hell have you been?
Dex didn't come home last night.
- Hello?
- Oh, my God.
- Rachel.
- Yes, I heard you.
He didn't come home last night.
He better have been hit by a car
or in jail or something.
Darcy, don't say that.
Do you think he's cheating?
No.
- He loves you.
- I know he loves me, obviously.
But where the hell is he?
Did you see him last night? At the bar?
Did you see him when you left the bar?
Oh, yeah.
Uh, he was with Marcus.
They were, uh, watching a game.
A game? At 2 in the morning?
It was something European.
Oh, cricket, maybe.
Cricket?
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]
Oh, my God. It's him.
I'm gonna see about this cricket crap.
I'll call you right back.
Cricket. Cricket?
DEX: You don't happen to have
four extra pens, do you?
Oh, I do, actually. I brought a bunch.
You're making fun of me.
No, I'm impressed.
You're making me feel
really inadequate right now.
[DOOR OPENS]
I'm Professor Dennis Zigman
and this is Torts.
A few ground rules: Never introduce
a contingency in your answer.
A supposed tortfeasor may be argued
to have committed a tortious act...
...when four conditions have been met.
Each is necessary.
None is, in itself, sufficient.
There must be a duty or obligation.
This duty must have been breached.
- This breach must have caused damage.
- [WHISPERING] What about you?
ZIGMAN:
Duty, breach, causation.
[WHISPERING]
That's okay. I'll just listen.
ZIGMAN:
Damage.
Thank you.
ZIGMAN:
Duty, breach, causation, damage.
Now this duty is not a statutory duty.
The breach. The breach may be
in the form of negligence.
[GRUNTING AND SHOUTING]
[RINGING]
- Darcy.
- It's Dex.
I borrowed her phone.
Um, I just wanted to make sure
that you were okay.
Oh. Yeah, I'm fine.
Are you okay?
I, um...
DARCY:
Hey. Who are you talking to?
DEX:
It's Rachel.
Oh! Hey. Sorry.
Totally forgot to call you back.
Yeah, no. Is everything okay?
No, it's fine. He just got drunk
and passed out at Marcus'. Whatever.
- Wish her happy birthday.
- Oh, my God. Happy birthday.
- Thanks. So everything's okay with Dex?
DARCY: Yeah, yeah.
Um, yeah. Yeah.
[WHISPERING]
Except he got a little weird...
...and acted really guilty
and said we have to have a talk.
Talk about what?
I don't know. Whatever.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
I gotta go. Kiss, kiss, kiss.
Wait, can I just talk to Dex real quick?
[GASPING]
DARCY:
Because the dress I picked was perfect.
Unless this one's even more perfect.
Darcy, you look incredible.
Wow. Wow.
She's having her bridal moment.
Hey, Darce. You okay?
- You okay, Darce?
- No, I'm fine. I'm just...
I wanna cry on the day...
...so I wanna check my mascaras,
make sure it doesn't run...
...so I'm trying out
all these different ones.
My mascara. Is it running?
I wish I could cry more.
Can we get a bigger train?
[DEX & RACHEL LAUGHING]
Shh!
Sorry.
Duty, breach, causation...
- Oh, jeez.
RACHEL: Hold on.
- What am I missing? What am I missing?
- Damages.
Oh, shit.
[STUDENTS HUSH]
[WHISPERING]
Sorry. I'm sorry.
Here.
Use a mnemonic.
D, B, C, D.
Deliver by Christmas Day.
Don't blame Cameron Diaz.
[LAUGHING]
- This isn't even that funny, is it?
DEX: No.
It's not funny at all.
How about when all of this is over...
...Dex buys celebratory dinner?
Oh! Yeah.
Sure.
[UPBEAT ROCK MUSIC PLAYING
ON STEREO]
- Actually, I spun the bottle.
- Yes.
- I would spin the bottle.
- Ha-ha-ha.
And, well, she manipulated the bottle
so that it landed on me, of course.
- And so we go in the closet.
- Ha-ha-ha.
But it was one of the best kisses
I've ever had.
Wow.
- And...
- And, um, my first kiss was on a golf course.
- Okay.
- In the middle of the night, and I was 13.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- That's...
DARCY:
Crashing.
Oh, I don't know. He's okay-looking.
Dex, this is Darcy. Darcy, this is Dex.
You've been talking about him
for nine months.
Well, he's been
a very great study partner.
Wow. You two, lighten up.
Your tarts are over.
- Torts. Th...
- Whatever.
Excuse me.
Uh, could we have six shots of tequila,
por favor?
So games, fun, let's get this party started.
Truth or dare.
Darcy.
It'll be fun. Come on.
Okay, fine. I'll start. Dare.
Ask Rachel out on a real date
instead of whatever this is.
Darce. We're just friends.
Fine. Then ask me out.
Hey, don't look at me.
- Who are you?
- Who am I? I, counselor, am fun.
Which you look like you could use
a lot more of.
- Oh, is that so?
DARCY: Mm-hm.
Yeah, it is fun, so I'm willing to share.
- Are you always this obnoxious?
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Yes. I am. Does that surprise you?
DEX: Yeah.
Surprise me? No. You seem like trouble.
DARCY:
Trouble?
[DEX & DARCY LAUGHING]
DARCY:
Rachel.
Did you hear me? Rachel?
[WHISTLES]
Veil, no veil?
Hmm?
Veil.
DARCY:
Oh, come on, Rachel. I mean, really.
You're 30, you can't afford to be picky.
Oh, my God. I can't believe I forgot to
tell you. Guess who thinks you're hot.
Marcus.
Oh.
Dex's friend, Marcus.
He was at your party.
- Yeah, no.
- What?
Oh, my God. You're like...
Whatever. So guess what I did.
I convinced Marcus to take
the last bedroom in the Hamptons house.
- Darcy.
- What? It'll be so fun.
It'll be like
your own little live-in boy toy.
Actually, I'm gonna have to work
most weekends.
RACHEL: Hey.
ETHAN: Hey.
Can't believe I'm doing this.
Oh, stop it. It's one weekend.
It's gonna be beautiful. You can write.
What are you talking about?
The Hamptons are like a zombie movie
directed by Ralph Lauren.
And I won't be doing a lot of writing...
...seeing as how
I'm your sexual chaperone from Marco.
- Marcus.
- Marky.
- Doesn't matter.
[DARCY CHEERING]
[UPBEAT HIP-HOP MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO]
- No.
- Yikes.
No, please tell me he's not coming.
- Good night, everybody.
- Darcy, be nice.
What's with the backpack, Ethan?
Like 1982.
- You're lame.
- Hey. What's up, buddy?
- Hey, look who it is. It's this guy.
MARCUS:
Dude. Three chicks, three dudes.
- Hi.
ETHAN: Thanks, bro.
- Get on in there, doggie.
- Don't touch me, though.
- Here... That's all right. I got it.
RACHEL: No, it's okay. I got it. Thank you.
I got that one.
DARCY: By the way, Ethan,
you're sleeping in a little girl's room.
ETHAN:
Oh, great. You're gross.
Pay the toll. Pay the toll.
- I'll get one later.
DARCY: Sun waiting for us!
DEX: You ready? You ready?
- Whoo!
MARCUS:
The Hamptons, baby, huh?
[DARCY CHEERING]
Oh, my God, you guys.
Welcome.
[DARCY LAUGHING]
DARCY:
Oh, my God. Honey. Honey.
MARCUS: Save it for the honeymoon.
DARCY: Yes.
I'd like to make a toast.
Here...
...is to my last and best summer
of my former life...
...before I become Mrs. Dexter Thaler.
May we all come up here as often
as possible before Labor Day...
...and spend the summer full of sun,
fun, drinking, partying...
We should do some shots.
[DARCY CHEERS]
MARCUS:
Cheers.
ALL: Cheers.
MARCUS: Cheers, buddy.
Cheers. Look in the eyes.
Look in the eyes, everybody. In the eyes.
Bad luck if you don't do it.
Dex, Rachel, look in each other's eyes.
Let's go out!
MARCUS:
Let's go to the Jetty.
[KING FLOYD'S "GROOVE ME"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
[CROWD CHEERING]
ETHAN: You gotta stop staring.
- What?
I wasn't.
What?
I'm talking about cuckoo bird over there.
Look at her. She's just a little gremlin.
She's like some weird animal.
She's like a freaking circus animal.
- What is that?
- Oh, just stop it.
She's a perfectly normal woman
who made the great mistake...
...of thinking some man wanted her
when all he wanted was sex.
- Thanks, Oprah. I don't need...
- Just go talk to her.
Okay. I should totally do that.
Not now, I'm not.
Oh, oh, oh!
What's up? How you doing?
- Ooh! Hey!
- Too much? Too much? All right.
How you doing?
Could I get a Maker's on the rocks, please?
Thank you.
You're like a shark.
That kind of hurts my feelings a little bit.
I'm actually a pretty sensitive guy.
- Oh, really?
- Once, when I was 9 years old...
...I saved the life of a chipmunk.
A chipmunk.
He fell out of our tree and almost died.
He didn't know what to do.
He couldn't move his legs.
So I built a tiny little splint
for his tiny, little broken leg.
And I carried him around
in a BabyBjörn.
And all the kids in my neighborhood,
they laughed. They made fun of me.
They threw rocks at me. But I didn't care.
- You know why?
- Why?
Because all I saw was this little fur ball
that needed love.
That's really sweet.
I know.
So next time you wanna call somebody
a shark, just remember the chipmunk.
All right.
How about we go outside
and get a little fresh air? What?
- No. Sorry. Not my thing.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- Not your thing?
- Not my thing.
Okay.
You know what? Why not?
God, I'm good.
MARCUS:
I don't know what you're talking about.
- But where did the guy end up?
- We never spoke to him again.
[ALL LAUGHING]
[SIGHS]
Bedtime, baby.
Yeah, you two should go.
You know what, hon?
I'm actually not that tired.
Good.
Yeah, well, good night, man.
What a great day, huh?
Come here. Love you.
[MOUTHS]
Come on.
- [MOUTHS] So hot.
DEX: Good night, Marcus.
Night, you two.
- Have fun.
- Good night.
[SIGHS]
[RACHEL CLEARS THROAT]
Alone at last.
MARCUS:
Here we go. Yeah.
DARCY:
Oh, Dex.
Dex.
[DARCY MOANING]
[TELEVISION STOPS]
- Is that...?
- It's a cat.
Oh, that was no cat.
I'm really digging the ambience
in this house.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Hey. Hey.
- Oh.
- It's so, like, crazy out there.
- Is it?
Um, do you think maybe I could, uh,
could sleep in here? In this room?
No. Nope. Nope.
Because it's...
Claire, I'm...
I'm really sorry. I should've talked
to you about this before.
I'm just... I can tell you from in there.
Um...
I think I'm gay.
That came out wrong. I'm definitely gay.
I'm really gay. I'm just figuring it out.
- Oh, my God.
- This weekend's been a lot.
I'm a little... Feeling vulnerable,
excited, liberated. Things...
Phew. Got a lot going on.
All these things I'm dealing with,
it's just...
There's not enough room for all of it
and you.
- Okay.
- You know?
- So...
- Okay.
All right. Thanks for being cool with it.
I accept.
- You accept what now?
- I accept the challenge.
I accept the challenge
of being your partner in this journey.
No. You're not getting it.
I don't need you as a partner.
I need another partner.
I need, like, a guy partner.
Like, dudes, maybe a lot of them.
Yes. We're gonna work through this.
There's no working through it.
It's not a curable thing.
This I got.
- We start tomorrow.
- We're not... What are we starting?
- Yeah.
- What? Claire. Claire!
DARCY:
Yeah.
Yeah! Yeah!
[DARCY MOANING AND SHOUTING]
- Well, I'm out of here.
DARCY: What?
You're leaving?
- No.
- My boss called. I have to go in.
Tell him you can't. What an ass.
Ass face.
- I know.
- Will you make her stay?
Rachel, you really should stay.
You're gonna miss them shooting
another porno.
You are obviously
still so in love with me.
[IN MOCKING VOICE]
Obviously.
Do we have the number for a taxi?
I need to get to the Jitney.
It's okay.
I could take you.
Yeah. Honey will take you.
Well, there you go.
You don't really have to go, do you?
I'm sorry. Can we, um...?
Can we just forget this happened?
Okay.
We'll forget it happened.
Good. Why did it happen?
Why did you kiss me?
Yeah...
[STAMMERING]
We shouldn't...
You were having wedding jitters.
And I was emotional
about turning 30.
- We were both really drunk.
- I wasn't that drunk.
What?
I wasn't that drunk.
- I'm sorry. I shouldn't even...
- No, it was just a mistake.
It was a big mistake.
Yeah, you know what?
It was, ha, a big mistake.
So how was the rest of the weekend?
I just had the best time
with your boyfriend, Marco.
- Marcus.
- Doesn't matter.
Everybody was okay with me leaving?
You know, Darcy?
Dex? Anybody say anything?
Well, we all had a good cry, but then...
No. No one cared. Why?
Nothing.
I'm having dinner with Darcy.
She said it was important.
It's important?
Oh, my God, should I be there?
Ha.
WOMAN:
Oh, that's great.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
MAN:
Just because we didn't...
Rachel is here.
Oh. Rach.
- Rach, we're back here.
MAN: A bit short.
- Hi.
Do you wanna sit down?
No, that's okay. I just... I thought that
we were having dinner alone, Darce.
DARCY: Right.
- So did I.
We're not. There's something the three
of us need to talk about that's important.
Let me get a chair. Can I steal this?
Scoot over just a smidge. Thank you.
Okay.
There's something going on here,
and I think we all know what it is.
I know there's something going on.
I've been noticing this for a while.
And I read in Cosmopolitan magazine toda...
Well, I skimmed it.
And it said it's normal for the best friend
and the fiancé to be...
...upset about losing the attention
of the bride.
That is what's going on here, right?
Actually...
- Guilty.
DEX: Yeah.
- That's it. That's it.
- Okay, all right. Let's get over it now.
Let's move on from this,
because there are no third wheels.
I love you both.
WOMAN: Thank you.
MAN: You're welcome.
Yes, thank you for dinner.
So did you and Marcus do it?
DEX: Darcy.
DARCY: Heh-heh-heh.
It's a legitimate question.
Did you?
- Tell me.
- No.
Was he a good kisser at least?
- Will you leave her alone?
- Come on.
Shush. This is between me
and my best girlfriend.
Well?
- Was he?
- Hmm?
I knew it. I knew it. Will you tell Dex
he doesn't know you at all?
He was like, "She's not into him.
Why would she be into him?"
I just...
- I think you two are different. That's all.
- So?
So what? We're different.
If people fell in love based on similarities,
the two of you would be a couple.
DEX:
I'm gonna get a taxi.
- Okay.
- Meet me up front.
DARCY:
Are you gonna leave me?
Okay. Maid of honor favor.
You have to see this '90s cover band
with me tomorrow night.
For the wedding.
You have to. It's the only time
they're playing and Dex loves the band.
- I'm slammed at work.
- Promised him I'd go.
He's working. You're coming. Please?
You have way better taste than me.
Than I. It's "than I."
- You have better taste than I.
- Than I do.
Sounds weird.
Fine. Ahem.
When do I ever say no to you?
[SINGING]
How's it gonna be
When you don't know me anymore?
Hey. Where are you?
Oh, something came up.
RACHEL:
Wait, you're not coming?
Well, I... Ow!
Um, why don't you just listen to a couple
songs and call me after? I gotta go.
How's it gonna be
When you don't know me anymore?
How's it gonna be?
[CROWD CHEERING]
[BAND PLAYING COUNTING CROWS'
"ROUND HERE"]
Step out the front door
Like a ghost into the fog
Where no one notices the contrast
Of white on white
In between the moon and you
Angels get a better view
I can't believe she sent you here.
- It's fine.
- No.
This is not fine.
How come you never told me
how you felt in law school?
Dex, I never should have
said anything. I'm...
I just wish I would've known.
What do you mean?
Rachel, you were all I ever thought about
in law school.
Did you really not know that?
Why are you saying this to me?
- Rachel...
- Wait, don't.
- Please, don't.
- Rachel.
This is not wedding jitters. It never was.
I just...
I can't stop thinking about you...
...and I don't know what to do.
Rachel, look at me.
Look at me.
If you feel the same way about me,
tell me now.
Please.
Just tell me now.
I can't.
It's too late.
SINGER:
We all look the same
I do feel the same way.
I wish I didn't.
But I do.
DEX [ON RECORDING]: Hey. I can't stop
thinking about what just happened.
God, this is crazy.
But I just wanna make sure you come
to the Hamptons this weekend.
I, um, hope to see you there. Okay.
CLAIRE:
Lunchtime!
- Hey.
- How are you?
- I'm good. How are you?
DARCY:
Ha-ha-ha. Hi.
- I, uh, forgot something.
DARCY: Ugh.
- What a dramatic day.
DEX: It is.
Oh. Heh-heh-heh.
Why are you wearing that?
What? Why shouldn't gays have
the same rights as we do?
I'm gonna go grab a beer.
Do you guys want anything?
I'll have a beer.
I agree, I just...
Hey, Rach.
I'm sorry about that.
Uh, I was just thinking...
No peppers, right, baby?
- When did you get here?
- Uh, this morning.
I didn't invite you back another weekend.
So why are you here?
Because I love you
and I can't stand to be away from you.
And, also, my apartment flooded.
Really? It flooded? That's so weird.
I don't care.
- Darcy.
DARCY: That's crazy.
Be nice to him. He's going through
something very difficult.
Thank you. Well, no, it was just
the apartment flooding is the only thing.
[GIGGLING]
MARCUS:
I think I need a wet nap.
You do.
MARCUS:
Good spread.
Spaghetti.
We're allowed to have guests, right?
Is there any vodka?
DEX:
Mom, don't worry.
Yeah, no, it shouldn't be a problem.
Okay, well, I'll call you tomorrow.
It's all gonna be fine, Mom.
I love you too.
That your mom?
Is she not doing well again?
She's actually getting better.
She's so excited about the wedding.
Right. Ahem.
You know, when I was a kid...
...and her depression got really bad,
my father made sure he wasn't around...
...so I'd just try to cheer her up.
The worst part was...
...I actually was afraid that if I couldn't
make her happy, I'd lose her.
That's a good reason to be afraid.
DARCY: Dex! FedEx! It's our proofs
for our wedding invites! Come see!
I'm sorry we haven't had any time to talk.
Nice jeans, dude.
Nice hair, bro.
MARCUS: You wanna go
dip your toes in the water with me?
I think she's asleep. Or dead.
MARCUS:
Well, I'm gonna go.
DEX: Something tells me you're not kidding.
DARCY: I'm not.
[DEX CHUCKLING UNEASILY]
Ha-ha-ha.
That's, like, the fakest laugh.
What's wrong with you lately?
I'm sorry. I'm just a little tense.
Tense.
I love you, baby,
even when you're tense.
What are you doing?
What do you mean?
What am I doing?
Don't even think about it.
What did I say, huh?
Darcy, you're so dead.
[SHOUTING AND LAUGHING]
[MISS EIGHTY 6'S "CAME TO PARTY"
PLAYING ON STEREO]
When I need to get away
I turn it up
I let it play
Let the DJ show me the way of the player
Until I'm feeling as good as
Oh, oh, oh
We came here to party
- My mom didn't know what I was doing.
- Oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh
We came here to party
- Get away from me.
- Oh, oh, oh
Oh, oh, oh
So I built this tiny little splint
for his tiny little broken leg.
And I had to do CPR on him. You couldn't
push hard. You had to just blow it...
- I need him. I'm sorry.
- Oh!
Oh, God! I need you.
Aah! Yeah!
[BUBBA SPARXXX'S "MS. NEW BOOTY"
PLAYING]
Bring it back to me
Hit the players' club
For about a month or two
Yeah, Rachel!
I found you
Ms. New Booty
Do it, girl!
I'm here for you, baby! Whatever you need!
Whatever you need, baby!
Put a tan on it
Then see what it do
Get it right
Get it right, get it tight
DARCY:
Oh, yeah.
[MOUTHS]
No.
Give him your back. Give him your back.
Girl, I don't need you
But you need me
Take it off, let it flop
Shake it freely
[SHOUTS]
I let 'em tell itself
And you ain't gotta sell, girl, it sell itself
Like nothing else
Yeah, I'm a country boy
Yeah.
Ain't life grand?
Live it up, daddy
[SHOUTING]
MARCUS:
Yeah, get in there.
[GROANING]
Are you all right?
Yeah, no, I just think I pulled something.
Your vagina?
No, I didn't pull my vagina.
- Ha-ha-ha. I'm just kidding.
- I just pulled near my vagina.
She's fine, she's fine.
Now I know how many flowers it takes
for you to call me back when you're mad.
Sorry. It just...
Look, I know this weekend wasn't
what we had hoped it would be.
RACHEL:
No, it wasn't just this weekend.
It's watching you with her.
And knowing what we're doing.
What are we doing? It's just...
It's hard to see you with her, Dex.
I can't believe I'm saying these things.
Rachel, what we need
is some time alone.
Just the two of us.
You know what,
next weekend is the Fourth of July.
I'll say I have to work.
And it'll be like a time-out.
A time-out to see what this is...
...without anyone or anything around us.
What do you say?
Gotta go. Call you back.
Sorry. Started without you. Good God.
Who are those from?
- Uh, Marcus.
- Really? Because they look expensive.
- Should we go?
- Yes, we should.
And that was him
on the phone too, right?
- You doing good?
- Should we go?
Yes, we should. There's a note.
It's private. Come on.
Come on.
I was just gonna check his spelling.
- Heh.
- Rachel.
Rachel, who are the flowers from?
Do you want me to guess?
Please don't.
Please say something.
I don't know what you want me to say.
I mean, I guess I'm impressed, actually.
I didn't think you had it in you.
Him either.
It's nothing to be proud of.
Oh, my God, it's terrible.
Why? Nobody's married yet.
And, besides, sometimes good people
do bad things, right?
And, hey, I could see you guys together.
So, what's the plan?
You gonna stay here,
spend Fourth of July weekend with him?
He wants to spend some time together
to see what this thing is.
And what do you want?
I want not to want him.
Is that true?
I don't know.
Well, I can tell you this.
If the roles were reversed...
...Darcy wouldn't even hesitate.
RACHEL:
Darcy, I really have to get back to work.
What about these?
Did you hear me?
- Can I read you something?
- Can you read it fast?
- It's my vows.
- I have to be...
Sit.
Ready?
"Dex.
Dex.
Our love is like the ocean.
Endless and deep, always flowing."
It's awful? You hate it?
I don't hate it. It's lovely.
Oceans don't flow. Rivers flow.
See, you're better at this than I am.
Help me.
Right now?
- Come on.
- Okay.
Well, forget the ocean.
Forget the ocean.
Uh, tell him that...
...when you're with him,
everything makes sense.
Right?
And he makes you giddy.
And...
...uh, tell him that...
...he makes you the person you want to be,
instead of the person you are.
And that...
...uh, the idea of life without him is...
...not only unbearable, it's unimaginable.
DARCY:
Oh, my God.
- Ha, ha. Hi.
- What's up?
DARCY: How are you?
I haven't seen you guys forever.
- How's it going? What's happening?
WOMAN 1: I know.
- Who's that?
DARCY: Oh, that's Rachel.
You remember Rachel.
My best friend from forever.
I know, I'm getting...
I'm getting shoes for my wedding.
- Can you believe it?
WOMAN 1: No!
DARCY:
Yes.
DJ [ON RADIO]: If you're driving to the
beach, I hope you packed your patience...
...because the roads are jammed, folks...
...as New York City does its annual
disappearing act for the Fourth of July.
[DOORBELL BUZZES]
- Who is it?
- It's Dex.
Hi.
Come on up.
You know what,
I'm gonna come down there.
I can come up.
No, no, no. I'm coming down.
Wow.
Sorry. I'm... Ugh, I'm just a...
- A wreck?
- Heh.
Yes. Heh-heh-heh.
- So shall we go?
- Yeah.
Wow. It really is deserted.
Yeah, it's just us.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
- Is that her? You can answer if you want.
- No.
You know what,
I'm gonna turn this thing off.
I'm sorry. I'm not... I just...
I'm not, uh, really comfortable.
No, it's okay...
...because this is already the best
weekend I've had in a long time.
Do you remember that night when
we were studying for our Torts final?
And you were laughing so hard?
You know exactly what I'm talking about,
don't you?
Yeah.
Didn't you feel what I was feeling?
I did.
At least I was hoping
that's what you were feeling.
Yeah, but, then,
that night when I met Darcy...
...I actually thought you set us up.
I just didn't think someone like you...
...could ever like someone like me.
[CROWD CHATTERING AND LAUGHING]
[SIGHS]
That's a nice way to wake up.
Good morning.
I wanna tell you something.
Tell me something.
I love you.
I love you, Rachel.
I think I always have loved you.
Imagine I'm holding your hand
right now.
RACHEL:
Okay.
- You're blushing.
MAN: Dexter.
Is that...?
- That's my parents.
- Who's that?
I wonder what he's doing.
He's not supposed to be in town.
Oh, my God. I should go.
No, don't.
- Dex.
- Stay.
Well, this is a surprise. Heh, heh.
Dex, what are you doing here?
We thought you were in the Hamptons.
- I had to work.
- Mm. Had to work.
Mom, Dad, you remember Rachel White.
Oh, my gosh, yes.
- Hello, dear.
- Hi. Good to see you.
BRIDGET: Guess who was asleep in the box
with his head on the pillow next to Buddy.
Little Dex did not come out of that box
for two days. Ha-ha-ha.
Dexter, come. Let's walk.
- Excuse us, ladies.
- Excuse us.
Mom, thank you for thoroughly
embarrassing me. Appreciate that.
My pleasure.
[CHUCKLES]
Your mother doesn't like me drinking
during the daytime.
Well, she looks good. She seems happy.
She sure does.
I don't think I've ever seen her so happy.
Must be the wedding.
Cheers.
Dad, can I ask you a question?
Have you ever gone down a road...
...I mean, far down it and...
And wondered maybe
if it wasn't what you want?
What you want.
The problem with that expression is...
...it's frequently at odds
with what's right.
Isn't it?
Now, whatever's going on
between you and that girl, you stop it. Now.
- But, Dad...
- No.
You know what I'm talking about.
That's not the kind of people we are.
Yes, sir.
Your mom is a sweetheart.
Your dad...
I see where the strong silent thing
comes from.
Is everything okay?
Yeah. Yeah, I'm just tired.
Do you wanna come up?
I do, but, uh, Darcy texted
and they're on their way back, so...
- Oh. Yeah.
- I should...
Rachel, just so you know...
...what I said this morning...
Yeah?
I meant it.
That's what he said?
It's complicated, Ethan.
Don't.
Don't what? Rachel, it's not complicated.
He's being a dick.
To be honest, you're being stupid.
- Whoa. I'm being stupid?
- Yes.
He's stringing you along. And the
worst part is you're just letting him.
How long are you gonna let this happen?
His wedding day?
- His first anniversary?
- He's not even married yet, Ethan.
Exactly, Rachel.
He's not even married yet.
Which means he can change his situation
anytime he wants.
But he hasn't, has he?
Have you even seen him, have you even
talked to him since the Fourth of July?
Rachel, when did you become one
of these women that just waits?
And is still waiting.
I don't exactly see you
living your happily ever after.
Maybe you're right. But at least I try.
At least I take chances.
When? When is the last time
you took a chance?
Two days ago, when I decided
to move to London.
- What?
- Yeah. I'm moving there in the fall.
When were you gonna tell me?
Um, today. Just now, actually,
before you yelled at me.
There's a publisher
who's really interested in my book.
She wants to work on it.
Ethan, that's incredible.
Hey, you wanna give me
a killer going-away present?
- What?
- Tell your boyfriend to make a decision.
MARCUS:
Nice, Justin.
I'm okay.
Oh, nice one!
Hey.
Hi.
MARCUS:
So I'm lying in bed last night...
...thinking about you,
wondering if I should jerk off or not.
But the thing was, I couldn't get it up.
And that never happens, by the way.
Just FYI. Never happens to me.
And it wasn't because
I don't think you're hot. I do.
I totally think you're hot.
I just feel...
I don't know.
I associate you now with failure.
[RACHEL LAUGHS]
How do you make the most hideous things
sound charming?
- That's a compliment, right?
- Sure. Ha-ha-ha.
So how big you think it is?
Excuse me?
Oh, my God.
The house. You think it'll be big?
What house?
The house that Dex's old man
is buying for him and Darcy.
What, Darcy didn't tell you?
Yeah, yeah.
My dad is Dex's dad's realtor.
They're... Right now,
they're out in Westchester...
...looking for $2 million mansions.
Must be nice, huh?
DARCY: Gorgeous.
REALTOR: Oak floors throughout.
This is the study.
DARCY:
You look good in here, babe.
REALTOR: Hand-cut
Vermont fieldstone. Watch your step.
Natural light to the left.
Southern exposure to the right.
So how many kids
you planning to have?
As many as Dex's father tells me to have.
- This is amazing.
- Isn't it great?
DARCY: We love you so much.
Thank you, thank you, thank you.
Hmm. So Dex?
What do you think?
It's great.
[CHUCKLES]
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
- Hello.
- Hey, you little tart.
Marcus just texted me.
He said you guys saw each other today.
So spill the beans. Circumcised?
When were you gonna tell me
about looking at houses?
How did you know? Oh, Marcus's dad.
Um, it wasn't, like, a little secret.
Wait till you see this house
that we loved.
Oh, my God. We loved it.
We haven't decided anything yet.
- Oh, am I on speaker?
- Hi, Rach.
Hey, Dex.
You like the house too?
Uh, yeah, it was... It was okay.
DARCY:
What are you talking about?
- We loved it.
- That's great. I gotta go. But, Darce?
- Yeah.
- Yes, Marcus is circumcised.
Opposing counsel gave me
a two-week extension to respond.
Yes, I'll hold.
[CELL PHONE BUZZES]
[WOMEN CHEERING AND LAUGHING]
RACHEL:
We only have one night.
DARCY:
Oh, I know. Me too.
CLAIRE: Bye, Rachel.
- Night. Bye.
- Good night. Good night, Darcy.
- Air, air.
Darce, where...? Where are you going?
You know what?
I'm gonna sleep over at Rachel's tonight.
Oh, come on. We haven't had
a sleepover in, like, forever.
And, plus, Dex is gonna be out
with all his bachelor buddies all night.
Oh.
Okay, bye.
DARCY:
Love you.
So, what's going on in Marcus-land?
You gonna marry him?
Stop it.
What? Marcus isn't marriage material?
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
Who is calling at this ungodly hour?
- Who is it?
- Hello?
Rachel, it's me.
Please, don't hang up.
- Rachel.
- [WHISPERING] Who is it?
I miss you. That's all I want to say.
Um...
Look, can I come up? I just wanna talk.
[IN NORMAL VOICE]
Who is it?
- Ethan.
- Ethan?
Ethan? No, it's Dex.
I'm downstairs.
- Can I see you?
- Wait, you're downstairs?
No! No, no, no! Darcy's here, so...
He's downstairs and he wants to come up
at 3 in the morning?
Um, I'm gonna...
Oh, my God.
- Ew.
- What?
Ew! Ew!
Oh, my God. You are having a fling
with Ethan?
Oh, my God, you're having an affair
with Ethan.
- I gotta go.
- He's downstairs.
- No, he's... Oh, shit.
DARCY: Ainsley?
Oh, Ainsley! Way to go, honey! I didn't
know you had it in you, you little shithead!
RACHEL: Close the window.
DARCY: You little tart.
Oh, my God. Why didn't you tell me?
Um, you know, it just happened.
It just happened.
Well, we're gonna celebrate
your just happening right now.
[SALT-N-PEPA'S "PUSH IT" PLAYING]
What are you doing? Oh, come on.
- It's your favorite thing in the world.
- Darcy, no. No.
- Not tonight.
- Sixth grade, second place.
RACHEL:
Not now.
We should've won.
Get over here right now.
I suck.
Five, six, seven, eight!
[SINGING IN UNISON]
Ooh, baby, baby
Baby, baby
Ooh, baby
Salt-N-Pepa's here, and we're in effect
Want you to push it back
Coolin' by day, then at night
Workin' up a sweat
Come on, girls, let's go show the guys
That we know how to become
Number one in a hot party show
Now, push it
Push it good
Push it real good
[DARCY CHEERS]
Push it good
Push it real good
[BOTH LAUGHING]
People who were friends as kids
almost always lose touch eventually.
I'm glad we didn't.
Me too.
And we never will, right?
No.
I don't think there's anybody
who knows me like you.
Not even Dex does.
Not like you do.
It's like you totally accept me.
Darce, why are you saying all this?
I don't know.
But when you're getting married, you start
thinking about all your big moments.
And you're in all of mine.
Me too.
Darcy?
[DARCY GRUNTS]
I have to tell you something.
Something I've done.
Rachel...
...I love you.
And I would never let
anyone hurt you, ever.
And you wouldn't let
anyone hurt me, right?
No.
DARCY:
Rach.
RACHEL: Hmm.
- Rach. Oh, God.
Good morning.
Do you think I should marry Dex?
What?
No, I mean it.
Do you think this is a good idea?
I mean, nobody knows me like you.
And you sort of know Dex too.
And you're much smarter than I am.
I mean, book-smarter, anyway.
But what I'm trying to say is...
...you're not gonna let me
do anything dumb, are you?
Darcy.
No, I mean it, because...
Ugh, I can really do...
I can really do dumb shit.
Because I do love him. I do.
And I know what he sees in me.
What?
You know what I mean.
He's never met anybody like me...
...because I don't let stuff get to me.
Which is true, because I always
assume everything'll just work out.
And I guess it's because it always has.
So I make him lighter, and he kind of...
He makes me heavier, somehow.
In a good way.
Does that make sense?
It does.
And what you said in your vows...
...I feel that.
Especially when you said...
Um...
What exactly did you say again?
- Life without him would be unimaginable.
- Yes. And it would.
But is that enough for a marriage?
I think...
Yeah?
You should marry him.
I love you so much.
I love you, Darcy.
You are the best girlfriend in the world.
Ever.
So it's okay that I kind of cheated on him
a little bit?
What?
I... Just barely. Heh. Once.
- With whom?
- Well, he was a guy from work.
And it was nothing.
You know me, it was just sex.
And I felt terrible, so that's good.
Right?
Plus, Dex hasn't had sex with me
since before the Fourth of July.
Ugh. I'm so happy I got this off my chest.
I hate feeling guilty. I hate it.
I feel so much better now.
Oh, my God.
So when are you gonna tell him?
Do you want me to tell him?
I would love to tell him.
It's none of your business.
I told Darcy to marry him. I'm bowing out.
She just told you she's cheating.
You want your opportunity, take it.
Ethan, stop.
I don't really get it.
I don't get how you let her win all the time.
Wow.
Oh. No, "wow" nothing. If the tables
were turned, you think she'd let you win?
Will you stop? What is it with you two?
Why do you hate her so much?
What? I don't hate her.
I hate the fact that you yield to her
at every turn.
So why do you do it?
Why do you let her win?
Because that's what Darcy does.
Darcy wins. She always has.
She sees things, she wants them,
she gets them.
Ethan, she got into Notre Dame.
Do you know how hard it is to get
into Notre Dame? It is impossible.
But she did. And with her grades?
You're kidding, right?
You're not kidding?
Did you see her acceptance letter?
- What are you talking about?
- Did you see the acceptance letter? I didn't.
Remember when she asked
Michael Jordan to prom?
They sent a letter
saying he couldn't make it.
How many times did she show us
that letter?
I could recite it right now.
That was a rejection.
Do you really think
if she were accepted...
...that she wouldn't make us
memorize that letter too?
Rachel, come on.
She never got into Notre Dame.
Rachel. Okay, look, I get it. You're in
a tough spot because you love him.
But you gotta do something about it.
He's a coward. If he breaks your heart,
I'm gonna take a swing at him.
- Then I'm gonna let him beat me up.
- I gotta go. I'm late.
I know! Rachel, that's the point.
Be late. Better yet, quit.
At least it would be a decision.
Rachel!
You're all going to hell anyway, so you
might as well do something for yourself.
For once.
Rachel, you deserve to be happy.
Then butt out.
That would make me happy.
I'll figure it out on my own.
Oh. Oh, that's great.
Let me know how that goes.
MARCUS:
Serve is up.
All right.
DARCY: Whoo!
DEX: Go! Yes!
Five-zip. We're killing you, Rachel.
Isn't that the truth?
It is, right?
MARCUS: I'm really competitive,
so I need you to focus.
You gotta pop it, Rach. Pop it.
- It's a backhand.
- Serve's up. Here we go.
Go, Dex, do it.
- Aah! Oops.
MARCUS: Yeah!
Who doesn't love badminton?
Have you ever even played
a sport in your life?
I think she's calling you gay, son.
- I heard it.
DARCY: Hey, Romeo.
Why don't you get up off your ass
and come help out your Juliet?
- What?
- Darcy.
Your secret lover. Wink, wink.
RACHEL: Darcy.
- Rachel shared your secret. Oops.
Oh. Oh, wow. We're sharing secrets now.
See, I didn't know we were at that part
of the day, but I am in.
- Ethan.
- This sounds like fun.
- Give me this. Let's do this.
- The novelist wants to play.
I got an idea.
How about it's us versus you guys...
...but we'll do a secret for every point?
- Love that.
- Ethan. Stop.
Gotta do this. Here we go.
- Don't.
- I love it so much, I'll serve first.
All right? Hit me, Dex.
Dex, hit me.
His name rhymes with sex.
You know that?
I knew that.
ETHAN:
I'm so happy to be here.
Ready?
[RACKETS THWACKING]
Yes, do it again.
Whoo! Yeah! Yippee! We got a point. I got
a secret. Rachel and Ethan are having sex.
- Ugh.
- What?
DARCY:
I was there the other night...
...and somebody showed up
for a little booty call.
I knew it. I called it, I knew it.
What? You told me you were gay!
That makes more sense.
I think that things
are getting a tad competitive.
- Why don't we just take it down a notch?
- No. Honey, serve.
Rachel's right. Why don't we...?
No, no, no. Let's do this.
- Serve it.
ETHAN: Do it.
DEX: Just...
- You know what?
Let's keep telling secrets.
DARCY: Come on.
ETHAN: Serve it!
DARCY:
Yeah. Serve it, Dex.
ETHAN:
Serve it, Dex.
DARCY:
Serve it.
Yep. Easy.
[GRUNTING]
Watch out.
- Excuse me.
- Aah!
- Rachel!
- Jesus!
ETHAN:
Come on, Dex!
Okay. Yeah, really?
I got it.
- There you go. Yeah. All right.
- Ethan, stop.
No. Let's hear a secret.
Rach, why don't you do this one?
Come on, guys.
I think we're done here.
- No, Dex. We're not.
- Ethan, stop it!
- What is going on?
- If she's not gonna tell you, I will.
Okay, here we go.
[SHOUTS]
[MARCUS LAUGHING]
Shit.
What the hell was that?
Me? You broke my nose.
I'm sure I didn't break your nose.
God. And what is all this
about us having sex?
Jesus, Rachel, just leave me out
of your goddamn soap opera.
No one asked you to get involved.
Really? So why have I been listening
to this bullshit all summer?
Rachel, do something, because this
is just pathetic. But you know what?
At the end of the day,
you deserve each other.
He's never gonna do anything.
You're never gonna ask him to,
and let's be honest...
...you and I both know that, even if you did,
she will never let you have him.
- You're an asshole!
- Yeah, maybe I am!
But I'm the only asshole here
who gives a shit about you!
[MELLOW POP MUSIC
PLAYING ON STEREO]
DARCY: I wanna know
what it is you're not telling me.
DEX: There's nothing to tell.
If you wanna know something...
DARCY: I'm sorry, that's weird
and bizarre. And I'm asking you.
I don't wanna talk outside.
He's not really gay, is he?
No.
Uh, Claire, we're not
having an affair, either.
That was just a...
It was...
He's never gonna love me, is he?
I don't think so.
Least I tried. Right?
Yeah.
Ethan's...
Like I said, I think it's weird too.
DARCY:
Whatever.
- You told Ethan?
- No. He guessed.
Darcy's upset. She keeps asking me
what happened on the beach today.
You know what?
Work it out with her, Dex.
Well...
Rachel.
Rachel, what am I supposed to do?
Forget what you're supposed to do, Dex.
Do what you wanna do.
Live your own life
the way you want to live it.
You wanna teach? Teach.
You don't wanna be the man
who lives in the big house you hate?
Then don't be him.
Or do. Just decide.
[CROWD CHATTERING]
[DEX & DARCY LAUGHING]
- That was awesome.
- What?
Nothing. You've got a great laugh.
Wait. When did this happen
that you were like, "I wanna be a lawyer"?
Who says, "You know what I wanna
do when I grow up? I wanna be a lawyer."
I'm sorry. I'm gonna take off.
Where are you going?
Come on, sit down.
I'm beat. This week has done me in.
I'll take you home.
- No, you don't have to.
- No, it's fine. I'd like to.
Stop it. You two stay. I'm exhausted.
- Darcy, I will call you in the morning.
- Okay.
Dex, you were incredible this week.
I owe you one.
DEX:
Rachel.
Rach.
Hey. What's up?
I just... I just wanted to make sure
you were okay.
Okay with...?
Well, with this.
Oh, yeah. Totally.
No, Darcy's fantastic.
And, hey, you never know where
it might lead, right?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, good night.
Good night.
[THUNDER BOOMING]
RACHEL:
Dex!
- Dex!
- What's wrong?
I shouldn't have left.
- No, it's okay. I understand.
- No. Six years ago.
That night. I shouldn't have left.
It wasn't okay what happened.
- None of it was okay.
- Rachel...
No, no, no, let me say it.
Cancel the wedding.
Tell her you can't marry her.
I love you. I've always loved you.
And I should've told you a long time ago,
but I'm telling you now...
...before it's too late,
before it's really too late.
You're not the only one
who hasn't been living his life.
I haven't either, but I wanna live it now.
And I wanna live it with you.
I can't, Rachel.
I'm so sorry.
I can't.
[TELEPHONE RINGING]
ETHAN [ON RECORDING]: Hey, it's Ethan.
Leave a message. Cheers.
[MOUTHS]
I'm sorry.
Wow, thank God you said sorry first,
because that would've been embarrassing.
- Heh-heh-heh. Hi.
- Hi.
- Wow. Are you trying to make me cry?
- Heh, heh.
Hey, so totally not a big deal,
but, um, why are you here?
I, uh, just needed to get away.
This close to the wedding?
Darcy must be freaking out.
You're where?
It is one week before my wedding,
Rachel, and you're in London?
RACHEL:
I know.
Um, I, uh...
I just need some time.
You're my maid of honor.
- And you needed time?
- It's Rachel?
DARCY: Are you kidding?
- I, um...
Rachel, Rachel, the band you picked sucks.
The caterer is a nightmare.
You need to get back here right now.
Right now.
- Darcy...
- Right now!
No.
Wow.
What the fuck?
Do you need me
to be your maid of honor?
Oh, my God.
I can do it.
I have dreamed about Darcy getting married
almost my whole life.
But I don't know how to stand next to them
while they promise those things.
While she says my words.
I still say you should've
told Dex she was cheating.
No. And, besides,
I didn't want him to pick me by default.
I wanna be someone's first choice.
Yeah.
You are.
No, I know what you're saying.
I'm not his first choice.
Maybe you're someone's first choice.
What?
You never wondered about me?
I don't know how to say this. Um...
God, Rachel, I like you.
I've always liked you.
And when another guy came in the picture,
I liked you even more.
You are home for me.
Wow. That sounded crazy. Heh.
Wow. And that's probably what all this is.
I mean, it's probably just crazy. It's not...
It's not love.
Even though it kind of feels like it is.
Don't worry, I...
My love's not really
the overwhelming kind.
Jesus, when I'm in love, I, uh, drink rosé
and watch Remains of the Day. So...
I don't know, Rachel.
Maybe it's just that I...
Maybe it's just that I miss you.
But I think you fell in love
with someone else.
And I think you still are.
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, damn it.
- I knew I should've gone for Claire.
- Ha-ha-ha.
- You still have a pump in every color.
Yeah, every night,
I put on my princess outfit.
[INAUDIBLE DIALOGUE]
[DOOR OPENS]
Oh, good, you're up.
Hey, Ethan?
I'm going back.
Yeah, well, I think you and I both knew
you weren't gonna miss that wedding.
No, I'm not going back for her.
This isn't who I am.
I can't do whatever I want
and not care if I hurt anybody.
Besides, Darcy didn't do anything wrong.
I did.
Rachel, I can't hear this "Daddy hits
me because he loves me" stuff anymore.
No, this isn't me
being pathetic anymore.
I have always thought it was Darcy
who took things from me...
...but really it was just me
who was giving everything up to her.
And Darcy may be...
...whatever Darcy is. I don't know what
Darcy is, but she is my best friend.
And I want to be there for her.
So I'm going to that wedding.
Then you win.
How did you, uh...?
Called your office.
I wanted to be here when you got home.
You have to go.
I can't do this anymore.
She deserves better. So do you. So do I.
I called off the wedding.
I told her I couldn't marry her.
When?
Couple hours ago.
What did she say?
What did she do?
She's pretty upset.
Mostly about what people
are gonna think.
Then she threw a few things.
Did you tell her about us?
She asked if there was someone else.
I said no.
Because I'm not sure yet if there still is.
I don't know what to say.
I don't expect anything.
I don't deserve to expect anything.
I was afraid of hurting people.
And I just want to thank you...
...for finally asking
for what you wanted...
...and for helping me to do the same.
I want to apologize...
...for being such a moron
outside that bar six years ago...
...and outside the Jetty last week...
...where I made the worst decision
of my life.
Basically, you and I shouldn't have
conversations outside bars anymore.
[BANGING ON DOOR]
DARCY:
Rachel. Open up.
- Darcy.
DARCY: Yes. Open the door.
How did you get into the building?
DARCY: There was a pizza guy and he
let me in. Who cares? Open the door.
I need to talk to you!
Yeah, um...
- I'm just changing.
DARCY: Ugh!
I've seen your ass. Open the door.
I called off the wedding.
- You did.
- Well...
...technically, Dex said it first,
but I was thinking the same thing.
Wow. I think I need some air
to process that. Wanna go for a walk?
No. I need to sit down.
- Before I tell you what I came to tell you...
- Okay.
...I just wanna say that I'm not
the only one of us...
...who's being dishonest here.
- What have I been dishonest about?
- Please.
Give me a little credit, Rachel.
Claire told me you were lying
about Ethan.
I know for an absolute fact
that you are not sleeping with Marcus.
So, what, you're making up stories
to make me jealous?
You know I'm more sexual than you.
I always have been.
I wasn't e... And there was never a...
How did you know
I never slept with Marcus?
Well, um, you said he was circumcised.
- Okay.
- And he is not.
Marcus is the guy you slept with?
That's what I wanted to tell you.
- Can you get me some water?
- Wait, when?
When did you sleep with him?
Fourth of July.
Well, we were both lonely,
and we were both drunk.
[FLOOR CREAKS NEARBY]
And we both felt awful afterwards.
I mean, we promised right then and there
that we would never do it again.
And we broke that promise,
because we did it again.
A couple times.
You slept with him more than once?
Oh, God. Marcus and I have a...
Sit.
Okay, Marcus and I have an extremely
powerful connection.
It's like...
...genetic.
Genetic.
Chemical?
Whatever. I'm not a word person.
Anyway, what I'm trying to say is,
I'm gonna need you now more than ever.
I took a test.
You're pregnant?
I am.
It's crazy.
I mean... And good.
I mean, Marcus has been amazing.
He is not what you think.
Yes, yes, he's a caveman,
a total caveman.
But one time, he made a little splint...
...for this little chipmunk
with a broken leg.
Is that not the sweetest thing
you've ever heard?
Yeah.
I gotta go. He's downstairs. He's waiting.
But I love you so much.
It's crazy...
...how things work out sometimes, huh?
Bye.
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Is that Dex's jacket?
What is it doing here?
Oh, he just left it at the restaurant.
I must've picked it up.
No.
No, he didn't, because he was
wearing it today, so...
What is it doing here?
Darcy...
Where is he?
Darcy.
Dex?
- Darcy. Please, let's just...
- Dex! Dex?
- Dex?
- Darcy, no!
Dex!
- You liar!
- Are you kidding me?
You told me there was nobody in...
You are pregnant! Are you pretending
you're the wronged party here?
Rachel?
How could you do this to me?
I never wanted to hurt you, Darcy.
I never wanted to hurt you!
- Rachel! How could you do this to me?
- Darcy, I never wanted to hurt you.
I hate you. I hate you.
I hate you.
I never wanna speak to you again! Ever!
Dude, you suck. I'm telling Mom.
Wish me luck, dude.
Hey.
You look good.
I know. Clearly, I'm gonna be one
of those girls who only carries in my belly.
I bought him that shirt.
Darcy, I'm really sorry.
You're really sorry
you slept with my fiancé?
No, I'm sorry I hurt you.
You always were jealous of me.
Ever since I got into Notre Dame.
You're right.
Darcy, I miss you.
Every day.
You know, I'm the happiest I've ever been
in my life...
...so whatever.
I'm glad.
Rachel?
I am, though.
Happy.
Good.
[CELL PHONE RINGING]
Hey. Where are you?
I'll take this.
[BELLS GONGING]
What'd I miss? What did I miss?
Okay, okay.
DARCY:
Ethan.
Ethan?
Ethan!
[English - US - SDH]