1
00:00:00,580 --> 00:00:03,750
AMC臺《行尸走肉》前情提要
Previously on the AMC's The Walking Dead...

2
00:00:06,400 --> 00:00:08,000
-我們不該這樣做  -必須這么做
- We're not supposed to be doing this. - We are.

3
00:00:08,010 --> 00:00:10,510
他竟然用刀砍下了那人的頭
He chopped a guy's head off with a sword.

4
00:00:14,780 --> 00:00:16,230
讓他們上大巴  隨時準備出發  
Get these people on the bus. Be ready to drive.

5
00:00:16,290 --> 00:00:17,940
-我馬上回來  -如果你回不來呢
- I'll be right back. - What if you're not?

6
00:00:17,950 --> 00:00:19,770
貝絲  貝絲在哪
Beth! Where's Beth?

7
00:00:21,330 --> 00:00:22,020
瑪姬
Maggie...

8
00:00:25,070 --> 00:00:26,800
我在找孩子們  讓他們上大巴
I was trying to find the kids to get them on the bus.

9
00:00:26,810 --> 00:00:29,510
我們必須走了  貝絲  必須走了
We got to go, Beth. We got to go.

10
00:00:32,230 --> 00:00:33,600
我知道已經有段日子了
I know it's been a while.

11
00:00:34,290 --> 00:00:35,730
老實說
I'm gonna be honest,

12
00:00:36,190 --> 00:00:37,460
我忘了你
I forgot about you.

13
00:00:39,270 --> 00:00:41,350
離開農場后  我們一直顛沛流離
After the farm, we were always moving.

14
00:00:42,920 --> 00:00:44,220
但是發生了一些事
But something happened.

15
00:00:44,780 --> 00:00:46,320
好事
Something good.

16
00:00:47,040 --> 00:00:47,960
終于發生了
Finally.

17
00:00:49,690 --> 00:00:50,930
我們找到了一座監獄
We found a prison.

18
00:00:53,860 --> 00:00:55,910
爸爸覺得我們可以把它改造成一個家
Daddy thinks that we can make it into a home.

19
00:01:01,060 --> 00:01:03,530
他說我們可以在田里種莊稼
He says we can grow crops in the field,

20
00:01:03,700 --> 00:01:05,670
找到豬和雞
find pigs and chickens,

21
00:01:06,090 --> 00:01:08,190
不再逃跑  不再尋找食物
stop running, stop scavenging.

22
00:01:13,260 --> 00:01:14,950
洛莉快生了
Lori's baby is just about due.

23
00:01:15,920 --> 00:01:17,880
屆時她會需要一個安全的地方
She'll need a safe place when it comes.

24
00:01:33,210 --> 00:01:34,400
對其余人來說
The rest of us,

25
00:01:35,510 --> 00:01:37,800
安全已足夠
we just need a safe place to be.

26
00:01:43,280 --> 00:01:45,870
昨天我在自己的床上醒來
I woke up in my own bed yesterday.

27
00:01:46,580 --> 00:01:49,600
屬于我的房間里的屬于我的床
My own bed in my own room.

28
00:01:50,540 --> 00:01:52,220
但我一直都帶著背包
But I've been keeping my backpack.

29
00:01:53,690 --> 00:01:55,230
把槍放在身邊
Keeping my gun close.

30
00:01:56,600 --> 00:01:58,370
我害怕"我們真的可以待在這里"
I've been afraid to get my hopes up

31
00:01:59,240 --> 00:02:01,050
是個奢望
thinking we can actually stay here.

32
00:02:03,030 --> 00:02:05,660
問題是  我開始擔心
The thing is, I've been starting to get afraid

33
00:02:05,670 --> 00:02:09,260
我變成了驚弓之鳥
that it's easier just to be afraid.

34
00:02:12,560 --> 00:02:15,360
但今早  爸爸說
But this morning Daddy said something.

35
00:02:16,240 --> 00:02:19,100
如果你沒有希望  那活著還有什么意義
If you don't have hope, what's the point of living?

36
00:02:21,630 --> 00:02:24,750
所以我解開包  找出了你
So I unpacked my bag and I found you.

37
00:02:25,450 --> 00:02:27,320
打算再用你記日記
So I'm gonna start writing in you again.

38
00:02:28,460 --> 00:02:29,830
我現在要把這個寫下來
And I'm gonna write this down now

39
00:02:29,830 --> 00:02:32,160
因為你得先寫下愿望
because you should write down wishes

40
00:02:32,160 --> 00:02:33,450
才能實現它們
to make them come true.

41
00:02:35,080 --> 00:02:36,270
我們可以住在這里
We can live here.

42
00:02:39,160 --> 00:02:42,000
我們可以在這里安度余生
We can live here for the rest of our lives.

43
00:02:44,100 --> 00:02:45,440
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0

44
00:02:44,100 --> 00:02:45,440
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172

45
00:02:44,100 --> 00:02:45,440
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35

46
00:02:45,450 --> 00:02:46,120
本字幕由人人影視字幕組翻譯
禁止用作任何商業盈利行為

47
00:02:46,120 --> 00:02:47,370
翻譯  冰藍

48
00:02:48,620 --> 00:02:49,870
翻譯  蘑菇

49
00:02:50,580 --> 00:02:51,790
翻譯  Reginamoon

50
00:02:51,790 --> 00:02:53,210
翻譯  重案組李Sir

51
00:02:53,210 --> 00:02:54,500
翻譯  小飯

52
00:02:54,500 --> 00:02:55,800
翻譯  Marshal同學

53
00:02:55,800 --> 00:02:57,130
翻譯  鳥の森

54
00:03:00,680 --> 00:03:01,930
翻譯   CS小明漫畫家

55
00:03:03,760 --> 00:03:05,010
翻譯/校對  送小孩  衛老哥

56
00:03:05,010 --> 00:03:06,260
校對  Lemony  米小勒

57
00:03:06,640 --> 00:03:07,890
時間軸  濤濤  森の鳥  雪貴人

58
00:03:07,890 --> 00:03:09,140
特效  吉吉

59
00:03:09,770 --> 00:03:11,020
后期  送小哥

60
00:03:11,020 --> 00:03:12,310
總監  送小孩

61
00:03:14,560 --> 00:03:19,140
行尸走肉
第四季  第十集

62
00:03:26,040 --> 00:03:27,540
我們該做點什么
We should do something.

63
00:03:32,660 --> 00:03:34,210
我們得做點什么
We should do something.

64
00:03:38,600 --> 00:03:40,430
我們不是唯一的幸存者
We aren't the only survivors.

65
00:03:42,020 --> 00:03:43,000
不可能
We can't be.

66
00:03:45,180 --> 00:03:47,120
瑞克  米瓊恩  他們可能還活著
Rick, Michonne, they could be out here.

67
00:03:47,950 --> 00:03:50,070
瑪姬和格倫可能逃出了A區
Maggie and Glenn could have made it out of A block.

68
00:03:51,690 --> 00:03:52,750
有可能的
They could've.

69
00:04:02,200 --> 00:04:05,400
你擅長追蹤  你可以找到他們
You're a tracker. You can track.

70
00:04:06,610 --> 00:04:07,490
走啊
Come on.

71
00:04:08,740 --> 00:04:10,960
太陽很快就要升起了  如果我們現在走  還能...
The sun will be up soon. If we head out now, we can--

72
00:04:15,650 --> 00:04:18,240
好的  如果你不找  我自己去
Fine. If you won't track, I will.

73
00:05:09,640 --> 00:05:12,590
可能是盧克的腳印  或者是莫莉的
Could be Luke's. Or Molly's.

74
00:05:13,470 --> 00:05:15,200
不管是誰的  說明他們還活著
Whoever they are, it means they're alive.

75
00:05:15,710 --> 00:05:19,030
不  這說明他們四五個小時之前活著
No. This means they were alive four or five hours ago.

76
00:05:20,300 --> 00:05:21,540
他們還活著
They're alive.

77
00:05:54,430 --> 00:05:56,250
他們從這里開始加速
They picked up the pace right here.

78
00:05:57,070 --> 00:05:58,460
匆匆忙忙跑出來
Got out in a hurry.

79
00:05:59,920 --> 00:06:01,190
情況變得不妙
Things went bad.

80
00:06:02,160 --> 00:06:03,990
你有點信念會死嗎
Wouldn't kill you to have a little faith.

81
00:06:04,860 --> 00:06:07,850
是啊  信念  信念幫不了我們什么
Yeah, faith. Faith ain't done shit for us.

82
00:06:07,850 --> 00:06:10,000
也沒能幫上你父親
Sure as hell didn't do nothing for your father.

83
00:06:32,310 --> 00:06:33,980
我們找到他們的時候他們肯定會餓的
They'll be hungry when we find them.

84
00:07:23,790 --> 00:07:24,640
怎么了
What?

85
00:07:25,910 --> 00:07:27,420
那不是行尸的血
That ain't walker blood.

86
00:07:28,550 --> 00:07:29,810
足跡一直往前
The trail keeps going.

87
00:07:30,730 --> 00:07:31,880
他們打退了行尸
They fought them off.

88
00:07:33,460 --> 00:07:36,690
不  這里到處都是行尸的足跡
No. Got walker tracks all up and down here.

89
00:07:37,010 --> 00:07:38,400
至少有十幾個
At least a dozen of them.

90
00:08:18,580 --> 00:08:19,430
走吧
Come on.

91
00:09:59,370 --> 00:10:00,650
我們不會死的
We're not gonna die.

92
00:10:02,980 --> 00:10:04,000
誰也不會
None of us.

93
00:10:06,620 --> 00:10:07,690
我現在相信了
I believe now.

94
00:10:09,110 --> 00:10:10,550
為了我爸爸
I believe for Daddy.

95
00:10:12,340 --> 00:10:13,760
如果這也行不通
If this doesn't work,

96
00:10:14,370 --> 00:10:16,440
我不知道我要怎么堅持下去了
I don't know how I could keep going.

97
00:10:28,070 --> 00:10:29,060
別哭
Don't cry.

98
00:10:31,430 --> 00:10:33,020
我想要卡蘿爾
I want Carol.

99
00:10:33,710 --> 00:10:35,040
她不在這兒
Well, she's not here.

100
00:10:37,620 --> 00:10:39,460
給你  放到腰帶上
Here, put this on your belt.

101
00:10:42,890 --> 00:10:45,790
天快黑了  我們要去哪
It's gonna get dark soon. Where are we going?

102
00:10:50,210 --> 00:10:52,330
再走遠點  跟上
Farther. Come on.

103
00:10:54,870 --> 00:10:56,240
大家都死了嗎
Is everybody dead?

104
00:11:24,540 --> 00:11:25,880
它們會聽到她的
They're gonna hear her.

105
00:11:30,310 --> 00:11:31,540
我們不該待在這兒
We shouldn't be out here.

106
00:11:31,540 --> 00:11:33,310
我們很快就會找到個安全的地方
We'll find a safe place soon.

107
00:11:34,320 --> 00:11:35,100
我們會的
We will.

108
00:11:41,650 --> 00:11:42,420
給你
Here.

109
00:11:51,260 --> 00:11:52,260
有行尸
Walkers!

110
00:11:57,550 --> 00:11:59,210
拿著  快點
Here, come on.

111
00:12:00,200 --> 00:12:01,990
走吧  沒事的
Let's go. It's okay.

112
00:12:02,340 --> 00:12:03,860
我們會找到吃的
I'll find you something to eat.

113
00:12:05,440 --> 00:12:06,830
好了  走吧
All right, go.

114
00:12:16,920 --> 00:12:18,890
看  有葡萄
Look, grapes.

115
00:12:21,410 --> 00:12:24,170
-這個可以吃嗎  -可以  它們沒毒
- Can we eat them?  - Yeah, they're good.

116
00:12:29,940 --> 00:12:31,520
給你  麗茲  吃點吧
Here, Lizzie, have some.

117
00:12:37,620 --> 00:12:39,010
好了  小寶貝
Come on, baby girl.

118
00:12:43,250 --> 00:12:45,340
麗茲  遞一張尿布給我
Lizzie, hand me a diaper.

119
00:12:46,200 --> 00:12:48,000
好了  不哭  馬上就好
It's okay. All right.

120
00:12:48,270 --> 00:12:49,560
再忍耐一下  朱迪思
Bear with me, Judith.

121
00:12:50,110 --> 00:12:52,730
很快就好  不哭不哭
Okay, that's it. Okay.

122
00:12:56,270 --> 00:12:57,550
它們會聽到的
They're gonna hear her.

123
00:12:59,160 --> 00:13:01,780
好了不哭  我們走
You're all right. Come on.

124
00:13:02,380 --> 00:13:05,420
好啦  我知道你不舒服
It's all right. I know. I know.

125
00:13:05,860 --> 00:13:07,750
好了  你想要什么
All right, what do you want?

126
00:13:07,750 --> 00:13:10,090
你想要什么
What do you want, hmm?

127
00:13:11,810 --> 00:13:14,260
噓  好了  不要哭了
Shh. Shh. Okay, come on.

128
00:13:16,720 --> 00:13:18,760
-它們來了  -我聽到了  米卡
- They're coming! - Ah! I heard it, Mica!

129
00:13:18,760 --> 00:13:21,470
不要吼她  她不了解行尸
Don't yell at her. She doesn't understand walkers.

130
00:13:21,480 --> 00:13:23,750
你才不了解行尸
You're the one who doesn't understand them.

131
00:13:24,700 --> 00:13:25,440
好了
Come on.

132
00:13:26,330 --> 00:13:27,620
看好孩子
Watch the baby.

133
00:13:45,000 --> 00:13:45,960
米卡
Mica!

134
00:13:47,590 --> 00:13:48,410
米卡
Mica!

135
00:13:51,510 --> 00:13:52,500
米卡
Mica!

136
00:13:57,050 --> 00:13:58,750
-米卡  -她跑了
- Mica.  - She's gone.

137
00:13:58,750 --> 00:14:00,730
你大聲吼她  她就跑了
You yelled at her and now she's gone.

138
00:14:01,640 --> 00:14:02,520
米卡
Mica!

139
00:14:04,350 --> 00:14:05,180
米卡
Mica.

140
00:14:10,230 --> 00:14:11,250
你還好嗎
Are you okay?

141
00:14:13,230 --> 00:14:14,630
我太害怕了
I got scared.

142
00:14:14,650 --> 00:14:17,160
沒事的  我們都嚇壞了
That's okay. We all get scared.

143
00:14:17,180 --> 00:14:18,750
遇到危險就該跑
You did the right thing running.

144
00:14:19,330 --> 00:14:21,040
-什么  -她做得沒錯
- What? - She did.

145
00:14:21,330 --> 00:14:23,190
聽到或者看到行尸  應拔腿就跑
You hear or see a walker, you run.

146
00:14:23,200 --> 00:14:25,140
不過  如果你處在團隊中
But when you're in a group,

147
00:14:25,310 --> 00:14:27,490
要盡量和大家待在一起  好嗎
you got to try to stay close to them, okay?

148
00:14:32,220 --> 00:14:35,110
你胳膊流血了  我傷你很重嗎
You're bleeding. Did I hurt your arm bad?

149
00:14:35,110 --> 00:14:37,590
沒事  我在監獄里受的傷比這嚴重多了
It was a lot worse at the prison. No big.

150
00:14:39,250 --> 00:14:40,330
對不起
I'm sorry.

151
00:14:41,940 --> 00:14:43,780
我知道自己做得不如麗茲好
I know I'm not like Lizzie.

152
00:14:44,000 --> 00:14:47,110
不用道歉  你們都有自己的處事方法
Don't be sorry. You each do things your own way.

153
00:14:47,280 --> 00:14:49,960
-但是你們都能做到  -就像你和薩沙
- But you both get it done. - Like you and Sasha?

154
00:14:49,960 --> 00:14:51,270
你才不像薩沙
You're not like Sasha.

155
00:14:51,650 --> 00:14:52,770
為什么
Why not?

156
00:14:53,380 --> 00:14:54,790
因為你還活著
Because you're still here.

157
00:14:54,900 --> 00:14:56,010
而薩沙不是
Sasha isn't.

158
00:15:02,930 --> 00:15:04,840
你要干什么
Wh....What are you doing?

159
00:15:04,840 --> 00:15:07,540
過來
Come on. Come on.

160
00:15:07,850 --> 00:15:10,510
我要讓你們能同時看到兩個方向
I'm making sure you can see in both directions.

161
00:15:10,520 --> 00:15:12,800
你們就這么小心待著
You stay like this and keep watch.

162
00:15:12,800 --> 00:15:14,340
你要離開我們嗎
You're leaving us?

163
00:15:15,250 --> 00:15:16,940
他們可能監獄的人
They may be from the prison.

164
00:15:16,940 --> 00:15:19,120
-我得幫他們  -我們需要你
- I need to help them. - We need you.

165
00:15:19,790 --> 00:15:22,370
米卡  把你的襯衣塞到匕首后
Mica, tuck your shirt behind your knife

166
00:15:22,370 --> 00:15:23,970
這樣更容易拔出來
so it's easier to grab.

167
00:15:24,500 --> 00:15:26,260
-我們不會有事的  -好
- We'll be okay. - Okay.

168
00:15:29,600 --> 00:15:31,100
如果你們看到行尸要怎么辦
What do you do when you see a walker?

169
00:15:31,100 --> 00:15:32,670
-跑  -跑
- Run. - Run.

170
00:15:32,730 --> 00:15:35,830
一起朝我這邊跑  不到萬不得已不要開槍
Together, towards me. Only fire if you have to.

171
00:15:35,840 --> 00:15:38,080
就在這里等著我回來  好嗎
You stay right here until I get back, okay?

172
00:15:38,080 --> 00:15:39,740
求求你  求求你不要走
Please, please don't go.

173
00:15:41,880 --> 00:15:44,000
米卡  看著我
Mica, look at me.

174
00:15:44,580 --> 00:15:46,270
你沒問題的
You can handle this.

175
00:15:46,540 --> 00:15:47,810
你很堅強
You're tough.

176
00:16:09,290 --> 00:16:10,700
克里斯  往林子里跑
Chris, head for the woods.

177
00:16:10,850 --> 00:16:11,880
不行
I can't.

178
00:16:27,380 --> 00:16:29,960
別哭了  朱迪思  安靜點
Come on, Judith. Be quiet.

179
00:16:30,310 --> 00:16:32,210
她就是不停
She's not stopping.

180
00:16:32,210 --> 00:16:34,350
拜托了  麗茲  想想辦法
Please, Lizzie, do something.

181
00:16:35,340 --> 00:16:37,130
它們會聽到我們的
They're gonna hear us.

182
00:16:56,770 --> 00:16:57,700
麗茲
Lizzie.

183
00:16:59,510 --> 00:17:02,200
-爸爸  -克里斯多夫
- Ah! Dad! - Christopher!

184
00:17:03,260 --> 00:17:05,270
-爸爸  -克里斯多夫
- Dad! - Christopher!

185
00:17:14,640 --> 00:17:16,010
麗茲  我們該跑了
Lizzie, we have to run.

186
00:17:18,550 --> 00:17:19,560
麗茲
Lizzie?

187
00:17:21,440 --> 00:17:22,370
麗茲
Lizzie.

188
00:17:42,580 --> 00:17:43,660
小心
Watch out!

189
00:17:56,290 --> 00:17:57,330
泰爾西
Tyreese.

190
00:18:07,680 --> 00:18:09,520
怎么會...
How-- how...

191
00:18:17,740 --> 00:18:19,160
你是怎么找到我們的
How'd you find us?

192
00:18:19,270 --> 00:18:21,780
你去哪兒了  你怎么...
Where were you? How'd you--

193
00:18:24,280 --> 00:18:25,750
待在這兒  姑娘們
Stay here, girls.

194
00:18:37,070 --> 00:18:38,650
沿著軌道走
Stay on the tracks.

195
00:18:41,490 --> 00:18:43,160
是我的錯
That was my mistake.

196
00:18:43,570 --> 00:18:45,020
但是林子里能提供更多掩護
But the woods have more cover.

197
00:18:45,020 --> 00:18:48,360
不  你不明白
No, you don't understand.

198
00:18:49,180 --> 00:18:51,660
軌道那頭有個地方
There's a place up the tracks.

199
00:18:51,670 --> 00:18:55,380
那里很安全  你們可以把孩子們帶去
It's safe. You can take the children there.

200
00:18:59,100 --> 00:19:00,200
相信我
Trust me.

201
00:19:01,250 --> 00:19:02,340
拜托了
Please.

202
00:19:03,120 --> 00:19:04,660
沿著鐵軌走
Follow the tracks.

203
00:19:26,510 --> 00:19:27,620
泰爾西
Tyreese.

204
00:19:28,760 --> 00:19:30,150
我沒跑
I didn't run.

205
00:19:31,010 --> 00:19:32,660
我沒有丟下麗茲
I didn't leave Lizzie.

206
00:19:32,750 --> 00:19:35,460
看吧  堅強的小姑娘
See that? Tough little lady.

207
00:19:38,880 --> 00:19:41,680
這里有水
There's some water in there.

208
00:19:42,370 --> 00:19:44,190
-還有吃的  -好
- And some food. - Yeah.

209
00:19:52,030 --> 00:19:53,110
給
Here you go.

210
00:19:56,240 --> 00:19:57,670
我沒看見你逃出去
I didn't see you get out.

211
00:19:58,600 --> 00:19:59,760
我以為你
I thought you--

212
00:20:00,210 --> 00:20:01,490
我當時不在那兒
I wasn't there.

213
00:20:03,010 --> 00:20:04,400
還沒回去
I hadn't gotten back yet.

214
00:20:05,370 --> 00:20:06,520
瑞克和我發現了一輛車
Rick and I found a car.

215
00:20:06,520 --> 00:20:08,950
他把我們找的東西帶回了監獄
He took what we had back to the prison

216
00:20:09,630 --> 00:20:10,400
而我
while I...

217
00:20:12,640 --> 00:20:13,710
繼續找
kept looking.

218
00:20:15,630 --> 00:20:16,940
你看見了嗎
Did you see it?

219
00:20:17,750 --> 00:20:19,110
只看到了結尾
I saw the end.

220
00:20:19,770 --> 00:20:20,700
然后
And then...

221
00:20:22,610 --> 00:20:24,080
我看見你跑進了樹叢
I saw you running into the woods.

222
00:20:24,080 --> 00:20:26,180
你離得太遠了  我找不到你  但是
You were far away. I lost you, but...

223
00:20:26,180 --> 00:20:27,560
你找到了我們
You found us.

224
00:20:30,800 --> 00:20:33,080
-我就知道你會找到  -是啊
- I knew you would. - Yeah.

225
00:20:38,330 --> 00:20:41,790
也許我們可以繞回去  找到你的車
Hey, maybe we can circle back and find your car.

226
00:20:43,130 --> 00:20:44,950
那些行尸  還有大火
The walkers and the fire--

227
00:20:46,570 --> 00:20:48,460
你不能回那片墓地
you can't go back to a graveyard.

228
00:20:58,470 --> 00:20:59,450
快看
Look.

229
00:21:07,660 --> 00:21:10,810
避難所  社區  歡迎所有人
"Sanctuary for all. Community for all.

230
00:21:11,170 --> 00:21:13,640
抵達就能活命
Those who arrive survive."

231
00:21:25,090 --> 00:21:27,340
終點站

232
00:21:51,840 --> 00:21:52,770
抱歉
Sorry.

233
00:21:55,740 --> 00:21:56,900
你可以笑
You can smile.

234
00:21:58,320 --> 00:22:00,000
你還活著  我理解
You're alive. I get it.

235
00:22:02,960 --> 00:22:04,040
不是因為這個
That's not it.

236
00:22:06,890 --> 00:22:07,770
好了
Okay.

237
00:22:11,170 --> 00:22:13,150
泰爾西也許還活著  薩沙
Tyreese could have made it, Sasha.

238
00:22:15,370 --> 00:22:17,080
我們不知道有沒有人逃出去了
We don't know if anybody got out.

239
00:22:21,670 --> 00:22:22,540
不
No.

240
00:22:24,600 --> 00:22:25,530
我們知道
We do.

241
00:22:37,200 --> 00:22:38,260
他怎么樣
How's he doing?

242
00:22:38,660 --> 00:22:39,880
不流血了
Bleeding stopped.

243
00:22:39,980 --> 00:22:41,040
他沒事的
He'll be all right.

244
00:22:44,120 --> 00:22:45,760
我們背靠河流
Got the water to our backs.

245
00:22:45,760 --> 00:22:47,240
岸邊的位置很有利
Decent vantage points from the bank.

246
00:22:47,240 --> 00:22:49,020
晚上就在這扎營吧
I'm thinking we camp here for the night.

247
00:22:49,510 --> 00:22:50,500
很好
That's good.

248
00:22:54,360 --> 00:22:55,850
你們在這應該很安全
You should both be safe here.

249
00:22:56,790 --> 00:22:58,660
大巴開出去了  格倫也逃出來了
The bus got out. Glenn got out.

250
00:22:58,660 --> 00:22:59,970
我要去找他
I'm gonna find him.

251
00:23:00,060 --> 00:23:01,080
瑪姬
Maggie.

252
00:23:02,640 --> 00:23:05,010
如果一切順利  大巴已經走遠了
With any luck, the bus is gone.

253
00:23:05,010 --> 00:23:06,640
它沿著主路向東走了
It was heading east down the main road.

254
00:23:06,640 --> 00:23:07,640
如果我沿這個方向走
If I follow in that direction,

255
00:23:07,640 --> 00:23:09,000
也許可以發現它的蹤跡
I might be able to pick up its tracks.

256
00:23:09,000 --> 00:23:10,610
你自己嗎  就靠那把刀嗎
Alone? With just that?

257
00:23:10,610 --> 00:23:12,160
我沒有彈藥了  是的
I'm out of ammo, so, yeah.

258
00:23:13,190 --> 00:23:14,620
我沒找到貝絲
I couldn't find Beth.

259
00:23:14,920 --> 00:23:17,250
我知道格倫逃出來了  也知道他的路線
I know Glenn got out and I know which way he went.

260
00:23:17,500 --> 00:23:19,920
我要找到他  然后再回來找你們
I'm gonna go get him and I'm gonna come back for you.

261
00:23:19,920 --> 00:23:21,490
-我們兩個一起  -瑪姬
- We both are. - Maggie.

262
00:23:21,490 --> 00:23:22,540
我要去
I'm going.

263
00:23:22,630 --> 00:23:24,500
我們不能分開  現在不能
We cannot split up. Not now.

264
00:23:26,150 --> 00:23:27,120
我要去
I'm going.

265
00:23:31,090 --> 00:23:32,060
你自己說的
You said it.

266
00:23:34,340 --> 00:23:35,550
我們不能分開
We can't split up.

267
00:23:40,890 --> 00:23:41,940
搭車者可能為逃犯

268
00:23:41,940 --> 00:23:47,020
搭車者可能為逃犯

269
00:23:43,850 --> 00:23:45,600
你可以幫我阻止她的
You could have helped me stop her.

270
00:23:48,970 --> 00:23:51,550
如果你這是想讓我同情你  不管用的
If you're trying to make me feel sorry for you, it's not working.

271
00:23:52,890 --> 00:23:56,070
該死  那我不是白挨了一槍
Damn, it means I let myself get shot up for nothing.

272
00:23:56,680 --> 00:23:58,550
我們找到他的可能性...
The odds of us finding him...

273
00:23:59,080 --> 00:24:01,810
我們應該去找食物  住的地方
We should be out looking for food, shelter.

274
00:24:01,960 --> 00:24:03,520
是嗎  為什么
Yeah, why is that?

275
00:24:03,770 --> 00:24:05,140
這樣我們才能活下來
So we can live.

276
00:24:05,700 --> 00:24:06,730
然后呢
Then what?

277
00:24:07,420 --> 00:24:08,380
什么
What?

278
00:24:09,010 --> 00:24:11,720
也許我們活下來不只是為了繼續活下去
Maybe we didn't survive just to keep surviving.

279
00:24:11,720 --> 00:24:13,290
世事無常
Shit happens.

280
00:24:13,290 --> 00:24:15,410
不是所有事情都有意義的
Not everything has to mean something.

281
00:24:15,460 --> 00:24:17,710
不是必須的  但是可以有
No, it doesn't have to, but it can.

282
00:24:17,860 --> 00:24:18,830
你的那種想法
If you make it that way,

283
00:24:18,830 --> 00:24:20,630
是我們一直以來的生活方式
and that's what it seems like we're doing.

284
00:24:21,200 --> 00:24:22,390
而我受夠了
And I'm down with that.

285
00:24:44,680 --> 00:24:45,650
瑪姬
Maggie.

286
00:24:46,150 --> 00:24:47,080
瑪姬
Maggie!

287
00:25:18,170 --> 00:25:19,250
你們該走了
You should go.

288
00:25:21,640 --> 00:25:22,690
瑪姬  住手
Maggie, stop.

289
00:25:22,690 --> 00:25:24,010
瑪姬  瑪姬
Maggie. Maggie.

290
00:25:24,010 --> 00:25:25,660
我一定得弄清楚他在不在里面
I have to know if he's in there.

291
00:25:27,150 --> 00:25:27,870
好吧
Fine,

292
00:25:28,610 --> 00:25:29,920
但我們得一起干這事兒
but we do it together.

293
00:25:31,200 --> 00:25:32,080
小心點
Smart.

294
00:25:33,180 --> 00:25:34,850
我們每次放一個出來
We'll let them out one at a time.

295
00:25:39,610 --> 00:25:41,130
我們得有兩個人站在門邊
Two of us should be at the door...

296
00:25:43,520 --> 00:25:45,210
防止它們疊在一起頂開門
in case they stack up against it.

297
00:25:46,040 --> 00:25:47,220
我必須站在這里
I have to be here.

298
00:25:47,660 --> 00:25:49,310
我要看它們的臉
I need to see their faces.

299
00:26:33,560 --> 00:26:35,040
我頂不住了
I can't hold it.

300
00:27:19,080 --> 00:27:20,190
抱歉
I'm sorry.

301
00:27:31,110 --> 00:27:32,570
但他們逃出來了啊
But they got away.

302
00:27:33,920 --> 00:27:35,250
他們都是好人
They were good people.

303
00:27:36,040 --> 00:27:37,130
全部都是
All of them.

304
00:27:57,120 --> 00:27:58,210
你應該讓我來
You should let me.

305
00:30:25,930 --> 00:30:27,400
瑪姬
Maggie?

306
00:30:32,410 --> 00:30:34,320
瑪姬
Maggie!

307
00:36:55,150 --> 00:36:56,340
子彈是滿的
It's full.

308
00:36:57,380 --> 00:36:58,730
你是不是一槍都沒開
Did you even fire a shot?

309
00:37:01,910 --> 00:37:03,510
好吧  走吧
All right. Let's go.

310
00:37:05,540 --> 00:37:06,650
走啊
Let's go.

311
00:37:09,630 --> 00:37:12,070
你就打算待在這兒了嗎
Are you just gonna stay here, huh?

312
00:37:12,190 --> 00:37:13,240
你打算送死嗎
You're just gonna die?

313
00:37:13,250 --> 00:37:14,830
我和他們是一伙的
I was part of this.

314
00:37:16,410 --> 00:37:17,700
我知道
I know.

315
00:37:18,880 --> 00:37:20,530
所以你要干什么
So what are you doing?

316
00:37:22,560 --> 00:37:23,630
我需要你的幫助
I need your help.

317
00:37:32,870 --> 00:37:34,270
我們的子彈要用完了
We're gonna run out of bullets.

318
00:37:34,420 --> 00:37:36,640
拿著這個  還有這個
Take this and take this.

319
00:37:42,240 --> 00:37:43,350
退開
Back up.

320
00:38:02,030 --> 00:38:04,870
好了  我要你走在我前面  行嗎
All right. I need you to stay ahead of me, okay?

321
00:38:04,870 --> 00:38:07,770
我會掩護你  但我一個人做不到
All right. I'll cover you, but I can't do it alone.

322
00:38:16,910 --> 00:38:17,940
你準備好了嗎
You ready?

323
00:38:19,200 --> 00:38:20,220
走吧
Let's go.

324
00:38:21,140 --> 00:38:23,010
快  走  走  走
Go. Go, go, go, go, go.

325
00:38:26,330 --> 00:38:28,350
開槍  開槍  走吧
Shoot! Shoot! Come on!

326
00:38:59,510 --> 00:39:01,230
你有沒有看見我們的人逃出來
Did you see if any of my people got out?

327
00:39:01,870 --> 00:39:04,180
我只見我姐姐出現在那片空地上
All I saw was my sister in that field.

328
00:39:05,750 --> 00:39:07,360
她本不應該出現在那里
She wasn't supposed to be there.

329
00:39:08,970 --> 00:39:11,760
她有槍  但它們向她涌了過去
She had a gun, but they just swarmed her.

330
00:39:15,020 --> 00:39:16,220
她不該在那兒的
She wasn't supposed to be there.

331
00:39:16,220 --> 00:39:19,080
我為他才這么做的  我信任他
I did it for him. I trusted him.

332
00:39:19,680 --> 00:39:21,630
但他卻殺了那個老人
And then he just killed that old man.

333
00:39:22,980 --> 00:39:24,100
赫謝爾
Hershel?

334
00:39:29,170 --> 00:39:30,740
他的名字是叫赫謝爾嗎
Was his name Hershel?

335
00:39:39,990 --> 00:39:41,120
對不起
I'm sorry.

336
00:39:42,230 --> 00:39:43,680
真的對不起
I'm so sorry.

337
00:39:46,600 --> 00:39:49,810
布萊恩跟我們說你們是壞人
Brian, that man, told us you were bad people.

338
00:39:49,980 --> 00:39:51,550
我知道那不是真的
I know it's not true.

339
00:39:51,970 --> 00:39:53,070
我能看出來
I can see it's not,

340
00:39:53,080 --> 00:39:55,520
所以我們的所作所為  我的所作所為...
so what we did, what I did...

341
00:39:58,610 --> 00:40:00,290
我太混賬了
I mean, I'm a piece of shit.

342
00:40:01,310 --> 00:40:02,880
你為什么還想要我幫忙
Why would you want my help?

343
00:40:06,050 --> 00:40:07,580
我不是想要  我是需要
I don't want it, I need it.

344
00:40:12,830 --> 00:40:14,200
我得找到瑪姬
I have to find Maggie.

345
00:40:17,840 --> 00:40:19,090
瑪姬是誰
Who's Maggie?

346
00:40:21,120 --> 00:40:22,380
我妻子
She's my wife.

347
00:40:24,350 --> 00:40:25,920
你倆分散了嗎
You guys got separated?

348
00:40:26,460 --> 00:40:27,440
我當時在巴士上
I was on the bus and then

349
00:40:27,440 --> 00:40:29,200
然后我下車去幫忙  她沒看到我
I got off to help and she didn't see me.

350
00:40:29,200 --> 00:40:30,810
你怎么知道她有沒有活下來
How do you know if she made it?

351
00:40:32,510 --> 00:40:33,620
我不知道
I don't know.

352
00:40:35,370 --> 00:40:36,560
但是赫謝爾
But Hershel,

353
00:40:37,670 --> 00:40:39,510
瑪姬的父親  是個偉大的人
Maggie's father, was a great man.

354
00:40:41,370 --> 00:40:43,210
他跟我說過  只要有信念就行
And he told me all I had to do was believe,

355
00:40:43,280 --> 00:40:44,310
而我正打算這么做
and that's what I'm gonna do.

356
00:40:44,780 --> 00:40:46,770
咱倆現在都不該活著了
Neither one of us should be alive right now.

357
00:40:49,300 --> 00:40:52,200
她逃出去了  所以你得幫我找到她
She got out, so you're gonna help me find her.

358
00:40:54,650 --> 00:40:55,790
事情還沒完
Things aren't over.

359
00:40:57,270 --> 00:40:58,390
他們還沒死
They're not over.

360
00:40:59,060 --> 00:41:00,320
我也想這樣去相信
I want to believe that.

361
00:41:03,980 --> 00:41:05,280
我也想
I want to.

362
00:41:19,260 --> 00:41:20,560
你必須相信
You have to.

363
00:41:49,720 --> 00:41:52,510
格倫  格倫
Glenn. Glenn.

364
00:41:52,730 --> 00:41:55,780
格倫
Hey, Glenn.

365
00:42:18,380 --> 00:42:20,670
希望你們看得開心  混蛋
Hope you enjoyed the show, assholes.

366
00:42:28,310 --> 00:42:30,680
你有一條毒舌  你知道嗎
You got a damn mouth on you, you know that?

367
00:42:33,230 --> 00:42:34,760
你還有什么
What else you got?

368
00:42:37,910 --> 00:42:41,920
現代汽車為您帶來《行尸走肉》下集預告
Hyundai presents scenes from the next episode of The Walking Dead...

369
00:42:42,280 --> 00:42:43,880
我是亞伯拉罕·福特中士
I'm Sergeant Abraham Ford.

370
00:42:45,690 --> 00:42:47,020
下周日

371
00:42:45,930 --> 00:42:47,140
他們是我的同伴
And these are my companions.

372
00:42:48,430 --> 00:42:50,180
我們需要人  越多越好
We need people, the more the better.

373
00:42:52,090 --> 00:42:53,370
我們彼此依賴  伙計
We need each other, partner.

374
00:42:57,080 --> 00:42:57,930
你看到了什么
What did you see?

375
00:43:00,240 --> 00:43:01,030
她死了
She's gone.

376
00:43:03,280 --> 00:43:04,460
你不必也去送死
No need for you to die too.

377
00:43:06,310 --> 00:43:09,310
更多視頻請登錄AMC官網查看
For more video go to amc.com.

