"Jean Gaborit and Jacques Durand
reconstructed this film
with the approval and advice
of Jean Renoir,
who dedicates this resurrection
to the memory of André Bazin."
THE RULES OF THE GAME
A Dramatic Fantasy
"This entertainment, set on the eve
of the Second World War,
does not claim to be
a study of manners.
Its characters are purely fictitious."
"Sensitive hearts, faithful hearts
Who shun love whither it does range
Cease to be so bitter
Is it a crime to change?
If Cupid was given wings
Was it not to flitter?"
You're listening to Radio-Cité.
It's exactly 10:00 p.m.
We're here
at Le Bourget airfield,
working our way through the crowd
that's turned out to welcome
the famous aviator André Jurieu,
who has just performed
a tremendous feat:
Crossing the Atlantic in 23 hours!
A record comparable...
Watch the cord!
A record comparable only
to the one set a dozen years ago
by Charles Lindbergh.
The crowd's moving!
Jurieu has arrived safe and sound,
executing a magnificent landing.
The crowd is invading the airfield
and crashing the police cordon.
The minister couldn't make it, but
he asked me to convey his admiration
and sincerest congratulations.
It's really the plane's doing.
Not at all.
It's a fine achievement.
Octave!
André! Am I ever happy!
Not about your flight!
It's you I'm glad to see!
It is you, isn't it?
Is she here?
She didn't come?
- She didn't come?
- She couldn't make it.
But I did this all for her!
I know.
Mr. André Jurieu,
a few words for our listeners.
Just a few words.
- What can I say?
You just flew solo over the Atlantic.
You must have something to say.
Anything. You must be happy.
I'm very unhappy.
I've never been
so disappointed in my life.
I made this flight for a woman.
She's not here to welcome me.
She didn't even bother.
I tell her this publicly:
She's disloyal!
The great aviator has performed
a stunning feat.
But remember,
it's cost him a great deal of effort,
and he's exhausted.
My purse, Lisette.
He can't really talk.
But we have here with us
an engineer from Caudron.
Jurieu's aircraft
was manufactured by Caudron.
It's a standard model with
a 200-horsepower Renault engine.
The copilot's seat was replaced
by an extra fuel tank.
You're a hero, but you just behaved
like a spoiled kid.
If Christine won't see you,
serves you right.
- I couldn't face her now.
- Get some sleep first.
Tell me, Lisette,
how long have you been married?
- Almost two years, Madame.
- That's true.
How time flies! Are you happy?
My husband's no trouble.
He's in service at the château
and I'm in Paris.
With you, Madame, I'm very happy.
- Do you have lovers?
- That's a big word.
Of course you do.
Octave, for example.
Give me my evening lipstick.
- I don't know where it is.
- Oh, yes, you do.
I don't like it. Too purple.
It doesn't look natural.
What's natural nowadays?
And your lovers...
What do they say to you?
Not much.
- Do they kiss you?
- If I let them.
- Do they hold your hand?
- It depends.
- And then what?
- Then what?
Same old story: The more you give,
the more they want.
My scarf.
Nothing doing.
Men are all the same.
What about friendship?
Friendship with a man?
When pigs have wings!
- Good evening, Madame.
- Good evening, Lisette.
- Mitzi...
- Yes, Madame?
- Did you take the dogs out?
- Yes, Madame.
- Where is Monsieur?
- In his study.
Calm has returned
to Le Bourget airfield.
The crowd is breaking up peacefully.
The victory reception is over.
We've just witnessed an event
that will go down...
- We're late, my dear.
- As usual.
A new one?
- I got it today.
It's a romantic Negress.
In perfect working order.
I prefer it to the radio.
So, you heard
what André Jurieu said?
I can well imagine what he thought.
He'd risked his life.
How could you have refused him
that small token of affection
he must have
pleaded for so touchingly?
He mistook it for love.
Men are so naïve.
How happy that makes me!
Thank you.
- It's nothing.
Telling lies is such
a heavy weight to bear.
Lies... Don't exaggerate.
Would you call me a liar?
I trust you completely.
Do you?
Excuse me a minute, my dear.
Madame de Marras, please.
Is that you, Geneviève?
I must see you.
Then come over now.
You're going out with Christine?
In the morning, then.
Not at 10:00. Yes, 11:00.
Be realistic.
La Chesnaye must be in a state.
- So why does he have a wireless?
- Progress.
You call that progress?
I call it exhibitionism.
I feel sorry for Christine,
because she's a foreigner.
And because
you have a crush on her.
No, but it must be hard
to leave the life she had in Austria.
An artist's life. Her father
was a famous conductor in Vienna.
And to move to Paris
where nobody speaks her language.
- Why did she marry? I didn't!
- Oh, you!
What's on your mind?
A maxim by Chamfort.
It could almost be a precept.
What does he say?
"Love as it exists in society
is merely the mingling of two whims
and the contact of two skins."
If I understand you right,
you want to leave me.
Last night I suddenly decided
to be worthy of my wife.
I see the family picture: Knitting,
the slippers and lots of children.
Exactly. I sort of feel now
that I've had my fun.
All this because of the radio
and André Jurieu.
How perceptive you are!
Let's say we do split up.
What would change with Christine?
Why, everything.
Nothing!
She's remained so Austrian.
A Parisian woman would understand.
Not her.
If she found out, it's not
our affair she'd hold against you,
but the fact that you lied
from the start.
She'd never forgive you.
I know.
Believe it or not,
you mean a lot to me.
I don't know if it's love
or force of habit,
but if you leave me, I'll be very
unhappy, and I don't want to be.
My dear, I'm so sorry.
I didn't intend to hurt you,
but put yourself in my shoes.
A good thing you're weak.
I take after my father.
The poor man
had such a complicated existence.
Let's go to lunch.
- With pleasure.
I don't know if it's
this sentimental talk,
but I'm famished!
No, old man! Go on if you want,
but I'm walking home.
- Don't leave me alone.
- Damn your problems!
Since you got back,
you haven't stopped bending my ear.
And now you drive us into a ditch.
Thanks, but no thanks!
Are you hurt?
I wonder if I'm not dead.
I hit the roof like a feather.
It's rattled my brains.
Want to kill yourself over Christine?
Go ahead, but without me.
- Understand...
- I do. You're nuts!
- So I'm nuts!
- Get help and get off my back.
You'd gladly see me put away.
You love her, too.
Sure I do, in my own way.
So you can't have her
like a glass of wine.
Get this:
She's like a sister to me.
We grew up together.
Her father, old Stiller, wasn't just
the greatest of conductors.
He was also the best of men.
When I went to study music
with him in Salzburg,
he treated me like a son.
I never got to show him my gratitude.
Now I can. He's not here to look
after his daughter anymore.
So I can and will look after her.
She needs looking after.
She's a foreigner among people
who don't speak her language.
If you want to make her happy,
let her come with me.
Because I love her.
Seeing her with that idiot
La Chesnaye!
Him and his hunts,
château and mechanical birds!
A two-timing snob!
He may be a snob,
but he's got his feet on the ground.
Your head's in the clouds.
You put your foot in your mouth,
like on the radio.
At Le Bourget when you got back.
You're back from America
after breaking all sorts of records.
You get a hero's welcome.
Ministers make speeches.
But instead of modestly and calmly
playing your part as a national hero,
instead of giving radio audiences
the twaddle they expect,
you start sounding off
about Christine. In public!
No wonder she won't see you!
But I did it for her,
for her alone, understand?
She encouraged me.
So when she didn't show up...
She's a society woman,
and society has strict rules.
I don't need lectures.
I need Christine.
I love her, you know.
If I don't see her again, I'll die.
You'll see her again.
- Think so?
- Sure you will.
Leave it to me.
So, Mr. Octave!
No hello?
Fresh as a rose.
But you look awful.
What's the matter?
I bet it's your pilot friend again.
What a nuisance!
Madame can't sleep at night.
Listen here. Do you trust me?
I'll settle it.
- Really?
Where have you been?
I've been very busy.
- Problems?
- I'll tell you later.
You came to see my wife?
Let me say good morning.
- What's that you got: A nightingale?
- A warbler.
- Looks like the moths got to it.
- But it still sings every 20 seconds.
- I bet it does.
- Cynic.
Where have you been all this time?
Were you away?
May I?
Good morning, my dear.
Sleep well?
Say, Lisette.
- I got a letter from Shoemaker.
- Schumacher!
Your husband. He says that
without her, my woods lack poetry,
and his gamekeeper's job
seems utterly dreary.
He wants you to join him.
And leave Madame?
Your lordship, I'd rather divorce.
Don't get melodramatic.
Are you two done talking?
Oh, yes,
you have a big secret for her.
You said it.
- I'll leave you.
- About time, too.
- Coming out to "La Colinière"?
- Maybe.
What did I say?
Twenty seconds.
A cup of tea?
A nice hot coffee
with bread and jam?
I'm not hungry.
Something's definitely out of order.
I've never seen Mr. Octave
without an appetite.
Won't you sit down?
Come now, tell me your secret.
- It's about André.
- Oh, no!
- You know he wanted to die?
- That's just talk.
Excuse me, but I was there.
How could he?
How? Why, in his car.
He tried to drive into a tree.
- And it's my fault?
- It sure is your fault.
- I don't understand.
- Don't you?
Listen, my dear.
You throw yourself around people's
necks like a 12-year-old.
You can do it with me.
You'll always be
my little Salzburg girl.
But with others
it can be... awkward.
So, in Paris, you can't show a man
affection without...
So I'm to blame for everything?
Not everything. Just a few things.
Must I apologize to your friend?
That's going a bit far.
But you might...
invite him to "La Colinière."
You're so improper!
In that case... I'm going.
Good-bye. Or rather, farewell.
- Where are you going?
- To see him.
You won't come out
to "La Colinière"?
I can't cut myself in two.
You silly thing!
You foolish old dear!
- So you'll invite him?
- I'll invite him.
I don't want to be
the woman who drove to despair
the great hero,
the idol of the masses.
If his plane crashes,
they'll blame it on me.
They'll call me a vamp,
public enemy, obstacle to progress.
They'll talk about "the foreigner."
And I hate martyrs.
And your husband...
what'll you do about him?
That's your business.
I've done my part.
I wash my hands of the rest.
- Christine, du bist ein Engel.
- An angel?
A dangerous angel,
but an angel nonetheless.
Cook me up two fried eggs,
a big slice of ham and a glass
of white wine. I'm starved!
- You'll put on weight.
- Don't worry. I'll deal with it.
All right, then.
I'll expect you at "La Colinière."
You have your own car, fine.
See you tomorrow.
I'm in a terrible predicament.
- Geneviève.
- You know?
- Who doesn't? Sick and tired of her?
But you want to end it?
Leave it to me.
If you could.
Easy enough. She's dying to get
married, so we'll get her hitched.
To whom? To you?
Oh, me, you know,
I'm not the marrying kind.
I'd be ready to sacrifice myself.
But only for Christine.
- I know.
But I need a favor in return.
You need money?
You know you're a decent guy?
I take after my mother.
I want you to invite André Jurieu.
To "La Colinière"?
That's a very serious request.
Serious?
I know what happened
between Christine and your friend.
I'm not blind.
- Nothing happened.
A good thing, too!
Then invite him.
I'd be taking a big risk.
I love Christine.
I'd never get over losing her.
You know what?
I feel like skedaddling.
I want to disappear down a hole.
What for?
So as not to have to figure out
what's right and what's wrong.
The awful thing about life is this:
Everyone has their reasons.
Of course they do.
And I'm all
for their free expression.
I'm against barriers and walls.
And that's why I'll invite André.
- Is it the right thing to do?
- I have faith in Christine.
If she loves Jurieu,
separating them won't stop her.
They might as well
see each other and talk it over.
You know, we could get Geneviève
together with André.
You idiot!
That would be way too practical.
I'll get dressed.
Staying for breakfast?
Yes, I'm staying.
Your lordship,
about "La Colinière"...
See my secretary.
- Is Madame bringing her dogs?
- Ask Madame.
My screw!
Move this bench away.
It's the screw for my warbler.
- I understand, sir.
My dear, put that on the table.
I have some big news.
"My pilot," as you call him,
will be with me at "La Colinière."
The things you dream up!
The things I dream up?
Dream up!
Excuse me! You know,
you're no fool, you're a poet.
A dangerous poet.
Your lordship.
Excuse me for bringing this up
while on duty.
It's about my wife.
- You wrote me, my friend.
With my wife in Paris
and me out here, it's hardly a life.
I feel like a widower.
What did his lordship decide?
What's there to decide?
If your wife wants to be with you,
it's her decision.
Very good, your lordship.
- I'm so glad to be here.
- So am I.
I lit the stove
and stocked all the fireplaces.
Inform Corneille.
- How is Gertrude?
- Just fine, your ladyship.
Was the coal delivered?
And the wood brought in?
Very good.
- Hello, Lisette.
- Hello, Edouard.
- Everything all right?
- Fine.
- Here you are, at last.
- Yes, here I am.
What's that?
It's Mr. Des Réaux's people.
They're shooting rabbits.
What keeps you from doing the same?
We've already put up fences
at Epinereaux and Tixier.
Along with what the gamekeepers
ferreted, we've killed about 250.
Is that all?
With the full moon,
we kill fewer than usual.
We need to put up wire fencing
to protect the plantation.
- I don't want any fencing.
- Yes, your lordship.
Nor do I want any rabbits.
Work it out.
- May I continue my rounds?
- Of course, Schumacher.
We'll head towards Foucherolle.
Musette! Here, girl!
What did the boss say?
He doesn't want fencing or rabbits.
How are we supposed
to work it out?
It's that pest of a miller's cat.
He's a real nuisance.
He's no nuisance now.
Marceau deserves the same treatment.
Marceau takes us for idiots.
But it won't last much longer.
- What'd you find, girl?
- A rabbit in a snare.
Marceau sets snares all over.
Leave them. Don't tip him off.
- He won't be by today.
- At dawn?
If he goes on a binge,
he won't be up early.
That bum's got it too easy.
What do we do?
Watch out for him.
There's one!
Hello, Marceau.
Hello, Schumacher. How are you?
Want my rabbit?
Give it here.
Go on, walk.
Get a move on!
- What's going on?
- Marceau, your lordship.
- Marceau who?
- Marceau the poacher.
Come here.
- We caught him red-handed.
- Doing what?
Setting snares at woods' edge.
To destroy rabbits?
Why, the man's valuable! Let him go!
- Is his lordship serious?
- He understands me.
He's an intelligent guy,
not like this big bully!
Bully?
I'll teach you manners.
Scum like you should be shot.
Just for a tiny little rabbit!
- So your name is Marceau?
- Yes, your lordship.
- You're a poacher?
- Actually, I mend chairs.
But times are tough even in my line.
His lordship understands me.
So I try to keep busy.
- Call that busy?
Back in the war,
I had men shot for less.
That's enough.
I like your face.
- His lordship's kind.
He's riffraff!
Enough.
Rather than work as an amateur,
would you like to kill rabbits for me?
His lordship wants to hire me?
I won't say no.
If I poach, it's not out of spite.
It's to feed my aging mother.
He has none!
What?
I don't have an aging mother?
Continue your rounds.
Leave me alone.
Say, Marceau.
You must have set other snares.
Will you show me one?
Being in your lordship's
service now, I can't refuse.
This way.
Over here, your lordship.
Here's a snare.
It's set in the wrong place.
- Why?
This trail isn't used anymore.
I should've noticed.
- We all make mistakes.
- No, it's annoying.
If Schumacher saw this,
I'd never hear the last of it.
- You can count on my discretion.
- Thanks, your lordship.
So, glad to be working for me?
Sure, but I'd rather work
at the château.
Why? Don't you like the woods,
Mother Nature?
With Schumacher around, not really.
This is more his world than yours.
At the château,
he'd have to leave me alone.
I always dreamed
of being a domestic.
- That's funny. Why?
- Because of the outfit.
I've always dreamed
of wearing a uniform.
- Has it been raining long?
- A half hour. It was sunny at noon.
- Will it last?
- Last time it rained for two weeks.
Charming!
Her luggage.
Every time I come out here it rains.
It clears out the mind.
Hello, La Bruyère.
Will you allow me?
You're drenched.
Your scarf.
Where's your wife?
With Christine,
discussing housekeeping.
How interesting.
You came from Tourcoing?
Is it raining there?
- Like everywhere else.
It took eight hours to get here
via Paris. The roads are slippery.
A record.
Hello, Jackie.
How you've grown!
- Think so?
- You're studying Chinese, right?
- No, pre-Colombian art.
Sounds thrilling!
How are you, Charlotte?
- Hello, my dear.
Have you lost weight?
Watch out for yourself.
- I swear.
What about these?
You can't fool me.
- Are you playing?
- I'll be right in.
Will you join us?
- Bridge bores me.
Who mentioned bridge?
It's belote!
Who does your hair, Geneviève?
- Did you really invite Jurieu?
- I did. Do you mind?
On the contrary.
- Isn't Jean here?
- He drove to Orleans for the fish.
Tell him about
Madame La Bruyère's diet.
She eats everything. But no salt.
On the contrary. But only sea salt.
And only once the food's cooked.
It's simple.
Even a child would understand.
- Do you have sea salt?
- No, but we'll see to it.
Adolphe, for Madame La Plante...
I almost forgot: No tea, just coffee.
And for the general,
a slice of lemon in hot water.
I know: Arthritis.
And for André Jurieu?
What do you think
of the diphtheria vaccine?
I don't know.
At the factory dispensary,
we've had very good results.
Really?
Find your suitcase?
My eldest had strep throat
and the youngest, measles.
You can imagine how worried I...
Who's that?
- André Jurieu.
- The aviator?
What luck!
I'll ask him for an autograph
for my eldest boy.
- So nice of you to come.
- You're very kind.
My dear André.
This is a pleasure.
It's an honor to have you.
You know everyone.
You haven't met my wife.
She'd like an autograph
for our eldest boy.
I hope we'll see you in Tourcoing.
You were magnificent.
My dear Jurieu,
I'm proud to shake your hand.
Very proud.
You're a man, a real man.
It's a vanishing breed.
You didn't fly in? I must kiss you.
Glad to see you here.
May I kiss you, too?
And me?
I'm entitled to.
It stays in the family.
- What's that supposed to mean?
- Jurieu and Christine.
What's it to you?
We're here to hunt,
not to write our memoirs.
So, did they or didn't they?
They did.
A pity. He's so elegant.
Dear friends,
I must confess something regarding
my relationship with André Jurieu.
I had a small part to play
in his exploit.
This is how...
While preparing for his flight,
André came to see me often.
We spent long hours together.
Very pleasant hours.
Hours marked by the rare sign
of friendship.
He told me about his projects
and I listened.
It's important to listen.
In this case,
it wasn't a waste of time.
I'm very proud,
and I wanted you all to know it.
Aunt, I'm so happy.
- We'll throw a big party for Jurieu.
- Excellent idea.
We'll put on a show.
We'll masquerade!
Sure, we'll masquerade!
We'll have as much fun as we can.
When, General?
- A week from now, after the hunt.
- Perfect!
Christine, let's show him his room.
These young people are charming.
Saint-Aubin, some billiards.
- Yes, sir.
- Anyone for a game of ping-pong?
- Me.
Coming, Geneviève?
A party for what?
To raise funds for the dispensary.
- Your coat, madam.
- I'll take it off in my room.
That Mr. Jurieu is charming.
He must have a good position.
- Most likely.
- A perfect match for you, Jackie.
- André doesn't notice I exist.
I could arrange a little get-together
at my home in Tourcoing.
This Jurieu's handsome.
A pity the lady of the house...
Did you know
she seated him at her right?
- What right?
- At the table.
That's bad.
I'm all for doing as I like,
but etiquette is etiquette.
Madame can do without your advice.
Asparagus?
- Never anything canned.
Only fresh foods, for the vitamins.
Pass the mustard?
Did you get sea salt
for La Bruyère?
She can eat like everybody else.
Diets I can accept,
but not obsessions.
Madame's gone too far
over her aviator.
"Constraint spoils pleasure."
- And you, Mr. Corneille?
- None of your business.
That's not very nice.
Pass the mustard.
Corneille, you spent 10 years
with Count de Vaudois...
Twelve. I'd still be there
if he hadn't gone bankrupt.
- Fine, but did the countess...
- She had no lovers.
Of course not.
She was 85 years old
and confined to a wheelchair.
You can't compare her to Madame.
- The count wasn't a yid.
- Meaning what?
Only that La Chesnaye's grandfather
was a Rosenthal from Frankfurt.
I'm sure your husband agrees.
Right, Schumacher?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
Speaking of Jews, I used to work
for the Baron d'Epinay.
There were no Jews there,
but I can tell you
they ate like pigs.
That's why I quit.
- Will you be long, Lisette?
- Madame still needs me.
La Chesnaye, yid as he may be,
chewed me out recently
over a potato salad.
You know - or maybe you don't -
that for it to be any good,
you pour white wine
over the potatoes
when they're boiling hot.
But Célestin was afraid
of getting burned.
Well, the boss sensed
right off he hadn't done it.
Say what you like, but that's
what I call a real gentleman.
So there you are.
Who do we have here?
- I'm looking for Mr. Corneille.
- Yes, my friend?
I'm the new domestic.
His lordship must have told you.
What do you do, my good man?
Oh, I dunno...
a bit of everything.
- You shine shoes, my good man?
- Oh, sure.
When it comes to cleaning,
I'm what you call a specialist.
Tomorrow morning you'll collect
the boots outside the guest rooms.
Will do, Mr. Corneille.
We eat here?
- Yes, my good man.
I'm on duty now.
Sit down here.
Germaine, a plate.
What's your name?
Marceau. And you, mademoiselle?
Madame. My name's Lisette.
I'm Madame Schumacher.
Don't let that stop you
from sitting down.
The game better be good.
Last year, at the Cahens,
we only bagged
60 pheasant the first day.
So long as I don't eat rabbit,
I don't care!
Anything but wild rabbit!
Do I serve rabbit other than paté?
I'm not saying you do.
Say, La Chesnaye,
enjoy driving your Delahaye?
Last month, Cannes-Paris:
10 hours and 35 minutes.
With a lunch stop.
So it's all set.
A party after the hunt.
- What party?
- Our party!
- A masquerade?
- Of course. Off to bed now.
I'll come check
you have everything you need.
As your guests,
we never lack for anything.
Such hospitality is dying out.
Christine,
you're the perfect hostess.
This way, General.
Before you go,
I was meaning to ask you...
What's this pre-Colombian art?
What are you studying?
American civilization
before Columbus's arrival.
- Oh, Negroes!
- There weren't any Negroes yet.
- Who was there?
- The Indians.
What a goose I am! Buffalo Bill!
- I forget where my room is.
- I'll show you.
We must have a splendid view.
Too bad it's dark.
A hunting horn!
You hunt on horseback?
In my father's day.
Is Octave too noisy?
- Not at all.
At the party,
I'll do a fencing demonstration.
I used to do a card trick.
Whatever you do will be fine.
- You're a great musician.
- Have fun.
William,
I won't be needing you tonight.
- Good night.
- Sleep well.
Good night. Sleep well.
You two happy?
- Very.
I adore you, Charlotte!
My dear, I'm so grateful to you.
- For what?
- For not making me look foolish.
It was delicate,
in front of everyone.
Jurieu handled it well too.
It was a trying moment, and you were
admirable. My compliments.
You can go now.
I won't be needing you now.
Oh, no?
Good night, Madame.
Don't you want children?
Sure I do, Madame.
But they demand a lot of time.
You have to keep after them.
Or else why bother?
That's the beauty of it.
It's your sole preoccupation.
Madame's heard about
the new servant? He's very nice.
His name's Marceau.
Watch out for your husband.
His name's Schumacher.
And Mr. Octave's friend's name
is André Jurieu.
So my aviator's not all that bad.
You sure smell nice. Perfume?
- Leave me alone!
Something's cooking!
Not in bed yet?
- So that's it.
- That's what?
It's working out. Happy?
Delighted. Now we can
put our cards on the table.
But you'd better hide your hand.
My good man, I hadn't heard
about that radio business.
It confirms my opinion
that our little Christine has class.
And that's a rare thing nowadays.
Sleep well, General.
What do you say?
- About what?
- Everything. It's going well.
I'm getting the hell out.
Oh, no, not after
all the trouble I went to.
You're here, you stay.
Do you like pillows?
I can't stand 'em.
You finished bouncing around?
Sorry, Saint-Aubin.
I shouldn't have shot that pheasant.
I thought it was in my range,
but it was yours.
No, it was clearly yours.
- No, it was past the pine tree.
- It was yours, my dear fellow.
You're too kind.
You'll have the seventh blind.
It's a bit far,
but there are plenty of pheasant.
Saint-Aubin, you're his neighbor.
- The beaters come from where?
- From there.
- Then the game will come this way.
At least we'll be upwind.
Schumacher will show you
to your blinds.
- Madame de Marras?
- I know where.
Mr. Jurieu,
you can go up that way.
You have to get some height
ahead of the beaters.
A lot of game
try to escape over the road.
- You coming with me?
- There?
They'll take us for rabbits.
- Don't be silly.
That's right, the last blind.
Happy being out here?
Very happy.
And far from the chatterers.
Say, Octave...
did you see Christine
with La Chesnaye?
- What'd they do now?
- Disgusting! They're overdoing it.
They have every right to.
They're married.
I hate her.
You're going through a rough time,
but you'll get over it.
Trust my experience.
It'll take a while, but you will.
One morning you'll wake up
and you'll notice the concierge's
daughter has gorgeous eyes.
There, you're cured.
To wake up I have to fall asleep.
But I can't sleep!
So I've noticed.
You can really be a pain at night.
Ready on the left?
Let's go.
Gentlemen, your positions!
Move it on the left.
Move ahead.
Stay close.
Flush 'em out.
- Jackie, do you enjoy hunting?
- Yes, Aunt. Don't you?
I missed them all.
I'm a poor shot today.
- You two were talking too much.
- Anyway, I'm sick of hunting.
Simple enough.
We'll take up winter sports.
Shall we display the kill?
No. Do that at the château.
That pheasant there on the left...
Sorry, sir, but this time it's mine.
You can't keep pulling this.
Last time I didn't complain.
Try to understand.
I get a bead on a pheasant,
and bang!
He shoots it down in front of me!
That's a bit rich!
They have a fine sport
in Austria: Hunting woodcock.
- At night?
- At dawn.
- I have something to tell you.
- Go ahead.
It's a secret.
May I borrow him, General?
- If you give him back.
- Have no fear.
None of that, Saint-Aubin.
Some people are really clumsy
with their guns.
Know what happened to poor George
last year at the Malvoisies?
He took his gun from his loader
in such a way
that he blasted his thigh to pieces.
He was dead in 20 minutes.
Wasn't that a good one, Christine?
Deyeux said, "Your day is done
with game bag full and empty gun."
- Jackie, it's yours!
- Where? I can't see a thing!
But where?
- There! Aim at the rabbit, not me.
We lost him.
You're the most
deliciously clumsy of women.
Am I?
- You are.
- I wish I were even clumsier.
- Why?
- So you'd kiss me more often.
Easy enough.
You know, Jackie...
I don't love you.
I know.
But you're wasting
your time with my aunt.
So you know.
It's no joke.
You're in pain and so am I.
The field master was lousy.
Mr. André shot poorly.
His lordship is a better shot.
You finished, kids?
I had no luck despite my position.
It can happen.
- Are you cold, Madame?
- Not when I walk.
When the sun goes down,
the temperatures plummet.
A squirrel!
If I only had my gun...
- Why? I'm fond of squirrels.
- They're charming but destructive.
Take a look.
How marvelous!
It looks so close
I could almost touch it.
Field glasses always come in handy.
This one's small enough to carry.
Their lenses are so fine
and their shape so practical
that at a short distance
you can watch that squirrel up close
without frightening it.
Fine. So you'll tell
Christine everything.
To what end?
- To hurt you.
Charming of you!
I hate suffering alone.
Misery loves company.
I want to see your face
when Christine leaves you.
And she will if I tell her.
I don't doubt it.
You really love her.
You've stopped loving me?
- Let's change the subject.
I'm like the shepherd Paris
without the apple. It's grotesque.
Please give me an answer.
No, I don't love you anymore.
I'm very fond of you, but...
But I bore you.
The words you come up with, my dear.
The right ones.
I give up. You can fight hatred,
but not boredom.
Well, the whole thing's
getting to me, too.
Seeing you play shepherd
to your Viennese shepherdess
makes me want to yawn.
I'm leaving.
- That would be best.
Yes, I'm leaving.
But bid me a tender farewell.
Not farewell. Good-bye.
No, farewell.
But a beautiful farewell.
For a moment, I want to go back
three years in time.
When Christine didn't exist.
Take me in your arms as you did then.
I'll close my eyes
and believe in everything
I could desire.
Come now, Geneviève.
Don't say a thing.
Kiss me.
- My dear...
Extraordinary!
A moorhen!
You could count its feathers.
- Still see it?
- No.
Here, Madame.
Two feet away from the tree.
Three if we use your feet.
I want to see it, too.
Isn't it sweet!
Let me see.
It's my turn.
Whatever you're looking at
seems damn interesting.
Very interesting.
'Morning, your ladyship.
- You're leaving?
- Yes, I am.
- Not staying for our party?
- I'm expected in Paris.
- You can phone.
- No, it's better if I go.
Better?
For whom?
For you?
For me, then?
My dear Geneviève,
can we speak frankly?
Am I a troublesome wife?
How could you be
troublesome to me?
Have I ever tried to hinder
your relationship with my husband?
You know?
Like everyone else.
Good old Robert.
He's so kind, so sensitive.
But he's like a child.
He's incapable of hiding a thing.
How true.
When he tries to lie,
you can tell right away.
He blushes before speaking.
His nose almost starts growing.
He has such tact.
I only have one complaint:
His habit of smoking in bed.
Isn't it awful, though!
And the ashes!
- The sheets!
- All burnt!
- The holes!
- As if beds were for smoking!
I ask you.
So you'll stay?
I don't know anymore.
Women should help each other out
once in a while.
If you stay,
my husband will look after you
and a little less after me,
which would suit me fine
right now.
André Jurieu?
André's very kind and very decent,
but too sincere.
Sincere people are such bores.
It depends what for.
What will you wear tonight?
A Tyrolian outfit. And you?
I didn't prepare anything.
Come with me.
We'll find some fabric.
Do you know any Tyrolian dances?
Wait, it must go like this.
No, like this.
Unbelievable!
Our shoes have vanished.
- My boots are missing.
- So are mine.
My wife's shoes are gone.
- Corneille will find them.
- I'll see to it.
What will you wear tonight?
I thought it over all night.
I'm going to dress as a bear.
Wait. I left the price tag on.
It's a fine cape.
Warm and waterproof.
But it's not flattering.
"Some men require not
reputation's yoke.
Their first sword's thrust
can be the master stroke.
The eye was in the grave
and was watching Cain."
Getting used to your new job?
She loves me.
Loves me not.
Loves me.
She loves me.
I hurt you.
- On the contrary. I'm glad.
- Why?
- You're close to me.
- Silly.
Leave us alone or I'll tell Madame
and you'll be fired!
- What are you doing here?
- I'm on duty.
We're on duty.
The boots, my good man!
All the men are waiting.
There's a house revolution!
Don't blame me.
Blame this big bully here.
- Why are you here?
- I came to see my wife.
This is hardly the moment.
Their party's tonight. Off you go.
I catch you with her again,
I'll fill you full of lead!
Stop bothering the staff.
We're busy enough as it is.
See? You're bothering the staff.
We're a hit.
Encore.
She's so annoying! Come on...
Author!
Feeling gay
we proudly made our way
Out to the racetrack
our hearts unafraid
Our step was brisk
We couldn't risk
Missing the military parade
All together now!
Where'd she go?
We must talk!
- Where is she?
- Who?
- Christine.
- Dunno. Help me out of this.
Berthelin.
- Don't bother me now.
I drank too much.
I don't know what I'm doing.
That's good.
- Aren't we playing anymore?
- I've had enough of this show.
Why'd I dress up like this, then?
Help me out of this bearskin.
- We're busy.
Busy!
- Help me out of this.
- I'm busy.
Have you seen my wife?
I'm looking for her.
For Christ's sake,
who'll help me out of this skin?
- I'm dying to play belote.
- A two-hander?
Ask the general.
Have you seen Madame?
I don't mean to be a nuisance,
but I can't manage.
You're a nice fellow, but...
- But I can't take it off by myself!
- Now's not the time.
And Christine?
What've you done with her?
You'll find out soon enough.
Let me just get this off.
Then they'll see!
Come here.
I'll take your bearskin off.
About time!
If she still loved you,
she wouldn't be with Saint-Aubin.
Let's leave together.
I live here.
I can't just walk out.
You and your sense of property!
As if a house were that important!
I must see Christine first.
Pull!
- You haven't seen me.
- Why?
- Schumacher's after me.
- What for?
On account of his wife.
We were playing around.
He saw us and he's not happy.
Oh, your lordship...
women are charming.
I like them a lot.
Too much, in fact.
But they spell trouble.
You're telling me.
- You've got it bad, too?
- Somewhat.
Ever wish you were an Arab?
- No. What for?
- For the harem.
Only Muslims show a little logic
in matters of male-female relations.
They're made like us.
- If you say so.
They always have a favorite.
But they don't kick the others out
and hurt their feelings.
If you say so.
I don't want to hurt anyone,
especially not a woman.
It's the story of my life.
- But that takes money.
Even with money,
I still hurt everybody:
My wife, my mistress
and even myself.
Whether it's to have a woman,
leave her or hold on to her,
first I make her laugh.
That way, her guard's down
and you have your way with her.
Why don't you give it a try?
Because it takes talent.
Naturally.
Would you mind doing me a favor?
- Gladly. What?
Check if the coast is clear.
If Schumacher's not at this end,
I'll slip out the kitchen.
- Use the terrace.
- Too much light.
- Stay here. I'll take a look.
- Thanks, your lordship.
- What are you doing here?
- Nothing.
You're restricted
to the hallways tonight.
Move into my bathroom!
You're needed.
- Is it time?
- Just about.
Where's Mr. Saint-Aubin?
I don't know, honestly.
Excuse me!
Where's André?
You realize I've been looking for you
for the past half hour?
By what right?
Yes, by what right?
You're being indiscreet.
Maybe so, but this time
I demand an explanation.
I refuse to give one.
- You can't order Christine around.
- Then you'll give me one.
I'll box your ears, sir.
- Just try, sir.
André, please!
My dear Christine, I'm sorry.
He'll receive my seconds
in the morning.
Mornings, I sleep.
I may have to throw them out.
- You won't duel?
- Not with you.
- You won't live it down.
- That's a laugh.
In my opinion,
you're a most contemptible coward.
You're putting me
in an inferior position.
You mustn't fight.
I'm going to break that clown's neck.
Clown?
Stay out of this.
So I'm a coward?
See to Saint-Aubin.
Why weren't you at Le Bourget?
Because...
I love you, André.
I never wanted to admit it.
But now I have a right to tell you.
I love you.
This is wonderful.
I'd given up hope.
What are we going to do?
We'll go away.
- Where?
- Anywhere.
- When?
- Right away.
I love you, Christine.
I think I can make you happy.
I've dreamed only
of the joy of being with you.
So I know...
this joy doesn't come as a surprise.
Are you afraid?
I must tell La Chesnaye.
What for?
It's only proper that I do.
Listen to me.
I can't run off
with the wife of a host
who calls me friend
and shakes my hand
without an explanation.
But since we're in love,
what difference can it make?
Even so, Christine,
there are still rules.
We went and kicked up our heels
Without drum or fife
we looked for thrills in life
We went and kicked up our heels
Though we each have a wife
we kicked up our heels
Dear friends, I have the pleasure
of showing you my latest acquisition.
It's the high point of my career
as a collector of musical
and mechanical instruments.
I think you'll like it.
I'll let you decide.
One...
Two...
Music!
If he bothers you,
come and get me.
I'll put him in his place, and fast.
- What are you doing here?
- I came down for an apple.
- Where's Marceau?
- Am I his keeper?
- Where you going?
- Upstairs with the others.
Get me a drink.
I'm leaving tomorrow,
and you're coming with me.
Whatever you say, Edouard.
I'll take you to Alsace.
Poachers, crooks, the likes of
Marceau we know how to handle.
A squeeze of the trigger
one night in the woods,
and that's settled.
Of course.
To hell with their money.
It's stupid to work for others
when you can be your own master.
And Alsace must be so beautiful,
with all those tall fir trees,
all that snow, and the storks.
Stop it! Do you hear me?
Let go!
Let go, Lisette!
For the last time!
Do you hear me?
I won't say it again!
No, André, I'll leave with you
right now or never.
We must walk out
with our heads high.
You'll thank me later.
Sorry, Madame.
I'll murder you!
Well, now...
Mr. Jurieu.
You have what you wanted.
You're stealing my wife.
- No, just give me five minutes.
I'll give you this, bastard!
Repeat that?
What's going on?
Let's get out of here.
Hold on!
Thief!
Are you crazy?
- I've had enough!
- What is it?
I just told your friend
that I love him.
Well, it's about time!
You really love him?
I don't know anymore.
Already? What'd he do to you?
He kept talking... about propriety.
He suggested that I spend a month
with his mother in the country
while he settled things
with La Chesnaye.
What did you expect?
That he'd take me in his arms,
kiss me and take me away.
Poor little Christine.
There's one thing you forget:
You see, he's a hero.
- I'll have his hide!
- You're crazy!
I've had it!
I'll break your neck!
- Was that a bullet?
- A bullet.
- From a gun?
- From a gun.
A bullet from a gun.
Does that surprise you?
- Christine disappeared.
- Christine disappeared!
Tonight...
Christine disappeared!
So it goes!
You fools! Didn't you see her
leave with Octave?
I don't blame her.
If you two think you're any fun!
Don't worry.
You'll find her someday.
Geneviève, please!
And now, darling,
let's talk about the two of us.
When are we leaving?
This isn't the moment!
I have other worries!
Your father walked by
without even a look.
And we hid behind a door.
The musicians were already
on their feet.
And out there,
the audience was applauding.
- The old atmosphere!
- Sure was.
The setting was strange.
It was meant to look
like a parlor in green and gold.
The kind of green
only the English can come up with.
And your father... what elegance!
He crossed the stage,
oblivious to everything.
The house went wild.
The king here...
As hard as he could.
He took his baton
from the first violin.
As usual.
And just like in a dream...
Leave me alone.
You dirty louse!
Let go!
Not another attraction?
This is too much.
- Enough is enough.
- I hate gunshots.
That will do, Schumacher!
- Get off my back!
- What?
André, please help me
calm her down.
Corneille, put an end to this farce!
- Which one, your lordship?
- Schumacher and company!
Right away.
You were standing here?
Yes, Madame.
And I have to thank you.
Thank you.
- Don't mention it!
- What's the dose?
- Two.
Give me four.
Sleeping pills?
I hate sleeping pills!
Be reasonable.
Where are you going?
- To dance!
- You can dance in bed.
- Yes, my love. I'm going to bed.
Yes, darling, I'm going to bed.
You really need it.
Go back to your room.
I'm asking you, go back inside.
Calm down, my dear.
We'll see each other tomorrow.
Good night.
The general!
Cigarette?
Turning in so soon, General?
Yes, I'm turning in.
I wanted to pay my respects
to Christine. Where is she?
A headache.
- Turning in because of that incident?
- Not at all.
- A slight dispute.
- Of course. Good night.
Where's Christine?
Something must be wrong.
She was tired and turned in.
- Really? And Geneviève?
- A bit weary, that's all.
She's so sensitive.
The staff was a bit excited tonight.
They're entitled to some fun, too.
We thought it was an act.
Had I known,
I would have stopped him.
It's all right. Sleep well.
My respects to your wife.
Kiss her for me.
Going already?
It's early yet.
If Christine has the flu,
try a footbath with mustard flour.
- Can't we see Christine?
- She's resting.
Great evening! This would have been
impossible in Tourcoing.
We once danced a farandole.
Charming, but so old-fashioned.
Of course. Good night.
Just a minute.
Was there a lot of damage?
Was anyone injured?
I just did an inspection.
None of the guests were hurt.
The stuffed birds suffered a bit,
and I found a bullet in a door.
Not to mention the glassware.
I have no choice but to dismiss you.
It breaks my heart, but I can't
expose my guests to your firearms.
It may be wrong of them,
but they value their lives.
When must I leave?
Straightaway. At once.
Corneille will pay you
some compensation.
I never want
to hear your name again.
- You're coming with me?
- I'm going to Madame.
To say good-bye to her?
I told you before! If Madame
still wants me, I'm staying.
- Isn't it excessive?
- Do as I say.
Very well.
Come with me.
My good man,
I have to ask you to leave, too.
I can't dismiss Schumacher
and leave you here with his wife.
It'd be immoral, you understand?
I understand.
No hard feelings.
Before I go,
I want to tell you how grateful I am.
You tried to help me up
by making me a domestic.
I'll never forget that.
Don't try to soften me up. Just go.
I've enough troubles as it is.
What a night!
Where were we?
- I asked you for five minutes.
Granted.
How good of you.
But you have quite a right hook.
You're too kind.
Where can we talk?
- In the dining room.
Yes, of course.
But first, accept my apologies.
- You don't have to...
You must.
I behaved like a real roughneck.
I was no better.
Know what our little athletic
display reminded me of?
I sometimes read articles
in the papers
about some Italian roadworker trying
to seduce a Polish laborer's wife.
It ends in a stabbing.
I never believed
such things happened. But they do!
I have an excuse.
I love Christine.
- And I don't?
I love her so much
I want her to leave with you.
Since her happiness depends on it.
But I'm glad it's with someone
from our set.
But still...
something bothers me.
- What?
- Your profession.
- What about it?
- Christine has a certain lifestyle.
You're young and famous.
You could have an accident.
- What optimism!
- One has to consider it.
What would
your financial situation be?
What peace after all that noise.
Are they all gone?
- Looks like it.
Good.
I must talk to you
about André again.
You have to understand.
It's the plight of all heroes today.
In the air, they're terrific.
But when they come back to earth,
they're weak, poor and helpless.
Clumsy as children.
They can cross the Atlantic,
but not the Champs-Elysées
outside the crosswalk.
That's how they are.
Look at the moon with its halo.
It will rain tomorrow.
I was looking for you.
I was worried.
Why?
- You're not mad at me?
- Not at all.
It's not our fault
if men are all mad.
- So I can stay?
- Of course.
I'm so happy!
Come inside.
You can't be out like this
on a November night.
You knew about Mme. De Marras
and my husband?
But it began before your marriage.
At a summer resort.
You see? Everybody knew.
And you never said a word.
- We didn't want to hurt you.
- Obviously.
For the last three years,
my life's been built on a lie.
It's been on my mind
since I saw them at the hunt.
And suddenly I understood.
That's also part of the times.
Today everyone lies.
Pharmaceutical fliers, governments,
the radio, the movies,
the newspapers.
So why shouldn't simple people
like us lie as well?
Let's go for a walk.
- I'll get your coat.
- I'm too warm.
That's because you're not well.
Take my cape.
It's not very fancy,
but you won't catch cold.
You up the creek?
So am I.
Did you see her again?
Me neither.
She said she'd stay with Madame.
With Madame!
She's not married to you,
but to Madame.
What'll you do now?
I'll go back to my little cabin
and get back to work.
Back to your poaching?
What's it to you,
now that he threw you out?
You must have poached
a few pheasant yourself.
A few rabbits.
I have an idea.
I'm gonna get myself
a license as a game dealer.
If a cop stops me -
"What've you got there?"
I say, "In my basket?
Ten wild rabbits,
which I have a license to sell.
Good day, Officer."
Have a cigarette.
And you?
What'll you do now?
I'll stay in the area.
Because of my wife.
I want her back.
- What are you doing?
- Spitting in the water.
It's all I know how to do in life.
Come now.
What's the matter?
- Nothing.
It's just unpleasant to be reminded
what a failure I am.
A leech!
If I didn't have a few tolerant friends,
I'd starve to death.
But you know how
when I was young,
I also thought my day would come.
The contact with an audience,
that's what I wanted to have.
It must be an overwhelming feeling.
To think that I missed out on it!
So I feed myself a lot of nonsense,
imagine that it did happen.
But it takes a drink.
Back on the porch,
I almost thought it had happened.
But after that comes the fall.
You have a rough time,
but you get used to it.
Beautiful night.
Look at the moon.
Aren't you cold?
No. What about you?
Put your hood up.
- It's Lisette.
- With Octave. The skunk!
You sure it's her?
- She's wearing her cape.
The one I gave her.
- I'm cold.
- Let's go back.
Not to the château.
Never again.
In that case,
here in the greenhouse.
- What are they saying?
- I can't hear a thing.
Got your gun on you?
Let him have it.
I used up my bullets on you.
Poor guy.
But my father wasn't like that.
He was a hero, too.
A hero in his own way.
But when you think of your father,
you're unfair to other men.
Not at all.
You, you're a fine fellow.
- I'm a failure.
No, you're not.
But you need someone
to take care of you.
I'll take care of you.
It's too late. I'm too old.
You fool.
You know...
it's you I love.
Do you love me?
Yes, Christine.
I love you.
Then kiss me.
On the mouth, like a lover.
- I'll kill them both.
- Not her.
Both of them.
I'll get my gun.
You can't. Not her.
Come with me.
Why don't I stay here
just to keep an eye on 'em?
No, we stick together.
There's a train at Lamotte-Beuvron
at 3:00 a.m. Let's take it.
I'll get your coat.
Where's Christine?
I'm worried.
Don't worry.
She's with Octave.
You can trust him.
After all, you met her through him.
I don't blame him.
He's a decent fellow. Very decent.
I know.
I believe in little, but I may start
believing in friendship.
But Octave
is someone special.
- Where's Madame?
- Get her coat.
Her coat.
Very well.
Somebody pinched my hat.
Just great!
- This is wrong.
- Why wrong?
When it's just for fun,
it doesn't matter.
But for living together,
the young are for the young
and the old for the old.
Did you find my hat?
And you don't have any money.
Madame needs lots of things.
What will you do without money?
They trampled it.
It's all ruined.
I speak my mind.
You're making a mistake.
Madame won't be happy with you.
Will you take me with you?
Sure. You'll join us later.
Where's Christine?
She's waiting for you.
Waiting for me?
In the greenhouse
over the footbridge.
Bring her this.
Hurry! In the greenhouse.
You mustn't catch cold.
- Thanks so much.
I have to kiss you.
You love her too.
Lisette, please. Am I crying?
I'm suffering and I just hate it.
She's alone.
- I'll go talk to her.
- Sure, let's go.
Not you.
Me.
Listen!
It's him.
Christine!
Did you hear a shot
in the park?
In the park?
I was in my room and...
- It's André, isn't it?
- Yes, Miss Jackie.
- And Madame?
- Madame is all right.
Thank you.
Is he dead?
He didn't suffer.
He was hit here.
He dropped like an animal
in the hunt.
He called out for Madame
and it was over.
Did you shoot him?
It was Schumacher.
But I was in it with him.
Hurry, Corneille.
Why didn't you let me go?
What's to become of me now?
Let me go. Madame needs me.
You're going to
give her a kiss.
Give her a kiss
and tell her that I left.
She'll understand.
I'll say good-bye now to you, too.
Good-bye.
- Good-bye, Mr. Octave.
I was so fond of you.
I was fond of you, too.
They need us, Corneille.
By the greenhouse?
Where are you headed?
Back to the woods.
I'll try to pick up
some odd jobs here and there.
And you?
I'm going to Paris.
I'll try to manage on my own.
We may run into each other
again someday.
I doubt it.
But you never know.
Anything's possible.
Good luck.
Will you excuse me?
The greenhouse is off-limits.
- Pointard's on guard.
Work out the formalities
with Corneille.
- I can't bear it!
- Be strong, Miss Jackie.
An educated young lady like you
has to put on a brave face.
People are watching.
I'll take care of her.
Try to get some sleep.
You must be exhausted.
We'll be leaving tomorrow.
It was all a deplorable accident
and nothing more.
My game warden thought
he saw a poacher and fired.
As fate would have it,
André Jurieu paid for this error.
Tomorrow we will leave,
in mourning for this delightful friend,
this wonderful companion
who made us forget
that he was famous.
And now, dear friends, it's chilly.
You're going to catch cold.
I suggest you come inside.
Tomorrow we'll do our duty
for Jurieu.
A new definition
of the word "accident."
No, this La Chesnaye has class.
And that's become rare,
my dear Saint-Aubin.
That's become rare.
THE END