BROOKLYN, NY One hour earlier
You're lying to me.
l'm not. l don't know what you're talking about.
l don't know what you want from me.
l swear l don't .
l have three children.
The first thing you have to learn as a father,
is to know when your children are lying to you.
You're lying to me.
And if you don't stop,
l'm going to use one of those tortures your people are so famous for...
...on your little body, until you tell me what l want to know!
For the last time...
Give me the numbers!
NANJlNG, CHlNA One year earlier
Try it the other way,
it adds up to three hundred and sixty five...
Only one answer is correct.
l mean no disrespect, Mr. Sook,
...but your calculations are wrong.
Mei...
we're going to move you to a different school.
But all my friends are here, and my mother...
Mei. you are so smart, a genius.
You have to go to an appropriate school...
You'll make new friends.
Don't бо be sad Mei, we'll always be your friends.
l hear the kids in Beijing are cool,
you'll have a good time there.
But l don't even like numbers.
l like my friends here.
l don't want new friends.
l don't like math.
Of course you do...
don't worry, we'll send you a letter every week.
You promise? Of course.
Think we want to miss out on having a famous friend
lt's gonna be great, Mei...
THE MEADOWLANDS, NJ
How dare you come here?
You have no right! Mom, mom! Enough! Stop!
You have no right to be here.
You should be in jail.
You get out of here!
- l'm sorry. - l'll kill you.
Piece of garbage!
He should never have been in there with me!
Come on! What, are you crazy man?
Get off!
l never liked you, Luke.
You're a better fighter than ninety percent of the guys you go into the cage with.
But you just let 'em pound on you like you're a side of beef.
You already lost to every chump in the circuit.
But last night, of all nights!
You're supposed to go down in the second, you son of a bitch!
Once. l hit him once!
Where'd you find him, in the fucking playground?
YouTube, you asshole!
The kid is an lnternet sensation, until you put him in a coma.
Which frankly, l do not give a shit about!
But you cost me a million dollars!
Which is nothing compared to what you cost Docheski.
Yeah, you recognize the name?
He was betting on you, big time to take the dive!
And he's going to take it out on me, too.
Because he knows l'm the schmuck who set this whole thing up.
Unless, l deliver your head with a down payment.
You know how the Russians are.
This is my niece, Bai Yu.
Recognize her?
She's in my class at school.
She says you mind is like a computer.
We spoke to your teacher and he said the same thing.
That's why you're here.
Lovely girl.
Computers are so annoying, they leave trails that are easy to follow.
They say what you learn you never forget. ls that so?
Then we will go to your home and kill your mother
for making such a stupid girl.
So they are telling the truth.
Mr. Sook also said your father ran away when you were very little,
left your mother,
And you mother is very ill.
Soon you will be all alone. So you want to be all alone?
Then we will take good care of your mother.
This is Chang, your new father.
He will take you far over the ocean,
where our enemies like to make trouble for us.
Once you are there... You will count for us.
You've got the Wright number, to leave the right message.
Call me when you get this Annie.
Leave right away.
lf you're out, don't go home.
lf l'm scaring you, that's good. Call me.
Annie?
He has some nice videos.
That's it?
l heard you were some kind of tough guy.
No fighting?
You're just going to sit on the floor like a dog who wants to die.
Sorry it had to be so messy.
The boy is still learning.
And l'm not a doctor, but l think she was eating for two.
We're like the Charlie Manson family. No?
My father was going to send someone else, but l'm making my bones.
You make your bones by killing someone who could hurt you back.
And who would that be?
You? Well, why not? You just killed you wife.
l didn't kill her. You did.
But, you want to hurt me?
Good. l'd like to see you try.
Get it over with.
Over? You cost my father money. Made my family look bad.
Now, we're going to make an extra special example out of you.
So, we looked into your records. Not much to find.
Worked for City, Garbage collections, Sanitation.
Good benefits, but no glamor.
Father and mother, dead.
No brothers or sisters.
Which is too bad,
because l would like to take them from you too.
But you loved your wife. We know that.
So, here's the deal. You are free to go.
But we will have eyes on you.
Not always. But when you least expect it, we'll be there.
Anyone you try to make friends with, or even talk to...
...other than ordering a hot dog or something,
will die.
Like your wife. Because of you.
Of course you can always end it.
Jump off a bridge, throw yourself in front of a train.
Damn your eternal soul to Hell.
lf you believe in that kind of bull shit.
Personally l don't , so l'd go for it if l were you.
But, l am not you. Thank God.
So do what you want.
lf you're still here tomorrow, we're going to kill the land lady.
What was her name? Tobolovski, or something.
Mrs. Tobolovski.
Nice lady.
Clean up the mess, Garbage man.
Alright, she's your daughter, and she's an American citizen.
l ain't going to ask what the deal is with her.
That is your business.
But l'm going to tell you, pulling strings is hard work.
And hard work don't come free.
Your price, Captain Wolf?
Chinatown Precinct take goes up twenty percent.
Bronx, hundred twenty first,
Brooklyn Divisions each go up by ten percent.
Monthly.
That's a steep price for a passport and some papers for a little girl.
Things are tough all over.
Chinatown gets up ten percent.
Bronx and Brooklyn will settle for the current rate.
And the fact that we won't start shooting cops and their families in the streets...
...like dogs at the first sign of pressure.
Things are tough all over.
Hey man, l know you.
l saw your fight in Jersey, it was really good.
You knocked that guy out.
No. That was some good shit, man.
Great fight.
Wei Lu's store, twenty six thousand this week.
Twenty six last week.
Hojin is even at fifteen thousand a week.
His store on Bowery St showed a profit for May.
CHlNATOWN, NY One year later Cheng Sao, forty two last week, forty two point five this week...
Cheng Sao, forty two last week, forty two point five this week...
His shop is showing a seven percent increase in earnings every month.
ln total Mott Street's earnings are up seventy two thousand,
five hundred and thirty five dollars.
Our other stores are all up five percent...
weekly profits should be between six thousand and eight thousand each.
And the Casino?
Eight hundred thousand last week.
This week also eight hundred thousand.
Exactly eight hundred thousand.
lt's almost eight hundred.
l'm not asking you if it's almost eight hundred.
l want the exact number.
Seven hundred eighty five thousand three hundred and seventy dollars.
And the week before?
lt's losing money.
You'll have a new floor boss tonight.
lf the tally comes up short again, he won't be the only one who suffers.
What?
Why?
Because he was hurting business, and business is a serious matter.
l understand business.
But why beat him if you're going to kill him anyway.
lf you're asking me that, it means you still don't understand business.
Now be quiet and eat.
The chicken's gone, l killed them. My grandmother used to sing.
Oh fuck you! Fuck you!
No, no. Okay, you're wet. Pink.
Oh nothing, nothing.
You can't come in the shelter.
l'm just trying to get something to eat, man!
You ain't going to eat in here. You got to get a shirt first. Just go back, man.
Wrap it up. Lights out in five.
Wrap it up.
Come on guys.
Nice kicks.
They better be here in the morning...
...or you'll be wearing them on your ears.
Because l'll chew your feet off at the God damn ankles.
l could really use some new shoes, man.
l'll do what ever you want, you know?
Whatever gets you through the night.
l just l can't take...
Shut up, shut up.
Shut up and take 'em. l've still got my old ones.
Go get those feet looked at.
Gangrene is setting in.
l will.
Thank you, man.
Jesus loves you, brother.
Jesus loves you.
Lights out. Wake up call is seven AM. Lights out.
Lights out.
Mei, l have sad news.
l heard them talking.
Your mother is gone.
She died two weeks ago in the hospital.
They weren't going to tell you.
But l'm telling you, so that you can pray for her soul to find its way to heaven.
Please don't say anything. lf they found out l told you.
l won't say anything. Thank you.
Everybody up. Shelter needs to be cleared by nine AM.
Remember, reservations for tonight must be made before by three thirty.
So you want to tell us what happened?
Someone liked his shoes.
Funny guy. You think this is a joke?
You know, you guys are a Hell of a crack Security Squad.
You were right here. You could have said something.
But you were too busy sleeping off this contraband. Right?
Come into this shelter again,
and l will run your raggedy ass back out into the street.
l want you to take this to your room and l want you to memorize it. Then...
l've memorized it.
This is an extremely important number.
For your mother's sake, answer me carefully.
Are you sure you have memorized it?
l can repeat it for you, but it would be long and boring.
Look at that. here hardly for a year, and already she has American attitude.
lf she says she remembers it,
she remembers it.
l can vouch for that.
Then l have a very important job for you.
Hey! Watch where you're going, man!
You could get your ass kicked for that. Okay? Huh?
Four fifty five.
lf you got no money, you got to get out of line.
l got money.
He doesn't have any money. Look at him.
Mister, l told you, if you don't have money you have to leave. Okay?
You have to get out of line. People are waiting.
Come on buddy, you have to go.
ls this guy giving you trouble?
He's crazy officer, get him out of here.
Alright come on, let us go.
Hey you! Come on, lets go! Out, on the street!
Let us go funny boy. You want to be a clown, go join the circus, not in my Precinct.
You hear me? l don't want to see you around here. Hey.
Jesus Christ.
Look at what the cat dragged in.
Unbelievable.
Look at him.
Look at him?
How about the smell?
l'll call the boys.
Mei, these are your instructions:
Chang will take you to meet a man who has a second number...
You will memorize it.
Then you'll be taken to another location,
where your final instructions will be given to you.
You miss us partner?
Welcome back to the force.
You're learning fast.
lf you do this job well,
you have a bright future in business with Uncle Han.
l'm sorry. l can't let them have you.
How's your day been, Luke?
Started lousy. But it's looking up.
Luke Wright, the Big Apple's hardest cop.
Once upon a time. Always could take a shot.
But you know what your real talent is? You're a uniter.
l mean, who'd have thought that us and the Ruskies
would ever be on the same page about anything?
Not me.
Nice to see you, rat.
l've been wanting to do this ever since the day you opened your big fucking mouth!
We heard what Docheski did to you. l mean, l had to laugh.
l mean, we felt bad for Annie and all but them's the breaks.
She knew who she was with.
When word come up you were on the street you were back.
We couldn't believe our fucking ears.
Now, why would you come back?
Why wouldn't you disappear somewhere far away?
Like the Moon.
l missed home.
You were one of us, Luke. We were a team.
We were family. Then you threw us under the bus.
We were Kings, you son of a bitch!
Now, we are a bunch of god damned serfrs!
Whoa, whoa. Hey, hey, hey, easy Benoit.
When you come back, We figured you wanted to die.
You know, we got a pool going on when you're going to end it, and how.
You know. Bus, train...
l got my money on suicide by cop.
Come on, take it.
Take a shot. Come on.
Annie's waiting for you.
Question is, do you really think she wants to see you again?
Actually, my real talent
is costing other people money.
You ought to know that, Lasky. You're going to lose that bet.
Unless you want to shoot me in the back.
lt wouldn't be your first time.
Why don't you just end it?
What are you waiting for,
more people around you to die?
What are you waiting for?
For the last time. Give me the numbers.
You're a very brave girl, and clever.
But do you know how exactly what you can do?
Where you're going to be and when?
Someone told you.
That's right. Can you guess who?
Let her in.
A friend. The one who told you who told you about your poor mother.
When the scum who took you from home would not.
She's working for us with a smile.
Mei, l tell these men what they want to know,
and they pay me lots and lots of money.
Do the same and they will help you too.
You are a stupid woman.
ln English.
You gave them what they want, now they're going to kill you.
l said, speak in English.
Well?
She won't tell me anything.
My father is a patient man.
l am not.
Tell him what he wants to know, or l will kill you.
NYPD, open the door!
What the Hell? This is the Police. We got a report of a disturbance.
Look, you can make this easy, or you can it hard.
Open the door, or we come in by force!
Bull shit Blue!
You come in here, you go out feet first. l swear on my mother!
Yeah, they're in there Captain.
l don't know what the Hell you're looking for
but they are not cooperating.
You'd better get down here before things go to Hell.
Negative, negative, this is big.
l'm going back to the station to monitor the city.
l'll get back to you.
Alright, we've got them pinned down, you know what l want.
We have a deal.
Get the girl. Alive if you can, dead if you can't .
We go in, Brooklyn stake goes up by ten percent.
That's the new deal.
Hold on, l got an incoming call.
Hey, Emile. What's up?
Back your men off, Wolf.
Whatever the Chinese offer to you, l'll up it by five percent.
Get here back here!
Alright Quan, l have the Russians offering up Brooklyn's stake by seven percent, Bronx is the same.
l don't know what to tell you.
l talked to my guys, they're willing to go to war over this.
You know, you're going to be stuck between us and the Russians and us like Hitler; fighting on two fronts.
So you had better think hard about this one.
Ten percent, both precincts; final offer.
Hey Mack, both these bastards are willing to pay a stiff price
for this little Chink girl.
What ever she's got, l want it.
So what is our play?
l get the Russians to drop their guard, you go in.
lf she catches a bullet l want you to take out everyone
last one of those Bolshevik scumbags.
Alright Emile, your offer is good.
l'm going to call my guys off, but only because l like you better.
Bullshit. You're a greedy bastard, Wolf.
You got the scent of something big and now you want it all for yourself.
But l have to pay something before you send your men in gun blazing.
She is gone.
What do you mean, she is gone?
l mean, she escaped.
And will all your men out there l can't follow.
l offer you a truce until we find her.
Trust me, if the Chinese find her first,
that will be a thing you regret as long as you live.
Docheski,
what does she have?
Do we have a truce, Captain Wolf?
The girl is Chinese, eleven years old.
She speaks Mandarin and English.
Her photo is being disseminated.
You are to find her and bring her straight to Center Street.
Move now, she is headed for subway.
The police have screwed us.
ls that so?
That's all you have to say?
You're an idiot.
lf you don't find the girl before the police do...
your head will be gone in an instant.
Let's go to war.
Sorry, Annie.
Lost my lock on the Russian Cell on " J" Street.
Sounds like they went into the Subway Station,
Manhattan bound.
You? The garbage collector?
You got bad information.
l never collected garbage.
l disposed of it.
Don't lose sleep. He had it coming.
Are you all right?
Get out, get out. Move.
lt's okay.
When found, she is to be brought to Captain Wolf at Center Street.
Whoa, easy. Easy there, Hon. We're the police...
...everything's alright.
Hey, what's you name, Hon?
This is her. l don't know, they all look alike to me.
You got that picture up? Yeah, let me see.
Fucking New York City,
don't see somebody for years...
...and you bump into them twice in the same day.
Hey, hey. l'm not going to hurt you.
What the Hell did you do, kid?
You know, those men who are chasing you are bad.
You want to tell me why they're after you?
Do you understand me?
Do you speak English?
What do you mean Chemyakin and the others disappeared? Someone else has taken her.
No, not the police.
He nearly killed a couple of cops.
Not the Chinese, either.
l don't know who the hell he is.
Then kill him, and take the girl alive.
lf you can't , then kill her too.
The other way. Cars go the other way!
Are you crazy, man?
Hold on.
This goes on, a lot of innocent people are going to get hurt.
You want that?
Good, then do what l say.
Are you okay?
Let us go.
l'm not five years old.
Then keep up.
You had her, and you lost her.
No Captain, we didn't lose her.
She was taken by force.
The Russians. No, not the Russians.
Well, it was Luke Wright.
What? - Captain Wolf. - Not now, Deke.
The mayor wants you, Captain.
Put him through on two. He is not on the phone.
He wants you at the mansion. Yesterday.
Here you go.
Thank you Mister lvanov.
Thank you.
Mister lvanov? Here you are Mister lvanov.
Room 1012 on the tenth floor.
Thank you.
You like a nice hotel.
l never stayed in a nice hotel.
No one is going to look for us in one.
She's in the area,
but there's a lot of interfrerence...
l can't be more specific.
Wait...
wait!
Got her.
Man, would l like a shower.
You could use one.
l could've just let those Russians grab you on the train.
Why did you save me?
l didn't save you.
You saved me.
l'm paying you back.
My name is Luke.
Mei.
You have parents, Mei?
l have a father.
What's his name?
Chang Quan.
lf we're talking about the same guy,
he didn't have any kids last time l checked.
Any that he made since wouldn't be a day over three years old.
l'm adopted.
Did he bring you over from back home?
Chang isn't the fatherly type.
Why are you here, Mei?
To count.
You were send over by the old guy, Chang's boss. What's his name?
Old school.
No computers, no electronic trails.
Just what you have in our head. Right?
You know Jiao Han?
l know of him.
He told me a number, a very long number.
l was going someplace where l would get another number and instructions.
But the Russians came and shot everyone.
Then the police came and l ran away.
Now you know everything. Happiness for you?
You want to go back to Han Jiao?
l make too much trouble. Bad business.
After l do what he asks, he kills me.
Good business. So, what about this number?
lt is long boring number.
l can tell it to you.
lt wouldn't mean anything to me.
But how do you know it is one number and not a bunch of separate numbers?
You're a crazy man. But not so stupid.
ls there anything interesting to you about these numbers?
Maybe a few of them.
Why?
Because they have a three or a seven before them.
All the numbers are random.
But, five of them have a seven before it.
And eight of them have a three before it.
That's too many times to be random.
lt's a code.
What else?
Nothing.
So, it's the three and the seven that are interesting.
Because they happen too many times to be random.
Because they're not numbers, they're words.
Right-left, or left-right.
Old school,
a combination to a safe.
ln the hotel?
Where? That's as close as l can track.
What do you have for me?
We're looking for a man now, who is supposed to be with the girl...
He's armed and to be considered extremely dangerous.
Dispatch says he's ...
About five, eleven, brown hair, thirties...
Ah, probably came in here less than a few hours ago.
Sir, we're not allowed to discuss our guests.
So, he's a guest? Did he check in?
l'm sorry, sir. We're not at liberty to...
He would be with a Chinese girl, eleven years old.
l'm her father. And l'm very worried about her.
l'm so sorry. l can call the police for you.
Do that and l blow your brains out.
Now, what room is he in?
What room is he in?
l think maybe, l put him on the tenth floor.
Room!
l swear he didn't have a little girl with him.
Room.
l just need to check. Then check quick.
Before l put a bullet in your brain.
Quick! Put your hands up.
You don't want any part of this!
Hands up so l can see them.
No one leaves the hotel!
Come on!
Ten, twelve. He's in room ten, twelve.
l thought you said no one would look for us here.
lt's off. l turned it off. So no one could call.
lt doesn't need to be on.
Get back!
Get down on the floor!
Everybody get back!
Write down the numbers. Just the ones with the three and seven in front of them. Quick.
You get over there!
Get up!
l'll try to get you someplace safe.
lf we get separated, don't tell them you told me anything. Lie.
lf they try to scare you...
Try? l'm so scared already.
Yeah, me too. Remember, lie.
We're almost there.
lf you see them downstairs try not to kill the girl.
Get back inside.
Follow them! l'm going back down to cut them off.
The cops are here.
Hold them off until l give the word.
Do not let them in!
Everybody stay down!
You ain't going nowhere! Stay!
Everybody's going to sit down!
Go! Get back! Get down!
Go!
Get up! Everybody up.
We're getting out of the hotel.
Up!
Or l start killing you. Up!
At the corner of 58th, we got a suspect.
Hey! Don't move.
Don't move.
lnto the street! Keep moving!
Anyone who doesn't dies like this.
lnto the street!
Go!
Hold your fire!
Suspects in the crowd. We can't lD them.
Hey! Stop right there!
Hey! Hey! What the Hell are you doing?
That's my car!
Look! That guy took my fucking car!
Head downtown, l'll give you an address in a minute.
Shit!
Hey Buddy, you want to give me an address? Piotor lvanovov Hey Buddy, you want to give me an address?
Piotor lvanovov ln a minute, just hold on.
ln a minute, just hold on.
Who's this? Who do you think? lt's Piotor.
Don't you have me in your phone?
Piotor? Police reports said you were found on the subway, with...
Police reports were wrong.
The others got...
What's that?
Sorry, bad connection.
l have the number.
You what? Before the guy grabbed her, we got the number from her...
l've been ducking the cops for hours.
lgor, put this number into your phone.
Go ahead, give it to me.
Are you crazy?
lt's on a piece of paper a kilometer long.
Where are you?
He might be bringing the cops.
Should we clear the place out?
lf there are cops we're better off in a crowd.
Still, we need better positions.
Alright Piotor...
now's your chance to be a hero.
Mamoschka's .
Be here soon.
l'll be there.
He's here,
Luke Wright, back in the city.
ln my city. Actually, he's been back for a while.
A while? What's a while?
Maybe a year, it's hard to say.
Turn that god damned thing off.
Alex.
What's going on Wolf?
And how is Luke Wright involved in it?
l figured l might ask you the same question.
Don't try to game me.
You're not even a pawn,
playing on a board so big you can't even see the edge.
That's all you've ever been.
l know about Luke Wright.
Which is more than you can say until five minutes ago.
What you know about Luke Wright rates less than a paragraph
in a very fat book.
After the towers fell,
and our manpower was spread out tracking terrorist activity...
l was the one who formed the special
task force to deal with the crime that was filling the gap.
And don't you ever fucking forget that l was the one who put you in charge.
l didn't forget, my work made you Mayor.
Your work.
You think Luke was just one of your cops?
When l put together your team, l knew l needed an edge.
No ordinary detectives could give me.
l needed something surgical.
l called friends in places buried so deep they don't officially exist.
They were sympathetic.
A week later they sent Luke Wright.
Those Wise Guys who vanished over the last seven years.
You think that was internecine war?
Those Coke Kings you found in the gutter in Harlem...
Freddy Petrovich in Brooklyn, Tommy Lau in Chinatown.
Luke Wright is a ghost.
A very deadly ghost.
And it worked like a charm, too.
Then you dicks had to get greedy and pad your pockets.
Luke's a killer, but he's an honest one.
When he threatened to take the whole thing to lA...
...it took some people with a lot of bronze stuffed in their pajamas to talk him off the ledge.
Yeah, and my team gets dismantled and we're peons again.
But if Luke Wright's so connected,
how's he wind up in Jersey cage fighting in the B circuit?
Do l look like a shrink?
Get everybody on this.
Once Luke Wright gets on a roll
there's only on man in this city can take him on one on one.
Excuse me. l know this this is a closed door.
But there was just a major gun battle downtown at a hotel.
The media is going nuts. You're going to need to make a statement.
Han Jiao is in the city, also.
He gave this little Chinese girl something.
l don't know what.
-Luke Wright grabbed her before l could. - What?
- l said Luke Wright... - Yeah, yeah...
l heard you the first time.
Close every exit out of Manhattan.
Make sure the neither Wright or the girl gets away; you get commission.
Let 'em go; you got a shovel to dig your own grave.
That girl does not leave this city.
Who was this man who killed the Russians?
l don't know. He didn't tell me.
Did he ask you about the number?
Everyone asked me about the number.
And what did you tell them?
Nothing.
What?
You are lying!
l would never lie to you, Uncle Han.
Call our men back home.
Tell them to kill Mei's mother,
because her daughter is a deceitful liar.
l swear, Uncle Han.
l pretended l didn't speak English, or understand it.
They screamed and shouted but l didn't say anything,
because l knew it would upset you.
l swear on my mother.
We recovered the girl.
But the information might have been compromised.
Should we change our time frame?
lmpossible, now that the whole damn thing has gone super nova.
lf it's going to happen, it's going to happen tonight.
The meeting place needs to be changed.
Where to?
l'll let you know. Here. Right here.
Slow down.
Stop the car.
No. You don't bring no hookers in my cab, man.
Just keep the meter running.
Ladies...
How about a drink.
Good evening.
Good evening. Will you be joining a reservation?
No, we don't have a reservation.
lt will be later tonight,
but we should be able to find you something.
You can sit upstairs, if you like.
Sir, do you have a preference?
l think we'll just get a drink at the bar.
Why don't you give me a kiss, turn around and walk out of here.
But l thought...
Just act like you forgot something outside.
Only, don't come back.
Give me a White Russian please, and a fork.
A fork?
Yeah, one of those.
l never know what to say in these moments.
What moments?
The ones before l kill somebody.
Boss!
What does he drive? And where is it parked?
lt's an SUV in the alley outside.
Vassily.
Not even close.
Who is this? The guy who's been killing your boys all night, Emile.
The guy who has your son tied up in a very dark place.
Now, here's what l want. Do you think l give a shit what you want?
Do you think you can blackmail me, because you have Vassily?
Kill him and go to Hell!
Oh, l'm going to Hell alright.
l'm not going to kill your boy.
l'm going to keep him around. Like a pet.
A very badly treated pet.
l'm going to do things to him that will make me ashamed to look in the mirror afterward.
But l will do them.
Vassily's going to tell me everything he knows about your operation.
And then what you going to do? Tell the police?
You want me to laugh? Who said anything about the police?
l'm going to share the information with the competition.
The one's l haven't already killed.
Anything they don't take from you, l will.
First, l'm going to take your trophy wife.
Then l'm going to take trophy children.
Then l'll leave you with nothing.
When l'm done, you won't even be a memory of a memory.
But that doesn't have to happen.
What do you want?
l want to know what is in the safe?
What safe? The safe the girl gave me the combination too. That safe.
Thirty million dollars.
The kid was on her way to get a second number.
What is in the second safe?
Something worth thirty million dollars.
To who?
No idea.
That is because you are only half smart, Emile.
So, here's the deal.
You tell me where the first safe is. l take the money and let your boy go.
Lie to me, and your world ends. You have my word on that.
ldiot.
l know when a man is working alone. And you're as alone as one can be.
You need a small army to get near that safe.
The kind of army l have.
Had.
lt's been shrinking by the minute.
Last chance before l hang up and go to work on your son.
You going to kill me, garbage man?
You could have taken us out that day, couldn't you?
But you just sat there. Let us ruin you.
Let us make you nothing.
l guess finding out about that safe gave you new motivation, Garbage man?
l wouldn't spend my time talking if l were you.
l'd spend it praying, when this is over,
that little girl is still alive.
Pray.
When and where? The underpass, under the bridge, one hour.
l'm sorry l pointed a gun at you,
when the Russians attacked us, Mei.
lt was... Business. l know.
That's good. lt's good you understand.
We're going to get this done.
And you'll be safe with me and uncle Han
l promise to be a better father to you than the one who left you and your mother.
There's no one in the world who cares more about you.
You know that, don't you?
Well, the gang's all here.
Almost.
Reddick have to call in sick?
He's in the hospital, dickhead! You broke his trachea.
l didn't know a trachea could brake. l hope they can fix it.
Yeah, how 'bout l fix you.
Hey, hey, hey... Not here.
Been a while, Luke.
Can't say l missed you.
So, let us get down to business.
Did you bring what l asked for?
Scotty's ?
Where else?
That's good.
l've been in restaurants all night.
All l got served was lead.
Anyone got a light?
You know what? Screw this!
Look, Cap, You asked us to come here. So we came.
But l ain't going to sit here and listen to this scumbag's big mouth.
Shut up Kolfax.
Still haven't quit, huh?
Hey, what the hell is that? Combination to the safe with thirty million bucks in it.
Whoa, whoa, What the hell you filthy piece of shit.
The only place it exists now is in here.
Remember that next time your little trigger finger gets itchy.
Why would Han Jiao stash it right in the middle of Chinatown's
busiest gambling den?
Because of sleazbucket cops.
Like you Benoit, who collect off of Chinatown's busiest gambling den.
Where else would he be surrounded by dozens of armed men
without attracting police attention?
Alight Captain, how do we know this son-of-abitch is on the level?
Huh? He's a bum. Where'd you get your information?
There's an exchange happening tonight.
The Triad half of the deal is in the safe at the Casino.
No way l could get to it on my own. So l called on you, my old pals.
Thirty million split six ways is still a lot of money.
We're risking a lot, Captain.
You especially. Everybody knows you have a bright future.
Promised by who? Hizzonor?
What carrot is he teasing you with, Wolf?
He's going to let off the street knowing what you know?
Hey, what's that supposed to mean? Meaning his second term is going to come to an end,
and his old on the city goes puff.
Just like that, he's Joe Citizen again.
Thirty million would be a nice retirement package.
What's he giving the Chinks?
lf l knew that, l wouldn't be standing here with you assholes, would l?
Bright future, huh?
Big headlines.
"Hero cops take down New York City's biggest underground gambling operation.
Five million bucks apiece.
No one will ever know about it, just to give it that extra sweet taste.
Alright, who's been in there?
For Christ sake, who's been in there?
Me Cap.
You two, you're on point.
The place is packed with civilians. So exercise some judgement.
Remember, l got the combination.
You want that money? Watch my back.
Hey, where you going?
Don't move!
Hey you! Settle down!
This way!
Jesus!
Warn them!
Lasky, heads up!
Go!
Kolfax, take him out!
Cover him!
Open it! Take it!
Oh fuck! Aww shit!
Aw shit. l got to get out of here.
Aww fuck. Aw Captain...
God, you shit! Shoot a man in the back!
Son of a bitch!
Alright, Mears. Where're we going?
This way.
Move!
We've been attacked...
Not by the Russians. Buy the police l think...
But they're better than police.
We need help. They've killed a lot of our people.
Call Chang. Tell him as soon as he gets that number,
he is to take out their errand boy.
We'll have to decipher the code quickly...
Do as l said!
The Gates of Paradise. Locked and bolted to sinners like us.
Yeah, well let's not wait for an invitation.
Alright you bastard. Get started.
Here's how we do this.
You put down your guns...
...l open the safe.
You want to shoot me, go ahead.
Make your minds up quick, because the real cops will be here soon.
On the floor.
Come on you son of a bitch, what are you trying to pull.
l got right left switched.
lt's going to open.
Oh fuck!
You'll live.
Left, twenty six.
Captain Wolf, what the hell happened in here?
What do you think happened, huh?
We had a raid on the place go bad.
We got dead cops, casualties, get in there will ya!
Captain Wolf, you need an ambulance.
l need a fleet of ambulances! Alright?
Call it in, will ya? l'll take my own busted ass to the hospital.
Not bad.
lf you weren't such a double dealing asshole,
l could almost like you.
Almost. Drive.
lt's a scratch.
l'm not going to kill you.
But l didn't say l was putting you up in the Ritz.
Wolf.
l have your money, Danny.
What?
You heard me.
Thirty million, five thousand and one thousand dollar bills.
- l want to talk... - No. No,
what you want to do is calm down so we can talk like adults.
Shut it, Danny.
l want to talk. But l don't want to talk to you.
l want to talk to your boyfriend.
This is Alex.
lt has been a while, Alex.
How did you get this number?
Come on, Alex. Reach up the Mayor's ass there you are.
A man has got to do, what a man has got to do.
Well, he was a better catch than Annie was anyway.
l never understood how you hooked up with a cow like that.
lt was never about her looks. lt was her sense of humor.
She is not so funny now, is she?
No, she is not, neither am l.
l have the money, Alex.
l had to kill a lot of people to get it, so listen up.
You haven't made the combination exchange yet.
What is in the other safe?
A disk.
Names, money trails...
...when our commanders sent the two of us to help Danny clean up the city,
they attached a price.
ln exchange Danny looked the other way...
...while the assets seized from every group deemed
a terrorist organization were funneled into their private accounts.
lt's amazing what people let you get away with
when they are scared and want to feel protected.
Amazing how many scumbags there are out there waiting to take advantage of it.
- Like you didn't . - l quit.
l bet that helps all those souls
you sent to meet their maker without due process,
rest a whole lot easier.
You thought you could atone by climbing into a cage
and allowing yourself to get beaten to a pulp.
Don't fucking preach at me, Luke.
l'm getting paid for services rendered.
Right. You sell the disk to the Chinese so they can black mail our old honchos.
Take the thirty mil and waltz off with Danny to a Villa in the Bahamas.
Bali, but whatever, eh?
So, now you know. Now what?
Now you're dealing with me.
Alright, l'm turning around.
No you're not.
What are you talking about?
You got the money, the Chinese have nothing l care about.
No, they have something l do.
Give her the combination to your safe.
And she will give you our number. We go to your location, you go to ours.
When we've gotten the disk, we will explain the code.
And you get the cash.
That's the deal.
Let's hear it.
lt's a very long number. You'll want to write it down.
Thank goodness l brought a pen. Huh?
You might want to close your eyes.
Have it your way.
Come on, Luke.
The old place. Just you and me.
You're a friend of Luke's ?
Not as far as you're concerned.
The violence that has rocked the city tonight continued in a bloody gun battle...
...in a Chinatown night club, less than an hour ago.
This is really getting out of hand.
You think? Thanks for that insight.
Your Honor. Alex Rosen is on your private line.
He says that it's urgent.
Excuse me, your Honor... Back in five, don't bother me now.
Why didn't he call me on my cell phone?
l thought l told you to put all my calls through to the Cell phone.
l always told you this place had lousy security standards.
Well, that's because noboby's been crazy enough to come in here and pull a stunt like this.
You got some balls, Luke.
Yeah, amazing l can even walk.
The disk.
What, you think l'm stupid enough to let a gang of Chinese
walk up the front steps and collect it from me in my living room?
lt's in a safe, far away from here.
l don't think you're stupid.
Which is why l don't for a second you gave away the only copy.
l'm going to meet Alex.
First you're going to give me the disk.
Or l'll put bullets in places that won't kill you.
But it will make you spend the rest of your life wishing l had.
Satisfied?
l want to make sure it's not "ABBA's Greatest Hits" .
Alex will kill you, you know?
Yeah, probably.
Jesus Luke, you look like Hell.
Just alcohol,
lack of sunlight, sleep deprivation...
...other than that l feel great.
You know, l was thinking.
How many bodies did we dump in this place?
You know, l didn't keep count.
They were all assholes though. Right?
Let her go, Alex.
Danny called,
told me about your visit.
l have to admit, even l didn't see that one coming.
You have the disk and the money.
What is she to you?
Life.
Well, enjoy it while it lasts.
Because she is the reason yours is going to be a whole lot shorter.
Money, Luke.
The Car.
Or in a bank.
Or in a series of lockers in Grand Central.
Or maybe l donated it to charity.
Out of the goodness of my heart.
lf you want to find out where that money is,
you are going to have to do it the hard way.
Are you alright Mei?
l saw him fight before.
Bad business for you.
Yeah, the worst.
You saved me. Again.
We save each other.
l know how you feel.
Help me get this sack of garbage out of the car.
Make sure he gets to his daddy safe and sound.
Fifty grand.
For your trouble.
l know it don't seem like much. But at least you're going to live to enjoy it.
You want him safe and sound?
After what he did to you?
For her sake.
We meet again, all bets are off.
Most revered Uncle.
Here is twenty nine million, nine hundred and fifty thousand dollars.
We will pay back the remaining fifty thousand, with interest.
But in case you are still angry,
l must tell you this;
l know every account of every operation you have in Chinatown...
and the money routes back to China.
You don't come after us, we won't come after you.
Come after us... and your world ends.
You have my word on that.
Get me on a flight home.
lf l never set foot in this damned city again...
lt will be too soon.
Watch where you are fucking going man!
Keep walking, pal.
Excuse me? Pardon me? Anything?
This is fucking New York City!
Bank number five. How many more?
That's it.
There are copies of the disk in security boxes all over the city.
Anything happens to us
a lot of important people are going to be very sorry.
Our security.
Good business for us.
What now?
Now we get out of town.
Mei, you're a kid and...
l'm not sure l could be a good father.
l think that ship has sailed.
l don't want no more fathers.
Will you be my friend?
Until my dying day.
l've got info on a school for gifted kids up in Seattle.
lt's a nice drive,
if you like trees and shit.
Are we safe?
One day at a time, Mei.
One day at a time.