Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
Come, come, come.
(BRAKE and crash)
Holy shit, bang!
(Yell indistinct)
I'm sorry. Sometimes we beat
a word, but we are in Rome.
My job, as you can see, you do
so that the traffic moves.
I stand here and from there, I see every
thing, every person. I see life.
In this city were born many stories.
(Firefighter) You see that young man?
Is Roman and is called Michelangelo.
Sorry... where the Trevi Fountain?
- Er... do two blocks... -
Two blocks away. - And cross the square.
- Ok, that is square Mignanelli? - No.
- Piazza di Spagna is there? - No. - Okay.
- This is Piazza Venezia. - Ok.
- I'll show you.
- This is square... - Yes?
- Er... - I do not know...
- I'll go that way. I'll walk you.
- Thank you. - You're welcome. - Thank you.
- I am American, New York.
- I often go to work in New York.
- Then you know well. - Yes
- What do you do? - Advocate.
- Did you? Let me guess...
You're a tourist. - Summer holidays.
- I'm Hayley.
- Hello, Michelangelo. - Hello.
(DIAL NOT AUDIBLE)
I'm having an incredible summer.
You know, just as we read
in all those romantic books.
An American in Rome knows a Roman
fascinating to the Trevi fountain.
No, he is absolutely adorable.
(Firefighter) I'm still me, the policeman.
(Firefighter) Even Antonio and Milly
are a young couple in love.
(Firefighter)
I am married and work in Pordenone...
... And the journey to Rome, where they want to settle
, it's like a honeymoon.
(Yell indistinct)
(Firefighter) Then there is a famous American architect...
... That at the end of the holidays,
spend a few days in Rome.
(Firefighter) Oh, yes, there is also
Leopoldo Pisanello.
(Firefighter) A Roman citizen normal,
middle class...
... Reliable, pleasant, predictable.
It all happened so fast!
- I can not wait to introduce my
. - And I know them.
- Is delicious.
- Good, mother, yes.
- What do you do, Hayley?
- I'm a freelancer.
I find artwork for my clients.
I graduated in Fine Arts
He is a lawyer. I am very proud...
all my children.
I worked day and night to get them to study.
(Giancarlo)
I would like to know your parents. Come to Rome?
Er... so.
To tell the truth are going to get.
(Pilot) Ladies and gentlemen, we begin the descent
Fiumicino Airport.
(Pilot) Due to the poor condition of the time...
... We have some turbulence.
(Pilot)
Keep belts fastened. Thank you.
Heard? Turbulence!
My favorite.
Try to relax and stop clenching fists.
I can not until there is turbulence.
You know I'm an atheist.
- Feel that bounces? -
Do you think we're going to know her boyfriend.
- Look what is communist. -
There is not even the Communist Party here.
No, it's just a lot left.
I too much left at his age, but I was not a communist.
I could never share the bathroom.
- It is not a communist. It's just a good Samaritan
. - What do you mean?!
What is not interested in material goods.
If you must marry an Italian, I
I have material goods...
... A yacht, a couple of Ferrari
and, perhaps, a villa in Sardinia.
You do not want our Hayley
marry a "euro-dude"?
I hate when he does these things.
- Stop it. - I. .. - Relax. -
I have a bad feeling. - Breathe.
- Please.
- Thank you.
- Like this? - A lot.
- It's beautiful. - Yes, yes.
Look, love, it's late.
My uncles are coming. Come on.
Yes, but if you do not like me,
we do?
- Love, but what do you care?
- Be '... - You are so beautiful!
You just to be yourself.
Do not worry.
They are important people. Maybe a little '
severe, but not put off.
They are nice.
From next week I will be working in their company.
I do not want to say or do things that could compromise...
... This wonderful opportunity that we offer.
- Will do nicely. To like,
trusted. - Are you? - Of course.
Listen, to the speech
that we used to train...
Yes, probably
Pordenone I will miss...
... But it is a job that you can not refuse.
Do you realize!
If all goes well, we will live in Rome.
Frequenteremo the beautiful people.
We will have children.
And maybe one day we will have a
villa with servants, as my uncles.
Yes, but I have to go to the hairdresser.
I look like a teacher provincial
with this hair and I do not.
- I would be a little 'more chic.
- E'tardi. Now you have to go?
- It takes me a moment. I do soon.
- I would not make them wait...
- Okay. Hurry though, eh?
- Okay.
- Hello.
- Hurry up, eh.
I'm sorry,
hairdresser is full.
- There is no one else around here?
- Sure.
She leaves the building, go to the right, the second left...
... Passes under an arch, and after the arc,
immediately to the right, there is a bridge.
After the bridge, the first
left, straight ahead.
- If it is on the right.
- Thank you.
In Rome you eat better in Malibu.
I can not wait to do the tourist.
John will guide us. He lived here.
- Oh, Carol!
It's been thirty years. - So what?!
- (Man) supposed to be beautiful then.
- Was fabulous.
I was young, in love with
and completely stupid.
But nothing changes in the Eternal City.
I also want to see the ruins.
In the end, we are in Rome.
All those ruins me down.
I am the "melancholy of Melpomene."
And then I've seen
when I lived here.
Then we'll leave you and I'll see you later, okay?
I do not enjoy doing the tourist.
I prefer to wander the streets.
"Melancholy of Melpomene"!
Where did you find this sentence?
("ROMA SEE YOU" BY RENATO rascel
INSTRUMENTAL VERSION)
Er... I'm sorry, she's...
She is John Foye?
Yes, how do you know?
I recognized it from the picture
Herald Tribune.
- She designs all the commercial centers
. - That's how you see me?
- No, I'm an architect, a student of Architecture
. - Really?
- Yes Are you working on a project here in Rome
? - No, holiday.
I lived in Rome for a year
when I was your age.
- Really? Where?
- Here in Trastevere.
- I live here, in the Baskets.
- He was my hunting ground.
It's all on the day that the
try and I can not find it.
Is just two blocks to the left.
- Well, 'I...
- What? Would you like me to show up?
I do not know if I want to see her again.
- Er... - Be '...
- Ok. Why not?
(RING THE ALARM)
This honey to the square of Rome
put it in the middle.
Two euro and 18! But it is! Oh!
Come on, finish your breakfast. Thank you.
You have to eat. Camilla where is it?
Did you see?
Do you know why there's all this unemployment?
- Because people are pissed
for the latest technologies. - Yes
- What movie do? - Is it too!
- Mangia! Always late!
(Indistinct murmur)
wherefore the world goes, eventually everything
the planet speak Chinese. According to me.
- Who wants your opinion!
- I I told you.
Do not give a damn about anyone
of what we think.
- We just have to pay taxes.
- We pay taxes. - "Eye".
Look who it is.
(Leopold) Where were you when I was in the elevator
closed two hours?
Being young and unmarried...
Or, at least, one of the two.
- Did you see when he did so?
- Be '? - Beautiful!
- Do not combineresti nothing. - Why?
- The weekend passes them on his head.
- (Leopold) But when?
- (Man) always.
- If you want my opinion...
- Again! - Can I say something?!
I think...
- Is an enigmatic film,
very interesting. - I did not understand anything.
It is the most beautiful of "The King's Speech."
- What tartagliava it was more beautiful.
- What do you mean? - I do not understand.
- E'voluto author.
- Why?! - Not at all wanted!
- The incomprehensibility of life...
- Let's eat?
- Did you see that shot...
- Yes
- If I had to vote for an Oscar, not
I would have doubts. - But you do not vote...
- Who is it? Maria! - I want to see.
- If I had to vote...
(Yell indistinct)
I did not understand, but I think Brad Pitt.
(TV) "Questasettimana
interviewing TonyBlalr..."
"... The winner of Miss Universe
and Johnny Depp."
(Phyllis) My God,
look at this city!
- Here.
- The're giving a tip in euro.
When you realize what you gave him, you are a heart attack.
- Gave us a great room.
- Yes - And I'm happy to be here.
You have always traveled for work.
It's not nice to be here for fun?
- No! I... I miss work.
I do not like to be retired. - Be '...
I still think I'll end up as an old man...
... In a nursing home
watching TV in the group...
... And drool with the attached
colostomy pouch.
- For you board the equivalent
death. - Yes, that's right.
But it's your imagination,
because you're not dying.
No, I'm not dying now, but
is plausible that happen to me one day.
That is, even if I'm talking
between fifty and sixty years.
- I get a bit 'of water? - Of course.
Your wish is my command.
Thank you. I did not leave a mark,
I did not realize what I wanted.
You did very well. Only
have a little ahead of its time.
I have a lot ahead of time.
You married a very smart.
I have a Q.I. of 150, 160.
're Calculating in euro.
In dollars is a lot less, honey.
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
- Hello! - Honey! - Hello, Mom!
Hello! Hello, Dad! - Hello, baby.
- How are you? - Hi. - Well.
- Hi. - Well.
- He is Michelangelo. - Hello. -
He ​​is my father. - Pleasure. - Pleasure.
- She is my mother.
- Pleasure. - Nice to meet you.
- You've done a good trip?
- Yes, a great trip.
Bounced a little on landing, but...
I read in the newspaper, if the line
air retrieve the black box.
- We would like to get married around Christmas.
- Really? - Yes
- You're a lawyer, "Miguelangelo."
- Michelangelo.
- "Michel", "Michel". - Yes
- I call it "Michel", right?
- Yes, the oppressed,
those who can not pay. - Ah!
Legal aid.
She will roll up their sleeves.
- Er... you want something to drink?
- Thank you. - Yes
- Er... Water. - Water. -
Do you want some water? - Yes - The water is fine.
- Hayley told me that
work in the field of music. - I'm retired.
I worked in the classical music section of a record company.
- I staged operas
for many years. - You know, Dad...
- His great-grandfather knew Verdi.
- Seriously! - Yes
I have set up some greens.
Basic stuff I was avant-garde, atonal
things...
... But I revisited a couple of classics.
staged an edition of "Rigoletto"...
... Where all the characters were dressed as white mice.
(Jerry) And once a "Tosca"
where everyone was in a phone booth.
- Jerry won the day. - Yes, I was
in advance for massive success.
In other words, the productions were... Be ',
among critics, costs and unions...
- Excuse me, does not agree
on unions? - Er...
- Well, 'the unions... -
Without them the worker would be oppressed.
- Yes, I understand what you say,
"Miguelangelo"... - Michelangelo.
- How? - Michelangelo. - "Michel".
- Yes, as "Miguelangelo", the painter.
Only he, for some reason,
"Michel"...
Michelangelo gets angry very
care for workers.
(Yell indistinct)
Excuse me...  Excuse me, can you tell me where is
because of the pen?
Er... Er... Ah, yes... ah, yes...
Well, take the first right.
- Take a hundred meters.
- Yes - You will find an ice cream parlor.
Then go on that way for 50 meters and
Livada... left.
- Thank you.
- Please.
At the next traffic light crossing the road.
There is a seafood restaurant,
can not go wrong.
It is still on, turn right, then
another 100 meters and turn right again.
- Do you follow me?
- Yes, yes, thank you. Thank you. - Please.
(Yell indistinct)
(RING OF CELL)
(RING OF CELLULAR AND thud)
(PHONE RINGING AVUOTO)
Well, I live here.
Oh! Of course, this was just
my way!
- Can I ask for a coffee?
- A cup of coffee?
Yes, it is. Sally is very good.
- Sally! - Yes, my girlfriend.
She studied here.
- Sally, you there? - Hello. -
I brought a person who has lived here.
- Ah! But really?
- John Foye Yes, she is Sally. - Wow!
- Hi. - Pleasure. - Sally.
It's amazing! - I know.
- You're right, it's adorable. - Yes, it is wonderful
. - Can I get you anything?
- I'll give you a coffee? - Yes, thank you.
- What a great idea, honey. Thank you.
I forgot! My friend Monica
is coming to Rome.
- I told her she could stay with us.
- Well. So I know, finally.
It is just left with her boyfriend...
so is "disconnected".
- Trouble in view, clouds
the Eternal City. - Why trouble?
You'll like it a lot. It's smart, it's fun and
... interesting.
The men adore. I think it is
to the sexual energy that radiates.
- And how long will it stop?
- I do not know.
Among the break with her boyfriend and
acting career did not take off that...
- Do not you see that the situation is fraught with danger
! - Please!
I'm not looking for anything.
I am very happy with Sally.
Judging from the description, Monica
is neurotic and unpredictable.
Beautiful, funny, smart, sexy and even neurotic
?
It's as if you entered a Royal Flush.
Monica... Even the name is sexy.
(Yell indistinct)
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
- Congratulations. - Yes?
- I have your super gift.
- What gift? -
A special gift for a special man.
- What would this special gift
? - It's me.
Is already all paid for.
I'm all yours, all yours.
- Look, there must be a mistake.
- Perqualunque what you want.
- Ah, yes? Please, go away.
- I can not. Those upset.
- Who?! - They told me that you're stressed and
you'd be surprised.
- But you are the lucky winner.
- Winner of what?!
- The winner of the bet.
- But what bet!
Domi and Fabio have paid me and told me
to congratulate you.
What they were wrong and that you need
accept their apologies.
- These two gentlemen do not know them.
Can go out? - I can not speak.
-
I am here to fulfill your dreams. - Where you going?!
Please, Miss, can go out?
But you're Mr. Debroca,
room 504.
I'm not Mr. Debroca
and the room is right.
- You, please, leave now...
- Is anyone there?
- Sorry, sorry.
- I told you to wait.
No, it is not what you think.
Have a seat, please.
We were to meet at noon, the door was open...
- So do not enter without knocking!
- Nice way to meet your wife!
- It is not my wife.
- No!
I hope you're joking.
Of course I'm kidding.
Is my wife.
I am Uncle Paul.
Giovanna.
Uncle Sal.
Aunt Rita.
Anna.
- Anna! But do not call Milly!
- Milly! Be '...
Milly, of course, Milly.
Anna is the second name.
- Milly!
- Milly.
We are waiting below,
do not worry. Come on.
- Paul... - Yes
- Yes, yes. - AAfter.
I want to die! My life is over!
I am ruined!
Tell him the truth, that there was a mistake
.
But how?! They've seen
on the bed! I am in my underwear...
You will understand... Those think...
Do not ever convince them, is useless.
'll Think I called an escort.
Why do you jumped on him!
I was paid to make love with Mr.
Debroca.
- And leave the door open! - Yes
- Are you an idiot? - I thought it was closed.
These are believed upscale
authorized to everything.
Milly's coming.
We have to get out of here.
You have to pretend to be my wife.
I pretend to be your wife?
I'm not an actress.
- And what's more, I've just called
"idiot". - I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
I need your help, because if he comes
Milly, I'll jump out the window.
- Do not you understand that sooner or later
discover everything? - Are you?
I need time,
then I invent something.
It is important that we leave immediately
and go away.
- (Sally) Walk faster!
- (Jack) Relax!
- The flight must have landed!
- It will take at least an hour.
- Hope you do not fall in love with her.
- What the hell does that mean?!
- Men are always...
crazy about her. - Well, 'I'm crazy about you.
Ok. Here it is! It's her! Monica!
- Hello! I'm so glad!
- Hello!
- You are a beauty!
- Stop it! You're a beauty!
- Nothing special, right?
- No. I mean, no thrill.
Do you think this would be the "femme fatale"!
Sure, it's been 14 hours in the air, but you
admit that there is something in her.
If something arouses in me belongs to the subconscious.
I do not notice it at all. It is certainly a formidable
seductress.
Unemployed is an actress and crumpled.
- What fantastic! It was so long...
- Hello, I sonoJack.
- She is Monica. - Hello. - Pleasure.
- I must look awful.
- I got it. - Do not make judgments
rushed. - No, you look great.
, over time, like me. Is that
I can not sleep on the plane.
I took a Scotch and 3 Ambien, but...
There is already a certain intimacy in this return.
I have no interest in Monica.
I just hope it does not interfere with my work.
There is an element of excitement, a
germ, a spark, a molecule...
God! I see it so clearly now.
But is age.
- Thank you, a wonderful dinner. - Thank you.
- You're getting a great cook.
Since it was your night here
why not dine at home?
Yes, it's perfect, just the three of us.
Ma .. you're reading?
- The poems of Yeats.
- "That gong tormented by the sea..."
- Yes, yes, you know? - You want to talk about
break with Donald?
', Donald was gay and it was my
ego to believe to be able to change it.
- It is not gone, but believe me, I tried
. - And how do you groped?
Well ', I mean...
I would not go into details, but... be '...
I've got it all set and
is a pity because he is wonderful.
It's so bright out of bed.
It was fun to be with him.
I have tried to prove that sex with a woman...
... Can be as exciting as it
with one of the same sex.
And he tried. Him ..
has tried, but in the end, nothing.
(Monica) Losses total, yes.
But you have fun when you brought her to Paris.
- Have you ever had sex with a man?
- I! Sex with a man! No.
Not at all.
Is not something that interests me. I mean...
- Why go red? Probably
why would you try. - I...
I have always had a great desire
going to bed with a woman.
When I finally did was very intense...
... Something very exciting, but
disturbing.
- I have not suppressed any...
- Once I turned a TV movie...
One of the scenes was an incredible
model lingerie.
I swear I took away your breath.
One day I get a message
dall'aiutoregista...
... That Miss Lee
wanted to see me in his dressing room.
Why was all of a sudden,
so obsessed with me I do not know.
So I go there.
She is Terry...
And if one takes it away.
And kisses me holding me close to him.
And I...  I... I... lost his head.
I have lost my mind.
I was so excited... You must believe me,
was too good to say no.
This went on for three months.
Yes, it was like living in a
erotic dream.
On the one hand, it was very exciting.
But on the other hand,
I was very confused.
Then I began to see an analyst
5 days a week.
Luckily Jamal arrived and we started a relationship
exceptional.
And if you have been great orgasms
had with Victoria...
... Those with Jamal
were more grandiose and much less confusing.
I'm sorry.
- Is special. - Yes, I need some
minutes to recover from the story.
- I'm still sweating.
- I find it fun.
Yes, but in the end got?
Nothing  career, no relationship,
sleeping pills, analysts...
I think you're trying to convince yourself.
I have a great idea.
Why not go for a walk?
No, I'm exhausted.
But you take it easy, no, Jack?
- No, it would be a catastrophe!
- Why are you so worried?!
- You think of me as a seductress.
This is your problem. - Bales.
You invented the story with
modeling lingerie to provoke him.
No, it was true, almost all. Ok, I exaggerate a little
, I love infiocchettare.
- It's part of my charm creative.
- Come on, why do not you?
Sally, you must not leave them alone.
(DIAL NOT AUDIBLE)
(RINGER DELLASVEGLIA)
(indistinct and yell excitedly)
What's the matter?! Are you crazy!
Go! You have the wrong person!
Sofia! Sofia! Coupons!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
- Sofia! But what happens!
- What do you want?!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
(Leopold) call the police!
Go away! I am a serious person!
I'm going to work!
I have to go to work! These are crazy!
- What is this car?!
- Getting late to study!
- But I'm late for work!
- Venga. - Sofia! - Have a seat.
Sofia... come along.
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
(DIAL NOT AUDIBLE)
Hello and welcome to TG3.
Today we have a special guest:
Leopoldo Pisanello.
- Welcome, Mr. Pisanello.
Welcome to TG3. - Thank you, yes...
Excuse me, but why am I here?
To answer our questions,
to our interview.
- What did you have for breakfast?
- I!
Er... white coffee and two slices of bread with butter and jam
.
Two slices of bread... And how?
Good... roasted.
- Ah, so she prefers
toast. - Yes, that's right, yes.
Why? I ask him?
Mah .. uh... I do not know. Just like that
I usually prefer the toast.
- (Journalist) White or wholemeal?
- White.
So we can say without a shadow of a doubt...
... Leopold Pisanello prefer two slices of toast.
Yes, and a latte... without sugar.
- (Journalist)
The beard has done before or after breakfast? - Er...
(Yell indistinct)
- Extraordinary!
- I!
It!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
Still here! Enough! Go! Sofia!
Sofia! Go away!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
Leopoldo! You were great!
- The phone never stopped ringing
. - Yes, but...
You want the news of tomorrow 20:00.
- What are you saying! I! But why?!
- You're famous!
- Er... - 95. - 95...
- I do not know, I can not find the address.
This is the 91, that is 93...
- It can not be 95! There are
the funeral! - Here we go.
- How's that?! - Mr. Santoli
do this job. - Seriously!
Has a funeral.
Do not make it so long.
Jesus! The son of a communist
and the father is a "gravedigger"...
The mother runs a leper!
- I think that dress above.
- Excuse me, is this the 95?
- Yes, it's 95. Santoli? - Yes, yes.
- Someone has died?
- No, but it is better to predict.
- No, we are the parents of Hayley.
- The parents of Hayley! - Yes
- Welcome!
It is a great pleasure to meet you!
Sorry, I have not yet washed.
I work all day...
- Please, take a seat as well.
We live here. - Thank you.
- Please. - Thank you. - Follow me.
Have a good trip?
- Yes, wonderful.
- Well!
- Please, have a seat. - Thank you.
- Mariangela, come!
- They came the parents of Hayley.
- Hi. - Pleasure. - Phyllis eJerry.
- Hi. - Good morning. - Here
no one ever comes. - Oh, no? - No.
- Here. - What do you drink? - Thank you.
- The wine is fine.
Michelangelo and Hayley arrive shortly.
I'm sorry, but I have to wash andarmi.
Is a must.
- Mariangela, open the bottle and take a drink
. - I'm going to open it.
- Meanwhile you sit down.
- Ok. - Be right back. - Yes
- (Hayley)'s us!
- (Michelangelo) Mom! - Hello!
- Hello! - Hi. -
Have you found the right place, right?
We followed a hearse
and we arrived.
- You have arrived! Well! - Hello.
- Taste my specialties.
The green ones are a kind of "tapenade".
- Yes, Try them, they're great.
- Ah, ok. - No. ..
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. It is delicious.
I will never be so.
- I will teach you.
Teach her to make croutons. - Yes, it is.
- No, really... - Come on!
- Is a cooking class for free!
- I do not want to disturb. - I'll
assistant. - Come. - No. ..
Eat one. I'm going to see.
Please.
Formaldehyde!
(Giancarlo) The time has fled...
(Giancarlo) and die in despair!
And die in despair!
And I amatoma the
tantola life!
(Giancarlo) win!
He showed me how to do...
... But here are the fresh mozzarella
that arrives daily from Naples.
- What do you do, Phyllis?
- I'm a "shrink".
Oh! It is a psychiatrist!
I've never been to Naples,
but I know it is beautiful.
Do not know what the Neapolitan cuisine.
You know Italy well, Jerry?
- Jerry, you asked a question.
- Eh?
Ah! Yes, yes, Naples...
Did you ever take singing lessons,
Giancarlo?
Singing lessons! No. Why?
You sing so naturally?
I'm not a singer.
Same song for me, since I was little.
- You have a fantastic, beautiful voice.
- Yes
But no! She says I do
just too noisy here at home.
- (Jerry) Has no one heard?
- Caruso is our staff.
You have a wonderful voice.
Have you ever thought to make something?
He sings for his own pleasure,
not for money.
There is a certain amount of money in
pleasure, a pleasure rustling.
- You groped banknotes.
- Oh...
I'm not a singer.
I... I do not know, I...
It is possible that, after dinner,
you sing something for me?
Who, me?! No, I feel embarrassed
, no.
- No, I'm here, among us.
- No, please.
- Michelangelo, tell him too.
- Yes
I have a friend here in Rome
it big.
If you only sing...
He ​​is very competent.
If you, when you're free, when you're not
cremating someone could...
- Look, he already said no.
- Michelangelo, but the gentleman...
With Dad is useless to insist.
It's not a singer.
- You do not want him to do a bad
figure. - Jerry, get it over with.
Ok, I'm done.
I will not say another word. I'm done.
But the guy has a fantastic voice and you...
Ok, dumb.
Forget it. The subject is closed.
But he has a great voice!
Someone should do something about it.
- Not me. - Jerry...
- I do not speak to me...
- This man is a genius.
- Enough. - He has a natural talent.
I'm not saying anything. I'm just...
I mean, I... Closed the topic.
(Heading) Great item, great.
As a true star. A beautiful talent.
- What do you call the hotel?
- I do not remember.
- It is in the center? - Yes, more or less.
Was... was red...
Here. Sorry for the delay.
We have been waiting for.
Er... yes... uh...
(Sighing) You could not get...
Something simpler?
We need to meet people rather important.
- We like you dressed like that.
- How!
But some of our fellow
may not understand.
- I lost my suitcase in the train,
then that's it. - Ah, well.
Um...  Well, we have organized a trip
private Vatican.
- Beautiful. True love? - Yes,
I know him well. - Come on, then.
- I hope that do enter.
- I do not do so enter!
- Miss... are you okay?
- Yes, yes, thank you.
Thanks, but...
Oh, but... but... but she is...
But she is Pia Fusari?
He recognized?
Yes, but you... Oh, my God, but she
is one of my favorite actresses!
I'm flattered.
But as you walk down the street here
like a normal person?
We're making a movie here.
- (Pia) Will you come to see?
- I!
Yes!
(Milly) Oh...
But that is Juliet Falcone!
(Milly) No! There Luca Jump! I love
Luke Salta, is so charismatic!
(Milly) No, I do not believe it!
It's amazing: he painted the ceiling
lying on scaffolding.
Working
all the time lying on my back! I can not imagine!
I do, perfectly.
Damn, I'm late to class.
You can carry around Monica today?
- No, today, no.
I have to work in these drawings. - Please!
- I do not know anything about Rome.
- No.
Do not have time to go to see
Coliseum for the millionth time.
- Come on, do it for me.
- Er...
- Thank you.
- Ok.
(Monica) is impressive.
With those lines and spaces...
(Jack) There is so much space to the negative.
Do not you will hide from something?
(Monica) No, I was worried
to distract you from work.
(Jack) No, I figured, I like it.
If it were not for you, I would do it alone.
(Jack) It's amazing that the Coliseum
is still here after thousands of years!
Sally and I have to repaint the bathroom
every six months.
These guys were really the architects fabulous.
The great irony here is that once there was a magnificent civilization...
... And now only the ruins.
- I call this sense of futility...
The "melancholy of Melpomene." - Ok.
(Monica) This is the kind of thing you want to achieve
?
(Jack)
I would be proud to have designed it.
(Monica) Have you always wanted to do
architect?
(Jack) You start to laugh when I tell
what my greatest aspiration.
- (Monica) What is it? No, do not laugh.
- (Jack) Designing structures extremes.
(Jack) I would like to scandal,
change the architectural landscape...
- Ate interested in architecture?
- I am interested in Gaudi. - Ah.
Antoni Gaudi.
For me, the Sagrada Familia
is a poem in stone.
Bullshit!
You were only six months in college.
Do not know anything about architecture,
except name a few.
Have you seen the movie "The Fountainhead."
I'm so sexy that young
architect's uncompromising film.
I would do anything to pass
a night with the young architect.
God, spare me, please!
Another young woman who wants to give his body to Gary Cooper.
- Come on! It's fun to talk to her.
- Sure.
You drink his bales because it seems
to know the right things to say.
Knows the names, terms of fashion...
... Some quotes that are educated
think of her as one who knows.
"The anxiety of influence",
string quartets of Bartok...
... The perversion of the dialectic, the Sagrada Familia...
... "Gong tormented by the sea"...
I should put it to narrow and does not allow the display of names?
- But you did not. - In the end, that
is a fraud, is fascinating.
Yeah, the girl has something special that
beats all logic.
So... continues,
thrown between the propeller blades.
It went well with Monica?
I have no time to carry it around.
I'm trying to work.
- I was taken back
insecurity today. - Stop it
Maybe this was not a good idea to make
out together all day.
- And if you felt attracted to her?
- Will you stop worrying?
Pseudointellectual is a narcissist.
Yes, it's pretty and with this?
- Yes, it's very pretty. - It's nice.
In short, not in the conventional way.
I would like to find someone.
There will be a friend to fix it.
- Yes, I'm sure that someone
rimediamo. - Who?
What do you think of Leonardo Basso?
Is a nice guy, smart,
earn a lot of "grain"...
I think he left with a
that she was an actress.
- Awesome! You could call it?
- Sure. I will pander. - Well.
Please sit down, Mr. Pisanello.
- This will be his new office.
- My new office!
Ma .. but I'm an employee.
(Chuckling) Very funny.
Serafina, come. Look
famous person we have in our company.
- Good morning. - You take care of her,
with everything they need.
- All day.
- With pleasure. - Thank you.
- You will take care of me
all day? - Yes
- Whatever he needed,
I'm here. - Yes
(yell indistinct)
Calm down.
(Yell indistinct)
- How did it go his day?
- My day? - Yes
It went well.
I spilled coffee on it is certain
documents, but I've taken on the fly.
For the rest, well, well, well.
Have you heard? Mr. Pisanello
happened to spill the coffee.
But his reflexes
avoided the tragedy...
... With the probable loss of human lives.
But why has spilled coffee?
Will be the deepening of the news of 21:00, with distinguished guests...
... What the leaders of Illy,
the ambassador of Brazil and the UN.
Mr. Pisanello a statement.
- A statement!
- Yes, a statement.
- A statement... so?
- Tell us something. - So?
I think... I think... Ah, maybe it's raining.
You heard it. Pisanello
Leopold says it could rain.
Can you tell us how to sleep tonight?
I normally sleep on my back.
Leopoldo Pisanello
sleep on your back.
Have you ever slept  on the stomach?
No, I suffer a bit 'of gastritis.
Not a serious thing...
- On the belly I do not like. It will be...
- How much?
- But enough! Please! Stop it!
- It's important! - Enough!
But enough! Go!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
What do you want?! How to sleep...
What do you think? I only have these printed dresses
dime.
I have to buy something now that you're so famous.
Sofia, I'm tired, I have a headache.
Forget it.
I had a terrible day.
Do not go to the premiere of the film.
How! But we must go!
We keep to our presence.
Sofia, but who?! But who cares!
Would you tell me that, without Leopoldo
Pisanello, do not give the first?
- Sure! - But Sofia, I am Mr.
"Foolish any".
And you're my wife, the wife of Mr.
You said you'd go.
(Applauses and ovations calm)
(Man) is Gina Francone.
(Man) Ah! Here Tony Branca.
(Applauses and ovations calm)
(Man) There he is. Good evening.
Good evening. Prejudice.
(Man) But who do I see? Here it is!
Leopoldo Pisanello.
(APPLAUSl, WHISTLES and standing ovations)
(Man) is accompanied by the lovely Sofia
.
(Man) Very elegant, with this dress
dime.
(Woman) Yes, Sofia is wearing a dress printed cotton
dime...
... And a coat that seems to take a stand
Charity.
- (Man) Yes, definitely. - And I
I've ever... a laddered stocking.
We're checking. Yes, it is a
gap in left stocking.
Lady Pisanello, the ladder,
tell us, is desired?
- I have a ladder? - Yes,
is very impressive, very fashionable.
(Woman) Do not see, Martina?
- Then we will see soon in Cannes?
- Absolutely.
- Well, sorry, but there's Gina Franconi.
- Please.
- Mr. Pisanello. - Yes? - I
Marisa Raguso, his fan. - Thank you.
I think she is very sexy
most of all these players "frocetti"...
... Making superhero movies.
- Sure. - It would be nice to have a little
'more time to talk.
- I would like to know what you think of
cultural situation in Italy. - I?
Tell you what, I'll give you my phone number
. Call me.
- Your Number?
- Anytime. - All right.
- Mr. Pisanello, tell us the truth.
- Yes - He wears briefs or boxers?
- Er... I boxers, wide, white.
- I knew it! I always knew!
Clearly, he is a boxer from her.
Is a fig! I knew it!
(DIAL NOT AUDIBLE)
(JACK SIGH)
- So, how do you feel now that you've
arranged with your friend? - I do not know.
Fun we found Sally and I come to visit these ruins.
Yeah, and then what happened?
- I regret having presented
Leonardo. - Yes, you're jealous.
All of a sudden, I wanted to be with her
in a room and tell her that I love her.
I have not tried anything so far
afternoon and suddenly...
Her face haunts me.
I love what wears her hair.
She was exceptional.
- So, you like Monica?
- Is adorable.
- I'm looking forward to seeing you again.
- Oh yeah? The need to revise?
- Tomorrow night.
- Me and Sally are free tomorrow night.
It is better if we go out just the two of us.
- Please.
- It brings the menu, please? - Now.
(Jerry) Giancarlo, I
allowed to call my friend.
- I fixed an audition society
label. - I said no!
But why?!
What's wrong with people alive!
You can not have only to do with
people with rigor mortis.
You have an exceptional voice.
You should sing "I Pagliacci" for the crowd.
- "Clowns"! - "Clowns",
yes. You were born to sing.
- I've always wanted to sing it.
- Of course, your voice is a gift.
- Listen to me: we will go away.
- "We"! - We, yes.
I will make you as a manager and put
on the scene for you, "I Pagliacci."
Believe me, I know what to do.
Trust me.
Do not know why I'm crying, because
you're in front of me. Believe me.
# Nessun dorma! Nessun dorma!
(Giancarlo clears throat)
# You, too, o Princess, in your cold room #
...
#
#... Watch the stars which tremble with love...
#... And hope.
# But my secret is hidden within me...
#... No one will know my name
# No, no! On your mouth #
down stars... Win!
# Win!
(DOOR THAT OPENS)
How did it go?
Do one thing: just ask your father.
Oh, oh...
- I'm sorry, Jerry.
I made you look bad. - No. ..
You should have seen his face.
Did you know that was terrible.
It was not terrible, I swear.
Ok, if it was at La Scala, the
would shoot fruits and vegetables.
But that was a cold
recording studio.
Images that his voice is better than it actually is
...
... Because you're looking for an excuse not to do the pensioner
.
Do not psychoanalyze me, okay?
You know that many have tried, all have failed
.
My brain does not fit the usual
Id, Ego and Superego.
No, you're the only brain with three Eg
- If we eat something, we feel
definitely better. - I'm not hungry.
That was stupid idea I know.
Your father is an adult and is capable of
make his own decisions.
Do not know why you came there.
Were you there with the face of those who disapprove.
You looked sour.
Maybe you have made your father nervous.
I came because he is a simple one.
I did not send him alone into a den of sharks
music industry.
- (Jerry) Lair of sharks!
- Do you think my father is a shark?
I have compared it to a spineless jellyfish
, but nothing more.
You defend your father.
This is your family and you'll understand.
- But he was wrong. - No, I
defend one because you're wrong.
It is not a fault
groped to make something and fail.
I do not want to say anything, but
I told you so.
Choose  projects destined to fail.
It seems that you try to fail taste.
Which projects would have chosen that were doomed to fail?
"Rigoletto" with singers
clothes from white mice.
(GIANCARLO SINGS IN THE SHOWER PERFECTLY
)
Do you feel it? It is not an amazing voice?
Sure, but what's the point if
unable to sing only in the shower?
Be ', however, admit that...
He's right, Jerry.
All sing well in the shower.
Yes, it's true... He does it in the shower...
Daddy,
even you sing in the shower.
I know, and...
In life I have a horrible voice...
... But when I soap
under a hot shower I look like a tenor.
You look strange.
Phyllis, I'm having...
In psychoanalysis there is a term for this.
I'm having a revelation and...
Epiphany.
- What is the term for what
I'm having? - Desire for death.
(Yell indistinct)
Bravo, you were fantastic. Come, let me introduce
a fan of yours unleashed.
- Have you seen all your movies.
Milly, right? - Yes, Milly.
- Hi. - I'm sorry.
- So you're one of my fans. - Yes
- I have seen all his films.
- So I'm flattered, go.
- No, it's true. - Yes? -
I believe that she is an amazing actor.
When ratted Arab or
terrorist or divorced father...
- I always dreamed of being able to know
. - We have lunch together?
- What? You and I! - Eh.
- Together? - I only have an hour.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
She is the sexiest man in Rome,
second World Film. Did you know?
Yes, they told me.
- Shall we?
- Yes
Thank you.
- You think you have so many children?
- No, child, no.
You become their slave.
Diapers, schools, diseases...
- Then they grow, they go
and do not see them anymore. - It is not so.
For me it was so.
I did not see the time running away from home.
My father was a drug dealer and stole my mother in stores.
(Anna) What could I do?
Was not I right?
(Yell indistinct)
- Look!
- He's a great actor.
- There is this actor: Luchino Salta.
- Where? - Yes, that's him.
(Aunt Rita) But he's married.
Who's that with him?
What's up? What is it?
I'm fine, I'm fine.
I can not believe you are here
to lunch with her.
What am I lucky, you know?
I'd be eating alone now.
No! But how alone! She is married,
there is written all over the papers.
(Luke) Marriage is like wine:
it is a wonder if it is good, if not...
We split up. The press does not know
still a secret.
Course.
No, I would not say nothing, for charity.
- What do they do? -
He ​​looks into her eyes. He wants to tow.
I wish you'd stop looking at me on the set
afternoon.
So can you give me your instructions,
can you tell me what you think...
Then, perhaps,
let's go to my hotel to talk about it.
Because, interested in my ideas!
- Well, 'but there is something to the contrary?
- No, no. - Ah. - No, absolutely
Is that Anthony, my husband always says
I head in the clouds.
This, perhaps, a bit 'is true, but...
Not serious about your ideas?
No, take it seriously, respect them, but
in science.
Yes, because I am a teacher of high school
. I teach astronomy.
- But think!
- Yes
So I doubt that interest
my ideas in the arts.
Astronomy, then the sky,
the planets, the stars...
- You're... you are... Wait, I do not mean
. - I say nothing, for charity.
- Are you a scale.
- No, I'm Sagittarius. - Oh...
He took my hand.
- You should give him a slap.
- No, actually, I'm sure she likes.
(Splash and yell indistinct)
- (Giovanna) Are you hurt?
- No. .. not.
Good morning. We are home of Mr. Leopoldo
Pisanello.
I'm half past seven, and Mr.
Pisanello you are doing the beard:
... an event that we document in
direct from first to last gesture.
Mr. Pisanello you are doing your hair.
- Look, just a trim.
- She opted for a trim.
(POP MUSIC)
We are full, sorry.
There is no place.
- You're wrong. My husband booked
yesterday. - There has been a misunderstanding.
- How is it possible? - There is no place.
- Okay, back again.
- No, Mr. Pisanello. - Be '?
- Please, this way.
- What a shame! - What ways are!
- How dare you!
We are old customers!
There will come again!
- Are they right. Were lined
before us. - Nonsense.
Please, this way. Come in.
(APPLAUSE)
I saw you in the office and I could not resist.
They say that power is an aphrodisiac.
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
- (Leopold) And who is he?
- My best friend.
I promised her I'd do
love with her after me.
This will be one of the happiest days of his life
.
You know, he cares
because he is married.
Mr. Pisanello, for her
rules do not count. She is special.
Yes, I agree with you completely.
- When I read "The Myth of Sisyphus",
my life has changed. - Yes.
- Not to mention the Russians.
- Dostoevsky, thank you.
- "Stavrogin's Confession"?
- E Kierkegaard.
- Her pain becomes your. - No
Rilke is your favorite author?
Oh, Rilke!
"You must change your life."
- Or maybe it's Ezra Pound?
- "Petals on a wet black bough."
But the feeling? Do you know a line of each
poet, just enough to pretend.
I got an idea is great.
Last night, after closing, there
slip in the ancient Roman baths.
- I "slip"! - Leo, you know
force a lock, right? - Of course.
Knows how to get us. Strength, will be
night, it will be spooky. Fun.
No, things are not
spectral Jack, trust me.
I love...
get into places are illegal, so...
Yes, of course I do not want to spend
killjoy...
Before Camus and Kierkegaard and now,
that has run out of names to show off...
... Invites you to a burglary.
From your point of view is crazy,
but wherefore I see it is...
(THUNDERS)
- (Leonardo) Ok...
- Not the best!
- Do you realize?! - Come on! - No
I never saw them at night. - Yes
- It's fantastic! How do you feel?
- Well, but I think it's going to rain.
- He did not break the rules.
- That was a flash!
- Do you believe that God is for us.
- Are you afraid?
- No, but here we are easy targets.
- It's so good! - Let's go back.
- I love thunderstorms!
- Now it's raining in earnest.
- Just a little. ' - No, no.
Just a little '! We gotta go.
- Come on, move on! Sally!
- Let's go there! - Move on!
- (Monica) Come, come!
- (Jack) ADouble that!
(RSV)
(Monica) is amazing!
- (Jack) It's a bit 'noisy.
- That was close. - Ok.
- Very close! - One of my fellow
school was killed by lightning.
- Odi lightning!
- No, I did not mean that.
I find that thunderstorms are so romantic...
Did you know that... you are...
Just beautiful... so wet?
- You're so sweet to say that!
- No, it's true.
I love it here.
I say that Rome is so charismatic...
Oh!
Restless with these crap!
-
Do you mind out of the picture and leave me alone with her! - Ok.
But remember that I know how it ends.
I feel that I
completely in love with Rome...
... In the short time I have been here.
- Eh... - I feel I can pass
life here and not volerandarmene more.
Leonardo might have known something related.
(RSV)
Oh, my God!
- This scared me!
- Yes
If we die... die together.
(Warm applause)
(WARM APPLAUSE)
(MUSICAAL PLAN)
Love forbids you nonamar.
The man who rejects me your lleve...
... Search the pressure of my hand.
Your eyes say: "I love it",
if the lips say: "I will love you."
(Applauses and ovations)
You were absolutely fabulous.
This gentleman entered history.
- I see a great future here.
- How would a future!
I see  New York, Opera
Vienna, I see... Paris!
- All in the shower! - Yes,
to the public like. Are identified.
-
Become the most famous singer in the world. - The cleaner for sure.
Do not want to continue with this farce! - Why not?
I have great plans for him. Now I want to stage
"I Pagliacci."
Percantare Your father is perfect in that role.
- This is decadent stupidity!
- It is a life that I sing that part.
All my life want to do it.
Do you want to deny him his chance?
- This is your chance, not his.
- Do not use that tone with my father!
- I am used to living
beating the drum. - Oh!
It's very interesting how choice of words.
You are retired, and involving the board to death.
He is in the funeral home.
Puts people in the chest.
While you want to beat the drum.
- Is true. - If you are in contact with
Freud, facts give my money.
But what  "Pagliacci"! But what
start! Which airplane!
- Where do you want to take my husband!
- She is a perfect Traviata.
- This is crazy! - I assure you...
- What does it say?! - Do not listen to her.
We already took away his son
and now wants to take away you too!
- Become a real star. -
But you can not sing! - It is not true!
- I do not know how to sing!
- I got it.
- Sings only in the shower. - Yes, I know
. - He can not sing. - I got it.
- Enough, enough... - I'll kill him, so I
I raise my thought.
Act as a shield! You probably do not
stabs a woman.
- Come on, come on, like that. Calm down...
- Good... - Relax. - What?
It has an aggressive-depressed syndrome.
Lay the knife.
- Stay calm. -
And this should be our mother-in-law?
(Yell indistinct)
We want to introduce people.
Mr. Massucci
delegate is the administrator of your company.
Has organized this festival to welcome you.
Is an opportunity to learn about the
crème of the business community in Rome.
We spoke very highly of you
and are eager to meet you.
- It would be nice to make a good impression even on
wives. - Yes
- Do not drink so much, honey.
- It is better that I take a coffee.
- Does anybody want?
- (Giovanna) No. - Coffee? - No.
Look who's there! Here it is, come on,
I want to introduce my nephew.
- Good morning! Thank you. Beautiful
party. - Meet Antonio.
Pleasure. She is the famous nephew.
I have heard great things about her.
Say it is perfect for the image of our society.
The image is very important for us.
- Do you follow football?
- No.
- But are you?
- Yes
- What are you doing here, Anna?
- Milly!
My wife.
- Hello, how are you? - Well, thank you.
- Pleasure. - All my. - Milly.
- We go. - Yes - We're sorry.
- Hello. Coffee? Thank you.
With milk, please.
- Anna!
- Hello!
- Milly. - Since when?
- I'm Milly. - Ok.
- There is my wife.
- Do not worry, do not worry.
- I was just calling. That
How about Tuesday? - Usual hours?
- Anna!
- Oh!
- Oh, Lady! Hello.
I did not expect to meet you here. - Here are Milly.
Ah, Milly? Anyways, 'Milly.
Can you pass me by tomorrow
in office about three?
- I do not know, I have no agenda here.
- I get it.
If you do not feel it, you'll look at three.
- I recommend the black bra...
- Yes - The thong, that... - Yes
- But sailing goes there.
- No.
- Er... hunting?
- Anna, how are you? - How are you all right!
- Milly. Milly, Milly.
I'm nervous!
I can not afford to make a fool of yourself.
-
Are the most important men in Rome. - Yes, the crème.
- This is the list of my clients
full. - I'm so nervous...
You're too tense, my friend.
Relax or you are a heart attack.
How do I relax, if my
life is falling apart!
How does your wife put up with you if
're always so nervous?
Because he loves me for who I am.
- This is sbaciucchiava
Luchino... what's it called? - Salta.
- Why, sbaciucchiavano!
- Pretty much.
You said that you only held hands.
There must be an explanation, because for me
Milly is like Madonna.
The explanation is simple: he is a
movie star, a sex symbol.
And Milly is beautiful and has never looked
another man.
But you women do not know their own.
Especially those who have a
hysterical husband who fears his own shadow.
What the hell had to smooch?
If he ate with his eyes.
You're probably not able to eat a woman with eyes.
One that makes your job
I look like a middle-class idiot.
Your wife was a virgin when you married?
- None of your business.
- I bet yes.
- We did wild things together.
- What do you mean by "wild things"?
Having sex with the lights on?
Believe me, I was not a virgin.
I was a virgin.
- You need a lesson!
- By whom? Certainly not from you.
And why not?
So everything is already paid for. It's Free.
- There are people.
- I do not see anyone.
- Do not make me forget the carrots.
- Ok. - Do you need all that dough?
- Yes, even more. - More!
Not cook for all Trastevere!
- (Monica) Tomatoes. - Ok. -
Who had the idea for this business?
It was Monica.
We decided to have dinner together.
And since Leonardo worked and Sally has
lesson, we'll cook.
- Can I make a prediction?
- Which one? - You do not know how to cook.
- There are things that can cook.
- What? - The chocolate brownies.
- The brownies. - Yes - And you shall eat
as the main course? - Yes
I find it funny.
Do you think we need more wine?
The Italians cook with a lot of wine.
- There is already a lot of wine and feels.
- Or maybe the French. - No, ok.
- I do not want to be too light.
- Definitely not.
- I can try?
- Yeah, I figured.
I think is...
I'll have some more wine.
- More! Are you sure?
We have already done this! - Er... - Ok.
We have to prepare the brownies.
You will know how to do?
- I! Did you tell them that you know you do!
- Yes, no, of course...
Only that I left the recipe
in Los Angeles.
But I make them by heart.
I'm sure you know how to do it by heart.
Want
we order at the restaurant and say that we cooked us?
- Be '... Expected to taste the sauce.
- Yes, now the taste too.
What do you want, penne or rigatoni?
- Do not throw the dough now.
Will arrive in three hours. - Ok.
- What? - I think I'm drunk.
- Really? - Yes.
- Then imbrogliamoli.
- Yes, I'm done with the sauce. - Good, ok.
- I'm done with the kitchen. - Ok. -
But I promised to cook dinner.
Yes, I'm glad it worked
between you and Leonardo.
Seriously, why am I
I have put together.
- Yeah, I mean, he... is cute.
- Sexy, you said Sally.
Look... now it's the wine talking.
It is a very spiritual, okay?
It is not... is not one that suffers.
What there is of interest in suffering?
There is something attractive in a man
sensitive to the agony of existence.
God, you... 'd be perfect as
Miss Julie. Strindberg, you know?
The tactics of Miss Julie:
I learned as a theater director.
'
an actress who would be perfect as Miss Julie and she will be yours.
I'm surprised that you say that.
Miss Julie
is the role for which I was born. She is me!
- How do you know? - I
I have a question not related to you now.
- I mean?
- As if you'd take the kiss?
Oh... uh...
- Yeah, it is not inherent.
- Oh, the girl is shocked!
But just two minutes ago you are putting in your mouth
a tic-tac. Why do you think?
I mean, really, that...
What would you say?
I would say that living with my best friend.
Yes, this is true, I just...
I can not stop.
- No! Not good!
- Is not you like it?
No, absolutely...
That's what... wrong.
You?
You think you recover that?
No, she is perfect.
It's too good to be true.
If something is too good to be true
, of course not.
I have to have.
No. .. But now we do, Jack?
're Playing.
What is a show?
I can not do this to Sally
in his house.
- But no, quiet, Sally does not come back.
- No, I mean... - What?
- I do not want to do here.
- What are all these stories!
If you have to fuck the boy
your best friend's...
... What does it matter where the seat is
?
- You'll never understand women do not!
- More than demonstrated.
This will never become an affair behind
behind Sally, okay?
Today is a rainy afternoon,
I'm a little drunk...
Yes, I feel excited by you, but...
You know, not here, not in his house.
Ok, it is not the time to discuss now
. Come on, let's go in the car.
Be ', then it is different.
I can fuck in the car, fine by me.
(Man) Smile! Smile!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
My God, you can not!
is my cousin!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
We met by chance.
I do not have anything to declare, nothing. Come on.
Nothing, nothing! Please...
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
(indistinct and yell excitedly)
We met by chance!
I was waiting for my wife.
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
(indistinct and yell excitedly)
Have some respect at least of the procession.
Roberto, do not take it anymore.
But why me, Roberto?
- What's going on?
- Sir, you must resign.
- She is a very, very famous
. - But why?!
- Look at this, the pills...
This morning was full. - Ah. - Mamma Mia!
- Why are they famous? - Why?
She is famous for being famous.
But I have not done anything, Roberto.
Excuse me, but, according to her, all those who are famous
deserve it?
I do not know! You see that you
I ask an opinion?!
All asking for my opinion.
I do not know!
All I ask questions.
My life is a living hell!
A journalist asked me two days ago if there is God
I said, "What do I know? I do not know"
and she is upset.
"Mr. Pisanello not know if there is
God" "But I do not know, do not you know!"
Everyone asks me things...
"Pisanello"
"How do you scratch your head?
With the right or the left?"
"With both of us."
"Oh, if the scratch with both!"
They are made private! I scratch my head
me with the hand that I think.
- It is private! - The way I see it,
I do not agree with her.
Being a celebrity,
excitement, special privileges...
... The adoring crowds who want his autograph
, never make a row...
Women! But you do not know...
I love it! They kneel!
"Ah, Pisanello! How beautiful!
She is beautiful!"
They want to be in bed all
with me... in three, four...
I already have my problems in two...
The wife of a man of his caliber
knows he has to share it with the public.
Normality...
No interrupt me...
A dialogue without being interrupted...
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
Enough!
Take me home! Enough!
Report you for violation of privacy!
You are heartless!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
Bravo!
You're better than what I had imagined.
- Why are you so quiet?
- Because I have committed adultery.
Consider it part of your training.
Some things I've never done.
- Why not? - Why Milly
I would be upset.
But with me you have not had any problems.
Because I'm a prostitute?
With you I felt uninhibited.
But now I feel guilty.
Milly would not commit adultery
and I never betray.
Maybe you do not mind knowing that you have learned something.
Some things I can do with
Milly, it's like a saint.
Yes, like Madonna.
Here the saint you are mica Milly.
Virgin at the wedding you've come to you and not her.
- Like this?
- It's beautiful here!
- Want a drink?
- No, thanks, I can not.
But why not?
- Here.
- Thank you.
I love the old songs,
those of my childhood.
- I am very beautiful.
- And even as they danced once.
Eh, yes?
- Eh? - You are very good.
- Yes, what do you...
Ma ..  did not want to talk about?
- Nostalgia is my weakness.
- The memories are beautiful.
Did he ever tell someone
that you're beautiful?
It is not true, no. My husband, maybe a
time, but a movie actor ever.
Please do not take me for an actor,
are a human being like others...
... The same feelings, the same
vulnerability, the same desires.
I'm sorry...
when you kiss those beautiful women in the cinema...
... You seem to me, as I'll explain...
A crazy man.
A kiss is just fiction film.
Yes, I know, but I've always wondered
...
... I wonder what it would be
Luke kissing Salta.
Now you know.
- It's fantastic. - I'm beautiful?
- No, more.
- Wait now comes the rest.
- What else?
Well ', we do. At this point I
I can not go back.
- You're charming.
- No, no, no, no. What a mess!
- I do not see any trouble.
- Yes that is a problem.
I would love to make love with you...
... So I could tell my grandchildren something to
, but should commit adultery.
Forget the semantics...
I love you all.
My Lady, I do not know what to do.
I do not know what to do.
I love my husband, but I am so curious
.
Life is so short, there are certain moments
already written in destiny.
- One is this. - No, wait.
Wait a moment please go to the bathroom.
Do not move, do not move from there.
Do not go.
- What is it?
- I swore that I would.
I know. Me neither.
I have to tell Sally.
But you said that your relationship
was dying, not my fault.
Do not say that, it is already off.
- Do you know... Yesterday I dreamed
of the two of us together. - Really?
To explore Italy...
... To see the beautiful architecture
Milan, Venice, Naples.
- I'll be master?
- I'm a good teacher?
We could be... in small towns...
... In boarding houses.
Since Sally has a week
exams...
First... I do not want to give her the news.
- No, of course.
- But soon after. I love you.
(Yell indistinct)
Okay. Yes
(yell indistinct)
But who is that?
Seems interesting!
(Indistinct and yell excitedly)
We're on the road with Aldo Romano. E '
is true that a bus driver?
What do you want, I do not understand?
- It is true that
is bringing the clothes in the laundry? - Yes, but what do you want?
- Do you like the hamburger?
- No, I do not like.
- It is a stain on his jacket?
- Yes, it's marinara sauce.
- As if procured?
- But I have to tell everyone?
E'successo while I ate a plate of rigatoni. What interests you?
- Gabriel, Camilla, Sofia.
- Hello, Dad! - Hello! - Hello!
You know it is all over?
It's back to business as usual,
I'm happy.
Now Aldo Romano is all over the news.
Perfesteggiare go to eat a pizza in Velletri. I'm buying.
- Who is it?
- Aldo Romano.
- I think I went well
exam. - Of course!
You got it passed with ease,
've studied much.
- I have tried so hard.
- Doubt itself for no reason.
- Do you want anything else?
- Sure. - No. - No.
- Ah, okay, so...
- Ok.
See how quiet?
The harbor for dinner tonight and tell him.
- Ok. Are you sure?
- Yes Yes.
I thought of a very beautiful:
I have not ever seen the Acropolis and the Parthenon.
Can we go to Sicily.
In fact we could rent a boat to sail and go around the boot.
I have always seen pictures of Palermo and I think it's romantic.
Nothing compared to being on the spot.
(PHONE RINGING)
- I'm sorry.
- Sure. Hello? No. .. Hello?
Yes, let me see if I can...
Hello?
- E'triste.
- What?
That you in love with Monica.
- There's something about her...
- Did you know that Sally loves you very much?
- I know. - And your common sense tells you that
Sally is a more sensible choice.
Yes, I know, I know everything, but still...
I can not explain.
I see.
- Guess what '? - What?
- I had a part. - A part?
A beautiful part in a film with a big budget...
... Turns to Los Angeles and Tokyo.
- When? - I have to leave tonight.
- What were you saying the boat in Sicily?
- They need me for five months.
- Five months in Japan?
A month in Los Angeles and four in Japan
, if consistent with the times.
I can not wait to go.
It is the dream of my life
to go in the Far East.
- It's your dream?
- Who's there?
Justin Brill, Ricardo Ramirez...
Ricardo Ramirez is very charming.
I worked with Justin Brill
when he was married to Rebecca Wright.
- The boy picked up a
crazy crush on me. - Now it is free.
It's all so exciting!
I can not wait to get back to Los Angeles.
See the drama teacher...
It's nice to see places,
but nothing is like home.
- Who is the director?
- Max Trommel.
I love it, I love his work.
Is the only one I trust to turn
of the nudity required.
Even though I know that a lot of drugs,
look so worn out...
... Is so sexy about him.
I have to lose weight.
The writer saw me on TV and
lost his head for my skill.
I have to lose three pounds.
I'll start to run.
This part is such an occasion for me...
I hope I can bring my dog, not
as in London which is impossible.
Milly Stay calm, stay calm.
Better to go to bed and have a regret...
... Or just go and have a
regret for life?
What do I do? Better remorse, no?
Better remorse, absolutely.
- Yes, better remorse. - Shut up.
- What? - Shut up or I'll kill you.
Now open the door and let's go, hurry
. Not a word.
- Are you ready love? - Shut
and not even open your mouth.
If you do what I say
there'll be okay.
- Got it? - Yes
- Then give me the money and jewelry.
- You are who I am? - No, I do not know
and I do not give a damn.
- You shut up and stop crying.
- Here.
- Give me your wallet.
- But does not rise.
- Give me your watch. - Yes
- The clock. - Yes
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
(Man) Open.
(Man) Open, I am in charge of
hotel security.
(Woman) Open, Luke!
I know you're there.
- My wife! She is my wife.
- Your wife? - Yes
- But you were separated?
- Oh, the food!
- I do not want to end up like the other woman
in the paper. - I'm finished.
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
Oh...
Listen to me.
Let's do this... Not yet finished.
Let's do this. You put yourself in
to the bathroom and hide in the shower.
- I put her in bed.
- Yes - Go and shut the door.
- Join. - Yes, good.
- Close. Go to bed.
(SHOTS AT THE DOOR)
(Man) Open up!
- Now this gentleman, I must explain why he did not open
. - Come on.
- (Woman) Come near the bed.
- Did not you hear knocking?
- What's going on? Are you crazy?
- Have not you heard?
But I need to hear? I'm
here with my girlfriend and I was...
But she is not the woman's husband?
- But who knows!
- She said it was her husband.
But you're crazy! I will sue you!
Please forgive us and please excuse us.
What have you done?
I do not understand what is happening.
(Yell indistinct)
- It was not my fault.
- Exit.
- Look, that was not my fault.
- Madam, be patient!
- I'm sorry. - (Thief) I call
lawyers. - Sorry.
- Anyway, I...
- Come, madam. Thank you.
- Did not have to end like this.
I do not know what... - Have a seat, ma'am.
- But...
- Enough!
- Thank you. Thank you very much.
- Imagine.
I take my disorder. Vado.
In fact here is the clock.
I give also the ring of his own.
- Thank you. Really, thanks.
- Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- Hello. Thank you. Hello.
I can not believe.
Course... right,
're really cute.
- What?
- He's right, you're pretty.
Thank you. Ma .. she is a thief, right?
Yes, I'm a thief specialized in hotels.
- But I also do some mugging.
- Oh yeah?
- Ah. Exciting.
- You're exciting.
You know I've never made love with a criminal
?
- My husband is a businessman
very respectable. - Yes? - Yes
know what they say,
opportunity makes the thief. We take this opportunity?
- Be '... sure. - Of course.
- We're in a hotel room.
- We're in bed, you're with the
petticoat. - I'm already dressed.
- So. - So what?
- So, anyway...
I think I will feel more Monica.
Yes, but you will read about
tabloid...
... That comes and goes with Justin Brill
vacationing in Aspen at his chalet.
Consider yourself lucky.
You saved my life.
A year with her and you might throw in a free fall...
... And adopt orphaned Burmese.
- With age comes wisdom.
- With age comes exhaustion.
-
We have met here the first time. - Yes
- Now I have to go back to the Excelsior.
- Nice. Are you doing well.
- You make a lot of money with shopping centers
. - Have you sold?
As a wise man once said:
"Things happen."
- Sure. So, I salute you.
- Yes, Goodbye.
How nice!
Tonight there is a preview film.
Can we go without
casino and enjoy the film.
We must not put ourselves posing for journalists.
- Look, we were not invited.
- Ah...
Then we can stay at home and enjoy the film.
And I no longer have to share you with
models, actresses and sexy secretaries.
Ma .. Hey! Hey! Hey!
I am  Leopoldo Pisanello.
Good morning, ma'am, this morning I had breakfast...
... I put the butter on two slices of bread and jam
.
Then I made the cream with the shaving gel
Because I do so the beard,
with gel. I really like the cream.
I am Leopoldo Pisanello.
Good morning. Want an autograph?
I Leopoldo Pisanello. You want it?
I Leopoldo Pisanello. Lady!
I give you a scoop: I wear boxers.
Do you want them to see?
Do you want them to see the boxer? Here they are.
I wear white boxers and wide.
Here they are. It's a scoop!
Lady! Are Leopoldo Pisanello.
Do you think it's better a trim?
And she's my wife.
Mrs., look has stretch marks.
The ladder in the stocking is fashionable.
It "trend" the ladder.
Want to see Pisanello
on one leg alone? Here it is, on one leg.
Is a great scoop,
this morning I had breakfast...
(Leopold) Just paparazzi!
Just paparazzi! Enough!
- Excuse me, but I know you. - Yes ..
- Yes, I remember the face.
She was not... What was his name?
- I Leopoldo Pisanello. - That's it.
- You want an autograph?
- Yes If you want to... Tenga.
- I'll give you an autograph. - Please.
- I Leopoldo Pisanello,
if you remember. - Thank you. - It's me.
- You see? - Yes, let's go home,
there are children. - Come on.
Here, here.
He ​​surely remember me.
This gentleman once,
I acted as driver. Right?
- Yes - Here. - I told you:
"Life is sometimes very cruel."
It does not give satisfaction
nor to those who are rich and famous...
... Or who is poor and unknown.
But to be rich and famous, between the two,
is definitely better.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
- Thank you. - Lord. - Goodbye.
Come on.
- You know what he said?
- Yes, I understand... I get it.
- Milly? Milly? - But where are
finished? I was worried.
- What happened to you?
- I went in and I found you.
Then I lost the phone, I'm lost for
Rome.
But you do that to you?
My uncles I have organized every
minutes.
- At least it went well?
- We're going home.
- As at home?
- Yes, let's go back to Pordenone.
- But we just got here.
- Does not matter.
I do not want to see my uncles and their friends
jerks.
I do not want that job.
I want my old job back.
Maybe we will not be rich, but we will have a better life
.
- Ate always like to teach?
- Yes Yes, but... - No "but".
We now return home and we will have a life...
... A life much better,
with children.
I also... I can paint a little. '
Okay. I'm surprised.
I do not know what to tell you.
Do not say anything. Make love?
- How?
- Before leaving, perfesteggiare.
Now I'll teach you something about the stars.
- I sconvolgerò. Do not be surprised.
- Sconvolgimi.
(MUSIC OPERA "I PAGLIACCl")
(CORI)
# accordandi I speak?
# #
A great show for twenty-three hours.
Put ​​on your costume...
#... And faccla flour.
# The people pay and they want to laugh.
# # And if Harlequin shall steal Colomblna...
#... Laugh, Clown...
#... And everyone t'applaudirà.
# Laugh, clown...
#... Your love is broken.
Laugh.
- No! - The name!
- Devil! But really...
(In chorus) - What are you doing?
- To you! To you!
In the throes of death you will tell!
- Help!
- Edda!
Ah, are you? So be it!
(CHORUS)
The play is over.
(MUSIC FINAL WORK)
(applauses and ovations)
critics define you "wonderful"
and "voice of the golden age."
- Incredible! - Great!
I can not believe it. But enough for me.
- I have proven to be good.
- You are beautiful here.
Mom does not fly, I no tour,
my life is fine as it is.
I have a beautiful family, I'm home...
... I relax, bury the dead,
I'm happy.
- Do not go away then? - No, stop.
- Tonight I apologize to everyone.
Now we go to the streets of Spain to the cocktail Max
- Are we late? - He's a friend, not
will take it, but now let's go.
- I beg your pardon? - I
cosìfelice for your husband, Mariangela.
As for you, how do I
not forgive you if I love you?
"Another Caruso
and in difficult conditions."
Have not been very kind to my father.
Er...
Maybe it's better that you do not read it.
Read it, but do not tell my father.
I do not read Italian newspapers.
- "With the exception of the magnificent voice of Giancarlo
Santoli..." -Magnificent!
(Mariangela)
has the most beautiful voice of all!
- "Whoever the 'minus habens'..."
Do you understand? - Yes, I understand.
"Whoever the 'minus habens'
who conceived the experiment..."
"
... Should be arrested and beheaded."
- Oh! Even.
- Ah, well, 'they told him worse.
This must be the most beautiful
terrace in Rome.
Yes, me and my wife
is a privilege to live here.
Of course, you have the
steps of Piazza di Spagna there.
I would say that the reviews are all exceptional.
What did you call the press?
What word they used?
It was not master... "Pettigrew habens"!
- I have failed in Latin, which means
. - What precorri time.
Your mother had the good fortune to marry a
"minus habens."
- I propose a toast to the future
-law. - Good luck, guys!
- Love, let's look at the square.
- Yes, of course. - Better toast.
(Phyllis) I'm glad,
are just a very nice couple.
This city is unique.
Why do not we get married there,
in front of the fountain there?
Anything you want.
I could stay here all night.
It's too good.
("FLY" by Domenico Modugno
INSTRUMENTAL VERSION)
I'm the one who knows best
Rome, not the policeman.
I see everything from up here.
The Romans, when they are in love,
are on the steps.
There are a lot of stories.
One day I'll tell you.