Dogs.
Mans best friend.
But do we really know
our faithful companions?
How they see their world?
What they really think of us?
In this film, well meet dogs
that seem to have a sixth sense...
I knew Id got breast cancer
because Max had told me.
undying loyalty...
That dog saved my life,
and for that, he won the yictoria Cross.
incredible intuition.
I¡¯ve not taught her to do it,
she¡¯s just done it.
Well follow the life of a growing poppy.
It could be any dog,
and in fact, many dogs will play this role.
But by watching it develop, we¡¯ll reveal
the hidden abilities in all dogs.
In the last few years,
scientists have delved deeper than
ever before into the canine mind and body,
and the results are extraordinary.
The way you see dogs
will never be the same again.
A puppy is born every second
somewhere in the world.
Md just moments ago,
this litter was joined by a sister,
our puppy.
She weighs under 500 grammes
and is remarkably vulnerable.
Shes born blind
and her ears are sealed closed
for the first two weeks other life
as theyre still developing
and theyre too fragile to be exposed.
She cant control her own temperature,
so shes totally reliant
on the warmth of her mom.
In essence, she¡¯s premature,
so why are puppies born too small
to survive on their own?
Well, the smeller the puppy,
the larger the litter,
and as long as they have
their mothers protection,
more of them will somive.
Combine this with the amazing abilities
hidden inside our puppies,
and you begin to see why dogs have become
so successful all over the world.
Today, dogs are found
in more shapes, sizes and varieties
than any other mammal on the planet.
There are some 500 million dogs alive today
and over 400 recognised breeds.
They¡¯re so familiar to us,
we can forget how extraordinary they are.
Even the simple act 0f shaking off water
hides a spectacular technique.
When you slow it down a thousand times,
you can see the head turns
a full 180 degrees.
This kick¡ªstarts a rotational momentum
that corkscrews down the body.
Expelling water from their fur quickly
so they dont get cold.
If youve ever been drenched by a dog
youll know how efficient this technique is.
Their physical abilities may be remarkable,
but it¡¯s their relationship with us
that lies at the heart of their success.
Weve trained them so they¡¯ll hunt for us,
guard our homes, retrieve on command
and herd our livestock.
But they also bring their own magic
to this partnership.
Dogs seem to understand our needs
and have a desire to help us out.
I¡¯ve not taught her to do it,
she¡¯s just done it.
Jess, come here. Here.
Sit down then. Sit. Sit.
Jess is a it¡ªyear¡ªold springer spaniel
that helps Louise Moorhouse with
the daily workings 0f her farm in Devon.
Mything you ask her to do, she¡¯ll do it.
Md she just lends her hand to basically,
well, her paw, to anything.
In lambing season,
Jess not only carries
the milk bottles for Louise,
but she helps feed the orphaned
lambs herself.
She¡¯s over¡ªriding her natural instinct
to chase or even eat the lamb.
She¡¯s just an extra pair of hands, really.
I think she does it
because she¡¯s grown up with the sheep
and I think she probably thinks
they¡¯re part 0f her family.
It¡¯s this willingness to please
that has led to an enduring partnership.
Some days she¡¯s just like a normal dog,
you know, not listening at all.
But other days, to be honest, and most days,
I don¡¯t really treat her as a dog,
I think I treat her as my best
friend, really.
Md the first stages of this relationship
are formed
when dogs are at their most loveable.
Back with our puppy and shes only just
beginning to be aware of her surroundings.
Her eyes and ears that were closed
for the first two weeks of her life
are now opening.
Md with this comes a whole new world
of sensory stimulation.
She uses her vision to move around,
but does she see the world
the same way we do?
Well, dogs are colour blind,
but that doesn¡¯t mean
that everything is black and white.
She does see colour,
but mostly just blues end yellows.
Its becsuse she only has
two types of colour receptors
compared to humans who have three.
Md it¡¯s also why your dog will often ignore
an orange toy in the green grass
as those colours look the same too.
Better to give them something blue.
But it¡¯s when things are moving,
that her vision comes into its own.
Dog¡¯s eyes process
what they see more quickly than we do.
It¡¯s almost like they see in slow motion.
That¡¯s why they¡¯re always in the right place
to catch the frisbee.
A dogs hearing is siso superhuman.
They can hesr things four times further away
and twice as high pitched as we can.
Its why we can¡¯t hear dog whistles,
but it also means
they can hear the hum of lights,
and even the pulsing sound
of a quart crystal in a digital clock.
But there¡¯s one sense she¡¯ll use
more than any other,
her sense of smell.
A dogs brain is one¡ªtenth the size of ours,
but the part that controls smell
is 40 times larger.
They have up to 300 million scent glands
in their nose compared to our 5 million.
So don¡¯t kid yourself,
you can¡¯t hide a bone from your dog
just because it¡¯s out of sight.
Our puppy is your weeks old
and shes busy exploring her home.
But not like we would.
We look around with our eyes.
She looks around with her nose.
Its why a healthy dog
likes to keep its nose wet.
This maximises the number of scent molecules
it can absorb from the air.
Their nose is their superpower.
Its so powerful
they can smell well into the distant past.
When we watch a dog
enter a new environment,
it looks like they just walk in
the same way we would.
But when you see the world
from their perspective,
you realise theyre picking up all the
information they need with their noses.
Not only can they smell objects
that were there
and have now been cleaned away.
Their senses are so keen,
they can smell events days, weeks,
even months after they¡¯ve happened.
So theyll know if there might just be a bit
of food left behind that they could eat.
This all comes naturally to a dog.
But when you train this wet,
snuffly, food¡ªfinding ability,
the results can save lives.
Good boy, go on.
The dogs are very, very efficient.
They¡¯re probably equal
to about 10 people searching.
Max is a wilderness air¡ªscenting dog
and he¡¯s trained to pickup human scent
so he can find missing people
for his handler, yjes Lyons.
We all smell, whether we like it or not,
and our scent gets carried in the wind
and that¡¯s what he¡¯s trained to locate.
He gets that excited he cant bark properly,
so he gives me a huff¡ªhuff thing.
Max is one of the most successful
search and rescue dogs in the country.
He knows what he¡¯s doing, don¡¯t you?
Dogs like Mao can really make a difference
when all reasonable hope has been lost.
I had been to Exeter to do shopping
and I came home on the bus
and I rang the bell to stop at the green
and it didnt.
Md it took me on,
further up here to Qoickes farm.
Mdl said to the driver,
¡®Oh, it¡¯s all right,
I can get off here,
go through the arboretum
and Fm at my back gate.
But I got in the arboretum,
I couldnt find my way out.
Seventy¡ªnine¡ªyear¡ªold Margaret Haverson
hadnt considered that the woodland
had been neglected for over 4t years
and was completely overgrown.
I get tied up with the brambles and that.
This was all covered in brambles.
Md then it got cold and dark and that¡ª¡ª
sol lay down under a big tree,
which could have been that one?
But it was a big tree.
Margaret lay under that tree for three days
and two frozen nights
while the police force, volunteers and
even helicopters with heat¡ªseeking cameras
combed the area trying to locate her.
Yes, and I was frozen.
So Max was called in
to see if a dogs nose could succeed
where everything else had failed
and before it was too late.
To tell you the truth,
I was not expecting to find Margaret alive.
I thought, because 0f the weather,
I thought she would have died
0f hypothermia.
But then I kept dozing off and on,
until you came and found me,
or you came and found me.
Yeah, Max found you, didn¡¯t he? Yeah.
¡ª You were a good boy, you were.
¡ªYeah.
Where humans had failed,
Maxs nose cut though the undergrowth
and saved Margarets life.
I was very cold and very relieved,
when I was licked all over by a dog.
He was so happy, weren¡¯t you?
Yes.
O course, you¡¯re good, aren¡¯t you?
¡ª Yeah, good boy.
¡ª You¡¯re good.
Our litter 0f pups are now five weeks old
and theyre becoming more adventurous.
Testing what they can destroy
with their teeth.
Md who they can and cant pick fights with.
But above all, theyre discovering
what it means to be a dog.
Simple play between two puppies
reveals the wild ancestor within.
Their hunting instinct,
the dominant and submissive behaviours
that are essential to pack life.
This is because all dots
can trace their ancestry back to the wolf.
So, if all dogs came from one species,
then how did they end op
to be so many different shapes and sioes?
When we first domesticated dogs,
we bred out some of the wild behaviours.
Md this process accidentally led
to new characteristics:
coloured coats, curly tails and floppy ears.
Add a few thousand years of breeding
from the dogs we love the most,
and you have the huge variety
that we see today.
In theory,
any dog can mate with any other dog.
But practicalities get in the way.
If humans were as different
as a pug and a Saint Bernard,
then our heights would range
from 65 centimetres to it metres tall.
But there¡¯s one thing
that just about every dog does,
bark.
So why do they bark?
Where does it come from?
Wolves don¡¯t bark, they howl.
Some scientists think that barking
has evolved just for our benefit.
So does this mean
that theyre talking to os?
Md if so, what are they saying?
They seem to understand our words...
Dig, dig.
Come on, speak.
Good boy.
But can dots really talk to us by barking?
I dont think anybody ever understands dog.
They understand you.
I dont think you ever understand a dog.
Lets see if these owners can understand
what different barks mean?
Put them on the doff, shell probably
be able to tell the difference than me.
Okay.
Cant hear a thing.
Its unhappy.
It wants attention, its frustrated.
I visual ise him in an open space on a lead
and he wants to be off
and to go to somewhere or somebody.
It sounds quite a happy bark,
it sounds as if it¡¯s playing.
To me, that sounds like you are just about
tothrowa baliforthedog
and theres that level of excitement.
Its running all around you.
Its been identified
that dots can communicate
at least six different emotions to us
through their barks.
That¡¯s why I know what you¡¯re thinking.
Well, that just proves, doesn¡¯t it,
that dots can talk by barking.
Back with our growing puppy,
she¡¯s not trying to communicate with us
just yet.
Only foe weeks old,
the puppies sre still finding their feet
and slowly gaining independence
from their mother.
Milk is replaced
with a first tentative interest in water.
The tip of a dogs tongue
has taste buds just for water.
They create a desire to drink
which is important as their natural diet
of meat is high in salt.
But even the simple act of drinking
is more complicated than it looks.
Dogs come their tongue into the water
to create a large surface area
to stick the water to.
They pull it up into their mouth,
snapping it shut
before all the water escapes.
Its a surprisingly complex
and beautiful process
for such a simple daily requirement.
Md it¡¯s also why dogs make such a mess
when they¡¯re drinking.
Puppies sleep far more than they are awake,
just like human babies.
Exhausted from a world of new experiences,
they fall into a deep slumber.
It looks like they are dreaming
about chasing rabbits,
but is that just our human sentiments
getting in the way?
Dogs do dream.
Md by monitoring their brain waves,
scientists have found out that puppies
dream far more than adult doss.
They can even tell that dots dream
about the days events,
processing their memories.
Looks like its been quite a busy day.
But what will the future huld?
A furtnight later and uur puppys arrived
at one of the world¡¯s most high¡ªtech,
specialist dog centres.
Shes here to find out
if she has what it takes,
to make it as one of the most
sought¡ªafter dogs in the country.
Is she fit, healthy, intelligent
and above all, the right character
to be a guide dog for the blind?
The first test is to see how she¡¯ll respond
to an unfamiliar, slightly scary sound.
She should react, but not panic.
¡ª Very good.
¡ª Really nice.
She set and watched that very intently.
Ready?
The most crucial trait is loyalty,
looking to her owner at all times
and in all situations.
Puppy, puppy, come on.
There we are. That¡¯s very good.
Md it seems like she¡¯s got what it takes.
¡ª A star in the making.
-Yes.
You might wonder if your dog could qualify
to be a guide dog
You can get an idea by observing them.
Research has shown
that dots are left or right¡ªpawed.
You a left¡ªfooter, Max, eh?
ke you a left footer, no?
You can test this by wstching closely
to see which paw they step off with.
I think that was the right foot
that started.
Here, yeah, she¡¯s left¡ªfooted, isn¡¯t she?
You¡¯re left¡ªhanded.
Okay, lets go.
I think weve proven there
in that unbiased test
that it was his right foot
that came forward.
Preliminary research has shown
that right¡ªpawed dogs
are statistically more likely
to pass their guide dot test.
You¡¯d get them run over by a bus you would,
wouldn¡¯t you?
There¡¯s another clue
to the chances of them passing,
in the swirls of hair on your dog,
and it all depends which way they turn.
CIodise.
MticIocise.
If your dog is right¡ªpawed
and the swirl goes anticlockwise,
then your dog is more likely to be calm,
confident and self¡ªassured.
Exactly the traits that a guide dog needs.
Do you want to be a guide dog?
You could be a blind dog for the guides.
Md if your dog is left¡ªpawed,
be prepared for some creative solutions
to your problems.
Back with our puppy, and she¡¯s joined
a group of other potential guide dogs.
Md what do you know,
shes also right¡ªpawed.
There¡¯s still a year of training
to complete,
but for now, she can have fun.
We¡¯ve trained doss for thousands of years
to work with us,
harnessing their incredible
physical abilities.
Md the husky is one of the best there is.
They¡¯re superb athletes,
able to run for over 15t kilometres a day
in subzero temperatures,
and they love it.
They have a coat of fur two layers thick
that insulates them from the cold.
Even at minus 60, they won¡¯t get frostbite.
Md when they need to cool down,
like all dogs, they pent.
By looking at these huskies
with a thermal camera,
we can see that their mouths and tongues
are white
with the heat that they are expelling
from their body core.
Md it means that when your dog
is panting after a run,
shea not puffed out,
shes just cooling down.
Its a dogs main method of losing heat,
as theyre covered in fur,
the only place they can really sweat
is through their paws.
Dogs have been our working companions
for as long as we can remember.
We¡¯ve used the basset hound¡¯s nose
to sniff out prey,
the Rottweiler¡¯s strength
for guarding our homes,
the Afghan¡¯s sight and speed to give chase,
and the huskys endurance
in extreme environments.
But from the very beginning,
we¡¯ve also chosen dogs that are cute
and give us comfort.
Md no matter what the size,
dogs have worked their way into our hearts.
Its a strong emotional bond,
and one that our rapidly growing puppy
is just beginning to discooer.
Now nine weeks old, she¡¯s taking
her first steps into her new home
and a very special new relationship.
This is the family who will raise her
until shes ready to be a guide dog.
Its here that shell learn
to live with people.
Md it¡¯s the perfect time
for this transition.
At this key stage in their life,
puppies actually prefer to go
to human companions than other dogs.
When a puppy holds our gaze
with its big eyes and infant¡ªlike features,
it causes our brain to react as though
were looking at a human baby.
But have you ever wondered
what theyre thinking?
Sometimes dogs look at us
with such knowing eyes.
But do they really know how we feel?
They can read what sort of mood you¡¯re in.
They¡¯re somebody who can understand
how you¡¯re feeling ins day,
whether you are feeling upset.
They know when Fm hurting,
they know when I¡¯m sad.
Md, yeah, 100 percent
I think they understand me.
Dogs definitely look at us
like they know what¡¯s up.
Md tests have shown
that theres truth in this.
Humans naturally look to the left hand side
of someone¡¯s face to read their mood
as that¡¯s where we display our emotions.
Dogs are one of the few other species
that haoe picked upon this
and they also do it
to tell how we are feeling.
Who can resist a dog
when its trying to cheer yoo up?
For some people, this irresistible affection
has transformed their lives.
Na officer Allen Parton suffered
a severe head injury
while on active duty in the Gulf War.
It left him confi ned to a wheelchair,
unable to talk
and he lost half of his life¡¯s memories.
You know, I cant remember
my children¡¯s first steps,
their first days at school,
their being born,
and I was there for all of those occasions.
But, sadly, those are memories robbed to me.
But more than this,
ilen didn¡¯t even recognise his children.
He had no idea who the lady was
that he had apparently married.
Md hed lost the ability
to feel any emotion.
I had two attempts at suicide
in rehabilitation
because I¡¯d lost my past, I¡¯d lost my future
and I was really in a psychologically
bad place, as well as physically.
But that all changed with a chance encnunter
with a dog named Endal,
who was failing his training
to be an assistance dog,
and needed a home.
At the time, there was
this one¡ªyear¡ªold Labrador up there
that had health problems
and a huge attitude problem
and bless him, you know, he saw something
on the floor by my wheelchair,
trotted across the training centre,
picked it up and put it in my lap.
Well, he didn¡¯t get a reaction,
he didn¡¯t get a treat,
he didn¡¯t get acknowledged.
Md this really hacked him off.
I mean, this was a dog
that didn¡¯t do anything for anyone
and he¡¯d done it for me,
and he wanted a treat,
a reward, praise, anything,
and he got the stone wall,
and then he trotted over
to the mock¡ªup supermarket
and took a tin 0ff the shelf,
brought it back and put it in my lap,
didn¡¯t get a reaction.
To cut a long story short,
I was disappearing under a mound of stuff.
Md just before I completely disappeared,
the brain switched on
and I smiled for the first time
in a long time.
Md it was the start of our relationship.
Endal became his 24¡ªhour companion,
aiding with every practical aspect
of his lit e.
He even helped Allen
reconnect with his family.
Md in 2002, AlIen remarried his wife
with Endal as his best man.
But this dog had to show his true devotion
when in the dead of night,
iIen and Endal were both hit bye car.
But though I was knocked unconscious
out of the wheelchair
and Endal had been stunned
by the vehicle as well,
he got up,
pulled me into the recovery position,
he retrieved his blanket
from under my wheel chair,
and covered me with it.
Md in the dark, he found my mobile phone
which had jettisoned off in the impact
and he brought it to my face.
Md then he made the brave decision
to limp off and go to a nearby hotel
and raise the alarm.
Md for that, he won the Victoria Cross
for animal bravery.
That dog had saved my life, my marriage
and brought me back to my children.
No one coold have predicted
the life¡ªchanging impact
that Endal would have on Allen¡¯s family.
It was a remarkable bond
and an incredible life,
but, inevitably, ate caught up with Endal.
I¡¯d had a lovely evening with Endal at home
knowing the vet was coming the next day.
I was able to tell him how much I loved him,
you know, what he¡¯d done for me.
Yeah, it was,
it was quite an emotional evening.
Md the final gift he gave me
was that gift of sadness.
I didn¡¯t know that emotion,
but that day Endal, you know, left me,
you know, put to sleep in my lap,
was the day that my heart broke
and I cried, yeah.
But there was a little guy in the corner
who was there with a han in his mouth
to wipe away the tears.
Hed been nurturing
alongside Endal for a year,
and that day,
he picked up the baton and ran with it.
Good lad.
Good boy.
Some people come up to me in the street
and they saythey wish they had a dog
as clever as Endal or EJ is,
and, and I think they have,
they just haven¡¯t opened
their minds and hearts.
Our faithful friend is now three months old.
Md her guide dog training
is starting in earnest.
Shes learning simple commands,
like returning to her owners call.
Md sitting on request.
Good girl.
PJI basic skills,
but really rather important
if you¡¯re gonna be a guide dog.
Shes also showing signs that her bond
with the family ingrowing.
A lick of the face or a kiss on the lips
definitely feels like true affection.
Md this is proof that your dog
is treating you like her mother.
Ps this behaviour originally comes
from a puppy licking her mums lips
to get her to regurgitate her dinner.
Nice.
We¡¯ve been watching a puppy grow,
and now that she¡¯s nine months old,
she¡¯s just about full size.
But like a lanky teenager,
shea not totally in control of it all
Jo St yet
Shes also taking the next steps
in her guide dog training.
Learning about strange sights,
sounds and smells.
Md most importantly,
bonding with her family.
Mother sure sign 0f this attachment
is a yawn.
It turns nut that the infectious nature
of yawns is a sign of empathy.
Suit ynu yawn and your dog yawns back,
it means ynuve got a good bond.
Have you ever wondered
why its so relaxing to hang out with a dog?
This is the Evelina Childrens Hospital
in London.
Md Magee is s normal dog,
with a very special job to do.
Hey, George, it¡¯s Magee.
George was admitted to hospital
on Christmas Eve just over a year ago.
Do you wanna stroke him?
He had a ruptured diaphragm,
and needed drastic surgery.
For the next 18 hours,
his parents didn¡¯t know if he would survive.
He¡¯s doing well now,
but he hasn¡¯t been home in all this time.
Give him a biscuit.
Oh, boy, he liked that. Oh, yeah.
So the one thing George looks forvard to
is this weekly visit from McGee.
That¡¯s nice.
But he gets a lot more out of it
than just a cuddle.
Oh, he gioes looely kisses.
When we stroke a dog,
it makes us feel happy and relaxed.
Tests have shown
that it lowers our blood pressure.
This is because our bodies release oxtocin
into our bloodstream,
the same hormone produced
when mothers breastfeed their babies.
This means we¡¯ll feel the peaceful,
warm sense of bonding and attachment
that a mother would with her newborn child.
Statistically, people live longer
if they own dogs.
That¡¯s lovely, isn¡¯t it, Magee?
They are less likely to have a heart attack,
and more likely to sumive one.
Oh, oh, that didn¡¯t take long, did it?
¡ª Oh, he¡¯s kissing you.
¡ª Oh, he¡¯s very lovely.
Yeah.
But the benefits go both ways.
Cuddle a dog,
and her blood pressure will also drop.
She even produces
the attachment hormone otocin.
So shes feeling that same bond
that goes between a mother and her child.
But how far does this special connection go?
Some people think their dogs
have almost supernatural powers.
Is there any truth that they can sense
when youre about to take them for a walk?
Or predict when youre going to faint?
Do some dogs really know us better
than we know ourselves?
The puppy we¡¯ve been following
is just over a year old.
Shes now living at the guide dot centre,
going through the toughest phase
of her training yet.
Shes made the important bond with humans,
but now, she must put it to practical use,
and do something really impressive.
Looking after a blind vulnerable
handler means
knowing to stop at the edge of the road.
Shes anticipating her handlers needs,
avoiding obstacles on the ground,
but also in the air.
She could walk right through this arch,
but she knows thst her blind handler
would hit her heed.
Good girl.
So how is she doing this?
It comes down to obsemat ion.
Dogs watch us all the time
in a way that no other animal does.
He senses whenever we are going to go out
and he knows before we even make a move.
They read nor body language,
and that¡¯s how they know
were going to take them for a walk,
before we think
weoe made the decision ourseloes.
Its this constant observation
that can sometimes appear
to give them a sixth sense.
Max isa red collie cross
normally full 0f energy and enthusiasm,
but in 2008, his owner Maureen Burns
noticed that something was wrong.
I thought at the time Mas was fading,
he was nine and a half,
and I was preparing myself for losing him,
because of... he just wasn¡¯t happy.
He wouldn¡¯t come with me,
wouldn¡¯t sit by me, wouldn¡¯t sit on my lap,
and the odd signs, he would come up
and touch my breast with his nose
and back off
so desperately unhappy,
with such a sad look in his eyes.
Maureen had a small lump in her breast
but her latest mammogram was clear
so she presumed all was okay.
Initially, I thought, ¡°Oh, it¡¯s just another
lumpy breast as people get.¡±
But then
I sort of connected it with the dog,
with his odd behaviour.
Md one day, I was looking in the mirror
in the bedroom here,
and I looked across in the mirror
at Max¡¯s eyes,
he was on the bed, as he is now,
and I knew it was cancer.
Maureen went to her local hospital
but both a scan and a mammogram
came back negative.
It took a surgical biopsy
to finally detect the cancer.
Maureen had it removed,
and the change in Mans behaviour
was instant.
The day I was picked up from the hospital,
he was his old hyper self again.
He put his nose across my breast
to check where the operation had been
and he was wagging his tail
and his eyes were happy
and it was unbelievable, the change
in him, instant.
I love Max xv much and lowe him so much.
Md even before Ego for a check¡ªup now,
I get him to check me out
and if he¡¯s happy and wagging his tail,
I¡¯m happy and I know I¡¯m okay.
We now know that dogs like Max
are smelling the tiny volatile chemicals
given off by cancerous tumours.
Most dogs can do this.
They just don¡¯t know that we¡¯re interested.
But with a little training,
dogs can accurately pick out a cancerous
patient from a selection of urine samples.
Good girl.
They can even be taught
to let diabetics like Steven know
that his blood sugar levels
are smelling low,
long before he can feel it,
and definitely before he passes oot.
Dogs like Stevens are now transforming
lives all over the coontry.
They are being trained
to detect the early warning signals
for severe allergic reactions,
epileptic fits and narcolepsy.
Our dog has also done something remarkable.
Shea done more
than just qualify to be a guide dog,
shes done so well in all her tests,
that Guide Dogs for the Blind would like her
to be a mother to the next generation.
Now aged it months old, our puppy,
who we followed from birth
is going to have a litter of her own.
Just like a human, she may esperience
morning sickness and strange food cravings,
but 63 days after conception,
she¡¯ll give birth
and the cycle will begin all over again.
A new litter of dogs,
with all their potential,
entering the world.
I¡¯m really surprised
how much she means to me, really,
weve always had them as a pet,
but shes definitely more than that.
I think every time you go out,
you learn something about the dogs,
you always learn something new.
There¡¯s so many benefits of having a dog
in one¡¯s life.
I cant recommend it highly enough.
Dogs give us an incredible amount.
il, all we can ever do
is look after them and love them.
Together, were steam.
Dogs are super intelligent
and have amazing powers.
God, I love him.
We now understand dogs
better than ever before.
Md the more we know aboot oor dogs,
the more we love them.
So dogs, slobbery, hairy mutts
only interested in food?
Sometimes, but mostly, just brilliant.