Good morning, America.
It's now 12 noon
in Salamanca, Spain.
In a short time, world leaders
from over 150 countries...
...meet here in Plaza Mayor...
...to sign up to President Ashton's
bold new counterterrorist strategy.
Since 9/11, more than 4500 people
have been killed...
...in the rising tide of global terror.
Those lives will not
soon be forgotten...
...as today, the world comes together
to take a stand against this violence.
We may be on the brink
of a historic agreement...
...between Western
and Arab leaders.
Security services are on high alert
in Salamanca...
...where we go live to our news team
and our reporter Angie Jones.
Five, four, three, two...
I am standing inside Plaza Mayor
in Salamanca, Spain...
...where crowds have lined up
for the kickoff of...
...what is without question
a landmark summit.
For months,
President Ashton's been working...
...with leaders
from five continents...
...to forge a new groundbreaking
alliance in the ongoing war on terror.
And now here, today...
...Western and Arab leaders
will meet for the first time...
...to formalize this new coalition...
...designed to once and for all...
...put a stranglehold
on international terrorism.
- Bring him up.
- Cue Mark.
- Tell us, Angie, what's the mood like?
- For the most part, hopeful.
Everyone here is very
sympathetic to those...
...who lost loved ones
in the recent bombing.
I did, however, speak to delegates...
What's she doing?
...both of whom took a hard line,
suggesting that U.S. Foreign policy...
Kevin, shut her down.
...has to bear some responsibility
for the recent events.
Thanks, Angie.
You'll have to keep us informed.
- What the hell was that?
- Not everyone loves us, Rex.
Why don't you leave the punditry
to someone paid to have an opinion?
I'm cool with censorship.
I know the American people love that.
- Come on, Angie. Lighten up.
- Got it.
- Gallery.
- Pass me over.
- Bruce.
- Yes.
- What was that? Stick to the script.
- I told her. Wanna tell her?
- Fine.
- That's fine.
- Who is the clown on two?
- Two is Luis.
Camera two, are you gonna move?
We're here for the summit,
not the sideshow.
Man, it's like training
a freaking dog.
Okay, everybody,
the president is about to arrive.
When he does, we're on him.
Let's get our ducks in a row.
Three, wider.
Four, stay where you are.
Kevin, keep it moving.
I'm dying here.
Camera five,
give me the motorcade.
Number seven, concentrate.
I wanna go close on the president.
All right, sir.
That's good.
Tighten up, five. Good.
- Isn't that?
- It's Thomas Barnes.
Why didn't we know he was here?
Shit, Grace. We should've had this.
Yeah, I don't...
- Kevin, pull the archives.
- Pull the archives, please.
The president's approaching
the plaza. All cameras ready.
Angie, we're back in 20.
And remember, we're here
for the summit, not the sideshow.
- There are other stories.
- I don't give a shit.
Unless the protesters set themselves
on fire, they're not our story.
- Kevin, you got it?
- Yeah.
Check this out.
This was only last year.
I can't believe he's back already.
If we're the only ones
who have this...
He won't talk. A year ago we had Hill,
we had that guy who saved Reagan.
- McCarthy.
- All of them.
A hero piece.
Barnes wanted nothing to do with it.
That was then.
It's a shame. It would've made a great
side story. We've no time to work it in.
That was then, this is now,
okay, guys? We've got our story.
Okay, cue graphics.
Camera five, give me a single.
- Here comes the mayor.
- Three, four, ready at the podium.
Three, wide. Four, in close. Start with
the leaders and end with the mayor.
- Thank you so much for being here.
- Three, pull back.
Yes. Camera six, get ready.
We're coming to you.
Good. That's good.
- Two, give me crowds.
- De Soto speech ending in one minute.
Camera five, give me something else
to work with. That's good.
Angie, when this is over,
I want a 15-second fill to wrap it up.
- Keep it simple.
- You mean dumb it down?
Get off it, Angie. Come on.
She's unbelievable.
I offer you my city...
The mayor's done in five.
Ready with the graphics.
This summit could be the
defining moment of his presidency.
Pull out, four, three...
Oh, my God.
The president appears
to have been shot.
- Shit.
- I heard two shots...
...and the president fell.
- Who's that guy?
What's he doing?
Okay, five, stay with that guy.
Everyone else, give me Ashton.
Three, stick with the president.
Just stay with him.
That's good. Just stay with him.
Stay with him. Hold it there.
This is insane.
Yeah, yeah. I'm coming back.
- Camera three, do better.
- They're not letting me through.
Don't give me this bullshit.
Figure it out.
Okay, you got him?
- What was that?
- There appears to be an explosion...
Camera four, turn around.
Find out what that was.
Kevin, get playback going. We have
to uplink everything we've got.
- Bruce.
- Uplink VTs 1 through 7 on my monitor.
Okay, Angie, you're on. Let's go.
We're live, Angie. This is it. Go.
I need a minute, Rex. All right?
Shit. Get Mark to stretch.
I know this is tough, okay?
I know that.
We need you to tell us
what's going on.
- Okay.
- Focus, okay?
Angie? Please, tell us
what you're seeing.
- Deep breath. Go.
- The president of the United States...
...has been shot.
There have been several gunshots.
It appears there was also a bomb
that went off outside the plaza.
There are people running scared...
Oh, shit!
Mark?
Mark, you gotta fill.
It seems that a huge bomb...
Oh, my God. Angie! Angie!
At the moment,
smoke from the explosion...
...mercifully covers the extent
of the human carnage.
There must be many people dead
and injured.
- Angie.
- This truly is terrible.
Come on, kiddo, get up.
Get up.
Kevin, pull the feed.
Turn it off!
Good morning, America.
It's now 12 noon
in Salamanca, Spain.
In a short time, world leaders
from over 150 countries...
It's time.
- Plaza Mayor to sign up
to President Ashton's...
...bold new
counterterrorist strategy.
Since 9/11,
more than 4500 people...
...have been killed
in the rising tide of global terror.
Those lives will not
soon be forgotten, as today...
...the world comes together
to take a stand against this violence.
We may be on the brink
of a historic agreement...
...between Western
and Arab leaders.
Security services
are on high alert...
All teams, this is Control.
- Motorcade one minute to landing.
- Copy.
- Level 4B, clear.
- Roger, Control.
- It was before he lost it.
- Come on.
- Guy had a nervous breakdown.
- Six months ago.
He's not that guy anymore.
Give him a break.
What are the chances he freaks out
the minute we walk?
I'd put it at fifty-fifty.
We doing this?
Mr. President.
All teams, this is Control.
Eagle is on the move.
Tell us, Angie,
what's the mood there?
For the most part, hopeful.
Everyone here
is very sympathetic to those...
...who lost loved ones
in the recent bombing.
Thanks.
For what?
For getting me back out here.
Don't thank me yet.
Mr. President?
Here we go.
All right, sir.
What a beautiful baby.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
It's a wonderful day.
Hey! Drop it.
Not now.
- Michael team's go for count off.
- All clear from above.
- And south?
- Yeah. Here too.
President Henry Ashton.
Welcome. Thank you so much
for being here.
This is a wondrous day.
Today, we make history.
Se? Or Presidente, fellow members
of the European Union...
...our friends from Africa,
Middle East...
...President Ashton,
citizens of the world...
...it is with great pleasure
that I invite you all to our humble city.
And it is with a sad heart...
...that we must meet in mourning...
...for those who lost loved ones
in the recent bombings.
Back annex, the building
should have been cleared.
Copy. It's clear.
I've got a flutter on the second floor.
Seventh window from the left.
- Copy. We'll check again.
- The hopes of the world...
...are with us.
Let us not disappoint them.
For we cannot today...
...or ever, let the specter of evil...
...overcome the hope
of a better tomorrow.
It's just a fan that's been left on.
We got it.
Therefore, I offer you my city,
my heart and my hope.
Barnes!
- Barnes!
- Eagle's down!
Repeat, Eagle's down!
Got a GSW. Repeat, GSW.
- Get him out of here!
- Move! Move!
Move him! Go! Go, go, go!
Pick him up! One, two, three.
You got him?
Find that shooter.
Control, I want a perimeter
set a half block out.
Sweep the buildings
along the back annex.
No one goes in or out
without our go.
- Okay, you got him?
- Veronica!
- Control.
- Do something!
Come in, Control!
I need a 20 on POTUS.
Control. Come in, Control. Damn it!
- Listen to me!
- I said back up! Hey, shut up!
Listen! We are in danger.
We gotta get out of here!
Now, get up! I said get up!
- Let me have him.
- Let me go.
Barnes.
Why'd you run for the president?
Why did you run for the president?
- Barnes, we're handling this.
- I hear bang.
- I protect the mayor. It's my job!
- You got there pretty fast.
- Barnes, he's a cop.
- I don't care, he knows something!
Get him out of here! Get him out.
Don't release him!
I've been set up!
You got the wrong person!
Control. Control, come in.
There's no response from Control.
I just spoke with them.
POTUS is secure.
Till we find that shooter,
we're shutting the city down.
This never should've happened.
Except that it did.
And it happened on our watch.
I can't live with that.
We gotta find him.
- Sir, we need your camera.
- Sure.
- Where's the zoom?
- It's that right here.
Right there.
That's where the flutter was.
But the shot was up and to the left.
Wait, you saw the shooter?
No. But I saw something.
Like a flash of light.
- I saw a man in that room, sir.
- I'll check it out.
- I'm coming with you.
- No! No.
If you're wrong, let me take the heat.
Sir, did you film this entire thing?
- Yes.
- Show me.
I think I got the shooter on tape.
Wait, go forward.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God!
There's a bomb at the podium!
Everybody get down!
This never should've happened.
Find that shooter.
Flash of light.
He just walked. He just walked.
Medic! We need a medic here!
Barnes.
We're gonna get you
some help, buddy.
Barnes? Barnes.
Anna?
Hey! Hey, stop him! Stop him!
Stop! Stop!
Hey, freeze!
Secret Service.
I need to see your tapes.
Yeah. Kevin.
I need to see any footage you have
of the back part of the plaza.
- We need footage of the plaza.
- How much do you need?
Just give me everything.
Can you hear me?
Camera three, can you hear me?
Just play it back from there.
Yeah.
- Barnes, you were right.
- About what?
About the shooter. I'm in pursuit,
leaving the back annex, heading west.
Repeat, heading west.
- Did you call it in?
- No. No, I need you to.
- I got it. Go.
- Camera seven.
Camera seven. This is Grace,
can you hear me?
- Camera seven, can you hear me?
- Control? Come in, Control.
Control, come in.
- I need you to tell us...
- Damn it.
Okay. We need you to tell us
where you are.
This is Agent Barnes. Control is down.
My partner is in pursuit of a suspect.
We need immediate assistance
just outside the back annex.
Grace, they have a suspect.
Headed west on the surface streets.
- West.
- Do you copy?
Camera six, if you can hear me,
turn around and go west.
Backup is on its...
What?
Barnes, what is it?
Rewind that.
Six? Six, did you get all that?
Stop.
Oh, my God.
What? What? What did he see?
Next.
Police, I work for the mayor.
Are you armed?
Yes.
Okay, I'll turn it off. Go through.
I'll be at the underpass.
You have a glow about you.
It's the heat.
The heat?
What have you been doing?
Nothing.
Taking in the crowd.
Some more than others?
I saw you just now.
- You saw nothing.
- It didn't look like nothing.
You don't have to worry about him,
I promise.
Enrique.
You're the one that I want,
there is no one else.
How many ways do I need to say it?
When you've finished here we'll go
away together, just you and me.
I love you.
Did you remember to bring my bag?
Thank you.
- I love you.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the president of the United States:
President Henry Ashton.
Mr. Mayor, this is a great day.
It's an honor to be here.
Welcome. Thank you so much
for being here.
This is a wondrous day.
Today, we make history.
I'll be at the underpass.
You don't have to worry about him,
I promise.
You're the one that I want,
there is no one else.
When you've finished here we'll go
away together, just you and me.
- My heart and my hope.
Get him out of here!
Let's go, move it! Let's go!
- Get moving!
- Let me go! I work for the mayor!
- Shut up and move!
- Let me go!
Hey. Who are you?
Let's go. Who are you?
Look at me! Look!
Hey! Who are you?
Who are you? Who are you?
Look at me, look at me! Look at me!
Answer the goddamn question.
Why did you run?
Answer the question.
Veronica!
- Veronica! Veronica!
- Hey, calm down!
We have to go!
We are all in danger!
She threw something!
Gun. It's loaded.
- Back up, I said!
- Listen! He's telling the truth!
- Listen!
- Shut up! Just shut up!
My badge is here.
- Listen. We have to go.
- He has a badge.
Calm down! You on duty?
I work for the mayor.
Listen to me! We are in danger!
We gotta get out of here!
We have to go!
Why'd you run for the president?
Why did you run for the president?
I hear bang. I go to protect the mayor.
It's my job.
- You got there pretty fast.
- He's a cop.
- I don't care, he knows something!
- Get him out of here!
I've been set up!
You got the wrong person!
Do not release him!
Medic! We need a medic here!
Holden.
Hey! Stop him! Stop!
Hey! Stop him!
Hey, freeze!
Out of the way! Out of the way!
Freeze! Stop! I said freeze!
Damn it!
Get out the way! Get out the way!
Stop him! Stop him!
Someone stop him!
I'll be at the underpass.
Stop!
Get down! Get down!
Move!
Let's go!
Move! Move!
Out the way. Out the way!
Get out of the way! Police!
Out of the way!
Shit.
Out the way!
Surprised to see me alive?
It's amazing.
Hello.
- Hello, how are you?
- Okay.
Excuse me.
What are you seeing?
- Speak English.
- I try.
I'm just watching
all the people up there.
Hi. My name is Sam.
Nice to meet you.
Howard Lewis.
Nice to meet you too.
- American?
- Yeah.
- What brings you here?
- Just looking for a little excitement.
- First time, huh?
- Europe? Yeah.
Yeah, it just felt like it was
the right time. What about you?
I go where the moment takes me.
That must be nice. No family, right?
No.
None that I know of.
Things change when
you got kids running around.
Are yours with you?
No, they're with their mother. We're
going through a bad patch right now.
I needed to get away for
a little while, give us some space.
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- It's fine, it's fine.
I think it's my cue.
Yeah. It's nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you too. Best of luck.
Yeah. To you too.
What's your name?
- Hey, tell him your name.
- Anna.
That's a pretty name.
You look about the same age
as my son, Nathan.
Can I buy her another cone?
- No, no, no, it's okay. Thank you.
- No, really, really.
No, no, it's okay.
- Please, Mom?
- That's enough, I said no.
Anna?
I'm sorry.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the president of the United States:
President Henry Ashton.
Welcome. Thank you so much
for being here.
This is a wondrous day.
Today we make history.
It is with great pleasure that
I invite you all to our humble city.
The hopes of the world are with us.
We must come together...
...on this day...
...in this renowned place...
...to band together for peace.
I don't think he's supposed to be
up there. What's he doing?
Therefore, I offer you my city,
my heart and my hope.
What's he doing up there?
Get him!
Eagle's down, Eagle's down!
We got a GSW. Repeat, GSW.
We gotta leave right now.
Get him out of here!
Let's go! Move him!
Go! Go, go, go!
- One, two, three.
- You got him?
- Let me go!
- Move!
Shut up! Move it!
- Let me go!
- What were you doing up there?
Hey! Answer the goddamn question.
Veronica!
We have to go!
Please! Listen to me!
Hey. Step away, sir.
- She threw something.
- Gun. It's loaded.
- Hey! Back up, sir!
- Listen to me! He's telling the truth.
Veronica. Veronica!
Anna! Anna!
Hi, leave a message.
Pam. It's me.
Probably waking you up, it's just...
You'll see on the news when you
wake up that the president's been shot.
He was here in Spain, and I think
I just saw the guy who did it.
Look, look. I'm all right, all right?
I just want you to let the kids know
that I'm fine...
...and that I love them
very much and...
Oh, man. I can't believe
what I just saw.
And I think I got it all on tape.
I don't know what to do,
but the right...
Sir, we need your camera.
- Sure.
- Where's the zoom?
Press this button right there.
Yeah. That's...
That's where the flutter was.
But the shot was up to the left.
- You saw the shooter?
- I saw something, like a flash of light.
Right there. There was something
in that window right there.
- I saw a man in that room, sir.
- I'll go check it out.
- I'm coming with you.
- No! No.
If you're wrong, let me take the heat.
- Sir, did you film this entire thing?
- Yes, I did.
Show me.
I think I got the shooter on tape.
Wait, go forward.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
There's a bomb at the podium!
Medic! We need a medic here!
Anna?
Anna!
Where's your mother?
Where is she?
Everybody evacuate
the plaza, okay?
- Come with me.
- Okay.
I gotta get you somewhere safe,
then we'll find your mother.
Someone stop him!
Hold it!
Are you okay?
Hey! Hey! Get out the way!
Stop him! Get out the way!
Stop him!
Anyone, stop him!
Help us! Someone help!
Excuse me. Excuse me.
I need your help.
I need you to watch her. Her mother's
gone, I don't know where she is.
She'll be safe with me.
I'm gonna be right back.
I've got to help the police.
Just stay with this lady
and I'll be back. I promise.
I'll be right back, okay?
I'll be right back.
Don't worry, we'll find your mom,
don't cry.
Stop! Get out the way.
Hold it! Stop!
Stop! Freeze!
Out of the way! Freeze!
Stop him!
Move! Move, move, move!
Move! Quick!
Turn left, I got right!
Move!
He's a cop.
Freeze!
He shot him. He shot him.
Anna. Anna.
Anna!
When do we think
the changes will be ready?
It's not like I have to make
a speech now.
I could just wing it. How much trouble
could I really get myself into?
Thanks. Nice to know
we both know my limitations.
- We're stopping?
- Yes, sir.
Rick, I'll call you back.
The NSA's just confirmed the threat.
- Control, handoff complete.
- Roger, point man.
Where's Phil?
The hotel.
He's on with the Joint Chiefs.
He's sending the double, isn't he?
Yeah.
We're moving POTUS to the hotel.
Control, we've N.D.'d the car.
POTUS is returning.
We issue a statement that we're
deferring to Prime Minister Gutierrez...
Deferring, that's great.
Control, E TA to castle
is two minutes.
Today of all days.
Christ.
Sir, we've used doubles
since Reagan.
That was for photo ops.
Not for anything this big.
Control, we have PO TUS
and we are moving to the castle.
Eagle has arrived at the plaza.
Control, we have PO TUS
and are entering the castle.
- Sir.
- Talk to me, Phil.
NSA called it five minutes ago.
It's real.
And the summit? You're not
thinking of pulling out entirely?
Why would we?
Do we know who's behind this?
A local group with a vague connection
to the Mujahedin Brigade.
- Why issue the threat now?
- U.S. Special Forces...
...uncovered a plot to smuggle
a bomb out of Morocco.
We took their bomb and their men,
and this may be their retaliation.
You think trying to kill me
is a retaliation.
POTUS is moving.
Safe for Eagle to exit vehicle.
Copy that.
This is them?
That's Benwar Suarez. As near
as we can tell, he leads the group.
And what do we know about him?
He's from Morocco,
educated in Paris.
He went off the map for awhile,
but he surfaced in Beirut, Darfur.
Couple days ago we intercepted an
e-mail between members of his group.
Embedded in it were links to maps,
blueprints of the area.
It was this morning
that we received the threat.
The Joint Chiefs,
what do they recommend?
That we go after their leadership.
Here in Spain?
Morocco.
We have a satellite lock
on one of their camps there.
You want me to call in a strike
on a friendly Arab nation?
They're harboring terrorists.
- And this intel, we're certain...?
- Absolutely.
Control, we're clear on seven.
Why not focus on the ones
who are here actually doing this?
This summit is too important.
But we're looking for five people
out of 6 million. We are trying.
Try harder.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the president of the United States:
President Henry Ashton.
A wonderful day. Some words now.
Welcome.
This is a wondrous day.
Today, we make history.
- He doesn't even look like me.
- Se? Or Presidente...
...fellow members
of the European Union...
...President Ashton...
...and citizens of the world...
...it is with great pleasure that
I invite you all to our humble city.
Is that Thomas?
Yes, sir.
I thought he was still inactive.
He was.
Well, if he's back,
why isn't he with me?
We weren't sure if he was ready.
- You sent him out there.
- We need someone to sell the double.
Sell? He took a bullet for me, Phil.
And look at him.
He hasn't stopped
punishing himself since.
I liked him every bit
as much as you did.
But we needed to know
we could count on him again.
So you threw him out there
to see if he could?
That's how we treat
our friends now?
Therefore...
...I offer you my city,
my heart and my hope.
This summit could very well be the
defining moment of his presidency.
Jesus!
The president appears
to have been shot.
I heard two shots,
and the president fell.
Get the Joint Chiefs on the line now.
Admiral Houston, it's McCullough.
Have you seen the situation?
The president is secure.
Get him out of here!
How long do we have to get
the birds in the air?
So you're ready to strike now?
Mr. President.
Sir.
The Chiefs have a satellite lock
on their village. They're ready.
Sir?
Ted?
- There's an issue of when we can go.
- We go now.
You can't give the order.
You've been shot.
We go now, we risk telling the world
that you weren't there.
We weren't there, Ted.
Get the vice president to do it.
No, we are not going near
the 25th Amendment.
Tell Rick to work up a story
I was shot, but I'm okay.
That's not gonna fly.
If we have to go to some hospital
and put on a show, we do it.
- We have to talk...
- I'm done talking!
Christ!
Sir, we gotta go now.
We have to attack.
Sir?
Cavic, find out what's
going on down there.
Mr. President, please step away
from the glass.
- Cavic to Control.
- Mr. President.
Tell them to stand down.
Sir, we have to respond!
Bombing a camp in Morocco will
blow this summit out of the water.
That is what the people
behind this want me to do.
Mr. President,
we have to act strong.
No, we have to be strong.
They sent us a warning
because they want us to react.
They know our playbook.
They're banking on us doing
what we always do. We will hit back.
We have the world's sympathy
right now.
Let's honor that. Let's finish
what we came here to do.
Okay, copy that.
Everything is being prepared
to transport the president.
We need to get the president
to Air Force One now.
I'm done hiding.
This is the president, is my wife there?
- We have to be better than this.
- Sir.
- Yeah, get Air Force One ready...
- Kay, it's me.
No, we're fine here. We're safe.
Good morning, America. It's now
12 noon in Salamanca, Spain.
In a short time, world leaders
from over 150 countries...
...meet here in Plaza Mayor...
You like it?
Thank you.
All right, then. Let's eat and walk?
Security services are on high alert
here in Salamanca.
We go live to our news team on the
ground and our reporter Angie Jones.
I am standing inside Plaza Mayor
in Salamanca, Spain.
I thought you'd want it for luck.
I want to know he's okay.
This was taken 15 minutes ago.
You would find that we are
taking good care of your brother...
What have you done to him?
He's still in one piece.
You should be happy about that.
Do what you're supposed to do
and your brother will be fine.
If you fail, then this would be the last
thing you have to remember him by...
You look out for yourself.
I'll be at the underpass.
Luis, stick with the protestors.
We never see this side of the story.
Are you gonna move or what?
I've got her lecturing me now.
We're here for the conference
not the sideshow.
Is everything going to plan?
To the last detail.
And the president?
Are you sure they sent a double?
The beauty of American arrogance...
...is that they cannot imagine a world
where they're not a step ahead.
Has the package arrived?
- As we speak.
- Perfect.
Javier will be by.
Understood.
Felipe.
You will make us very proud.
Control, we have PO TUS
and are entering the castle.
Copy that.
Eagle has arrived at the plaza.
- Javier.
- Yeah.
Are you in position?
- I'm on my way.
- Good.
For the moment, the Americans think
they've dodged a bullet. Do not be late.
- Don't worry about me.
- I won't.
Your brother spoke very highly
of your Special Forces training.
Do not disappoint him.
You just make sure my brother
will be at the underpass.
How's our boy doing?
Are we go?
Good day.
Good day, sir.
Control, we have an active
crossing the lobby.
- Honey, I'm coming up to the room.
- He's clear. Area secure.
What are you seeing?
- I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
- It's fine, it's fine.
I think it's my cue.
Yeah. It's nice to meet you.
- Best of luck.
- All right. To you too.
Se? Or Presidente...
...fellow members
of the European Union...
...our friends from Africa,
Middle East...
Let's make ourselves a shooter.
...President Ashton,
citizens of the world...
...it is with great pleasure
that I invite you all to our humble city.
And it is with a sad heart...
...that we must meet in mourning...
...for those who lost loved ones
in the recent bombings.
- That should keep him occupied.
- Today, we stand together...
...and what we achieve here
will be remembered forever.
- Crowd detail, hostile check.
- All clear from above.
- Javier. Are you good to go?
- This is Control. Keep us updated.
We must come together
on this day...
...in this renowned place...
...to band together for peace.
Therefore...
...I offer you my city, my heart
and my hope.
We gotta get Eagle out now.
Eagle's down! Eagle's down!
We got a GSW!
Let's go, move it! Move it!
- Control of the building
along the back...
- Control room cleared.
- Do you have the frequency?
Four, one, nine, one, zero.
No one goes in or out
without our go.
Control. Come in, Control.
I need a 20 on PO TUS.
- Move it! Go!
- Control!
Take care of him.
Let's go.
Control?
Come in, Control.
Control, are you there?
This is Control. We have agents down.
I repeat, agents down.
We have a situation at the front
requiring immediate backup.
Copy, Control.
Coming to the lobby to assist.
ETA, 30 seconds.
Come on, guys. Move, move, move!
What's the status on level seven?
Blue team's clear on seven.
Get Air Force One ready and send
a chopper. We can get out of here.
No, we're fine. We're safe.
Get up! Get up!
Multiple casualties.
Repeat, multiple casualties.
Hey.
We need your help. Now.
Come on. He's over here.
We've done everything we can.
He's got no pulse.
Secret Service.
- I need to see your tapes.
- Yeah.
I need to see any footage
of the back of the plaza.
We need footage
Again.
Two. Again.
- Washington, this is Agent Barnes.
- Go ahead.
Control is down. My partner
is in pursuit of a suspect.
We need immediate assistance
outside the back annex.
- Give me a heading.
- They have a suspect.
Headed west on surface streets.
Do you copy?
West, copy that.
Camera six, if you can hear me,
turn around and go west.
Backup is on its...
What? Barnes, what is it?
Barnes.
Oh, my God.
- I'm coming with you.
- No.
If you're wrong, let me take the heat.
- Barnes, you were right.
- About what?
About the shooter. I'm in pursuit,
leaving the back annex, heading west.
What?
Barnes, what is it?
Barnes.
Hey!
Secret Service, get out of the car.
Get... Get out of the car.
- Washington.
- This is Barnes.
Look, I know how this is gonna sound,
but Agent Taylor has gone rogue.
Call the other agents back.
I know I made the call,
but there's something else going on.
- Barnes.
- Control is compromised.
- All agents are heading west.
- Listen to me! Damn it!
Goddamn it!
Let him go.
What are you talking about?
My brother. I've done my part.
Now you let him go.
Put the gun down.
Make the call. Or I pull the trigger,
and your plan's finished.
Again.
Go ahead.
Do it.
Do it and your brother is dead.
Can you live with that? Knowing that
your brother died because of you?
Javier, listen to me.
He's going to be delivered
at the underpass.
Don't mess it up now.
You'll get your brother back.
Nothing...
Nothing had better happen to him.
Nothing will.
Shit.
Washington.
This is Barnes. I've lost Agent Taylor.
I need a GPS location on his cellular.
Copy that.
Hold him. Hold him.
Thank you, he's gonna be all right.
Veronica.
I'm here.
We did it.
Not yet.
- Yeah.
- Barnes, PO TUS has been abducted.
Present location unknown.
No signal from Taylor's phone.
It's imperative we locate
and apprehend Taylor.
Son of a bitch.
He fell down.
Leave him.
It's me.
They bought it.
What about Barnes?
He took the bait.
He's pissing in the wind.
He's created a manhunt
for a shooter that doesn't exist.
Have you got Javier?
We may need him later.
I'm on my way.
I thought he was
supposed to be dead.
We need to tie up
all of the loose ends.
Who's a loose end?
You are.
Give me the keys!
You're late.
Let's go, let's go!
Relax.
We've pulled it off.
This is Agent Barnes.
I've located Taylor.
He's driving a Salamanca police
vehicle, registration Sierra-073654.
At present heading south,
repeat, south, on Calle de San Pablo.
That looks bad.
We've waited too long for this.
Thank God this double life
is almost over.
Just get me to my brother.
Christ. It's Barnes.
Got company.
It's Barnes.
Can you lose him?
I'm working on it.
Come on, come on, come on!
Just relax.
Oh, shit. Shit, shit!
Shit.
Shit!
Have you lost him?
I'm still working on it.
Well, until you do, stay clear
of the rendezvous. All right?
No. We're going to
the underpass now.
- You heard what he said.
- I'm picking up my brother.
Are you out of your mind?
I've worked too hard.
Either you're coming with,
or I drive myself. You choose.
Shit!
Oh, shit!
Shit! Get him off my ass.
Look out!
Happy?
Just drive.
Where's my brother?
Surprised to see me alive?
- Where's Veronica?
- Veronica said...
I don't care. You both tried to kill...
- Where's my brother?
- What brother?
Where's my brother?
Looks like we've both been set up.
Anna. Anna.
Come on, let's go!
Where is he?
Back off.
Let's go, let's go! Come on!
I won't ask you again.
Where's my brother?
Go to hell.
Freeze!
Give me my brother!
He's dead.
Goddamn you!
You used me.
I trusted you, you son of a bitch.
Who's got POTUS?
You're too late, Tom.
Why the fuck did you do this?
You can't stop us.
You'll never stop it.
This war will never end.
Kent.
Kent. Kent, what have you done?
Kent, who's got the president?
Kent!
Stop him.
Get him under control. Stop him!
Anna!
No! Don't kill him!
Look out!
Anna!
Jesus Christ.
- Anna! Anna!
- Oh, my God.
Are you all right?
Oh, my God. Mr. President?
Barnes? Is that you?
Mr. President.
I've got you.
- Can you sit up?
- Yeah.
Are you injured?
Yeah.
It's not important.
This is Agent Thomas Barnes.
POTUS is in hand.
I repeat, POTUS is in hand.
We need a pickup
seven blocks east of the plaza.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
Bye, Anna, bye.
- Hello?
- Oh, thank God.
- Howard, are you okay? Are you hurt?
- No, I'm...
- Are you sure? Are you okay?
- I'm all right.
We were watching the news.
We got your message. You're all right?
- Yeah.
- Because we were so worried.
- I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
The kids have been really concerned
about you. Nate wants to talk to you.
I'm so glad you're okay.
- All right, put him on the phone for me.
- Okay, all right, hold on.
Here's your daddy, Nate.
He's okay.
Nate. That you?
Hi, Dad.
How you doing, buddy?
I'm okay. I'm fine.
Don't you worry about anything.
- Will you be coming back?
- Yeah.
Tell your mom that I'm coming home
right now. I love you guys.
Back off, sir. Back off.
Thank you, Thomas.
You're welcome, sir.
Reports out of Salamanca
now suggest...
...that the president
is out of intensive care.
His condition is listed as stable.
President Ashton
has made a point...
...of reassuring Americans
that he's all right...
...and the summit will continue
in the days to come.
Meanwhile, word from Spanish
and United States authorities...
...is that they've shot and killed the Ione
assassin responsible for today's attack.
Our own Joan Kendrick has more.