1
00:00:27,195 --> 00:00:30,740
爪哇，印尼
Java, Indonesia

2
00:00:32,450 --> 00:00:35,912
第四个世界上大的国家
the fourth largest nation in the world...

3
00:00:37,956 --> 00:00:40,709
地球上穆斯林人口最多的地方
... the most populous Muslim
Earth.

4
00:01:21,583 --> 00:01:25,003
美国人 可口可乐 你喜欢？
Americans. Coca Cola. You like?

5
00:02:04,375 --> 00:02:07,087
约翰·杰森·威尔德
-杰克
John Jason Wilde.
- Jake.

6
00:02:07,253 --> 00:02:09,798
我的朋友叫我杰克
My friends call me Jake.

7
00:02:11,841 --> 00:02:15,428
威尔德先生 我是哈辛中尉
Mr Wilde. I'm Lieutenant Hashim.

8
00:02:16,304 --> 00:02:19,641
隶属于88区
Detachment 88

9
00:02:19,808 --> 00:02:22,060
你在美国听说我们
You have heard of us in America

10
00:02:23,686 --> 00:02:27,065
我们并不是恐怖份子
We are not all terrorists.

11
00:02:30,401 --> 00:02:32,237
说吧！
Begin !

12
00:02:32,946 --> 00:02:35,990
我在那里，大概1小时
- 真主至大|
I was there, maybe an hour
- Allahu akbar.

13
00:02:37,075 --> 00:02:42,664
等等，我们从你的目标开始说
Wait. Begin with...
how you came to my country.

14
00:02:42,914 --> 00:02:45,208
听着，我毕业留校助教
Look, I am a grad school TA

15
00:02:45,375 --> 00:02:51,005
我是康奈尔大学毕业 我在美国
因为常春藤联盟的一个交换活动来的
I'm on Anthology program from
Cornell University. Ivy League. In America.

16
00:02:51,214 --> 00:02:54,551
在这里研究
东南亚艺术历史的
here to do a pen on fucking
Southeast Asian art history

17
00:02:57,470 --> 00:03:00,473
就是说你是助手？
-是的
A teaching assistant?
- Yeah.

18
00:03:00,849 --> 00:03:04,435
你认为我们会相信吗？
Do you lecture to your students
with that language?

19
00:03:05,562 --> 00:03:07,897
你应该听我好好说
You should hear what they call me.

20
00:03:09,691 --> 00:03:11,734
继续
Lanjutkan. (Indonesian lang.)

21
00:03:13,570 --> 00:03:15,321
继续
Continue.

22
00:03:19,284 --> 00:03:25,331
我在上星期，他们
邀请我到这一个派对
I flew in last week and they
invited me to this party.

23
00:03:26,749 --> 00:03:31,171
他们说正式的，还提供了夏威夷风格的礼服
They said formal, I didn't realize it was
like "Hawaiian Shirt" meeting.

24
00:03:31,337 --> 00:03:34,716
蜡染 那是蜡染
Batik. It's called: Batik.

25
00:03:34,883 --> 00:03:37,758
好了
你没和其他人说？
All right.
- Did ​​you speak with anyone?

26
00:03:37,760 --> 00:03:40,430
我这里不认识任何人
I don't know anyone here.

27
00:03:56,404 --> 00:03:59,240
那是个漂亮的女孩
I hit on a pretty girl, so..?

28
00:03:59,449 --> 00:04:01,951
我们的黛安娜公主
Our Princess Diana.

29
00:04:02,994 --> 00:04:07,040
而你是最后一个
和爪哇王妃说话的人
You were the last,
who has spoken with the Sultana of Java,

30
00:04:07,207 --> 00:04:09,292
在她死了之前
before she died.

31
00:04:11,669 --> 00:04:16,132
现在，你最好一五一十告诉我每件细节
Now, You will tell me every detail

32
00:04:28,561 --> 00:04:31,814
哇！
那些很美丽
Wow!
Those are beautiful.

33
00:04:32,607 --> 00:04:34,984
-对不起？
-钻石
- Excuse me?
- The Diamonds.

34
00:04:35,151 --> 00:04:38,319
这可是国宝
Khmer Royal Treasury.

35
00:04:38,321 --> 00:04:41,489
我说对了吗？
-你对珠宝有研究？
Am I right?
- You know Jewelry.

36
00:04:41,491 --> 00:04:44,077
而且对美人也是
- 苏丹娜王妃？ 你的演讲
And the beauty.
- Sultana? Your speech.

37
00:04:44,911 --> 00:04:48,206
你叫什么名字
-威尔德
A pleasure to meet you Mister..?
- Wilde.

38
00:04:48,373 --> 00:04:50,667
-可以叫我杰克
-杰克先生
- Call me Jake.
- Mr Jake...

39
00:04:53,753 --> 00:04:59,968
因此，你只是做了这些？
So, you just hit on her?

40
00:05:00,802 --> 00:05:02,720
她在派对是最漂亮的女孩
She's the prettiest girl at the party

41
00:05:05,765 --> 00:05:09,060
那是你开始的地方
然后我就不知道了
That's where you start.
Then you work your way down...

42
00:05:09,227 --> 00:05:12,146
我们的苏丹娜是这...
Our Sultana is the...

43
00:05:14,524 --> 00:05:20,697
我们国家最受尊重的女人是
是无价之宝
Was the most revealed woman in my country

44
00:05:26,035 --> 00:05:30,957
你可以走了 
填一下这一个证人报告
You may go. 
Just fill out this witness report.

45
00:05:57,066 --> 00:05:59,569
这个白人
想要连络他的大使馆
This "Bule" (White Person)
wanted no contact with his embassy

46
00:05:59,819 --> 00:06:01,487
我知道
I know.

47
00:06:02,739 --> 00:06:04,449
他可真是嘴紧啊
There's no "Bule" will do such thing.

48
00:06:07,076 --> 00:06:09,162
他知道我们的国宝
A "Bule"
who knows about Majapahit (Java Kingdom)

49
00:06:09,537 --> 00:06:13,583
但不知道我们出色的蜡染布
But doesn't wear "Batik" at formal occasions

50
00:06:15,460 --> 00:06:16,294
他正在说谎
He's lying.

51
00:06:17,962 --> 00:06:19,881
我知道
I know.

52
00:06:20,214 --> 00:06:23,092
将军是等候你，爵士
The General is waiting for you, Sir.

53
00:06:23,384 --> 00:06:26,512
是的，我知道
Yes, I know

54
00:06:47,825 --> 00:06:49,450
将军阁下
General! Sir

55
00:06:49,452 --> 00:06:53,456
英语！ 你去了哪了？
English! Where have you been?

56
00:06:53,790 --> 00:06:56,667
对不起，先生
但是我们需要证人
I'm sorry, sir.
But every witness must be...

57
00:06:56,876 --> 00:06:59,754
我的人跟我报告
那没有关联
My man told me that there is no link

58
00:06:59,962 --> 00:07:04,592
在这次爆炸
和恐怖分子之间
is between this bombing and the
Malaysian fanatic Faruq Al'Assan.

59
00:07:05,343 --> 00:07:08,221
法鲁克是很有政治手腕的人
Faruq is far too politically sophisticated
for this.

60
00:07:08,388 --> 00:07:11,849
我需要给媒体一个说法
I need someone to string up for the media

61
00:07:12,100 --> 00:07:14,977
而且缺少法鲁克，
你将会做
And the absence of Faruq,
you will do.


62
00:07:15,144 --> 00:07:17,563
我已经和上级反映了你对这件事的关注
I'll be sure to mention your thoroughness
to my superiors.

63
00:07:30,284 --> 00:07:33,746
对于爪哇
需要一个强壮的新管理者
For a secure Java
A strong new governor

64
00:08:27,925 --> 00:08:32,430
杰克
-嗨！ 妮达？
Mas (Respected male in Javanese or brother) Jake!
- Hey! Nita?

65
00:08:32,722 --> 00:08:34,599
是的
Yes.

66
00:08:34,765 --> 00:08:37,643
笔记，你准备好了吗？
Notes. For your sections.

67
00:08:40,438 --> 00:08:43,983
-这些就是炸弹，你知道
-什么？
- They killed her, you know?
- What?

68
00:08:44,567 --> 00:08:47,612
她将成为第一个女元首
She has been the first female Sultan

69
00:08:57,788 --> 00:09:00,750
你们伊斯兰就是这么款待客人的
So much for "Muslim hospitality."

70
00:09:00,917 --> 00:09:03,250
我是一个基督徒 "白人".
I am a Christian. "Bule".

71
00:09:03,252 --> 00:09:05,004
放开他
Take the cuffs off him.

72
00:09:11,844 --> 00:09:13,763
"白人"小子
"Bule"?

73
00:09:14,013 --> 00:09:18,434
操！
-照字面是 愚蠢的白色人
Shit!
- Literally means: stupid white person.

74
00:09:20,311 --> 00:09:24,315
但是它有时候是
亲切的 -是的，
But it can be a term of
Endearment. - Yeah, right!

75
00:09:30,363 --> 00:09:32,490
这里是现场，是的
The bomber stood here, yes?

76
00:09:35,409 --> 00:09:38,079
- 嗯
-想想威尔德先生
- Uhm..
- Think Mr. Wilde

77
00:09:48,631 --> 00:09:50,841
是的，她在那里站立了
Yeah, he stood there.

78
00:10:00,476 --> 00:10:04,313
王妃呢？ 她在这里？
And the Sultana? She was here?

79
00:10:04,939 --> 00:10:07,400
是的 但是...
-你无法见到
Yes. But...
- You could not see.

80
00:10:07,567 --> 00:10:09,860
-因为这一个帘子
-是的
- Because this screen.
- Yeah.

81
00:10:10,653 --> 00:10:13,573
而且你 你在这里吗？
And you. Were you here?

82
00:10:14,949 --> 00:10:18,119
不，我在这里
No. I was here.

83
00:10:21,497 --> 00:10:25,001
你就能看到爆炸者，他长得什么样
You had a clear view of the bomber.
How did you see?

84
00:10:25,585 --> 00:10:28,629
他举起他的手而且呼喊
He ​​held his hands up and shouted.

85
00:10:29,088 --> 00:10:31,797
威尔德先生，
上帝给你两个眼睛和一张嘴，
Mr Wilde,
Allah gave you two eyes and one mouth,

86
00:10:31,799 --> 00:10:33,843
以便你可以看到的比说的多
so that you may see twice as much as you speak.

87
00:10:34,010 --> 00:10:38,053
因此你，你见到什么？
-我告诉你
So please, what did you see?
- I've told you.

88
00:10:38,055 --> 00:10:40,891
我听到他尖叫，然后整个...
-不！
I heard him scream, and he blew the whole...
- No!

89
00:10:41,100 --> 00:10:43,269
你见到什么？
What did you see?

90
00:10:57,783 --> 00:11:00,036
他的手是空的
His hands were empty.

91
00:11:01,871 --> 00:11:04,790
有别人人引爆了炸弹
Someone else detonated the bomb.

92
00:11:05,541 --> 00:11:10,461
我肯定错过些什么？
-这些肯定不是会在课堂上教你的
How did I miss that? - No doubt, 
not part of your training in Southeast Asian studies.

93
00:11:10,463 --> 00:11:13,382
-艺术历史
-是的
- Art history.
- Yes.

94
00:11:17,053 --> 00:11:20,222
谁在这里？
Whose this?

95
00:11:21,849 --> 00:11:23,893
苏丹娜王妃
The Sultana.

96
00:11:24,810 --> 00:11:27,355
这是你发现苏丹娜的地方？
This is where you found the Sultana?

97
00:11:29,148 --> 00:11:31,067
是的
In deed.

98
00:11:32,401 --> 00:11:36,489
你的身体应该被爆炸摧毁
Although that her body was blown toward the explosion

99
00:11:37,531 --> 00:11:38,949
继续吧
One more stop.

100
00:12:12,525 --> 00:12:14,985
她是派对的最漂亮的女孩
She was the prettiest girl at the party.

101
00:12:19,198 --> 00:12:23,077
可以给我们一点时间吗？
Do you want to become a permanent guess here?

102
00:12:26,706 --> 00:12:32,169
也许，比你在外面等候维齐先生的感觉要好些
Perhaps, it is less painful for you to wait outside (Pak)Mr. Vizier

103
00:12:38,759 --> 00:12:40,720
你知道
Did you know

104
00:12:40,886 --> 00:12:45,224
它是伊斯兰教中，
伤毁自己身体是不可饶恕的罪吗？
it is a great sin in Islam,
to deface his own flesh?

105
00:12:47,977 --> 00:12:50,936
而且关于女人可兰经说到什么刺穿她的阴蒂？
And what does the Koran say about woman pierce her clit?

106
00:12:50,938 --> 00:12:53,023
你什么意思？
Excuse me?

107
00:13:00,322 --> 00:13:02,575
她鼻子有问题
She also had a nose job

108
00:13:02,783 --> 00:13:05,035
植入器
implants.

109
00:13:05,202 --> 00:13:07,830
这不是 苏丹娜
This is not the Sultana.

110
00:13:09,874 --> 00:13:13,377
你如何能知道这？
-相信我，我认识这个女人
How can you know this?
- Trust me, I know women.

111
00:13:13,544 --> 00:13:16,130
是的，你了解美女
Yes, you know beauty.

112
00:13:16,338 --> 00:13:18,632
我亲眼见过她
I met the lady.

113
00:13:19,550 --> 00:13:21,886
我们该离开了
It's time for us to leave.

114
00:13:52,458 --> 00:13:53,584
和平和你在一起

Peace be with you.
(assalamualaikum)

115
00:13:53,751 --> 00:13:55,085
而且与你

And with you.
(waalaikumussalam)

116
00:13:56,837 --> 00:13:59,256
-警察...
-是的，是，好
- The Police...
- Yes, yes, all right.

117
00:13:59,465 --> 00:14:03,594
拿着，男孩 走吧！ 好
Here, boy. Get out! Okay.

118
00:14:10,351 --> 00:14:12,394
侦探回又出现了
The detective returned to the site.

119
00:14:12,603 --> 00:14:14,563
" 布列"白人
The "bule".

120
00:14:14,730 --> 00:14:17,983
我认为...
I think he's English...

121
00:14:23,072 --> 00:14:24,073
美国人
American.

122
00:14:26,784 --> 00:14:28,577
你认识他吗？
Do you know him?

123
00:14:32,832 --> 00:14:35,209
他头发变长了
He's grown out his hear.

124
00:14:36,502 --> 00:14:39,755
他的眼睛的蓝色
-这不是一场游戏
The blue of his eyes.
- This is not a game.

125
00:14:40,631 --> 00:14:42,967
当然它是
Of course it is.

126
00:14:43,717 --> 00:14:45,384
现在，我的朋友
now, my friend.

127
00:14:45,386 --> 00:14:48,264
伊斯兰教的另一个敌人
在你的手里
Another enemy of Islam
into your hands

128
00:14:51,851 --> 00:14:54,520
哦看你，
我能说出你的名字
Oh look at you,
I can take your name out.

129
00:15:03,237 --> 00:15:05,114
死的女孩是谁？
Who is the dead girl?

130
00:15:07,032 --> 00:15:08,617
你吃的是什么？
How do you eat that shit?

131
00:15:08,784 --> 00:15:11,787
曾经听说 素食脂肪？
面筋？
Ever heard of trans fats?
Gluten?

132
00:15:13,289 --> 00:15:16,166
这是炒饭
健康美好食物
This is nasi goreng.
Fried rice. Good for you.

133
00:15:17,251 --> 00:15:20,880
而且我们正要去哪里？
-没有 "我们"
And where are we going?
- There is no "we".

134
00:15:21,589 --> 00:15:24,508
我们是一伙的
Come on Hash?
We can taser them.

135
00:15:25,801 --> 00:15:28,429
美国人
你像孩子
Americans.
You are like children.

136
00:15:29,096 --> 00:15:32,099
你总是认为你是 "兰博"
-你知道 "兰博"?
You always think you're the "Rambo".
- you know "Rambo"?

137
00:15:33,434 --> 00:15:37,146
我一直认为内心
会是最好的防卫”
"I always thought that
the mind would be the best defense."

138
00:15:38,147 --> 00:15:40,774
" 武器 "!
-什么？
"Weapon"!
- What?

139
00:15:42,860 --> 00:15:45,154
"我总认为内心是最强的武器”
"I always thought that
the mind would be the best weapon."

140
00:15:46,864 --> 00:15:49,408
看到了吧？
那是我们为什么是一队的
See?
That's why we make a good team.

141
00:15:49,783 --> 00:15:54,371
你知道你能信赖我
-是的，那是你为什么在背面坐下...
You know you can trust me.
- Yes, that's why you're sitting in the back...

142
00:16:22,483 --> 00:16:24,234
哈希？ 哈希？
Hashi? Hashi?

143
00:16:38,582 --> 00:16:40,167
非常好

God is great.
(Allahu Akbar)

144
00:18:06,170 --> 00:18:07,421
哈希姆！
Hashim!

145
00:18:26,899 --> 00:18:28,067
安东
Anton.

146
00:18:29,902 --> 00:18:32,571
你救了是我的丈夫
那没什么，夫人
You saved my husband's life.
That's nothing, ma'am

147
00:18:32,821 --> 00:18:35,407
我是杰克
I'm Jake.

148
00:18:38,786 --> 00:18:40,329
哈希姆
Mas Hashim.

149
00:18:43,957 --> 00:18:46,001
他将会和我们一起吃早餐
Mas Jake will come to our house for breakfast.

150
00:18:46,668 --> 00:18:51,423
谢谢夫人，但是我 我真的要回美国
-是的，你的学生将会想念你们
Thanks Ma'am, but I.. I really should be getting back.
- yes, your students will miss you.

151
00:18:52,549 --> 00:18:56,553
我们得感谢
-她说的对
It's the least we can do.
- She is right.

152
00:19:00,099 --> 00:19:03,602
-你要拿糖吗？
-不，谢谢
- Do you take sugar?
- No, thanks.

153
00:19:06,063 --> 00:19:08,023
它非常好，夫人
It's very good, ma'am.

154
00:19:08,649 --> 00:19:11,235
炒饭很营养
nasi goreng. Gluten free.

155
00:19:14,613 --> 00:19:17,282
告诉我们有关你的研究的事，杰克
Tell us about your studies, Mas Jake.

156
00:19:18,700 --> 00:19:21,328
马斯在爪哇语里是兄弟的意思，杰克
"Mas" in Javanese means "brother."

157
00:19:21,662 --> 00:19:23,705
你哪里学习如此好英语？
Where did you learn such good English?

158
00:19:24,039 --> 00:19:25,666
小孩，准备好
Kids, Get ready.

159
00:19:26,041 --> 00:19:29,878
维特里亚在美国受过高等教育
Vitria went to university. in Gradschool.

160
00:19:31,964 --> 00:19:34,591
-你是一个幸运男人
-是的
- You're a lucky man.
- In deed.

161
00:19:37,553 --> 00:19:41,807
布迪，艾德，你准备好了吗？
Budi, Ade, Are you ready?

162
00:19:48,856 --> 00:19:51,775
-再见
-是的
- See you later.
- Yes.

163
00:19:52,776 --> 00:19:55,527
在家庭里面，我们不握手
Within family we don't shake hands

164
00:19:55,529 --> 00:19:57,990
它表示较深的爱
It shows deeper affections.

165
00:20:00,951 --> 00:20:02,995
奇怪风俗
Strange country.

166
00:20:03,203 --> 00:20:07,040
而且男人能当众吻你的妻子？
但是我不会
And man can kiss your wife in public?, but I can not.

167
00:20:07,624 --> 00:20:12,129
奇怪国家 -有趣，你没有学习过这些
Strange country. - Strange that you did not learn this in Southeast Asian studies.

168
00:20:13,881 --> 00:20:15,632
艺术历史
Art history.

169
00:20:20,345 --> 00:20:22,181
我想要谢谢你
I want to thank you.

170
00:20:22,389 --> 00:20:25,058
它什么也不是
It was nothing.

171
00:20:25,225 --> 00:20:27,519
我是某事
I was something.

172
00:20:28,687 --> 00:20:30,772
这场枪战
This shooting...

173
00:20:30,939 --> 00:20:33,650
这你在艺术历史中学习过射击？
This you learned in art history?

174
00:20:35,944 --> 00:20:37,779
正直的幸运，我猜测
Just Lucky, I guess.

175
00:20:45,913 --> 00:20:49,041
现在，我们有英特网，你知道？威费
Even here we have Internet, you know?. WiFi.

176
00:20:51,001 --> 00:20:54,296
维特里亚认为
你可能喜欢这个
Vitria has found something
that you might like to see.

177
00:20:57,966 --> 00:21:00,302
给你
大家好，我是约翰·杰·威尔德 而且今天...
Here.
- Hi Everyone, I'm John J. Wild. And today...

178
00:21:00,552 --> 00:21:02,804
我们会讨论
远古的爪哇艺术...
We would be discussing
Ancient Javanese Art...

179
00:21:03,013 --> 00:21:05,307
我要把以下东西和大家分享
I would like the following questions today
on to you,

180
00:21:10,687 --> 00:21:14,149
从你的国家我们学到
了关于恐怖分子的东西
Your country lectures us about cooperation in the world from terror

181
00:21:16,318 --> 00:21:18,278
但从9.11 以来
Since 9/11th

182
00:21:18,487 --> 00:21:21,156
我们已经拘捕了多于你们两倍的恐怖分子
We have caught twice as many terrorists as you

183
00:21:21,907 --> 00:21:24,493
你不是约翰 杰森 维尔德
Mister "not-so-Wild".

184
00:21:26,453 --> 00:21:29,456
国际刑警在巴格达是爆炸案
Interpol shows your fingerprints at bomb sites in Baghdad

185
00:21:29,623 --> 00:21:31,833
喀布尔和贝鲁特的现场发现了你的指纹
Kabul and Beirut.

186
00:21:34,461 --> 00:21:37,005
我跟了这个人2年
I've been tracking this terrorist in the last 2 years

187
00:21:37,172 --> 00:21:40,217
快结束了，哈希  真正的结束
I'm close, Hashi. Real close.

188
00:21:41,134 --> 00:21:44,638
而且没你们联邦调查局告知我们
And no one at your FBI inform their agent is here?

189
00:21:45,472 --> 00:21:47,432
他们不相信你
They don't trust you people.

190
00:21:47,599 --> 00:21:50,727
因为我们是穆斯林？
-因为当我们和你说话时，
Because we are Muslims?
- Because when we talk to you,

191
00:21:50,936 --> 00:21:53,146
我们是不确信我们和谁说话
We're not sure who we are talking to

192
00:21:53,313 --> 00:21:55,107
是吗？
In deed.

193
00:21:55,274 --> 00:21:58,318
因为无法跨国行动
Because we're not allowed to operate outside US soil.

194
00:21:59,361 --> 00:22:03,115
这就是为什么你没接到消息
-我花了两年的时间
That's why you can't tell the embassy.
It will ruin 2 years of work.

195
00:22:04,616 --> 00:22:07,703
-我要相信你吗
-听着 哈希
- Nor can I take your story.
- Look, Hashi.

196
00:22:07,869 --> 00:22:10,580
这是我的案子
This is my case.

197
00:22:12,708 --> 00:22:15,294
这里是我的国家
And this is my country.

198
00:22:16,295 --> 00:22:19,298
而且我现在应该做就是遣返你
And what I should do now is elevate you.

199
00:22:19,881 --> 00:22:22,801
作为一个友情的帮助
From bad witness to good suspect.

200
00:22:36,398 --> 00:22:37,649
你疯了吗？
Are you crazy?

201
00:22:39,943 --> 00:22:42,154
将军是一个民族主义者
The general is a nationalist

202
00:22:42,738 --> 00:22:47,200
当他知道我们和
一个美国人，一位间谍在一起...
When he knows we're dealing
with an American, a spy...

203
00:22:48,118 --> 00:22:50,329
我的神啊
听天由命
Jesus God and Holy Mother Mary
will protect us.

204
00:22:50,704 --> 00:22:52,497

但凭天意
God's will is great.
(Insyaallah)

205
00:23:19,358 --> 00:23:21,902
嗨， 特拉维斯
Hey, Travis.

206
00:23:22,652 --> 00:23:25,614
我在听
-你们很久没动静了
Did it come through?
- Hold your horses, man.

207
00:23:29,034 --> 00:23:31,203
你在那干嘛，老虎拳
What you got here, Jake? Tiger?

208
00:23:31,870 --> 00:23:34,581
这是从一个受害人身上发现的纹身
A tattoo.
From a victim.

209
00:23:35,832 --> 00:23:38,375
我没有搜查
但是我不能够答应任何事
I'm running it through the system.
But I cannot promise anything.

210
00:23:38,377 --> 00:23:41,086
是的，是，是的 我们有好消息
Yeah, yeah, yeah. We're even.

211
00:23:41,088 --> 00:23:45,050
没有必要，我现在想知道你在哪
No, we are not. they are all
over me to find you, your ex, your folks

212
00:23:45,967 --> 00:23:50,764
你要问候我吗
Would you,
check on them from me?

213
00:23:50,972 --> 00:23:52,891
是的，我让她来了
Yeah, I added it to the list.

214
00:23:53,100 --> 00:23:57,644
另外一件事 不要那里告诉当代警方
One more thing. Don't tell the cops over there
a fucking thing

215
00:23:57,646 --> 00:24:00,607
你在那里的代号就叫西姆博·费
They're all dirty in their country.
"Semper Fi", brother.

216
00:24:01,650 --> 00:24:02,901
西姆博·费
Semper Fi.

217
00:24:13,370 --> 00:24:15,664
我们不能信赖他的 兄弟
We can not trust him, Brother

218
00:24:15,997 --> 00:24:18,917
他知道我们不知道的情况
He has information that we do not have.

219
00:24:20,752 --> 00:24:23,463
他没有解救你，
He did not save you,
because he liked you like.

220
00:24:23,713 --> 00:24:25,924
他需要你
He needs you

221
00:24:26,133 --> 00:24:28,009
而且那很好
And that's good.

222
00:24:28,218 --> 00:24:30,011
信赖我
Trust me.

223
00:24:31,263 --> 00:24:35,350
将军想要见你
The General wants to see you.

224
00:24:53,785 --> 00:24:55,787
我的老练的美国佬
My American. He lives.

225
00:25:01,877 --> 00:25:05,380
他休学了
我感激它 极好的
He stay tuned.
I appreciate it. Superbe.

226
00:25:06,006 --> 00:25:10,302
我的两个手下死了
言论是对阿拉
Two of my men were killed - remarks is to Allah.

227
00:25:11,428 --> 00:25:14,598
是的 我们将会记得他们的牺牲
Yes. we will remember their sacrifice.

228
00:25:14,764 --> 00:25:17,434
但是谁将会记得你？
But who will remember you?

229
00:25:18,727 --> 00:25:20,604
那个男孩
The boy will.

230
00:25:21,813 --> 00:25:23,607
你搞砸了一切
You devour what you touch.

231
00:25:23,857 --> 00:25:27,194
我把他们扶上位，就像你一样
Like you, I pick someone out of the dirt

232
00:25:27,527 --> 00:25:31,406
我让他们的价值得到发挥
I cleanse them and bring them in to the light.

233
00:25:32,365 --> 00:25:38,246
这么多年来受害者不在少数
The Cendrawasih (Bird of Paradise). for
2,000 years they were killed for their feathers.

234
00:25:39,789 --> 00:25:43,208
我在新几内亚发现她
他在排水沟中管道
I found her in New Guinea.
He ​​was sitting in a drain pipe

235
00:25:43,210 --> 00:25:45,545
我们得继续下去
It's the worse place on earth

236
00:25:49,799 --> 00:25:53,678
我们不会这样做了
Me and My men will not take part of this anymore.

237
00:25:59,726 --> 00:26:02,310
不要扮演无辜者，艾哈迈德
Do not play the innocent, Achmed.

238
00:26:02,312 --> 00:26:06,233
你说我们是在
圣战，不是做这些勾当
You said we would be fighting
a holy war, not this

239
00:26:06,441 --> 00:26:08,775
当你和一只蛇上床睡觉，
When you go to bed with a snake,

240
00:26:08,777 --> 00:26:11,029
如果你被咬，不要感到惊讶
Do not be surprised if you get bitten

241
00:26:11,988 --> 00:26:16,535
你得到了你想要的
现在是回报了
You got what you wanted.
Now you help me to get what I came for.

242
00:26:22,707 --> 00:26:24,793
-先生？
-你的搭档在哪里？
- Sir?
- Where is your partner?

243
00:26:25,126 --> 00:26:27,887
警官安东马上到
-不，你的美国合伙人
Sergeant Anton following a lead.
- No, your American partner.

244
00:26:28,046 --> 00:26:31,091
他是一个有价值的证人
我想他... -不再必需
He is a valuable witness.
I think he... - No longer necessary.

245
00:26:32,217 --> 00:26:35,343
我们找到了他？ 谁？
We got our man - What? Who?

246
00:26:35,345 --> 00:26:37,806
法鲁克·阿尔·阿桑 我们发现他
Faruq  Al'Assan. We found him.

247
00:26:58,660 --> 00:27:02,414
法鲁克·阿尔·阿桑，你被包围
Faruq Al'Assan, you're surrounded

248
00:27:02,747 --> 00:27:05,500
我们是警察
Here speaks the chief of police

249
00:27:05,667 --> 00:27:07,544
放弃吧！
这是你的最后机会！
Surrender!
This is your last chance!

250
00:27:31,067 --> 00:27:34,362
CNN 、BBC，优图
CNN, BBC, Youtube.

251
00:27:35,322 --> 00:27:37,073
还有推特
Even Twitter.

252
00:27:47,083 --> 00:27:48,543
你要杀他？
You're going to kill him?

253
00:28:05,101 --> 00:28:06,019
中尉 哈希姆
Lieutenant Hashim.

254
00:28:06,853 --> 00:28:08,813
到这里回来！
Come back here!

255
00:29:41,322 --> 00:29:43,450
回去！ 回来！
Go back! Get back!

256
00:29:46,536 --> 00:29:50,373
法鲁克·阿尔·阿桑！ 你被逮捕！
Faruq Al'Assan! You are under arrest!

257
00:29:59,716 --> 00:30:00,717
射击他！
Shoot him!

258
00:30:03,678 --> 00:30:05,305
苏丹娜，法鲁克在哪里？
Where is the Sultana, Faruq?

259
00:30:05,972 --> 00:30:07,807
苏丹娜？
The Sultana?

260
00:30:10,685 --> 00:30:12,395
举起手，否则我将开枪！
Hands up or I'll shoot!

261
00:30:25,825 --> 00:30:26,993
等等！
Wait!

262
00:30:27,160 --> 00:30:28,870
等等，你不一定要做这！
wait, you don't have to do this!

263
00:30:33,917 --> 00:30:36,419
真主至大！
Allahu Akhbar!

264
00:32:01,296 --> 00:32:03,713
是的
-我得到了某些有趣的东西，兄弟
Yeah.
- I got something, brother.

265
00:32:03,715 --> 00:32:06,968
那老虎不是一个纹身
它是商标
The tiger is not a tattoo.
It's a brand.

266
00:32:07,218 --> 00:32:08,718
是一个帮会的
Used by The "Tong".

267
00:32:08,720 --> 00:32:10,305
华人？
The Chinese?

268
00:32:10,471 --> 00:32:14,058
这种东西是纹在那些女孩身上
So this particular Tiger brand
is for their working girls.

269
00:32:14,726 --> 00:32:19,314
妓女？ -是的 这是
他们最好的商标，像定价格的牛
Hookers? - Yes. The "Tong" is like the
brand of their best performer, like price cattle.

270
00:32:19,522 --> 00:32:22,565
他们送她们到泰国
就可以得到一切
They send them to Thailand.
for body sculpting.

271
00:32:22,567 --> 00:32:25,653
屁股、奶头或脸
这样她们会成为头牌
Ass, tits or face.
Turn them in to like hooker royalty.

272
00:32:28,031 --> 00:32:30,617
谢谢你，金博
兄弟
Thank you, Jimbo.
- Semper Fi, brother.

273
00:33:42,146 --> 00:33:44,897
嗨，先生 买光盘吗？
Hi, Mister. DVDs? Blueray?

274
00:33:44,899 --> 00:33:49,112
不，先生不想要它
No, Mister doesn't want it.

275
00:33:51,030 --> 00:33:52,657
黎明，黎明
Twilight? Twilight

276
00:33:52,907 --> 00:33:54,867
黎明， 不，他不想要黎明
Twilight? No, he doesn't want twilight.

277
00:33:56,869 --> 00:33:58,955
哈罗，先生！ 让我介绍我自己的
Hello, Mister! Let me introduce my self.

278
00:33:59,247 --> 00:34:02,041
我是安迪 -安迪
-我知道每件事物 我认识每个人
I'm Andy. - Andy.
- I know everything. I know everyone.

279
00:34:02,208 --> 00:34:04,252
我带你去 快点
I'll show you. Come on.

280
00:34:04,877 --> 00:34:07,797
-你想要女孩？
-不是
- You want girls?
- Not right now.

281
00:34:08,006 --> 00:34:10,008
男孩，你想要男孩？
Boys, You want boys?

282
00:34:10,216 --> 00:34:12,301
不，不，不！
No, no, no!

283
00:34:12,510 --> 00:34:14,429
你不是基佬
No boy for you.

284
00:34:14,595 --> 00:34:18,222
我正在找寻特别的东西
I'm looking for something special.

285
00:34:18,224 --> 00:34:19,932
哦，特别的
Oh, special.

286
00:34:19,934 --> 00:34:23,229
瓦里亚
你想要瓦里亚  瓦里亚，当然
Waria (Transgeners)
You want Waria. Waria, of course.

287
00:34:23,438 --> 00:34:25,521
-这是老虎的意思
-不！
- Does that mean Tiger?
- No!

288
00:34:25,523 --> 00:34:27,525
瓦里亚 非常特别
Waria is very special.

289
00:34:29,110 --> 00:34:32,280
人妖 非常漂亮的！
A Ladyboy. Very Pretty!

290
00:34:32,447 --> 00:34:34,866
哦！ 我爱你，这么多
-我知道你喜欢他们，对不对？
Oh..! I love you, so much.
- I knoy you love them, right?

291
00:34:35,033 --> 00:34:37,827
这不是我的口味
Something of no.
Definitely not my type.

292
00:34:38,036 --> 00:34:39,370
那不是他们的错
我们将会回来
Then not, lovelies.
we'll be back.

293
00:34:39,537 --> 00:34:41,873
先生，你喜欢什么？ 我将找到
Sir, What do you like? I'll find it.

294
00:34:42,081 --> 00:34:44,290
听着
Look, aah..

295
00:34:44,292 --> 00:34:45,918
我们去那里
Check this out.!
there we go..

296
00:34:47,003 --> 00:34:49,297
像那，我在找这个
I'm looking something like that.

297
00:34:51,340 --> 00:34:53,468
老虎淑女！
-是的，老虎淑女
Tiger Ladies!
- Yes, Tiger Ladies.

298
00:34:53,676 --> 00:34:55,094
老虎淑女
Tiger Ladies.

299
00:35:28,294 --> 00:35:32,757
安迪！ 啊，你来啦 喝吧
Andi! Ah, there you are. Here, for you.

300
00:35:34,008 --> 00:35:35,718
不好意思先生
我是穆斯林 我不能够喝
I'm sorry sir.
I am Muslim. I cannot drink.

301
00:35:40,681 --> 00:35:42,558
这老虎是淑女的地方？
And where these tigers are ladies?

302
00:35:43,935 --> 00:35:46,270
二楼 安迪 说我的名字
second floor. Andi can not go.

303
00:35:47,063 --> 00:35:50,815
专门为外国人提供的，走吧
Foreigners only.
- There you go.

304
00:35:50,817 --> 00:35:52,193
谢谢你先生
Thank you sir.

305
00:36:12,672 --> 00:36:14,841
离我远点，婊子
Leave me alone! Whore!

306
00:36:58,801 --> 00:37:01,429
-老大
-它没有安静吗？
- The Djihadist.
- Did not it still?

307
00:37:01,721 --> 00:37:03,764
我想要另半我的钱
I want the other half of my money

308
00:37:03,931 --> 00:37:06,559
他是个混蛋
Masturbation fucking '

309
00:37:06,809 --> 00:37:09,312
我打赌
那家伙根本就没有钱
I bet
is on his way to Pakistan.

310
00:37:14,275 --> 00:37:15,401
他来了
He's here.

311
00:37:21,991 --> 00:37:23,993
余领先生很忙
Mr. Yoshiro is busy.

312
00:37:24,160 --> 00:37:26,412
我也是
So am I.

313
00:37:27,371 --> 00:37:32,877
- 余领很忙碌
-哦 如此...
- Yoshiro is busy.
- Oh.. So...

314
00:37:40,551 --> 00:37:44,096
放松 我在这里见她
Relax. I'm here to see her.

315
00:37:44,263 --> 00:37:46,432
你让我有了感觉
You just blew a big deal for me

316
00:37:52,313 --> 00:37:56,192
给你钱... -快点！
-我的钱... -快点！
My money... - Come on!
- My Money... - Come on!

317
00:38:02,782 --> 00:38:05,701
这些女人
What a dog! always about women!

318
00:38:20,132 --> 00:38:20,716
在那里！
There!

319
00:38:23,719 --> 00:38:26,222
来，来！ 来这里！
Come, come! Come here!

320
00:39:12,226 --> 00:39:15,521
一个胆怯男孩！
A shy boy!

321
00:39:33,331 --> 00:39:36,459
这时什么做的
What is this made out of?

322
00:39:36,917 --> 00:39:40,129
它有最软的材料
我感觉从未有的温柔
It's like the softest material
I  have ever felt.

323
00:39:41,088 --> 00:39:44,133
那是丝吗？ 或合成物质？
Is that silk? Or Synthetic?

324
00:39:44,342 --> 00:39:46,635
合成物质，合成物质
Synthetic, synthetic.

325
00:39:47,219 --> 00:39:48,721
很好笑，不是吗？
Sounds funny, doesn't it?

326
00:39:48,971 --> 00:39:52,224
觉得棒！ 这...
Feels great! The...

327
00:39:54,310 --> 00:39:56,187
你需要先沭浴，先生
You got to bathe first, Mister.

328
00:39:58,147 --> 00:39:59,690
你见到这？
You see this?

329
00:40:01,275 --> 00:40:04,362
它意谓你必须支付大的代价，是！！
It means you have to pay big, yeah..!!

330
00:40:11,285 --> 00:40:13,120
从哪弄的
Where'd you get that, baby?

331
00:40:14,205 --> 00:40:19,627
它是一个礼物-你认识
大腿上纹身的女孩？
It's a gift - Do you have a
who has something on her thigh?

332
00:40:23,172 --> 00:40:26,467
你认， 她是谁？
You do. who's she?

333
00:40:28,094 --> 00:40:30,304
为什么？
Why?

334
00:40:33,933 --> 00:40:40,940
你想要干她还是干我？
Do you want to fuck her? Or me?

335
00:41:01,168 --> 00:41:03,295
-来这里！ -冷静！
Look. - Come here! - Calm down.!

336
00:41:03,754 --> 00:41:08,551
我需要你告诉我在大腿上有老虎纹身的女孩
I need you to tell me about a girl with a tiger brand on her thigh.

337
00:41:08,717 --> 00:41:11,345
什么，妈的！
-快说
What the fuck!
- How do you know her?

338
00:41:12,138 --> 00:41:14,014
她是我的妹妹
She is my sister.

339
00:41:15,266 --> 00:41:16,892
你说什么？ 你的妹妹？
What do you say? Your sister?

340
00:41:18,436 --> 00:41:19,895
放开我
Just let me go!

341
00:41:20,062 --> 00:41:23,691
我会杀了你
-你他妈的告诉我你妹妹在哪？
I will kill you, come here!.
- Where the fuck is your sister now?

342
00:41:23,899 --> 00:41:26,735
他们送她到泰国，好？
They send her to Thailand, OK?

343
00:41:29,071 --> 00:41:30,698
泰国？
Thailand?

344
00:41:30,865 --> 00:41:34,616
她得到了很好的条件
一个上等的人
she got really good gig.
A classy guy.

345
00:41:34,618 --> 00:41:37,079
富人
Rich

346
00:41:37,246 --> 00:41:39,123
是阿拉伯人吗？
Is the guy Arab?

347
00:41:40,374 --> 00:41:44,460
欧洲人？ 中国人？-不！
-法国人？ 美国人？ 俄国人？ -不！
Europeans? Chinese? - No.
- French? Americans? Russian? - No!

348
00:41:44,462 --> 00:41:48,007
和你一样的白人
Just Bule. they're all the same like you

349
00:42:53,155 --> 00:42:55,948
不要他妈的骗我，艾哈迈德
Don't fuck with Ling, Achmed!

350
00:42:55,950 --> 00:42:57,618
没有！
Not me!

351
00:42:58,160 --> 00:43:00,079
林的钱在哪里？你他妈的
Where is Ling's money, you raghead motherfucker?

352
00:43:02,373 --> 00:43:03,874
我的女孩在他妈的哪里？
Where's my motherfucking girl?

353
00:43:04,291 --> 00:43:06,460
除了安拉之外没有上帝

There is no God but Allah.
(la ilaha illallah)

354
00:43:06,794 --> 00:43:09,588
谁杀了林 谁引爆了炸弹
The killed them, Ling
With a blast.

355
00:43:19,390 --> 00:43:21,308
他们杀她的女孩
They killed her sister.

356
00:43:23,269 --> 00:43:25,771
你杀我的老虎淑女，艾哈迈德？
You killed my tiger ladies, Achmed?

357
00:43:28,065 --> 00:43:30,192
你认为我他妈的不敢动你
You don't think Ling will come for you?

358
00:43:31,610 --> 00:43:33,862
警察！  88区!
Police! Detachment 88!

359
00:43:34,446 --> 00:43:37,783
警察？ 我就是警察
Police? I own the police.

360
00:44:15,571 --> 00:44:19,033
你把那个女孩卖到哪了？
-去你们的！
Who did you sell the girl to?
- Fuck you!

361
00:44:20,409 --> 00:44:21,785
女孩卖到哪了？
Who did you sell the girl to?

362
00:44:23,120 --> 00:44:25,205
不，不，是另一个
No, no, no. There's another guy.

363
00:44:25,456 --> 00:44:27,791
而且一个白人
警察，你们是怎么搞的？
And a white guy.
- What you gonna do, cop?

364
00:44:27,958 --> 00:44:30,334
读你的权利？
Read your rights?

365
00:44:30,336 --> 00:44:32,838
给我他的名字
你这龟儿子
Give me his name.
I'll kill this son of a bitch.

366
00:44:35,007 --> 00:44:39,386
马利克 他的名字是马利克
Malik. His name is Malik.

367
00:44:40,804 --> 00:44:42,806
哪里，林？
Where, Ling?

368
00:44:43,515 --> 00:44:47,436
我能哪里找他，
-不要着急
Where can I find him, Ling?
- Don't worry, cop...

369
00:44:47,603 --> 00:44:50,648
他会找你
He finds you.

370
00:44:55,110 --> 00:44:56,737
放下枪！ 警察！
Guns away! Police!

371
00:49:41,396 --> 00:49:48,403
在一个充满肮脏罪恶的地方寻找美丽
To find beauty in a place like this where
so much dirt and grime is.

372
00:49:50,989 --> 00:49:53,283
你什么也看不到
You don't see anything

373
00:49:57,120 --> 00:50:00,123
沭浴是更亲密的超过作爱
To bathe is more intimate than making love.

374
00:50:01,291 --> 00:50:03,710
你别乱摸
You don't touch anything

375
00:50:15,847 --> 00:50:17,349
非常专业的
Very professional.

376
00:50:17,557 --> 00:50:19,559
狗屁不是
You're no body.

377
00:50:39,621 --> 00:50:42,040
维特里亚？
Vitria?

378
00:50:42,249 --> 00:50:46,128
艾德？ 布迪？
Ade? Budi?

379
00:50:46,420 --> 00:50:48,088
维特里亚？
Vitria?

380
00:50:48,422 --> 00:50:49,965
布迪？
Budi?

381
00:51:06,523 --> 00:51:07,733
哈罗？
Hello?

382
00:51:11,194 --> 00:51:14,698
中尉 哈希姆 你好
Lieutenant Hashim. Assalamu alaikum.

383
00:51:14,948 --> 00:51:19,119
这是谁？ -他们告诉我，
你是一个非常可靠的男人
Who is this? - they tell me,
you are a very reliable man.

384
00:51:20,245 --> 00:51:23,288
88分队中的最好的
The best In the Detachment 88.

385
00:51:23,290 --> 00:51:26,293
我的家人在哪里？
-中尉，我能仰赖你吗？
Where is my family?
- Can I rely on you, Lieutenant?

386
00:51:26,460 --> 00:51:28,795
是的
-好
Yes
- Bien.. (Good)

387
00:51:30,172 --> 00:51:31,673
我有重要的生意
I have Important business.

388
00:51:31,840 --> 00:51:33,925
当我完成，我将会释放
你的家人
When I finish, I will release
your family

389
00:51:34,301 --> 00:51:37,220
在此际，你要花的时间见见我的一位朋友
In the meantime you take some time off to grieve for your friend.

390
00:51:38,346 --> 00:51:40,015
中尉，你明白吗？
Do you understand, Lieutenant?

391
00:51:40,807 --> 00:51:41,975
是的，我了明白
Yes, I understand.

392
00:51:43,351 --> 00:51:50,275
这么说你同意了？
是的
Then we are in agreement.
- Yes. Complete agreement.

393
00:52:18,804 --> 00:52:23,600
哈希！ -听着
-他们抓走了我的家人
Hashi! - Listen - You gotta...
- They took my family.

394
00:52:23,850 --> 00:52:27,270
如果你是联邦调查局的，
为什么是你带着手拷？
If you're FBI,
why are you in handcuffs?

395
00:52:27,437 --> 00:52:29,689
为什么不和你的部门联系
Why are there U.S. Marines
outside this door?

396
00:52:32,567 --> 00:52:35,153
我不知道 我不是一位超级间谍
I do not know. I'm not a super spy.

397
00:52:43,829 --> 00:52:48,375
我曾在海军陆战队中像你一样
是一个警官
I was in the Marines.
As a cop. Like you.

398
00:52:49,960 --> 00:52:53,255
在巴格达，我跑我 遇到了炸弹袭击
In Baghdad I ran I MC detail in a Musemum opening.

399
00:52:53,463 --> 00:52:55,799
珠宝，艺术品
Jewels, arts,

400
00:52:57,050 --> 00:52:59,052
继续
Go on.

401
00:52:59,219 --> 00:53:01,177
有爆炸
There was bombing.

402
00:53:01,179 --> 00:53:05,267
36个平民被杀了没有我们的人
36 civilians were killed. And one Marine.

403
00:53:06,184 --> 00:53:11,481
中央情报局把目标指向基地 但是宾拉登已经死
它似乎不太可能
The CIA tapped Al Qaeda. But Bin Laden was already dead
It seemed pointless.

404
00:53:12,983 --> 00:53:15,191
我开始检查情报
So the watch with the Intel.

405
00:53:15,193 --> 00:53:18,780
所有炸弹袭击都有相同的方式
More bombings,

406
00:53:18,947 --> 00:53:22,659
都在重要部门
都有珠宝和艺术品
VIP events.
Jewels and art.

407
00:53:24,077 --> 00:53:27,914
而且？
-他们不是恐怖份子，哈希
And?
- They're not terrorists, Hashi.

408
00:53:29,374 --> 00:53:32,669
苏丹娜 在她被杀时了有一条七百万元的项链
The Sultana had a seven million dollars necklace on when she was killed.

409
00:53:32,878 --> 00:53:35,587
是的 它在 伊夫黎雪锁柜中
Yes. It is in evidance locker.

410
00:53:35,589 --> 00:53:37,589
你检查它是否是真的吗？
Did you check whether it's real?

411
00:53:37,591 --> 00:53:41,259
他们转移了女孩，工人
They switch girls, Hash.
And necklaces.

412
00:53:41,261 --> 00:53:42,971
在爆炸之前
Before the bombing.

413
00:53:44,181 --> 00:53:45,891
你必须把我弄出这里！
You gotta get me out of here!

414
00:53:48,435 --> 00:53:49,811
我们是警官，男人！
We are cops, man!

415
00:53:50,312 --> 00:53:52,397
我们一起必须团结
We gotta stick together.

416
00:53:52,772 --> 00:53:55,734
你相信你的老板找到 维特里亚？
kids？
You're gonna trust your boss to find Vitria?
The kids?

417
00:53:58,111 --> 00:54:00,447
你是海军陆战队中的一个官员
You are an officer in the Marines.

418
00:54:00,614 --> 00:54:02,532
一个中尉 和你一样
A lieutenant. Like you.

419
00:54:11,166 --> 00:54:12,918
理查德·特拉弗斯
Richard Travers.

420
00:54:13,126 --> 00:54:16,755
-一等兵，美国海军陆战队
Look, I...
- Private First Class, USMC.

421
00:54:16,922 --> 00:54:19,962
你不了解
-是的 你是一个骗子
You do not understand.
- Yes, I do. You are a liar.

422
00:54:20,091 --> 00:54:22,052
老实人先生
Mr. Not-Wilde.

423
00:54:22,219 --> 00:54:24,554
见鬼
- 哈希
Lieutenant Not-Jake
- Hashi.

424
00:54:25,513 --> 00:54:30,852
你应该进监狱
在那里他们给你个编号，而不是一个名字
They belong in prison.
Where they give you numbers. Not a name.

425
00:54:33,939 --> 00:54:36,024
我得到一个名字了
I got a name for you.

426
00:54:39,277 --> 00:54:42,030
他抓了你的家人
The guy that has your family.

427
00:54:42,197 --> 00:54:45,323
我知道他的名字
-告诉我！
I know his name.
- Tell me!

428
00:54:45,325 --> 00:54:48,370
你需要把你的家人找回来，
放了我
you need to get your family back?
Get me out of here!

429
00:54:49,621 --> 00:54:51,748
我们俩都拿我们想要的
We both get what we want.

430
00:54:55,252 --> 00:54:56,962
你一定是中尉 哈希姆
You must be Lieutenant Hashim.

431
00:54:57,128 --> 00:55:01,132
谢谢你们帮助提高我们抓到了逃犯
Thanks for helping for cover up our fugitives.

432
00:55:01,466 --> 00:55:03,885
逃犯？
Fugitive?

433
00:55:04,135 --> 00:55:05,720
我们有逮捕的理由
I have an arrest warrant for him.

434
00:55:09,391 --> 00:55:11,017
对不起，先生
I beg your pardon, sir.

435
00:55:11,268 --> 00:55:15,105
我一定和你说
关于政治
I must speak with you.
And about politics.

436
00:55:16,147 --> 00:55:17,897
再来点
In.

437
00:55:17,899 --> 00:55:19,859
抬起来
Up?

438
00:55:28,868 --> 00:55:30,829
极好的 对于我的买主
Superb. For my buyers.

439
00:55:31,913 --> 00:55:34,874
华人了解王室的物品
The Chinese are great lovers for royal things.

440
00:55:36,293 --> 00:55:39,377
而且谁知道？
And who knows?

441
00:55:39,379 --> 00:55:41,589
也许他们甚至会买你
Maybe they even buy you.

442
00:55:55,353 --> 00:55:58,857
他们伤害你和你的孩子吗？
Did they hurt you and your children?

443
00:56:17,417 --> 00:56:19,461
年轻就是一种美
Youth is of particular beauty.

444
00:56:20,795 --> 00:56:25,008
也许因此它如此快溜走
Perhaps because it slips away so quickly.

445
00:56:27,093 --> 00:56:32,932
警察的妻子和他的孩子
这是不我们的交易的一部份
The policeman's wife and his children.
This is not part of our deal

446
00:56:34,476 --> 00:56:36,644
你将会被奖赏
You will be rewarded.

447
00:56:37,354 --> 00:56:39,647
不，你这小东西
No, not you pretty little thing.

448
00:56:39,981 --> 00:56:41,399
这对你不是好的食物
This is not good for you.

449
00:56:48,531 --> 00:56:50,656
她喜欢巧克力
She loves chocolate.

450
00:56:50,658 --> 00:56:55,705
我们不关心钱，
-这似乎为你的讨伐异教徒更重要
We care nothing for money - Yet,
you seems to need much of it for your jihad.

451
00:56:56,122 --> 00:56:59,501
吉哈德绝对是无辜的
Jihad is not a license  for desecration
of innocence.

452
00:56:59,709 --> 00:57:01,419
不，
No, no.

453
00:57:01,586 --> 00:57:05,382
以后你就知道了
Just a murder.

454
00:57:07,967 --> 00:57:13,223
我警告过你 马利克  你不能够
绑架无辜的妻子或孩子
You are warned Malik. You cannot
have the good wife or the children.

455
00:57:19,187 --> 00:57:24,567
我能得到任何我想要的
不然我来这里干嘛
I can have anything I want.
Why do you think I'm here?

456
00:57:39,624 --> 00:57:43,253
上尉，你必须让我去！
你知道为什么
Captain, you gotta let me go!
You know why.

457
00:57:43,420 --> 00:57:45,463
以我为才走小路
That's why I'm taking you home, Jake.

458
00:57:55,932 --> 00:57:57,434
因为基督的缘故！
For Christ's sake!

459
00:58:14,742 --> 00:58:16,286
出来！出来！
Get out! Get out!

460
00:58:30,717 --> 00:58:31,926
不！ 不！
No! No!

461
00:59:00,622 --> 00:59:03,875
这是你自己的选择
你已经决定
This is your own choice.
You have decided.

462
00:59:05,210 --> 00:59:07,170
他是你的了
He's all yours.

463
00:59:20,725 --> 00:59:22,435
名字！
The name!

464
00:59:23,019 --> 00:59:25,939
哈希？
-告诉我他的名字
Hashi?
- You promised me a name.

465
00:59:26,773 --> 00:59:28,650
如果再次对我说谎...
Lie to me again...

466
00:59:28,816 --> 00:59:31,861
而且我发誓，我将会送你
回到美国
And I swear, I will send you
back to America.

467
00:59:32,028 --> 00:59:34,113
不过是在运尸袋中
In the body bag.

468
00:59:35,740 --> 00:59:38,826
他的名字是 马利克  他是美国人
His name is Malik. He's American.

469
00:59:39,536 --> 00:59:41,162
或欧洲人
Or Europeans.

470
00:59:43,498 --> 00:59:45,750
不是穆斯林
Not even Muslim.

471
00:59:52,006 --> 00:59:58,263
当他说 " 祝你平安",
它缺乏尊敬
When he says "Assalamu alaikum",
it lacks respects.

472
01:00:03,017 --> 01:00:06,062
为什么如此大费周章
So why all this street theater?

473
01:00:06,688 --> 01:00:08,690
将军和我作交易
The general and I made a deal.

474
01:00:08,856 --> 01:00:10,650
美国人不可能知道
The Americans may not know.

475
01:00:14,487 --> 01:00:17,156
现在，把真相全部告诉我
Now, the truth.
All of it

476
01:00:18,032 --> 01:00:21,953
炸弹只是一障眼法
The bomb is just a distraction.

477
01:00:25,415 --> 01:00:27,750
什么障眼法
What a distraction...

478
01:00:35,133 --> 01:00:38,011
... 它非常昂贵
-他又不缺钱
... it is very expensive.
- Fuck Hash.

479
01:00:38,261 --> 01:00:40,597
那是完美的犯罪
We're talking big bucks.
The perfect crime.

480
01:00:40,763 --> 01:00:46,227
每个人都在归罪该死的阿普杜拉让恐怖分子更嚣张
Everything is playing fucking Abdul's terrorists.

481
01:00:47,312 --> 01:00:50,152
那为什么那么多人在找他？
How does he get people to blow them self up for him?

482
01:00:50,189 --> 01:00:54,736
他使用一个遥远的雷管，不留一点线索
He uses a remote detonator, right?
He ​​leaves nothing to change.

483
01:00:54,986 --> 01:00:58,448
你知道马利克用一个女人换了苏丹娜
-我知道
You think Malik switched Sultana with another woman?
- I know he did.

484
01:00:58,656 --> 01:01:01,284
为什么？ 而且如何做的？
Why? And how?

485
01:01:03,328 --> 01:01:05,705
他如何做了它，我知道
How he did it, I know.

486
01:01:05,872 --> 01:01:09,042
但是为什么，一会儿就知道
But why, haven't figured out yet.

487
01:01:10,877 --> 01:01:15,340
我会的
-我们会的
I will.
- We will.

488
01:01:15,882 --> 01:01:17,342
是的 对的
Yes. Right.

489
01:01:18,635 --> 01:01:21,638
因此我们现在去哪？
-去和苏丹聊聊
So where are we headed?
- It's time to speak with the Sultan.

490
01:01:40,239 --> 01:01:43,159
谢谢你
你接见我们，陛下
Thank you
that you receive us, Your Majesty.

491
01:01:44,243 --> 01:01:47,330
你说它牵涉了我的女儿？
You said it involved my daughter?

492
01:01:47,622 --> 01:01:50,416
我们需要谈谈关于她的项链
We need to discuss about her necklace.

493
01:01:52,669 --> 01:01:55,380
她的项链？
Her necklace?

494
01:01:55,546 --> 01:02:01,803
我不了解 你是谁？
- 特拉弗斯 联邦调查局 绑架调查小组
I do not understand. Who are you?
- Travers. FBI. Kidnapping Squad.

495
01:02:07,266 --> 01:02:12,146
对不起，陛下
关于爆炸一些的细节......
Sorry, Your Highness. There are
some details about the bombing, that you...

496
01:02:12,438 --> 01:02:17,110
将军告诉我们，
案子已经被解决了
The General told us,
The matter has been resolved.

497
01:02:18,027 --> 01:02:20,071
凶手已经被绳之以法
The killers have been given justice.

498
01:02:22,073 --> 01:02:27,034
不过仍然有大量的细节
炸弹爆炸的时候你就在她身边
But still, there are details that...
- You were right next to her when the bomb went off.

499
01:02:27,036 --> 01:02:28,621
杰克！
Jake!

500
01:02:28,830 --> 01:02:34,293
你到底在说什么？
-我谢谢你 你两个
How dare you?
- I Thank you. Both of you.

501
01:02:35,378 --> 01:02:38,172
感谢你们的关心
For your concern.

502
01:02:40,925 --> 01:02:42,719
谢谢你，苏丹
Thank you, Sultan.

503
01:02:54,689 --> 01:02:56,482
他们隐藏了某些事情
They were hiding something.

504
01:02:58,776 --> 01:03:02,613
他们也太假了
-如果涉及到利益，很多人会撒谎的
Has used up his life in lies.
- many people lies when they share their interest.

505
01:03:03,156 --> 01:03:06,033
但你也不能视而不见
We had him by the balls.
that's when you squeeze partners...

506
01:03:09,537 --> 01:03:10,496
够了
Enough!

507
01:03:10,872 --> 01:03:12,957
你害死的人还不够吗？
Haven't you gotten enough people killed?

508
01:03:14,167 --> 01:03:17,503
美国人
总是指手画脚，不听别人的意见
Americans.
Always you are telling. Never listening.

509
01:03:17,670 --> 01:03:20,256
总是战斗不会聆听
Always fighting, never hearing.

510
01:03:20,423 --> 01:03:24,218
是的 那是我们 一个暴力的国家
Yes. That's us. A violent country.

511
01:03:24,385 --> 01:03:26,844
这不是开玩笑的时间
This is not time for jokes.

512
01:03:26,846 --> 01:03:28,973
我的家很危险
My family is at stake.

513
01:03:29,223 --> 01:03:32,099
从现在开始，我们按照我的规矩来
From now on, we play by my rules.

514
01:03:32,101 --> 01:03:34,437
爪哇规矩
Java rules.

515
01:03:51,412 --> 01:03:54,290
那个爪哇空手道是什么玩意？
What was that sneaky Javanese karate?

516
01:03:54,499 --> 01:03:57,335
没有空手道，是搏击
No karate. Pencak Silat.

517
01:03:58,252 --> 01:04:01,712
一个远古的武艺，
对付狡猾的敌人非常有效
An ancient martial art,
is more important than the cunning over strength.

518
01:04:01,714 --> 01:04:03,591
狗屎
Aw, shit.

519
01:04:03,800 --> 01:04:06,219
这是我们必须学习的东西
This is how we must act.

520
01:04:07,345 --> 01:04:10,181
而不是在中国店横冲直撞的一只公牛
Not like a bull in a chinese shop.

521
01:04:10,389 --> 01:04:11,808
瓷器商店
China shop.

522
01:04:12,183 --> 01:04:16,229
相似的盘子？
所以笨牛才买盘子
Like dishes?
Why would a bull but dishes?

523
01:04:18,773 --> 01:04:21,692
苏丹就是在耍我们
-他们把一切都告诉我们了
They told us jack shit in there.
- They told us everything.

524
01:04:21,859 --> 01:04:23,861
是你一直说个不停
You weren't need talking.

525
01:04:24,070 --> 01:04:27,271
关于维齐 胡说，胡说，胡说
-我正在尝试理解他们所知道的
About Vizier. blah, blah, blah.
- I was trying to figure out what they know.

526
01:04:27,281 --> 01:04:29,450
你找到了吗？乡下佬
And did you? Think Jake.

527
01:04:29,617 --> 01:04:32,954
甚至把苏丹娜的尸体放在他眼前
Even the Sultana's body must be viewed by next of kin.

528
01:04:34,372 --> 01:04:38,290
因此苏丹都已经知道了？
-他的女儿活着？ 是的
Then the Sultan already knew?
- That his daughter is alive? Yes.

529
01:04:38,292 --> 01:04:42,088
因此，我告诉...
So, Tell me...

530
01:04:42,296 --> 01:04:45,007
" 联邦调查局绑架专家 "先生
Mister  "FBI kidnapping expert".

531
01:04:46,092 --> 01:04:50,596
为什么做为
绑架受害人的父亲拒绝跟警察提供线索？
Why does the father of a
kidnap victim refused to speak to the police?

532
01:04:52,014 --> 01:04:57,812
因为 绑架者告诉他不要和警察说话，
不然就撕票
Because the kidnapers told him not to talk to the cops. While they wait for the ransoms.

533
01:04:57,979 --> 01:05:03,484
啊哈 你看
多看，少说话
Aha. You see?
Speak less, learn more.

534
01:05:04,277 --> 01:05:07,947
所以苏丹最好不在 维齐面前说话
It was interesting, too, that
the Sultan refused to talk before the vizier.

535
01:05:09,448 --> 01:05:12,243
你如何知道苏丹需要和我们说话？
How do you know the Sultan wants to talk to us at all?

536
01:05:13,119 --> 01:05:16,247
因为当我吻他的手时，
他给了我这个
Because when I kissed his hand
He gave me this.

537
01:05:18,916 --> 01:05:23,004
午夜？ -在水道
-我们需要证明
At midnight? - At the aqueducts.
before that we need proof.

538
01:05:45,067 --> 01:05:46,402
答中了！
Bingo!

539
01:05:47,278 --> 01:05:50,531
闪闪发光者未必是金子
- 灿烂！
All that glitters is not gold.
- Glisters!

540
01:05:50,698 --> 01:05:53,242
灿烂？
-莎士比亚
Glitters?
- Shakespeare.

541
01:05:53,826 --> 01:05:55,536
"威尼斯的商人".
"The Merchant of Venice".

542
01:05:55,703 --> 01:05:57,496
嗨！
-该走了
Hey!
- Time to go.

543
01:06:13,846 --> 01:06:16,807
有人跟踪你吗？
Are we followed?

544
01:06:17,350 --> 01:06:19,435
我怎么知道
How does man know.

545
01:06:19,602 --> 01:06:23,356
陛下，我相信你的直觉
You listen and trust your instinct.

546
01:06:23,564 --> 01:06:27,568
我的 直觉引导我信赖你
Why do my instincs tell me to trust you?

547
01:06:28,319 --> 01:06:32,365
因为已经绑架你的女儿的人，
也绑架了我的家人
Because of the man who has kidnapped your daughter,
has my family.

548
01:06:32,573 --> 01:06:34,700
陛下，我们带来了项链
Sir. We brought the necklace.

549
01:06:34,951 --> 01:06:37,286
如果它是假货，你能告诉吗？
Can you tell if it's a fake?

550
01:06:39,288 --> 01:06:41,040
我知道它是假货
I know it is a fake.

551
01:06:41,832 --> 01:06:48,839
-为什么这么说？
-我的堂兄弟， 维齐想要王座
Then why not say so?
- My cousin, the Vizier wants the throne.

552
01:06:49,715 --> 01:06:52,341
他虽然与绑匪在一起
但不是一伙的
He sticks with the kidnappers under a blanket.

553
01:06:52,343 --> 01:06:54,428
这可不止一条项链那么简单
This is about more than the necklace.

554
01:06:54,679 --> 01:06:57,598
做这些都是为了一件事
The jewelry is part of a collection.

555
01:06:57,807 --> 01:07:00,224
爪哇王冠上的珠宝
The Crown Jewels of Java.

556
01:07:00,226 --> 01:07:02,228
将用来交换什么？
How's the exchange gonna take place?

557
01:07:03,270 --> 01:07:05,856
不会有了特拉弗斯先生
There will not be one, Mr. Travers.

558
01:07:09,151 --> 01:07:10,486
走，快走！
Get out, go!

559
01:07:11,237 --> 01:07:12,488
快的！
Quick!

560
01:07:41,350 --> 01:07:43,019
我们必须赶紧走
We gotta move out.

561
01:07:53,696 --> 01:07:55,656
打电话给警官！
Call the cops!

562
01:08:00,786 --> 01:08:04,165
- 哈希！
-我在这里不能离开他！
- Hashi!
- I can not leave him here!

563
01:08:04,623 --> 01:08:07,126
好 钥匙给我
Okay. The keys.

564
01:08:19,013 --> 01:08:22,975
你能信赖这个人吗
Can you trust this Bule?

565
01:08:28,189 --> 01:08:29,815
不
No.

566
01:08:34,862 --> 01:08:38,741
你之前说的将不会有交换，是什么意思？
Whay did you mean? there will be no exchange.

567
01:08:38,991 --> 01:08:42,119
我已经叫中央银行，
I have instructed the Central Bank,

568
01:08:42,328 --> 01:08:46,499
将我们的宝物送到宫殿
To send the our treasures to the palace.

569
01:08:47,500 --> 01:08:50,044
在夜晚之前
Before night.

570
01:08:52,213 --> 01:08:56,967
等我的表弟得到他们
When my cousin, He gets...

571
01:08:58,844 --> 01:09:01,180
一切都没了
... Everything is lost.

572
01:09:08,020 --> 01:09:09,855
哈希！ 快点！
Hashi! Come on!

573
01:09:16,028 --> 01:09:19,321
警方确认，受害者是第10世苏丹
... It was confirmed that the victim is
Sri Sultan X

574
01:09:19,323 --> 01:09:21,532
他的尸体被发现的 2个小时前
His body was found 2 hours ago

575
01:09:21,534 --> 01:09:23,659
苏丹继承人， 维齐目击了罪行
The Sultan's heir, the Grand Vizier witnessed the crime.

576
01:09:23,661 --> 01:09:26,411
他说是一名外国特工
Which he said was initiated by foreign agent

577
01:09:26,413 --> 01:09:29,834
当做对抗爪哇穆斯林反对
As a strike against Javanese Muslims

578
01:09:30,084 --> 01:09:33,546
嫌疑犯是
美国海军中尉杰克·特拉弗斯
Among the suspects is
U.S. Navy Lieutenant Jake Travers...

579
01:09:33,712 --> 01:09:36,465
参与对苏丹的谋杀
... Also wanted in Sultan's murder

580
01:09:36,632 --> 01:09:40,134
以及88分队的哈希姆中尉
Lieutenant Hashim
from Detachment 88

581
01:09:40,136 --> 01:09:43,180
两人携带武器 极度危险
Both men are armed and considered dangerous

582
01:09:45,099 --> 01:09:47,810
你可以哭， 苏丹娜
It's Ok if you want to cry, Sultana

583
01:09:50,104 --> 01:09:52,606
不，不能在他面前
No, not as long as he is here

584
01:10:04,326 --> 01:10:05,911
在那里
There.

585
01:10:11,917 --> 01:10:13,627
我们要干掉他们
Are we gonna get this guys?

586
01:10:14,461 --> 01:10:17,173
说实话，你到底是谁？
Who are you? Really.

587
01:10:18,007 --> 01:10:22,636
杰克？理查德？还是什么人
-先看前边
Jake? Richard?
- We aren't doing this right now.

588
01:10:30,394 --> 01:10:37,651
随时可以说实话，不用再骗人，杰克
There's always time for truth.
No more lies, Jake.

589
01:10:49,955 --> 01:10:53,792
该死的到哪他都跟着，你知道吗？
He's followed me everywhere, you know?

590
01:10:54,501 --> 01:10:57,254
我扮坏人他也扮
He wanted all the time to be like me.

591
01:10:57,588 --> 01:11:00,591
当我离开学校，他也离开
When I left school, he went off well.

592
01:11:03,469 --> 01:11:04,929
我加入海军陆战队
I joined the Marines.

593
01:11:05,137 --> 01:11:10,267
而且他也来到巴格达，
因为他想要像他兄弟一样
And he came all the way to Baghdad,
because he wanted to be like his big brother.

594
01:11:10,976 --> 01:11:13,977
他被杀了
The Marine who was lost.

595
01:11:13,979 --> 01:11:17,066
在爆炸中？
In the bombing?

596
01:11:19,652 --> 01:11:20,736
是的
Yes.

597
01:11:25,449 --> 01:11:29,119
他们甚至跟我说把案子放下
They don't even put me on the case.
They offered counseling.

598
01:11:29,286 --> 01:11:33,082
“嗨，伙计，我们将会将你送到医院
帮你整理好情绪”
"Hey, man, we'll send you to the hospital
As you roll up your order total.."

599
01:11:33,249 --> 01:11:35,292
就像我可能对我的母亲说那样：
As if I could have said to my mother:

600
01:11:35,459 --> 01:11:38,879
"我知道，你不想要我入伍
因为你是想要理查德
"I know you don't want me to join up 
because you're affraid Richard may come"

601
01:11:40,214 --> 01:11:44,885
现在里奇再也会不来了
Now Richie never coming home

602
01:11:45,344 --> 01:11:48,597
你知道，但一切很好，
我在疗养，所以...
You know, everything is good 
because I'm in counseling.

603
01:11:50,891 --> 01:11:54,311
该死，你应该是最棒的，那是你弟弟啊
Fuck that! You go after the bastards.
I kill your motherfucking brother

604
01:11:54,979 --> 01:11:57,815
回答我，妈的，你都做了什么
Counsel that motherfucker.
That's what you do.

605
01:12:00,859 --> 01:12:02,403
谢谢你
Thank you.

606
01:12:05,906 --> 01:12:07,116
我需要知道
I needed to know

607
01:12:20,963 --> 01:12:22,798
去收拾那些混蛋
They stole the shit already.

608
01:12:26,343 --> 01:12:29,263
这些人是无罪的 像你的兄弟
These men are innocent. Like your brother.

609
01:12:31,265 --> 01:12:34,184
我们拿我们需要的
然后走
We take what we need
and go.

610
01:12:35,019 --> 01:12:38,188
好吧
-系上你的安全带！
You got it.
- Put on your seat belt!

611
01:12:39,440 --> 01:12:43,944
你在他妈的开玩笑吧？
-这是法律要罚 500，000 印尼币
Are you fucking serious?
- It's law. You pay 500.000 Rupiah fine.

612
01:12:44,111 --> 01:12:46,697
你必须在开玩笑
-我是
You gotta be kidding.
- I am.

613
01:12:49,283 --> 01:12:50,909
我必须减轻压力
I have to reduce stresses.

614
01:12:54,872 --> 01:12:55,956
稍等
Hold on.

615
01:13:04,757 --> 01:13:06,759
别动，放下武器
Do not move! Weapons drop!

616
01:13:11,513 --> 01:13:13,724
好的 脸朝下，手在上面
Alright boys! Faces down, hands up.

617
01:13:15,934 --> 01:13:18,771
我说举起手
I said Hands up!

618
01:13:19,521 --> 01:13:20,689
哈希？
Hashi?

619
01:13:21,440 --> 01:13:23,942
警察！ 88分队!
Police! Detachment 88!

620
01:13:24,193 --> 01:13:28,906
我认为他们和我们不是一样的
他们认为我们正在偷王冠珠宝
I think they like different division.
They think we're stealing the crown jewels.

621
01:13:29,073 --> 01:13:32,159
我们就是
但我们不是很擅长
We are.
But we're not very good at it.

622
01:14:17,413 --> 01:14:19,957
把门打开！
Open the door!

623
01:14:25,295 --> 01:14:26,463
起来！
Get up!

624
01:14:31,593 --> 01:14:34,763
现在打开这该死的门！
Now open the god damn door!

625
01:14:34,930 --> 01:14:37,224
杰克，不要！
Jake, don't!

626
01:14:38,851 --> 01:14:43,647
我说
打开他妈的门！
I said
open the fucking door!

627
01:14:50,279 --> 01:14:52,781
滚下来，蹲下！
Get the hell out! Get down!

628
01:15:00,456 --> 01:15:01,874
哈希！
-来了
Hashi!
- Yes.

629
01:15:05,169 --> 01:15:06,503
走！
Go!

630
01:15:19,224 --> 01:15:23,812
你要杀那个人
- 不！ 我保险都没打开
You were going to kill that man.
- Nah..! I had the safety ON.

631
01:15:57,346 --> 01:15:58,680
请，先生
Please, sir.

632
01:16:04,019 --> 01:16:07,814
你是认真的？
-别来这套
Are you serious?
- Don't even start.

633
01:16:08,732 --> 01:16:10,212
你离开一会好吗，小妹
Could you leave us for a minute, sister?

634
01:16:11,610 --> 01:16:13,612
这按摩很好的
This is a great hide out.

635
01:16:15,280 --> 01:16:18,534
此外，简单的活都给你了
Besides, you had the easy part.

636
01:16:19,868 --> 01:16:21,995
我还有很麻烦的活啊
The big part because I've hauled.

637
01:16:30,629 --> 01:16:33,006
你的衣服试试
Your clothes. for Disguise!

638
01:16:36,802 --> 01:16:38,220
好吧，谢谢你
Well, thank you.

639
01:16:38,971 --> 01:16:43,350
最好穿着
要不然人人都知道你是杀人犯
Better to dress as an ex Marine
who is wanted for murder?

640
01:16:43,517 --> 01:16:48,272
哈希，你肯定不了解陆战队的座右铭
永远忠诚
Hashi, don't know a thing as an ex Marine? Semper Fi.

641
01:17:08,125 --> 01:17:09,958
祝你平安
Peace be with you.

642
01:17:09,960 --> 01:17:11,128
哈希姆中尉
Lieutenant Hashim.

643
01:17:11,878 --> 01:17:15,799
这不是游戏
你知道我是谁
Let's not pretend.
You know who I am.

644
01:17:16,049 --> 01:17:17,634
听好了，混蛋！
Listen up, asshole!

645
01:17:17,884 --> 01:17:20,510
放了他的家人，
也许我们能进行交易
Let his family go,
maybe we can make a deal with this whole...

646
01:17:20,512 --> 01:17:24,600
妈的
这不就是看着弟弟死去的废物特拉维斯吗
Is not shit, Travers,
You have failed your brother, again.

647
01:17:26,560 --> 01:17:28,353
听听，我的朋友
Until then, my friend.

648
01:18:00,260 --> 01:18:04,681
美国技术
对付恐怖份子真好
American technology.
very good for striking terrorists.

649
01:18:17,194 --> 01:18:18,487
怎么样？
Are you ok?

650
01:18:36,755 --> 01:18:39,257
快走！
-不，我不会 我的家人
Do not!
- No I can't. My family.

651
01:18:39,424 --> 01:18:41,259
你死了还有什么用
Not good if you're dead.

652
01:18:58,235 --> 01:18:59,444
趴下！
Go, get down!

653
01:19:06,952 --> 01:19:09,121
闭嘴！ 闭嘴！
Shut up! Shut up!

654
01:19:09,287 --> 01:19:11,915
放轻松点
Take it easy.

655
01:19:26,513 --> 01:19:28,974
他们去哪里？
快说
Where did they go?
Quick! Say it!

656
01:19:47,492 --> 01:19:49,619
起来
对不起
Get out!
Sorry.

657
01:20:26,656 --> 01:20:28,617
这里一切皆有可能
Anything can grow here.

658
01:20:29,117 --> 01:20:30,660
你将会很快回家
You'll be home soon.

659
01:20:40,045 --> 01:20:42,879
我们都快死了她们怎么还活着
You want us all to be killed.
She's supposed to be dead?

660
01:20:42,881 --> 01:20:46,009
很快她们就会死了
Easy. Only through them that we are safe.
They will be dead.

661
01:20:46,635 --> 01:20:49,387
你们也一样，滚开我的视线
as soon as your men,
Give my merchandise to my merchant.

662
01:20:50,263 --> 01:20:52,557
我警告你 走开
I warned you. Over there!

663
01:20:53,099 --> 01:20:54,142
走
Move!

664
01:21:01,191 --> 01:21:02,609
按他说的做
Do as he says.

665
01:21:02,818 --> 01:21:04,986
出来，快点
Come on! quick!

666
01:21:16,581 --> 01:21:18,041
愿你安息，朝圣者
Peace be with you, pilgrim.

667
01:21:30,220 --> 01:21:31,638
不！
No!

668
01:21:32,180 --> 01:21:33,723
我的家人
My family!

669
01:21:34,391 --> 01:21:35,433
快点！
Come on!

670
01:22:03,545 --> 01:22:07,632
在那里！ 看
There! Look.

671
01:22:40,081 --> 01:22:41,875
钥匙
Key.

672
01:23:17,535 --> 01:23:20,664
你正在与一个美国军人合作？
You are working with an American soldier?

673
01:23:25,085 --> 01:23:28,755
-他们把炸弹扔在我们的孩子身上
-是的
- They bomb on our children.
- Yes.

674
01:23:29,881 --> 01:23:32,634
但是他也在战争中失去了亲人
But he also lost someone in the war.

675
01:23:33,218 --> 01:23:36,054
他帮助我找到我的家人
He helps me to find mine.

676
01:23:37,305 --> 01:23:39,516
你的家人仍然活着
Your family is still alive.

677
01:23:43,687 --> 01:23:45,146
直到今晚
Until tonight.

678
01:23:47,148 --> 01:23:48,858
真主保佑

God willing.
(insyaallah)

679
01:23:49,943 --> 01:23:51,778
真主保佑

God willing.
(insyaallah)

680
01:23:51,945 --> 01:23:54,114
你必须去庆典
You'll be at the festival.

681
01:23:54,280 --> 01:23:57,033
马利克 没绑架你的儿子
Malik may not get your boy.

682
01:24:05,000 --> 01:24:06,084
不
No.

683
01:24:07,544 --> 01:24:09,546
你一定宣要相信主
You must declare your faith.

684
01:24:27,731 --> 01:24:31,609
我证明
除了安拉之外没有其他主
I testify
that there is no other God but Allah

685
01:24:32,027 --> 01:24:34,821
而且穆罕默德是他的预言者
and Mohammed is his prophet.

686
01:25:14,778 --> 01:25:16,404
继续干！
Get back to work!

687
01:25:48,520 --> 01:25:51,815
我希望你为这有一种解释
I hope you have an explanation for this.

688
01:26:17,132 --> 01:26:19,843
他们在哪里？ 珠宝在哪里？
Where are they? Where are the jewels?

689
01:26:20,260 --> 01:26:22,554
你是悲哀的！
You are pathetic!

690
01:26:22,720 --> 01:26:25,431
我们数年前卖了他们帮助我们的人民了
We sold them years ago to feed our people.

691
01:26:30,603 --> 01:26:31,771
是的
Yes.

692
01:26:32,438 --> 01:26:34,691
唯一的东西我的父亲不愿意卖的...
The only thing my father wouldn't sell...

693
01:26:37,277 --> 01:26:41,322
那一条项链 我接掌王座后会领导国家很多年
That necklace. For year when I take the throne.

694
01:26:52,000 --> 01:26:55,378
你的散弹猎枪露出了了
-见鬼！
Your shotgun is showing.
- Shit!

695
01:27:18,193 --> 01:27:20,195
嗨！
Hey!

696
01:27:20,904 --> 01:27:22,655
都走开！ 我自己来
Get out! I'll do it

697
01:27:27,368 --> 01:27:28,786
滚出去！
Get out!

698
01:27:30,079 --> 01:27:31,998
去看看
Check it out.

699
01:27:33,958 --> 01:27:35,293
不能有目击者
No Witnesses

700
01:27:43,968 --> 01:27:45,428
嗨，在那里！
Hey, there!

701
01:27:47,472 --> 01:27:48,681
嗨，杰克！
Hey, Jake!

702
01:28:00,151 --> 01:28:01,152
不！
No!

703
01:28:27,470 --> 01:28:28,304
我的亲爱 维齐...
My dear vizier...

704
01:28:28,846 --> 01:28:33,101
中国人
他们花二百万欧元买一只老虎
The Chinese
They pay 2 million euros for a tiger.

705
01:28:33,309 --> 01:28:35,603
而且为一个犀牛花一个百万
And a million for a rhino.

706
01:28:36,813 --> 01:28:38,815
你认为他们会为一位公主花多少？
What do you think they're paying for a princess?

707
01:28:54,414 --> 01:28:56,833
给我一个理由！
Give me a reason!

708
01:28:58,710 --> 01:29:00,128
给你两怎样
How about two?

709
01:29:02,505 --> 01:29:04,090
你们自自己选择
Your  have a choice.

710
01:29:04,299 --> 01:29:06,716
索尔希，萨斯塔！
Thoersi, Sastha!

711
01:29:06,718 --> 01:29:08,094
你们知道我是谁
You know who I am.

712
01:29:13,182 --> 01:29:14,851
他杀 维齐
He killed the Vizier.

713
01:29:15,268 --> 01:29:17,810
让开
Stay back!

714
01:29:17,812 --> 01:29:19,270
给我刀
Give me the knife

715
01:29:19,272 --> 01:29:21,482
放下刀
让她们走
Protect her!
- Let them go

716
01:29:21,858 --> 01:29:23,359
不，不
No, no.

717
01:29:38,207 --> 01:29:39,542
哈希！ 你还好吗？
Hashi! are you OK?

718
01:29:39,751 --> 01:29:41,085
是的
Yes.

719
01:29:48,801 --> 01:29:50,553
苏丹娜，她还活着
Sultana, she lives

720
01:29:50,720 --> 01:29:52,305
让开，白痴
Out of the way, you idiots!

721
01:29:53,139 --> 01:29:55,058
不！ 停下！
No! Hold it!

722
01:29:55,266 --> 01:29:57,769
不！ 阻止他！ 不
No! Stop him! No.

723
01:29:58,811 --> 01:30:00,063
不，不，不！
No, no, no!

724
01:30:02,148 --> 01:30:03,566
我属于这里
I belong here with you.

725
01:30:04,901 --> 01:30:07,362
我丈夫是个警官
You are a police officer.

726
01:30:16,704 --> 01:30:19,374
警察！
让开，警察！
Jake! Police!
Out of the way, police!

727
01:30:23,544 --> 01:30:24,629
让开！
Move!

728
01:30:25,713 --> 01:30:30,134
趴下，
让开！ 警察！
Back there he is. After him!
Make the way! Police!

729
01:30:30,301 --> 01:30:31,761
让开！ 让开！
Apart! Apart!

730
01:30:47,485 --> 01:30:50,488
让开，警察！让开！
Out of the way, police! Get back!

731
01:31:01,207 --> 01:31:02,792
走，母狗！
Move it, bitch!

732
01:31:04,502 --> 01:31:06,879
趴下！趴下！
Get down! Get down!

733
01:33:06,541 --> 01:33:09,627
嗯 他的散弹猎枪
Look at that. His shotgun.

734
01:33:10,336 --> 01:33:17,134
这真是差劲的选择，就像你一样
没有一点用处
It's a poor choice, my friend.
Like you. It lacks precission.

735
01:33:51,252 --> 01:33:54,420
项链在我的口袋中
The necklace is in my pocket

736
01:33:54,422 --> 01:33:59,885
它能买我的离开这个发狂地方的机票
It can buy my way out of this crazy place.

737
01:34:01,554 --> 01:34:03,139
我什么都有了
I have everything.

738
01:34:05,516 --> 01:34:08,436
可是现在...
And now...

739
01:34:09,478 --> 01:34:11,022
...我有你
... I have you.

740
01:34:15,318 --> 01:34:16,609
怎么了？
What's wrong?

741
01:34:16,611 --> 01:34:20,531
你用光美国强硬人勇气了？
Did you run out of American tough guy insults?

742
01:34:24,076 --> 01:34:26,787
你曾叫我是混蛋
You want to call me asshole?

743
01:34:27,413 --> 01:34:29,165
或狗娘养的
Or motherfucker.

744
01:34:30,166 --> 01:34:33,252
我的这一位朋友告诉我要少说话
you see? this friend of mine told me to talk less...

745
01:34:35,713 --> 01:34:37,006
要多听
And listen more.

746
01:34:37,173 --> 01:34:39,300
喂 牛仔
好忠告，听听这个
Well cowboy,
A good advice then you listen to it.

747
01:34:47,141 --> 01:34:48,267
杰克？
Jake?

748
01:35:11,791 --> 01:35:14,919
那是你如何使用一个散弹猎枪，狗娘养的
That's how you use a shotgun, motherfucker!

749
01:35:37,483 --> 01:35:39,235
杰克！ 杰克！
Jake! Jake!

750
01:36:21,318 --> 01:36:24,862
对不起，我知道你当众不能在嘴上吻
Sorry, I know you can't kiss on the mouth in public.

751
01:36:24,864 --> 01:36:28,576
这不违法吧
-你说什么呢
It againsts the law.
- It is not.

752
01:36:30,202 --> 01:36:32,246
谁告诉你？
Who told you that?

753
01:36:40,546 --> 01:36:42,965
哦！ 差点忘了
Oh! Almost forgot.

754
01:36:44,800 --> 01:36:47,595
小小的礼物
A little gone away present.

755
01:36:51,766 --> 01:36:56,437
你不知道这意谓着什么
-是的 我知道
You do not know what this means.
- Yes. I do.

756
01:37:14,622 --> 01:37:17,291
嗨，杰克
Hey, Jake.

757
01:37:20,002 --> 01:37:21,585
如何做的你？
How did you...?

758
01:37:21,587 --> 01:37:25,339
很明显你的老板也不是那么干净
I figured your boss will have a price for spring this police jarhead.

759
01:37:25,341 --> 01:37:28,844
我们也在法庭上得到了政治
还有你的将军
We got politics in court too.
And with generals.

760
01:37:29,887 --> 01:37:33,849
我们从陈尸所偷的假货...
The fake we stole from the morgue...

761
01:37:34,600 --> 01:37:36,936
... 然后在我换了马利克身上的
... Then after we got Malik.

762
01:37:40,648 --> 01:37:42,858
好吧，这你就不懂了
Well, you get the picture.

763
01:37:44,193 --> 01:37:46,153
我给将军假货？
I gave the General a fake?

764
01:37:46,987 --> 01:37:49,448
他会怎么做？报警？
What's he gonna do? Call the cops?

765
01:37:51,951 --> 01:37:53,786
这才是是最好的武器
This is the best weapon.

766
01:37:55,538 --> 01:37:59,124
你的兄弟会以你为骄傲的，
我也是
Your brother would have been proud of you.
I am proud.

767
01:38:00,668 --> 01:38:03,963
希望我上级也能看到
Hopefully the court marshall sees it that way.

768
01:38:04,630 --> 01:38:07,007
再见，杰克
Good bye. Mas Jake.

769
01:38:09,009 --> 01:38:10,344
再见， 哈希
See you, Hashi.

