What's wrong, miss?
I have a flat tire.
Drive to the side first.
Don't block the road.
Sorry, I need to make a call first.
Hurry. You're blocking the traffic.
Outrageous!
Send someone to help me.
I'm at Yin Chong Street.
y car is blocking the road.
Move the canvas, old man.
It's from upstairs!
Hello, police? I'm atYin Chong Street.
A man was hit by falling glass.
Police is on its way.
Sir, over here.
Mister, what's your name?
Help me.
Control, is ambulance on its way?
...and he collapsed here.
What's wrong with your car?
I have a flat tire.
We need to clear the street
for the ambulance.
What should I do?
You can still move your car. Hurry!
How?
Release the handbrake.
We'll push from behind.
Mister, hang in there.
Ambulance is coming.
Mister!
He is dead.
Fatty, collect the payment.
"one message"
According to the police,
this was a falling object accident.
Our source reveals the victim...
...is a Triad gang boss.
The victim is a Triad boss.
OCTB is taking over...
...the investigation.
Police has no further comments
at this moment...
Worried?
Howwill police conduct...
... the investigation?
There was no evidence to indicate murder.
They'll conclude it was an accident.
The cigarette butt has your saliva.
But I'm clean.
I've never been arrested.
They won't suspect me.
Remember how many jobs we've done?
We've always been discrete.
But you slipped this time.
If the police finds you,
they'll trace it to us.
Our jobs will no longer
appear as accidents,
but murders.
You can't go back now.
I picked up the cigarette for you.
You got me.
Brain must notfind out about this.
I want to play.
I meet clients, I collect payments,
My job comes with risks.
Why are you keeping secrets from me?
We have no secrets.
He's one of us. Tell him.
I left a cigarette butt at the scene.
But I have it now.
Brain doesn't have to know.
How careless of you.
It's fine now.
Well done.
Why did you lie?
What do you mean?
Why tell Uncle to lie?
I was trying to stop him
from going back to the scene.
How can I ever trust you again?
Should we go our separate ways?
Butwe've been partners for so long.
You are working for me.
Don't let mistakes jeopardize our safety.
Everyone, I've quit smoking for good!
There's always someone watching.
We're not the only ones in this trade.
Any mistake
can cost our lives.
How are you?
"Namo-Amitabha"
Mr. Wong?
This is he. Are you...
Yes. Turn into Ap Liu Street.
Stop.
Take the plastic bag in the trash can.
Keep walking.
Put all your belongings in the bag.
Yourwallet and cell phone.
Everything.
What next?
Do you see No. 165?
Go to the sixth floor.
Put the phone in the bag. Toss it.
Looks delicious.
Thanks.
Morning.
What's the son's motive?
An old grudge?
Inheritance money? Insurance scam?
Doesn't matter to us.
"Wing Wah Pawnshop"
Sorry I'm late.
Does electric leakage happen to trams?
No. Trams run on direct current.
What if we tip over the tram
to kill the target?
How?
It's difficult. Keep thinking.
We could kill him from up close.
Liking firing poison dart from an umbrella.
But that won't look like an accident.
How about electrocution through
the tram track?
We could connect a wire...
...from the tram's inverter to the track.
But that'll blow the tram's fuse.
And where do you place the inverter
on the tram?
Think of something else.
How about a car crash?
No. The street is too crowded.
How about at night?
I said no.
Use electricity.
Electrocution only works...
...when the tram's cable is connected
to the track.
How can it work?
How to get target into position?
That's very hard.
We're on the right direction.
Keep thinking.
I got a hot dog for you.
Electrocution.
Tram cable.
If we hang a wire from the cable,
target will come in contact
with it when crossing the track.
How will it conduct electricity?
Will the wire conduct electricity?
Rain.
Water conducts electricity.
How do we hang a wire from the cable?
We'll fly it.
Hard to fly it in rain!
Keep practising.
Forecast predicted rain tonight.
If it does, we'll take action.
No rain.
Abort.
Get ready.
Wait.
A car accident is holding me up.
I need to come from another side.
Fatty, are you in position? Almost.
Abort.
Uncle, why are you smoking?
Why can't I during work? Leave me alone.
But you quit already.
I did?
Why would I do that?
Uncle is ill.
Mind you words, fatso.
Uncle is not well. Should we abort?
I'm fine. There's no problem.
What should we do?
Uncle.
Can you do it?
Yes. Why not?
Are you sure?
Yes.
Action.
Heavy rain.
Have you cut the line?
Yes.
It's approaching position.
Fatty.
Uncle didn't release the balloons.
Balloons? What balloons?
Uncle.
The camera can't see you in the rain.
Go.
I trust you.
Find Uncle immediately.
Was this an accident?
Are you a tenant here?
Yes. What is it?
Are you Mr. Ho?
Your flat was broken into.
Mr. Ho, your door was opened...
...so I called the police.
Thank you.
Mr. Ho, we need to see your lD.
"Ho Kwok-fai".
Mr. Ho, please take off your hood.
Thanks. Report to Control.
Control, I need a Code-Five.
Send.
Male Ho Kwok-fai, lD# A337287(.4).
Over.
What time did you leave home today?
Did you see anyone suspicious?
No.
I left home early this morning.
You can check your belongings.
Notwanted.
Roger.
Mr. Ho, here's your lD.
Thank you.
Do you want to contact your family?
No, thanks.
Other flats in this building...
...were also broken into.
This was not an accident.
The number you're trying to reach...
...is not available at this moment.
A deadly car accident took place
at North Point last night.
A bus lost control and left 2 dead
and 8 injured.
The accident happened at approximately
10:30 PM
The 102 Bus was on its way...
... to Mei Foo
when it lost control
and ran up to the sidewalk.
The bus driver...
...is still unconscious.
Initial police investigation indicated
it was an accident.
I'm worried about you.
Abort.
We're done here?
Aren't we waiting for rain?
Fine, abort.
Your place?
Sometimes.
How long have you been ill?
I'm fine.
Wait, am l?
I can't recall.
How did I become forgetful?
I can't remember things I have done.
We've known each other. Your wife...
She was killed by a speeding car.
It was terrible.
But I believe in you.
Someone wanted you dead.
It was a set-up.
You took them already.
When do we start work?
Keep your eyes on that position.
What's the job?
Woman will contact you.
Who's the target?
I'll tell you later.
Yes, it's taken care of.
"For Rent"
How long has it been vacant?
Not long. About a month.
Who was the last tenant?
An old couple lived here for years.
The wife passed away.
Here is the key.
I'll bring you the rental contract later.
Sunny Diner.
I want to order take-out.
Is this a prank?
"Mr. Chan Fong-Chow"
"Commence surveillance."
Did I screw up?
I remember about the balloons.
The job is done. Don't worry.
No, I remember about the balloons.
Uncle.
What?
It's better not to remember.
Really?
Goodnight.
Where are you?
I'm collecting the payment. You?
How do you know who to contact?
Fatty told me about the client.
I'm replacing him to collect the payment
for all of us.
Fatty couldn't have told you.
You followed him.
What are you talking about?
How did Fatty die?
It was an accident.
No. The bus was after me.
It was a set-up.
It was an accident. 2 dead and 8 injured.
We both know all accidents can be staged.
Are you suspecting me?
Who ordered the hit?
No one. I don't know.
Who is the insurance agent?
You're making everything up.
You're lying. Stop fooling yourself.
I thought you'd believe in me.
Who ordered the hit?
You're crazy.
You betrayed me.
Damn you!
We can't approve the money
before the procedure is completed.
I have to ask my boss.
I'm following up with Mr. Wong's case.
How about the other client?
The old man.
I've told you he fell out of a window
from the second floor.
"Flawless. Clever Man."
Mom, you also read it in the papers?
Yes, the victim's father was my client.
I met him on the day he killed himself.
When he gave me
his father's death certificate,
he acted strange
and kept saying he was sorry.
Someone saw him...
...taking the elevator to the rooftop.
Right, I shouldn't have let him...
...Ieave the office alone.
"Did Mr. Wong kill himself?"
I'll pick you up afterwork.
Call me. We can have dinnertogether.
What do you want to eat?
You're messing it up. I'll do it myself.
Uncle.
Help.
How about the other client?
The old man.
He fell out of a window
from the second floor.
"...fell from second floor..."
Take care of him.
Didn't you hear the doorbell?
Why are you messing up the flat?
Make sure you clean it up...
...when you move out.
Here's your contract.
What is this?
Here's another one.
Are you alright?
I'm sorry.
Fai.
How did I fall out of the window?
The doctor said it was
because I took too many pills.
I don't remember anything.
Someone pushed you over.
Who did it? Why?
I'm busy. I'll call you later.
Last month a deadly accident took place...
...at North Point.
The bus driver finally woke up...
...from coma last night.
and gave his statement.
Fai.
I killed Fatty.
Honey.
Uncle, what did you say?
I dropped the balls.
They hit the bus.
That's how Fatty died.
It was an accident.
It can't be. No.
It can't be!
Dad!
Look!
Why did you lie?
How can I ever trust you again?
How did I fall out of the window?
The doctors said it was
because I took too many pills.
You took them already.
I knew you'd betray me.
You're making everything up.
It was an accident. 2 dead and 8 injured.
I killed Fatty.
I dropped the balls.
They hit the bus.
It was an accident.
I was wrong.
You're crazy!
"Renovation Notice"
I'm sorry.
Dad, the workmen's quotation
doesn't seem right.
What did you say?
Daughter!
Why did you do this to us?