Fixed, edited and rearranged by Hwa Sayuri, personal and alone.
Shared in Shooter.
Please keep this message, thanks.
MEDUSA
Mediaset Group
Medusa Film
Presenta
un film di
Giuseppe Tornatore
I still ask myself if I did the right thing
when I abandoned his floating city.
And I don't mean only for the work.
The fact is, a friend like that,
a real friend,
you won't meet one again.
If you just decide to
hang up your sea legs,
if you just want to feel something
more solid beneath your feet,
and if then you no loner
hear the music of the gods around you.
But, like he used to say :
"You're never really done for
as long as you got a good story...
and someone to tell it to."
Trouble is ...
nobody'd believe a single word of my story.
Tim Roth
Pruitt Taylor Vince
It happened everytime...
someone would look up and see her.
It's difficult to understand.
What I'm saying is...
there were more than
a thousand of us on that ship,
travelling richfolk, immigrants,
and strange people, and us.
Yet, there was always one!
One guy alone who would see her first.
Maybe he was just
sitting there eating,
or walking on the deck.
Maybe he was just fixing his pants.
He'd look up for a second,
A quick glance out to sea,
and he'd see her.
Then he'd just stand there,
rooted to the spot, his heart racing.
And every time,
every damn time, I swear,
he'd turn to us, towards the ship
towards everybody and scream...
America !
And I lost big money betting on
who'd be the first guy to see her,
America !
La Leggenda del Pianista Sull'Oceano
Mélanie Thierry
Bill Nunn
Clarence Williams III
nella parte di Jelly Roll Morton
Peter Vaughan; Alberto Vázquez; Niall O'Brien
e Gabriele Lavia
nel ruolo del contadino
Soggetto e sceneggiatura
Giuseppe Tornatore
Tratto da Novecento di Alessandro Baricco
Giangiacomo Feltrinelli Editore s.p.a.
musiche originali composte orchestrate e dirette da
Ennio Morricone
direttore della fotografia
Lajos Koltai a.s.c.
scenografie
Francesco Frigeri
costumi Maurizio Millenotti
arredamento Bruno Cesari
Casting
Fabrizio Castellani; Valerie McCaffrey; Jeremy Zimmermann
It's a miracle, Santa Rosalia!
montaggio Massimo Quaglia
What do you mean Santa Rosalia,
it's the Madonna di Lourdes !
coordinamento produzione Pietro Notarianni, Francesco Tornatore
supervisione effetti visivi digitali David Bush
direttore di produzione Riccardo Neri
organizzatore riprese all'estero Walter Massi
produttore esecutivo Laura Fattori
prodotto da Medusa Film
una realizzazione Sciarlò s.r.l.
regia Giuseppe Tornatore
New York
The one who sees America first.
There's one on every ship !
And don't be thinking it's an
accident or some optical illusion.
It's destiny.
Those are people who always have
that precise instant stamped on their life.
And when they were kids,
you could look into their eyes,
and if you looked carefully enough
you'd already see her,
America.
And I've seen a few Americas !
Six years on that ship,
five crossings a year :
Europe, America and back.
Always soaking in the ocean.
When you stepped on land
you couldn't even piss straight in the john.
It was steady.
The john, I mean,
but you'd keep bobbing
like an idiot.
You can get off a ship all right,
but off the ocean...
I was just closing.
What can I do for you?
When I boarded
I was twenty-four years old,
And I only cared about one thing in life
Playing the trumpet
I'm selling it.
A Conn.
Not bad.
Best brass money can buy !
Could buy, in its day.
Been a while since you played, eh ?
If you mean for money, a couple of years.
Have been spurned by got through that thing, get rid of the blues concert's playing, and I've never stopped.
Don't get me wrong...
The greatest jazz players in the world
blew through brass like that.
I'm sure, Sir.
But after the war,
people want brightness thing.
...sweet sounds, never mind jazz !
... your conn,
just a collector's item, now.
Six pounds, ten shillings Best I can do.
Christ,
that's only 25 dollars !
That horn's my whole life, mister.
Okay, no-body's going to remember me,
like Buddy Bolden or Satchmo.
But even just being a nobody
it's got to be worth more than
twenty lousy bucks!
It that's how things are,
I suppose it's barely worth half a crown.
Shut the door when you leave, please.
Okay, Pops, you win !
You just bought yourself
a piece of musical history.
Now, if you want my advice...
go out,
treat yourself to a decent meal.
At least
let me play it one last time.
Young man I don't have time to waste!
All right.
Hurry up, then, I'm closing.
Thank you.
Two peas in a pod, wouldn't you say?
You are all right?
You aren't going to be ill here, are you?
It's the music you were just playing.
Sure you recognise it?
What is it ?
It doesn't have a name.
Just a handful of people
have had the privilege of hearing it.
That style.
I was wondering since this morning, but...
I can't work out
who this amazing piano player is.
I don't think
you've ever heard of him.
Who is he ?
If I told you that this pianist
never existed, I wouldn't be lying.
I don't like secrets.
They stink, like dirty underwear !
Come on now, Yank,
who the devil is playing ?
It's my secret.
It was the first year
of this frigging century,
as defined by an unknown
colored coal stoker on the Virginian.
Fucking rich-ass bastards!
Can't lose nothing but cigarette butts
and dirty-ass handkerchiefs !
Can't lose no watch,
not even a beat-up Elgin
or a sorry-ass cufflink.
What am I talking about?
Not even a fake fucking ring !
Hey, look here, a whole cigar !
Must've been somebody poor at the party.
Look at this shit !
Nasty fucker !
Damn rich. Don't forget nothing
unless they owe you some money.
What in the scuts you doing here ?
T.D. Lemons.
Howdy do there, Lemon !
Immigrant bastard !
Give birth in secret
somewhere on deck,
and then leave on the ship
another mouth to feed !
And that's a big trouble
with the immigration office !
What's a boy like him going to be
when the baby grows up?
Another immigrant !
Don't pay those bastards,
no mind Lemon.
Go on, lap it up boy !
It's not you mama's tip,
but it's real milk.
Go on!
This one they left in first class on top the piano.
They are hoping some rich guy will come take it
and give him a happy life.
- Isn't that so, Danny?
- What do you think ?
And who does the little ape get instead? A poor worthless nigger !
Fuck poverty,
you stinking sewerrats !
T.D.was written on the box.
Any of you shitheads know what that means ?
I forgot,
You all can't read !
I'll tell you what it means.
It means, "Thanks, Danny."
"Thanks, Danny"
They left that boy for me
and l'm keeping him.
Rest of you all can go fuck yourselves.
Danny, what are you going to call the nino?
Hell, I didn't think about that.
To start off, I name him after me,
Danny Boodman.
Then l'll put T.D. in the middle like
the rich folks puts on their cuff-links in shirts.
That give it class, to put that in the middle,
don't you think?
All fucking lawyers gots initials
in the middle of their names.
One of mine own was
Jonathan P.T.K. Wonder.
The one who sent you straight to jail for ten years?
You got one good memory, chicky China man!
If my son grow up to be a lawyer,
I swear I'll kill him myself !
But the boy's name is still going to be
Danny Boodman T.D. Lemon.
What do you think ?
You got to like it, Danny.You're the mama!
I like it firmly, but it's short.
I mean, it got no finish.
He ain't the son of no fucking duke, Danny !
You found him on a Tuesday,
call him Tuesday !
You ain't as dumb as you look,
colored boy!
I found him the first month of
the first year of this frigging new century,
so I'm calling him Nineteen Hundred !
Nineteen Hundred? But that's a number!
It was a number, now it's a name!
Danny Boodman T.D. Lemon
Nineteen Hundred !
Danny, your little bambino is not so happy!
Come on, hurry, Hurry up. Don't worry, your mama's here.
Damn. How can something
that small shit so much?
"the wheels are turning"
"the Steam keeps on rising"
"oh Lord send down your light today"
Thanks Danny?
"A child is crying"
"a new life is starting"
"oh Lord stay with us here below"
Thanks Danny
"One day this boy will tell a tale or two"
"for now his soul is in your hand"
Thanks Danny...
It was like
the second coming of Christ.
Maybe it was that, with all the miracles
that little kid had up his sleeve.
Hell, he did everything on the water
but walk.
And l heard he'd done that, too.
And that's how
little Nineteen Hundred grew up
inside that cradle
as big as a ship.
But, since Danny was afraid they'd take him away
on account of some business concerning documents and visas,
the boy lived his early years
always hiding
in the belly of the Virginian.
Okay, now try one for yourself.
Now, look here.
Push your fingera gainst these words,
so the letters can't run off on you !
"Man"
All right, keep going
"go"
go on
"Ma"
Just a little bit more
Boy, you read like a god, Lemon !
Now, go on, put them all together,
kind of like them boiler valves.
Come on.
"Man... go...Mama"
Mango Mama. All right. Keep going.
"Ya-nk my ch-ain"
Danny, why are you laughing so much ?
Because these are names of horses.
Don't that make you laugh?
I"m just crazy about these horses' names.
Look at this one here.
Read there,
that one ran yesterday at Cleveland.
"Ha-ppy Hoo-fers".
Listen to this
"Sa-ssy La-ssy".
Sassy Lassy !
And this one,
"Red Hot Mama"
What's a mama, Danny?
A mama?
A mama's a horse !
A horse ?
Racehorse
Matter of fact, you know what I say.
Mama's the best horse in the world?
Thoroughbred, You bet on a mama,
you always win.
"Tano D'Amato
The King of Lemons"
Dad, put your finger here and read.
T.D. doesn't mean "Thanks, Danny"
Who's this pansy ass?
That's enough reading for tonight.
Too much reading's bad for you !
What else is bad, Danny?
Everything off the Virginian is bad.
Everything.
They got sharks on the land, they eat you alive.
You keep away from they, you hear?
See this here.
That's the white sharks,
worst kind.
Danny, what's an orphanage?
Well, a orphanage is like a great big prison
where they lock up folks that ain't got kids.
So if I wasn't with you
they would put you in an orphanage?
You got that right, little Lemon.
Night-night.
On that extraordinary floating city called Virginian,
more than a father,
Nineteen Hundred found a whole family
made of truly unique people,
like the ship's doctor.
Open your mouth, like this.
Shit, doctor,what's that red thing
hanging from your throat ? Are you sick ?
What's your name, doctor?
Dr Klausermanspizwegensdorfentage.
What a name ! If they had to
call you quickly ,they've had garner !
All that circus...
cooks, sailors,
radio operators and waiters
took good care of him.
and in their own way tried to give
him what they thought was a good education.
Also the ship's Captain, other way he
ended up being part of that crazy family.
Captain Smith, a wise man,
he only had three defects :
he suffered from claustrophobia,
had a horrible fear of drowning,
and he hated sweets.
Nineteen Hundred, how many times
have I told you not to come up here ?
Especially if it's to steal !
Put the booty back where you found it
and return to your den
or I'll send you to the orphanage !
Quick...!
Mr. Danny Boodman, this orphan nuts must come to an end !
On the case, It's even against the law.
Fuck the law !
Hey, Mick, what do you think about
in the middle of a storm ?
What ? Do I think my lawyer
should never have been born ?
Yes,the storm.
You bet he was warned,
then I blew off his head !
You think of jam and bread ?
Yes.
Know what I think, Mick ?
I think you're loco !
I have gusto?
Danny, tell Pedro how I cut
that lawyer's balls off !
The Warldorf?
I've never been there.
The whites wouldn't let me in unless
they full of the shit out the toilets !
Watch out, Danny!
- Danny !
- Run, quickly !
Danny!!
- Get out the way, let me see.
- Call a doctor.
The doctor, quickly.
Danny, you bloody cow. Talk to me.
Ain't nothing but a pat on the back, boys.
Hang on,
the doctor's coming.
DDoctor Kla-Kla-Klaus...
Klau-Klauserman!
Klausermanspizwegens
Frischerri... Kemmanschov...
Quick on the Trigger
lead over Holy Shoot...
and Times Were Good
was disqualified.
Saucy Bossy
ain't a soon tooker was Brave Victory, over...
It took him three days to go toes up, old Danny.
He let go on the sixth race in Chicago,
Drinkable Water by two lengths over Vegetable Soup,
and five over Blue Foudation.
"Yea, though I walk through the valley of the shadow of death
I will fear no evil for Thou art with me..."
Dr. Klausermanspizwegensdorfentage
declared that if Danny hadn't laugh so much ,
he probably would have recovered.
But history isn't made of "ifs".
And the only thing we can say for sure
is that suddenly,
Lemon Nineteen Hundred
became an orphan for the second time.
"Thanks Danny"
In the name of the Father and of the Son, and of the Holy Ghost.
Amen.
おんがく(on gaku)
Music.
Nineteen Hundred
was eight years old then.
He'd made the trip between Europe and America about fifty times, I imaged.
The ocean was his home.
Yeah, and his skin was covered in scales
and he had two fins, instead of arms !
It's all true, Pops.
You can bet your soul on it.
But that's absurd !
The God's truth!
He never set foot on dry land.
Never.
He'd seen it from the ports a hundred times,
but he never got off the boat.
Problem was as far as the world was concerned he didn't even exist,
there wasn't a city, a parish, a hospital, jail or baseball team
that had his name any place.
He didn't have a country, he didn't
even have a birth date. No family.
He was eight years old, but officially,
he had never even been born.
"No Entry"
America !
It's Kidnapping.
Charges of kidnapping could be
brought against you, Captain,
if one fine day the boy's kin
were to show up.
After eight years,
l seriously doubt it.
However, I think the time has come to
allow the boy to have a normal life.
I've written a personal note which I'd ask you
to deliver the head of state orphanage.
Very well, Captain.
Now where will we find the lad ?
Boatswain,
show these gentlemen the way.
Forward.
They are looking for 1900.
they got to find
the entire space.
Stand aside
You there! Hold that cargo!
I'm going to search everything.
- Have you seen a little boy?
- I never saw him.
22 days later, when the Virginian
headed for Rio de Janeiro,
nobody had found Nineteen Hundred,
one hadn't crew knows what happened to him.
Everybody, they had death in their hearts,
because they had all gotten
attached to the little boy,
although no-one would say so.
Captain...! Wake up !
Let me sleep.
Captain, this is emergency!
Christ !
We are sinking?
We are sinking!
Worse! Much worse!
What's his name ?
Nineteen Hundred.
Not the song, the boy.
Like the song !
He would have wanted to ask him a lot of
questions that moment Captain Smith.
Like : "Where the hell
did you learn to play the piano?"
Or : "ln what damn hole
have you been hiding?"
Or : "Where in Christ's name
are you getting this music from?
which seems to enter your veins
without you even realizing it."
But he was a man in uniform,
and the only thing he managed to say was:
Nineteen Hundred, all of this is
entirely against the regulations.
Fuck the regulations !
His exact words :
"Fuck the regulations !"
But l don't understand what the
record has to do with any of this.
You're not the sharpest knife in
the drawer, Pops.
That's his music.
The music of Danny Boodman
T.D. Lemon Nineteen Hundred.
The greatest ivory tickler
on the seven seas.
Amazing !
So..., if that's all true,
this record must be worth a fortune !
This record can make us both rich.
That record shouldn't exist.
The only existing matrix
was destroyed right after it was cut.
Well, this is a matrix.
Quite handy for on-the-spot recordings
that sort of business.
How did you get your hands on this?
I spend the better part of the day
putting the bits and pieces together.
I found them by accident.
Hidden inside one of those two pianos.
I bought them from a second-hand dealer
They've emptied out an old hospital ship
down at Plymouth.
They're going to destroy it
in a couple of days.
What do you mean "destroy" ?
Where's the old hospital ship ?
It's over there, mate.
Thank you.
Slow down....
Not so fast with that pulley.
Watch that! These aren't bananas, you know.
Easy up there, easy.
Where are you from ?
Liverpool.
- What do you do?
- I'm a barber.
- Sign him on.
- Thanks very much.
Next.
What's your trade ?
I'm a carpenter. A cook, barber...
Too many things for our test. Get out !
- I'm also a good mechanic.
- Get out ! Next.
What do you do ?
I play the trumpet.
We've already got musicians on board.
Next.
Get out!
Where the hell's he going ?
What's that?
I don't know.
When you don't know what it is,
it's jazz !
Jazz !
What's your name ?
Max Tooney, Sir.
Right !
It was the happiest day of my life.
All those people
with hope in their eyes,
the goodbyes, the sirens....
And that big floating world starting to move.
It felt like one big party,
a huge bash just for me.
But just three days later
the ocean got tired of the festivities.
Suddenly, in the middle of the night,
she went berserk and all hell broke loose.
Now, a guy blowing a trumpet on a ship
can't do much
when there's a raging storm.
Not playing the trumpet is about the only thing
you can do just not to complicate matters.
But I couldn't bear being down there.
Same line kept raging in my brain :
"he died like a rat."
And the last thing I wanted
was to die like a rat.
Damn it, I'm lost !
Hey, Conn?
What's the matter?
Lose your sea legs?
You're the new trumpet man,
aren't you?
And you blow a Conn?
Come with me.
I have a cure for your misery.
Follow me.
Take the brakes off, please.
What...! That's crazy!
Trust me.
Just take the brakes off.
Hop on next to me.
What are you,
some kind of nut case.
You better get on now or you never will.
Tell me something, do you have children?
Shit, They'll lock you up
in the orphanage one of these days!
He's nuts.
Whoa, Mama !
I see you know your horses.
Just a litte.
Good man!
It was like the sea was rocking us.
And while we were floating around the colorants
and brushing the lamps and furniture,
I realised that what we were really doing was dancing with the ocean.
Us and her, crazy dancers,
locked in a joyful waltz
on the golden parquet of night.
Want some ?
Cheers !
Good evening, Captain.
Care for a ride?
Nineteen Hundred !
I should know it was you.
Who else on this ship
would do anything as lunatic as this ?
Except you! Nineteen Hundred!
I was just experimenting, sir.
When I get kings up,
I'm sure you nothing among this will never happen again.
Yeah, it's missed brakes.
should fix those. grace!
Tell me again how big the fucking window was?
What a big fucking window!
You know, we're going to be shoveling coal on this ship till eternity.
No shit !
Least you know
what you'll be doing when you grow up!
- Hey, Conn.
- What ?
You're from New Orleans, right ?
How did you know that ?
I love that town.
Really? I haven't been there in a while.
In winter, it's beautiful.
And in March,
you can always count on one afternoon
when you least expect it.
The fog slides in a milky barrier
hangs just below the street lamps.
It cuts everything off!
Iike a white blade. And it's magic!
Houses lose their top floors,
trees lose their branches,
St. Louis Cathedral loses its spires,
people passing by they lose their heads.
So from the neck up everything disappears.
All you can see in Jackson Square
is a bunch of decapitated bodies,
stumbling around
and bumping into each other saying:
"How's your mama and them?"
That's it!
Too bad it doesn't last long.
But how do you know all these things ?
You know,
ever since I came on board,
I been hearing a lot of talk about a guy.
He got this name runs on like
a Georgia freight train.
He's supposed to have been born on this ship and never been off it since.
Crazy story.
Twenty years without ever setting foot on land?
Twenty-seven.
They say this guy makes music
that's never been heard before.
I've heard of him, too.
First off, I thought you were the guy.
- But then something didn't add up.
- Of course.
I figured:
if he's Nineteen Hundred
how could he know New Orleans so well?
Because you've been to New Orleans.
If I told you I'd never set foot in that town,
would you believe me?
Whoever you are,
Max Tooney.
Glad to meet you.
How we doing?
We're supposed to blow it up
not wait for it to be eaten by the fishes!
We're almost done,
just laying the last charges.
Where the hell are you going ?
- I have to look for someone.
- Stop him!
It's not eazy....
Get down there....
You bastards, let me on board !
Could you run that by me again?
I don't think I got the straight.
You bet. I'll run that by you again.
You're not going to blow up a goddamn thing,
'cause my best friend's on this ship.
You'll all be responsible for murder.
Get him out of here.
Do whatever you want,
but get him off my case!
I'm not making this up and I'm not crazy.
If I tell you there's a man aboard the Virginian,
it means there is !
Jesus Christ,
it means there's a man aboard the Virginian.
We cleaned that scuttle from stem to stern.
Not even doorknobs were left.
Only dynamite. Dynamite!
Lots of dynamite.
How can you be so sure
that's a man on board?
If you've any proof, out with it.
Because I'm the horse's arse
who has to throw that switch.
I'm sure he's there.
I spent the best years of my life
on the Virginian.
Did you find an upright piano
in third class ?
The Virginian is the only ship in the world
with a piano in third class.
Was there or wasn't there
an upright piano in third class ?
Well, there was a piano in third class,
but it was not right. It was horizontal.
Even it was round,
I don't see what the hell is the goddamned piano
got to do with a ghost aboard that ship?
there's thousands of poor dead souls
hanging out of that hospital ship!
Get out of my sight,
or I'll call the police.
You kick off your hands off me !
Listen...
Amongst those thousands of dead souls
is the greatest piano player in the world !
Yet don't say:
a bleeding piano player.
And what were you doing
all those years aboard the Virginian?
Tuning the strings?
What was I doing on the Virginian ?
What were you doing ?
I played!
Ladies and gentlemen,
Meine Damen und Herren,
Signore e signori,
Mesdames et Messieurs,
Bill Douglas here to
welcomes you aboard the Virginian.
And wishes you a pleasant evening
in the accompany of the Atlantic Jazz Band !
Perfetto !
Please, Nineteen Hundred,
just the normal notes. Okay?
We played because
the ocean is big and scary.
We played so that people
wouldn't feel the time passing
and could forget where
and who they were.
We played to make them dance,
because when you dance you can't die and you feel like god.
We played ragtime,
because that's the music God dances to,
when nobody's watching him,
assuming that God is black !
End of the line boys !
Jesus, I must be a real sinner.
Is that it, God ?
Right! Look he'd done !
It's sweet!
But it was in third class
that Nineteen Hundred
played the music which was really his.
He'd go in the afternoons
or late at night,
when he didn't have to play the normal notes.
And his music was made of notes
that were everything but normal.
What the hell do you think about
when you're playing?
Where does your mind go?
when you hit the keys?
Last night
I was in a beautiful country.
Women had perfume in their hair.
Everything glowed.
And it was full of tigers.
He traveled.
And each time he ended up someplace different.
In the heart of London,
on a train in the middle of the country,
on the edge of a giant volcano,
in the biggest church in the world,
counting the columns
and staring up at the crucifixes.
He travelled.
Guaglio', facci sentire una bella tarantella!
(Hey, man, play us a tarantella !)
E tu fammi capire come fa questa tarantella, paisa'!
(Tell me how the tarantella goes, man !)
The people getting off the ship
would talk about a strange music
and a pianist who looked like
he had four hands, for all the notes he was hit.
Weird tales circulated,
some even true.
Like the one about an American senator
named Wilson,
who used to travel in third class
just to hear the music of Danny Boodman
T.D. Lemon Nineteen Hundred.
America !
Why did you stop ?
Please, continue.
I'm sorry, Senator, it made port.
I only play on the open sea.
But that's absurd.
Ports are land to me.
I don't play on land.
You mean, you've never gone on tour?
What does that mean ?
Long trips on which artists display
their talents around the world.
In a sense, that's all I ever done.
In my way.
Excuse me.
Would you grant me an interview?
An inter. . .what ?
An interview?
What's that ?
The senator asks :
Is there anything you enjoy about
when you go back to your home town?"
Nineteen Hundred answered:
What I like to do best in Paris is....
wait under the Eiffeltower at sunset, for the people who throw themselves off the top
and try to guess what country
they're from by their screams
before they go splat
all over the ground !
Why the hell don't you get off?
Just once? One time?
See the world for yourself
with your own eyes?
You ever think about it?
You could do anything you wanted to.
People would go crazy for you.
You could make beaucoup bucks, man.
Get yourself the finest house,
Get yourself a wife.
Why not ?
God knows you can't spend the rest of your life
traveling back and forth like some yo-yo.
The world is out there.
Nothing but a gangplank to cross.
And what's a gangplank?
A few stupid steps.
Christ, everything is waiting
at the bottom of those steps.
Why don't you just do it?
One time.
Why don't you just get off?
Why? Why? Why?
Why? Why?
I think you land people
waste a lot of time wondering why.
Winter comes and
you can't wait for summer.
Summer comes and
you live in dread of winter.
That's way you never tire of traveling.
Always chasing someplace far away
where it's always summer.
Doesn't sound like a good bet to me.
Hold it, stop everything !
Tell them to lose the detonators.
Unhook them !
What's going on, boss?
If I were you, I'll pray hard we'll find somebody hidden on this paterost.
Even somebody who can mistake a three-legged cockroach for a piano.
It's like looking for a needle in a haystack.
Sir, i found it.
This was his cabin.
Forgive me for allowing myself to,
your music was so strong.
Northern ltaly, I'll bet.
Bravo, Friuli, to be exact.
But don't stop playing. suona.
Want a cicca?
You don't look too happy
to be going to America.
It's not America.
It's everything I leave behind.
Until a few years ago
I know only my field.
The world for me started and ended there
in that little piece of the land.
I never walked down
the main street of a city.
Maybe you can't understand, but....
I understand that perfectly.
I know someone
who went through something very similar.
And one fine day
did his field go dry, too?
And did his wife also run off with a priest?
And did the fever take his five children?
No. But he ended up alone, too.
Then he is more lucky than me
I still have a daughter.
The young one.
She survived.
And it's for her that I decide
one day to fight against my bad luck,
and travel all over without a destination.
And then one day, when I go through
one of the many towns I never see before,
I come to a hill,
And then I see...
the most beautiful thing in my life.
The sea !
The sea?
I never see it before.
It was like lightning hit me.
Because I hear the voice.
The voice of the sea?
Yeah, the voice of the sea.
I've never heard it.
The voice of the sea,
it is like a shout.
A shout big and strong,
screaming and screaming.
And the thing it was screaming was:
"You !
with shit instead brains!
life is immense,
can you understand that?
lmmense !"
I never think of it that way.
A revolution was in my head.
That's how I suddenly
decide to change my life,
to start fresh.
Change life. Start fresh.
Tell that to your friend.
1900!
It's Max Tooney, your friend.
Come on out, Nineteen Hundred!
I'm your friend, too.
Even if we've never met.
Don't worry, no cops !
You said something about a piano.
Where was it exactly?
We found it over there.
Nineteen Hundred !
Ladies and gentlemen,
Meine Damen und Herren,
Signore e signori,
Mesdames et Messieurs,
maestro Bill Douglas here,
welcoming you on board the Virginian.
wishing you a very pleasant evening
in the accompany of the Atlantic Jazz Band !
On the violin yours truly, Bill Douglas!
(The role's name should be Fritz Hermann)
Tuba and bass, Freddie Loyacano!
Max Tooney on trumpet!
Jim Jim Breath Gallup
on trombone !
Sam Scalisi on the drums !
On saxophone,
Sam Sleepy Washington !
On banjo,
Oscar Delaguerra !
And finally, on piano,
Danny Boodman T.D. Lemon Nineteen Hundred
The greatest !
For the last time Nineteen Hundred, just...
just the normal notes
What are you doing here ?
Take your places !
Hey, end of the line !
You've really got over me,
you son of a dirty stoker !
One night the public's not going to
appreciate your antics.
And that night, I swear,
I'm going to throw you overboard myself.
Where do yu get it?
What?
The music.
I don't know.
You see that woman over there?
for example?
She looks like someone
who's just killed her husband
with the help of her lover.
And now she's running off
with the family jewels.
Don't you think this music's her?
Damn, it's true!
You see that guy over there?
He can't forget a thing.
His head bursts with memories
and there's nothing he can do about it.
Listen to his music.
And look at that one there?
She looks like a prostitute
who's thinking of becoming a nun.
That's incredible!
Now, look at this one.
See how he walks?
I'd say he's in someone else's suit
judging by the way he wears it.
I'd say he's a stowaway slipped into first class
looking for an amorous adventure.
This one's got America stamped on his eyes.
He'll be the first one to see it.
l can already hear him screaming.
He knew how to read,
Nineteen Hundred.
Not books,
anybody can do that.
He knew how to read people,
the signs people carry on them.
Places, sounds, scents,
their land, their story.
Everything written on them.
He would read, and with infinite care
he would catalogue, organise,
and make order in that immense map
that he was drawing in his mind.
Maybe he'd never seen the world,
but for almost thirty years, the world
had been passing on that ship.
And for almost thirty years
on that ship, he'd been spying on it
and he would steal its soul.
America !
I went into her room,
she jumped on me,
- and I tore her clothes off.
- Go on !
- Do you always make up this crap ?
- Sure !
Singleton, Lee Claire.
Hallo ?
Hallo, you don't know me,
But I was wondering
if we could have a little chat
A little chat? What about?
About anything you like....
Weather conditions? anything you choose.
Anything You pick or chuck the subject.
Is this an obscene phone call?
Hallo ?
Hallo, is that the race-track ?
Yeah, you betting ?
Can you tell me if Mama's racing ?
No, it's your sister !
I think there's a misunderstanding.
You take you misunderstanding and shove it!
As I known, the telephone should
bring out the best in people.
You keep this up, I swear I'll come over there
and bring out the best in you.
you got still the time.
You think I don't know who you are!
Christ, he's already here !
Hey, You the fish
with the twenty-dollar name?
Come on out.
Shit!
Hey! You! Wait a minute!
Hey! Wait! Just want to talk to you!
Holy shit!
What hell are we, men?
Hold still, you little son of a bitch!
Come on out!
We don't want to hurt you.
We're players, man.
Sidemen.
Damn
Bon appetit ! (enjoy your meal)
You can that again, brother.
You can that again.
You the one that plays ten kinds
of jazz rolled into one?
Tell you the truth, I've never counted them
I'm just a piano player.
It's him.
Well, you would better start counting, buddy.
The man who invented jazz
sent us here.
Really? What does he want with me?
He challenges you to a piano duel!
A piano duel ?
What the hell is a piano duel ?
It's a duel,
but instead pistols of pianos.
It's a musicians thing.
No blood, just a little hate.
Real hate, under the skin.
It riffs like you never heard.
It could last all night sometimes,
at the end, one would win.
Nineteen Hundred !
If I were you, I wouldn't be so sure he's still here.
If I know him at all,
he won't be any place else.
I'm sure of that.
He's gone.
What would he
have done here without a piano ?
Everything has gone!
Besides, with the war, who knows ?
Maybe he's no longer part of this dirty world.
One like him
doesn't end up like everyone else.
It's not his style.
Think what you want.
But I can't ask the owners
to keep this carcass in the water
just because somebody on board
who doesn't exist.
I can't put it off much longer.
Nineteen Hundred, listen,
I have to talk to you !
And what about the duel?
What happened?
Jelly Roll Morton boarded the Virginian in Boston,
summer of 1931.
Dressed entirely in white,
had a diamond on his finger
as size as a meatball !
Even the garters on his socks
were diamond studded.
Jelly Roll, what's the reason
for a trip to Europe on a steamer?
when you've never set boat
that bigger than in Mississippi river.
I don't give a damn about Europe !
The only reason why I'm hopping this crappy tub
is because there's a gentleman I want to meet.
They say he plays a hot piano!
But I hear he has a little thing about setting foot on land.
Is he talking about me?
You bet, he's talking about you.
...He say,"Hey, Jelly,
Someone plays better piano than you."
So I say to myself:
Self how can this cat play so well
when he don't even have the balls
to get off the goddamn ship.
Hey, hot damn, Jelly,
You invented jazz!
Then I says to myself :
"you can afford a first-class ticket to Europe
and the boat that's going to take you just by lifting a finger."
Get a shot of it, boys, get a shot!
Tell the truth: Are you scared?
I don't know.
Why a duel?
What happens when you have a duel?
It seemed like he really didn't care much.
Like he didn't even understand it. But he was curious.
He wanted to hear how the devil, the inventor of jazz played.
He didn't say that is a joke. He really believed
that the guy invented jazz.
I believe he thought he can learn something new.
That's just how he was,
a little like old Danny.
He didn't have any sporting sense.
He didn't give a damn who won,
it was the rest that amazed him.
All the rest.
It's true !
I believe you're sitting in my seat.
You're the one who invented jazz, right?
That's what they say.
And you're the one who can't play unless
you have the ocean under your ass? right?
That's what I say.
Excusez-moi, s'il vous plait !
(Excuse me, please!)
Jelly Roll Morton did not play,
he caressed those notes.
It sounded like a silk slip
sliding down a woman's body.
His hands were butterflies, so light.
He got his start in the famed
tenderloin districts of New Orleans,
and all did he learn to stroke
the keyboard in those whorehouses.
People doing the deed upstairs didn't want any uproar.
They wanted music that would slip
behind the curtains, under the beds,
without disturbing the passion.
That's the kind of music he played.
And in that, he truly was the best.
- Bravo !
Your turn, sailor.
Come on.
What's he doing ?
"Silent Night"?
Isn't that a Christmas carol?
Does he understand it's a contest?
"Silenet Night" is jazz?
Is it Christmas already?
Did he win, signor?
No, they're just warming up.
Bravo !
Come on, Jelly Roll, show us what jazz is all about!
What is wrong with you?
I can't help it. Music makes me cry.
The whole crew bet on you!
I put a year's pay on the line!
And you're crying ?
Now you cut that out and start thinking your music!
Can I bet, too ?
No! It's bad luck to bet on yourself.
I don't want to bet on me. I want to bet on him. He's the greatest.
You are crazy, you know that?
That way, if you lose I'll get your money back.
It's exactly the same piece of music, darling.
Yeah, sure, it's OK. But this is a competition.
This is really the end of the line.
Unbelievable.
Did he lose, signor?
Not yet.
Bravo!
You stick this up your ass!
Hey, Max?
Give me a cigarette, will you?
You're not handling this well.
Just give me a cigarette.
You don't smoke.
What is the matter with you?
You could lick this guy with one hand!
Come on!
Pardon me, I didn't catch that.
I didn't say anything, signor.
Bravo !
Are you going to give me a cigarette?
We'll be chucking coal a couple hundred years, and all you can say is...
Give me a fucking cigarette, will you?
Clown !
You asked for it, asshole.
You smoke it.
I don't know how.
Well done !
Bravo !
You're the greatest !
Divine !
Did he win, signor?
Yes, he won.
I knew he would, signor!
Jelly Roll Morton spend the rest of
that trip locked in his cabin.
When we got to Southampton, he got off
the Virginian and went back to America.
I remember Nineteen Hundred watched
him as he walked off down the dock.
And all he said was:
Fuck jazz, too!
That's just what he said :
"Fuck jazz,too !"
This is an incredible story.
Did I miss anything important?
You couldn say that.
Damn !
Don't worry, our friend will fill you in later.
Won't you?
You can count on it.
Thanks.
He's really good at telling tales.
This is no tale, sir.
Yeah, I've done
lots of stupid things in my life.
If you were to hang me upside down
nothing would fall out my pockets.
I even sold my trumpet.
Everything !
But not this story,
I haven't lost that.
Now, I've decided to tell it
only because I want to save him.
But there's no-one here. Nobody !
Understand ?
It's because there are
too many of us, we've scared him.
I'm sorry. Now, you leave this ship
or I'll have to have you arrested.
Get back to work. Quickly !
Give me another chance.
Piss off, friend.
Noon tomorrow this ship is history!
And yet....
Here it is.
Stop or I'll shoot!
Gotcha.
Pops, easy, it's me.
You again? Is it.
Yes, lower that cannon, will you?
Sell your instrument and then steal it back, that's an old trick !
I should have known you're a thief.
No, I was looking for this.
And what do you need that for?
It's a matter of life and death.
And I need a phonograph, too.
A thief and a liar.
Look! Pops,
I don't have a whole lot of time here.
Well, I do! Seeing as I have a gun.
And now that I think of it, since when
were records made on board steamships?
Impostor !
If that music really was played by your friend,
it means that at some time in his life he got off that ship!
Correct?
Not a chance, Pops.
He cut this passionate recording personally.
I think it's his best work!
But he didn't jump ship to do it,
not even for a second.
It was an extraordinary, unique event
in the history of record-making.
The sky's the limit Mr. Nineteen Hundred.
If this record sells like hotcakes and we think it will,
you'll go far, Mr. Nineteen.
Do you mind if I call you Nineteen?
This is going to hurt, isn't it?
Ready now, gentelmen.
On the count.
And one, two, three.
Oh, Nineteen!
That is one amazing piece of music.
What is it called?
It's going to have people crying buckets.
It's got to have the right title though,
something catchy like....
"Swinging in the Breeze" or...
Great, as usual.
..."Sweet Nineteen," that's it...
You're going to be big time.
And all you got to do is take that big step.
What big step?
Getting off.
Getting off these lousy planks of wood and going after...
going after your fame and fortune.
I don't mean to butt in fellas, but...
with this, you can have anything you want
and never have to set foot off this boat.
We'll print millions of copies,
so that people all over the world
can hear your wonderful music, Nineteen.
Mr Nineteen ?
I won't let my music
go anywhere without me.
No! Don't touch.
What are you doing? You can't do that.
We have a contract.
You can't go back now.
I always go back.
Miss,
I'd be pleased if you...
Miss, I'd be...
I'd be thrilled...
if you'd accept this...
small token...
Hey, Miss Padoan, what are you doing
here all alone? Counting the waves?
The captain said we'd be passing
the Tropic of Cancer soon.
Great! At least we'll have
something to look at.
You ever notice how the sea changes colors? Ten times a day.
Even more.
I could look at the sea all day long.
You know farmers don't ever look at the sea.
It scares them At least that's what I heard.
That's not true.
Once, my father told me he heard the ocean's voice.
Really? What did it say?
I can't tell you. It's a secret.
And secrets should be kept.
Gosh, it's really coming down now.
Let's get back inside.
Come on !
Let me take your arm.
"Women's dormitory 3 class"
America
Damn it,
I wanted to say it !
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Please, miss.
I have to talk to you.
You're meeting your father, aren't you?
Yes.
How did you know?
I think I've met him.
On this ship,
quite a few years ago.
I don't know if he took this same ship.
I'm sure of it.
He has a musette. Yes?
I think we played together.
I don't know if he'd remember,
but...say hello to him.
All right, I will.
But how did you know who I was?
It's very strange, no?
It's a secret.
And secrets should be kept.
Although I think your father
felt differently back then.
Come on! Keep moving! Or we'll be here all week to discipline!
Please accept this...
small musical token.
I'm sorry, but I can't hear you.
I want you to...
accept this small token.
I can't hear you.
Good luck.
Thank you. Good luck to you, too.
Why don't you come and visit us some day?
We live on Mott Street. Number 27.
My father has a fish shop.
Maybe....
Padoan, okay. Next.
Next.
He never mentioned her to me again,
and I never asked.
At least not for
the next twelve crossings.
Besides, he was happy
just like always.
His popularity was at its peak.
None of us could have imagined what was smoldering beneath the ashes of his apparent happiness.
Then, one evening in spring,
halfway between Genoa and New York,
right in the middle of the ocean,
the painting fell.
What do you meaning ? The painting fell?
Pops, have you ever asked yourself
why paintings fall ?
No, not really.
I've always been impressed
by this thing about paintings.
What's the painting got to do with this ?
It does.
Because for Nineteen Hundred, that night
went the way it does for paintings.
They hang there for years, and then
without any happening...
Nothing at all...
Down that come.
They're hanging there on that nail,
no-body even touches them,
but at a certain point...
They fall down anyway,
in the most absolute silence.
With everything perfectly still
around them.
Not even a fly moving.
And they. . .
There's no reason.
Why in that instant ?
Who knows ?
What happens to a nail
to make it decide
that it just can't anymore ?
Does he have a soul, too,
poor thing ?
Does he make decisions ?
Sit down....
Did the nail discuss this at length
with the painting ?
They were unsure about doing it.
They talked it over every night for years ?
And then they decide on a date,
a time, a minute, a precise instant ?
Or they both know it from the beginning?
Both of them was already set up ?
"Look! I'm letting go in seven years."
"Fine with me."
"So understand, on May 13."
"Okay."
"At twelve o'clock?"
"How about twelve fifteen."
"OK."
"So good night."
Seven years later,
on May 13,
at twelve fifteen....
It's impossible to understand.
It's one of those things
that probably better not to think about !
Because it makes you nuts.
Paintings fall,
when you wake up one morning
and discover she doesn't love you anymore,
when you open a newspaper
and read that war has broken out,
when you see a train and
you think: I got to leave this place,
when you look in a mirror
and realise you're old.
When one evening, in the middle of the ocean,
Nineteen Hundred looks up from his plate,
looks me in the eyes and...
In three days when we get to New York,
I'm getting off this ship.
I was flabbergasted.
Cat got your tongue?
No,I'm glad.
But all of a sudden?
All of a sudden.
My man...
That's aces.
I've got to see something down there.
What ?
The ocean.
The ocean ?
You're pulling my leg ?
You've seen nothing but the ocean
since the day you were born.
But from here.
I want to see it from there.
It's not the same thing at all.
Wait till we dock, lean over the side,
take a good look.
It's the same thing.
No, it's not.
From land, you can hear its voice.
You don't hear that from a ship.
What do you mean, its voice?
Its voice.
It's like... a big scream...
telling you that life is immense.
Once you've finally heard it,
then you really know
what you have to do to go on living.
I could stay here forever,
but the ocean would never tell me a thing.
But if I get off, live on land for a couple of years,
then I'll be normal. Just like the others.
Then maybe one day,
I'll make it to the coast,
look up, see the ocean,
and hear it scream.
I don't know who's been telling you all this
bullshit or if you're just making it up.
But you want to know what I think?
I think...
the real reason you want off this ship is the girl.
It's always the girl.
But even if it's not the reason,
that suits me just fine.
Because I've always wanted you to leave this ship and play for the people on land.
And marry a nice woman and have children,
and all those things in life which are not immense
but are worth the effort.
You'll come visit me, won't you, Max? On land?
Of course.
That way, you'll introduce me
to the mother of your children,
and invite me for Sunday dinner.
I'll bring the dessert and a bottle of wine
and you'll tell me I shouldn't have.
And while you're showing me around
your house shaped like a ship,
your wife will be cooking a turkey.
And then we'll sit at the table.
And I'll tell her she's an excellent cook,
and she'll say how you
talk about me all the time.
You know,
I'm going to give you my camel coat.
You'll cut a fine figure
when you get down there.
You think I could have a family with a horse ?
- Nineteen Hundred !
- Hey !
How many people I have seen saying goodbye
on the docks without giving a damn.
But when I said goodbye to
Nineteen Hundred, it was a real blow.
Look after yourself, all right ?
Take care.
We laughed,
we kept saying "see you soon",
But inside, we both knew
we'd never see each other again.
And there was nothing we could do
about it, it had to happen that way.
And now it was happening.
How the hell we get off?
Goodbye, Nineteen Hundred, take care.
- Bye !
- Don't forget us.
Remember to wear your
woollen vest in winter.
Take care Nineteen Hundred, take care.
Write us a letter sometimes.
- Take care yourself!
- Give my regards to Broadway.
Good luck !
What'd he do, step in shit?
Maybe he just forgot something.
Maybe he's forgotten
why he's getting off.
What's he doing ?
Whatever he saw
from that damned gangplank,
what kind of thoughts
crossed his mind standing up there,
he never told me.
- No, go away !
- Wait !
I'll give you all the money I have,
take it.
He was strange for a long time after that.
He wouldn't talk to anyone.
He preferred keeping to
himself for days and days.
He seemed taken by very personal matters.
Then, one day,
while I was sitting at the bar...
Look!
Thanks for the coat, Max.
Fit like a glove.
It was a real shame.
I'm much better now.
I'm done with all that.
He looked like somebody
who wasn't kidding,
one who knew
exactly where he was going.
Like when he'd sit at the piano
and start to play.
There were no doubts in his hands.
It was as the keys had been
waiting for those notes forever.
It seemed like he'd made them up
then and there,
yet somewhere in his head, those
notes had been written all along.
Now, I know that on that day,
Nineteen Hundred had decided to sit before the keyboard of his life
and start playing his most absurd music.
And this music would have marked the rest of his days.
Look at that guy with the trumpet,
he's got be drunk or half crazy.
Look! He's crying as he plays!
I left the Virginian on
August 21st, 1933,
with my leave papers and back pay.
Everything in order.
I knew that sooner or later
I'd have been through with the ocean.
So that's what I did.
I heard no more about
Nineteen Hundred or the Virginian.
Not that I ever forgot them.
On the contrary.
During the war, I'd always ask myself...
Who knows what Nineteen Hundred
would do if he were here?
Who knows what he'd say?
Fuck war, he'd say.
But said by me,
it wasn't the same thing.
A lot of time's gone by, you know.
Who could say he really didn't leave?
Maybe one fine day, he went to Mott Street, the fish shop, to ask for the woman.
Maybe.
Hey, Conn, what's the matter?
You lose your sea legs?
Where the hell did you find that record ?
What have you been up to all these years ?
Making music.
Even during the war?
Even when no one was dancing anymore.
Even when the bombs were falling.
The music helped them get better.
The wounded, I mean.
Or else it kept them entertained,
as they slipped away into another world.
Sometimes they didn't even mind the voyage
if they could listen to the music.
Mine was the last face they saw.
And I kept playing
till the ship got here.
Call this a ship ?
It's more like a mountain of dynamite about to explode.
A bit dangerous, don't you think ?
And you, Max ?
Where's your trumpet?
I gave it up as well, a while back.
But, you know, now I'm in the
mood for starting again.
I'm busting with new ideas.
Let's start a duo,
you and me.
Or our own band :
The "Danny Boodman T.D. Lemon
Nineteen Hundred Big Band !"
It gets the blood going !
We'd be a smash.
Come on, Nineteen Hundred.
Come with me. Let's get off.
We'll watch the fireworks from the pier,
and then we'll start from scratch.
Sometimes that's the way you have to do it.
You go right back to the beginning.
"You're never really done for
as long as you've got a good story
and someone to tell it to".
Remember?
You told me that.
Well, what a stack of stories you got now!
The world would be hanging
on your every word,
and they'd go crazy for your music.
Believe me.
All that city. . .
You just couldn't see an end to it.
The end !
please?
You please just show me where it ends?
It was all very fine
on that gangway
and I was grand, too,
in my overcoat.
I cut quite a figure.
And I was getting off, Guaranteed.
That's wasn't the problem.
It wasn't what I saw that stopped me, Max.
It was what I didn't see.
Can you understand that ?
What I didn't see.
In all that srawling city,
there was everything except an end.
There was no end.
What I did not see was
where the whole thing came to an end,
the end of the world.
You take a piano.
Keys begin, the keys end.
You know there are 88 of them,
nobody can tell you any different.
They are not infinite,
you are infinite.
And on those keys, the music that you can make is infinite.
I like that.
That I can live by.
You get me up on that gangway
and you roll out in front of me
a keyboard of millions and billions of keys that never end.
And that's the truth, Max,
that they never end.
That keyboard is infinite.
And if that keyboard is infinite,
then on that keyboard there is no music you can play.
You're sitting on the wrong bench.
That's God's piano.
Christ, did you see the streets? Just the streets.
There were thousands of them.
How do you do it down there?
How do you choose just one?
One woman, one house,
one piece of land to call your own,
one landscape to look at,
one way to die.
All that world just weighing down on you.
You don't even know where it comes to an end.
I mean, aren't you ever just scared of breaking apart at the thought of it?
At the enormity of living it?
I was born on this ship.
And the world passed me by,
but two thousand people at a time.
And there were wishes here,
but never more than fit between prow and stern.
You played out your happiness
on a piano that was not infinite.
I learned to live that way.
Land?
Land is a ship too big for me.
It's a woman too beautiful.
It's a voyage too long.
Perfume too strong.
It's music I don't know how to make.
I could never get off this ship.
At best, I can step off my life.
After all, I don't exist for anyone.
You're the exception, Max.
You're the only one
who knows that I'm here.
You're a minority.
And you'd better get used to it.
Forgive me, my friend.
But I'm not getting off.
Hey, Max.
Picture the scene at the Golden Gates.
Some guy searching a list trying to find my name, not finding it.
What did you say your name was again?
Nineteen Hundred.
Niemann, Nightingale, Ninestock...
Nittledeen?
Well, you see, sir. I was born on a ship.
Beg your pardon?
Born, raised, and died on a ship.
Maybe I'm not registered there.
Yeah, Shipwreck ?
No, six and a half tons of dynamite.
Feeling better now?
Yeah, I'm fine, except I lost an arm.
An arm ?
Yes, in the explosion.
Well, you should be able to find one over there.
Which one did you say you were missing?
Left, sir.
I'm dreadfully sorry.
We only seem to have two rights.
Two right arms?
Yes.
Afraid so.
Would you mind awfully if....
If I what?
Well, if you take a right arm instead of a left?
Well, all things considered, a right arm than nothing, I suppose.
Couldn't agree more.
By the way, we have one black arm
and one white arm.
Oh, no.... matching color, please.
I have nothing against the other race,
but it's just a question of aesthetics.
No laughing matter, Max.
What a cock-up, Spend eternity with two right arms?
I mean, how would you make the sign of the cross?
Hey, Max.
Imagine the music I could play with two right arms.
Hope I can find a piano up there.
Okay, that's fine like that.
- Slowly.
- Get hold of it there.
What would you have done in my shoes?
I don't know.
I wouldn't probably have felt quite useless.
Sooner or later all stories end,
and there's nothing left to add.
Anyhow, thanks, pops.
Conn, there's just one thing I don't get.
Who hid the broken record inside the piano?
You're looking at him.
So you weren't so useless after all.
Conn.
Here.
Take your trumpet.
Well, you'll be needing it.
But I....
Never mind the money.
A good story's worth more than an old trumpet.
Okay, Pops.
La Leggenda Del Pianista Sull'oceano
Giuseppe Tornatore