1
00:02:49,587 --> 00:02:52,756
Carter, what d'you reckon?
Nice bit of glass, eh?

2
00:02:54,633 --> 00:02:56,552
Yeah, it's a nice ring.

3
00:02:56,635 --> 00:02:59,013
Just don't feel the same way about you,
Miller. Sorry, mate.

4
00:02:59,096 --> 00:03:01,223
Yeah, it's for Sue.
Cost me two months' wages.

5
00:03:01,307 --> 00:03:03,517
I'm gonna pop the question.

6
00:03:03,601 --> 00:03:07,479
- Oh, Miller.
- What's up? I thought you'd be happy.

7
00:03:07,563 --> 00:03:10,024
Problem is she's a six out of ten, man.

8
00:03:10,107 --> 00:03:11,859
- Right, Sim?
- Yeah, a six.

9
00:03:11,942 --> 00:03:13,694
Six and a half.
And I'm being generous there, mate.

10
00:03:13,777 --> 00:03:14,778
You what?

11
00:03:14,862 --> 00:03:18,240
If you're gonna tie the knot with someone,
make sure they're a nine or a three.

12
00:03:18,324 --> 00:03:21,327
A stunner or a complete shitter.

13
00:03:21,952 --> 00:03:26,332
If you fall in the middle you're fucked, mate.
It's never gonna last.

14
00:03:26,415 --> 00:03:30,461
- That's bollocks, man.
- I'm talking bollocks, yeah?

15
00:03:30,544 --> 00:03:34,298
All right, we'll ask the others.
Oi, text Clarkey. Ask her.

16
00:03:42,431 --> 00:03:44,725
MAN: Back up, back up! Go!

17
00:03:55,152 --> 00:03:58,364
- Everyone on the floor now!
- Don't move!

18
00:03:59,448 --> 00:04:01,408
You, move over in there!

19
00:04:01,492 --> 00:04:04,536
- Get over to the wall!
- Get on the floor!

20
00:04:04,620 --> 00:04:06,372
Don't fucking look at me!
Keep your hands high!

21
00:04:06,455 --> 00:04:08,415
You, get over here!

22
00:04:08,499 --> 00:04:11,085
(SHOUTING CONTINUES)

23
00:04:11,168 --> 00:04:13,462
Look at the fucking floor!

24
00:04:15,673 --> 00:04:17,591
Sixty seconds.

25
00:04:18,676 --> 00:04:19,969
Look at that gold!

26
00:04:24,515 --> 00:04:29,270
Got a text from Carter.
Wants us to score Miller's girlfriend out of 10.

27
00:04:29,353 --> 00:04:30,562
Don't know. I ain't slept with her.

28
00:04:30,646 --> 00:04:32,773
Oi! It's based on looks.

29
00:04:32,856 --> 00:04:34,942
Four and a half in a balaclava.

30
00:04:35,025 --> 00:04:38,028
- What about you, Lewis?
- Don't know her.

31
00:04:38,696 --> 00:04:41,365
What about me, then?
What would you rate me?

32
00:04:41,448 --> 00:04:47,121
Well, if it was prick size I'd give you a two,
but since we're talking about faces,

33
00:04:47,204 --> 00:04:49,206
I'll give you a two.

34
00:04:51,834 --> 00:04:53,127
Thirty seconds!

35
00:04:53,210 --> 00:04:55,212
Stay down there!

36
00:04:55,296 --> 00:04:57,381
- (PHONE BEEPS)
- Ah.

37
00:04:58,090 --> 00:04:59,508
Average.

38
00:04:59,591 --> 00:05:01,343
- Average?
- Yep.

39
00:05:01,427 --> 00:05:02,970
Not low enough to be grateful to you

40
00:05:03,053 --> 00:05:06,473
and not high enough
to make you grateful to her.

41
00:05:06,557 --> 00:05:08,434
Fucking recipe for disaster.

42
00:05:08,517 --> 00:05:10,853
What about your girl then?
What does she score?

43
00:05:10,936 --> 00:05:13,022
We're not married.

44
00:05:17,067 --> 00:05:19,111
(BRAKES SQUEAL)

45
00:05:20,988 --> 00:05:23,907
- Armed police!
- Police! Get on the floor!

46
00:05:23,991 --> 00:05:25,868
(SHOUTING)

47
00:05:28,329 --> 00:05:30,456
Can you get out of the car for me?

48
00:05:30,539 --> 00:05:32,416
Get out of the fucking car now!

49
00:05:32,499 --> 00:05:34,877
You all right, Miller?

50
00:05:37,379 --> 00:05:40,341
Armed police! Get on the fucking floor!

51
00:05:47,890 --> 00:05:49,516
Come here!

52
00:05:55,981 --> 00:05:57,232
Oi!

53
00:05:58,859 --> 00:06:01,278
- You Okay?
"Yeah, 90, go, go.

54
00:06:02,071 --> 00:06:05,032
- Get on your fucking front!
- Come here!

55
00:06:05,491 --> 00:06:08,702
Don't move! On your front, yeah?
Don't fucking move!

56
00:06:08,786 --> 00:06:10,579
Get over here now!

57
00:06:36,980 --> 00:06:38,399
Fuck!

58
00:06:39,650 --> 00:06:41,151
(GRUNTS)

59
00:07:02,047 --> 00:07:05,050
We're the Sweeney, shithead. You're nicked.

60
00:07:11,390 --> 00:07:13,183
(LOW CHATTER)

61
00:07:13,267 --> 00:07:15,436
Yeah, nice work, Regan.

62
00:07:15,519 --> 00:07:17,896
But did you really have to
destroy the whole place in the process?

63
00:07:17,980 --> 00:07:19,314
We got the villains, didn't we?

64
00:07:19,398 --> 00:07:21,942
Well, I got the headache of explaining
why you smashed their heads in

65
00:07:22,025 --> 00:07:24,528
and wrecked the whole depot.

66
00:07:25,863 --> 00:07:27,656
You know we'll have Internal Affairs
on our back again.

67
00:07:27,739 --> 00:07:30,033
We got the villains, didn't we?

68
00:07:30,117 --> 00:07:32,703
Shit always rolls downhill, Jack, to me.

69
00:07:32,786 --> 00:07:34,079
Yeah, well, I'm sorry about the mess,

70
00:07:34,163 --> 00:07:36,498
but there just happened to be
an armed robbery in progress.

71
00:07:36,582 --> 00:07:39,668
Listen, if we wanna stay operational,
we gotta play the game.

72
00:07:39,751 --> 00:07:43,881
It ain't a game when you've got a G3
sticking in the back of your nut.

73
00:07:43,964 --> 00:07:47,134
You get Internal Affairs off my fucking case
and I'll get you results.

74
00:07:47,217 --> 00:07:50,137
Oi!
Remember who runs this unit, Jack, all right?

75
00:07:50,220 --> 00:07:52,097
Yeah, well, you know how we go to work.
Deal with it.

76
00:07:52,181 --> 00:07:54,057
Yeah, who put it all together
in the first place?

77
00:07:54,141 --> 00:07:55,309
(POLICE SIREN WAILS)

78
00:07:55,392 --> 00:07:58,187
- Who keeps the wolves from your door?
- Yeah, all right.

79
00:07:58,270 --> 00:08:00,397
- Well done, kid.
- All right.

80
00:08:02,733 --> 00:08:04,735
What was the estimate?

81
00:08:04,818 --> 00:08:08,655
Half a mill plus. Krugerrands and ingots.

82
00:08:09,573 --> 00:08:10,782
Everyone's okay?

83
00:08:10,866 --> 00:08:14,578
Yeah, Miller took one,
but he'll live to fight another day.

84
00:08:15,996 --> 00:08:19,249
The world's running out
of men like you, Jack.

85
00:08:27,758 --> 00:08:29,843
(LAUGHTER)

86
00:08:33,722 --> 00:08:35,933
Yeah, yeah, fuck you!

87
00:08:40,938 --> 00:08:45,150
Hey, a toast. A toast to the new boy.
Popped his cherry on the pavement!

88
00:08:45,234 --> 00:08:47,069
Raise a fucking glass.

89
00:08:47,152 --> 00:08:49,530
- Go on, the Sweeney!
- Go on, Paddy.

90
00:08:49,613 --> 00:08:52,950
Yeah, yeah, and maybe next time
Regan will give you a weapon to hold!

91
00:08:53,033 --> 00:08:54,576
Fuck that.

92
00:08:55,494 --> 00:08:57,746
I became a copper because I'm Irish.

93
00:08:57,829 --> 00:08:59,039
(LAUGHTER)

94
00:08:59,122 --> 00:09:02,834
All right, well, I became a copper
because I'm black.

95
00:09:04,419 --> 00:09:08,840
- What about you, Wex?
- I become a copper 'cause I'm black!

96
00:09:08,924 --> 00:09:10,217
What about you, pretty boy?

97
00:09:10,300 --> 00:09:11,552
As pretty as my face is,

98
00:09:11,635 --> 00:09:14,429
I obviously don't give a fuck about it
that much, as you can see.

99
00:09:14,513 --> 00:09:16,640
As far as I'm concerned,
there ain't any other job in the world

100
00:09:16,723 --> 00:09:18,767
that gives me the kind of buzz this one does.

101
00:09:18,850 --> 00:09:20,435
Good boy.

102
00:09:21,228 --> 00:09:24,982
So if this pretty little face of mine has to take
a couple more beatings from time to time,

103
00:09:25,065 --> 00:09:26,650
so fucking be it, right, Sim?

104
00:09:26,733 --> 00:09:28,235
Got you, boy.

105
00:09:28,318 --> 00:09:30,946
- To Carter's face!
- ALL: To Carter's face!

106
00:09:31,029 --> 00:09:33,240
It's an improvement on when you left
the house this morning, darling.

107
00:09:33,323 --> 00:09:35,367
Yeah? Yeah?

108
00:09:35,450 --> 00:09:39,288
I'm only kidding.
You're better looking than this lot!

109
00:10:12,362 --> 00:10:15,824
- When you gonna leave him?
- When you gonna ask me?

110
00:10:17,200 --> 00:10:20,495
I don't like the fact you go home and fuck him.

111
00:10:21,580 --> 00:10:24,041
I haven't fucked him in over a year,
you know that.

112
00:10:24,124 --> 00:10:25,626
Please.

113
00:10:28,211 --> 00:10:30,714
He hasn't made me laugh in over two.

114
00:10:34,384 --> 00:10:36,094
(MOBILE BUZZES)

115
00:10:48,148 --> 00:10:50,233
- Duty calls.
- Yeah.

116
00:10:51,443 --> 00:10:53,362
It always does.

117
00:11:13,590 --> 00:11:15,550
All right, Harry?

118
00:11:16,718 --> 00:11:19,930
- How's your luck?
- Okay. Yourself?

119
00:11:20,013 --> 00:11:22,474
Well, still in with a shot.

120
00:11:25,936 --> 00:11:28,980
- How's your leg?
- Still giving me agg.

121
00:11:29,064 --> 00:11:30,607
(CLINKING)

122
00:11:34,778 --> 00:11:36,321
I hear the work went off well?

123
00:11:36,405 --> 00:11:39,950
Yeah, it was just like you said,
almost fell in our laps.

124
00:11:40,033 --> 00:11:42,119
Word is, one of them got a good hiding.

125
00:11:42,202 --> 00:11:44,454
(LAUGHS) George did it.

126
00:11:48,750 --> 00:11:50,961
Have you got anything else for me?

127
00:11:51,044 --> 00:11:53,547
Heard about a private bank
on Trafalgar Square?

128
00:11:53,630 --> 00:11:56,299
Apparently it's being looked at.

129
00:11:57,426 --> 00:12:00,053
Nah. No one's that fucking silly any more.

130
00:12:00,137 --> 00:12:02,180
They say it's a sitting duck.

131
00:12:02,264 --> 00:12:04,433
I'll swing past it tomorrow with George.

132
00:12:04,516 --> 00:12:06,435
How is he?

133
00:12:06,518 --> 00:12:09,312
Who, George? George is George, isn't he?

134
00:12:10,147 --> 00:12:12,149
What about you, Jack?
Seeing anyone special?

135
00:12:12,232 --> 00:12:14,776
Schtum. What's the matter with you?

136
00:12:15,485 --> 00:12:18,155
You're getting a nosy old bastard.

137
00:12:20,490 --> 00:12:24,745
I'd better get back in there.
Make sure Carter's behaving himself.

138
00:12:30,375 --> 00:12:32,169
REGAN: Sweeney!

139
00:12:34,421 --> 00:12:37,966
Sweeney! Sweeney!

140
00:12:38,049 --> 00:12:40,761
Sweeney! Sweeney!

141
00:12:46,475 --> 00:12:48,143
(SNORING)

142
00:12:58,361 --> 00:13:01,323
- Uncle Jack, what are you doing?
- What are you doing?

143
00:13:01,406 --> 00:13:03,617
Looking for a cigarette.

144
00:13:05,035 --> 00:13:06,787
Give us one.

145
00:13:09,915 --> 00:13:11,416
Ta.

146
00:13:12,000 --> 00:13:15,170
- Anyway, you shouldn't be smoking.
- Why?

147
00:13:15,253 --> 00:13:17,798
Because you're training for your sports day.

148
00:13:17,881 --> 00:13:19,674
Looks like you should be in training as well.

149
00:13:19,758 --> 00:13:21,968
Saucy little sod. Go on.

150
00:13:23,595 --> 00:13:26,807
And don't listen to George,
he's a bad influence.

151
00:13:26,890 --> 00:13:30,143
Are you listening, Neil?
Your stepdad's a bad seed.

152
00:13:30,227 --> 00:13:32,604
You can talk, can't you, mate?

153
00:13:33,480 --> 00:13:34,981
(GROANS)

154
00:13:35,690 --> 00:13:37,317
Very romantic, toilets.

155
00:13:37,400 --> 00:13:39,402
God, is that the time?

156
00:13:39,486 --> 00:13:41,738
- We gotta go.
- When was you gonna tell me?

157
00:13:41,822 --> 00:13:45,826
We've gotta flop on thatjug
that Harry was talking about.

158
00:13:45,909 --> 00:13:49,830
- How long you been banging her for, Jack?
- And Haskins has called for a briefing.

159
00:13:49,913 --> 00:13:52,499
You do know she's married, don't you?

160
00:13:55,836 --> 00:13:59,589
I've known you half my life
and you didn't think to tell me?

161
00:14:02,175 --> 00:14:03,635
What you don't know won't kill you.

162
00:14:08,098 --> 00:14:11,768
- Do you know her husband?
- Yeah, we knock about together, don't we?

163
00:14:11,852 --> 00:14:14,437
- I mean, do you know who he is?
- Armchair Old Bill.

164
00:14:14,521 --> 00:14:15,814
And he knows about you and her?

165
00:14:15,897 --> 00:14:18,483
What? Me banging her?
Yeah. Thinks it's a great idea.

166
00:14:18,567 --> 00:14:19,860
Nice bloke, then?

167
00:14:19,943 --> 00:14:22,529
- Couldn't roll downhill.
- He what?

168
00:14:22,612 --> 00:14:24,531
He's a fucking square!

169
00:14:24,614 --> 00:14:28,618
Right. You've got 30 seconds
to tell me how you'd rob this bank.

170
00:14:31,872 --> 00:14:35,208
I wouldn't worry about the CCTV
'cause they don't feed out externally.

171
00:14:35,292 --> 00:14:37,627
Getting your hands on a tape
shouldn't be a problem.

172
00:14:37,711 --> 00:14:40,881
It's a private bank, innit? Private security.

173
00:14:40,964 --> 00:14:42,924
And this lot ain't got a license
to carry firearms,

174
00:14:43,008 --> 00:14:45,427
so, what? Pistols and cable ties
would keep them quiet.

175
00:14:45,510 --> 00:14:47,679
Driver out the front,
two to three through the door,

176
00:14:47,762 --> 00:14:50,056
neutralise the desk clerk, dominate the room

177
00:14:50,140 --> 00:14:51,683
and disorientate the security.

178
00:14:51,766 --> 00:14:53,226
You'll need one geezer to hold the floor,

179
00:14:53,310 --> 00:14:55,395
while the other two take the lift
up to the strong room.

180
00:14:55,478 --> 00:14:59,024
But only after collecting all mobiles
and depositing them over there.

181
00:14:59,107 --> 00:15:01,401
Got London Underground
situated conveniently close by.

182
00:15:01,484 --> 00:15:06,823
Again, if it all goes tits up out the front,
I'd definitely use that as a possible route.

183
00:15:07,449 --> 00:15:11,453
As for the loot,
I'd settle on any high-denomination bills.

184
00:15:12,829 --> 00:15:16,499
Nice to see you learnt something
in your childhood, George.

185
00:15:16,666 --> 00:15:20,086
Yeah, well, you gotta act like a criminal
to catch one, don't you?

186
00:15:20,170 --> 00:15:21,212
(CHUCKLES)

187
00:15:21,296 --> 00:15:24,257
Officers, Mr. Bledisloe is here to see you.

188
00:15:24,341 --> 00:15:27,802
- I'd much rather talk to you.
- Unlikely.

189
00:15:27,886 --> 00:15:29,387
What about me?

190
00:15:35,101 --> 00:15:36,937
Regan. Flying Squad_

191
00:15:37,020 --> 00:15:40,774
Just a routine check.
What do you actually do here?

192
00:15:40,857 --> 00:15:42,442
I'm the manager.

193
00:15:42,525 --> 00:15:44,986
No, I mean, what does the bank do?

194
00:15:45,612 --> 00:15:47,656
We're a private clearing bank.

195
00:15:47,739 --> 00:15:52,702
We hold large amounts of foreign currency
for mostly Middle Eastern clients.

196
00:15:53,453 --> 00:15:56,081
We work with Abu Dhabi, Qatar, Dubai...

197
00:15:56,164 --> 00:15:57,457
How large?

198
00:15:57,540 --> 00:16:00,794
On the right day and the right week,
up to 10 million in cash.

199
00:16:00,877 --> 00:16:02,629
And you ain't got proper security?

200
00:16:02,712 --> 00:16:04,297
- Yes, we do.
- No, you ain't.

201
00:16:04,381 --> 00:16:07,050
They'd shit theirself
with a 9-mil in the back of the canister.

202
00:16:07,133 --> 00:16:08,301
We're not a High Street bank.

203
00:16:08,385 --> 00:16:11,805
If you was, there'd be a blag here every week.

204
00:16:11,888 --> 00:16:14,140
And who's intending to "blag" us?

205
00:16:14,224 --> 00:16:17,102
As I said, this is just a routine check.

206
00:16:17,185 --> 00:16:21,314
We tend not to invite police in the bank
too often, it can unnerve the staff.

207
00:16:21,398 --> 00:16:23,066
No one invited us.

208
00:16:24,734 --> 00:16:27,904
Very well, if there's nothing else...

209
00:16:30,365 --> 00:16:31,908
What a cunt!

210
00:16:31,992 --> 00:16:33,576
- I like him.
- You would.

211
00:16:33,660 --> 00:16:35,662
- He's got panache.
- (SCOFFS)

212
00:16:35,745 --> 00:16:37,831
Oi. You want me to stick someone on here
and watch it?

213
00:16:37,914 --> 00:16:40,917
Yeah, Wextru.
He likes sitting on his arse doing nothing.

214
00:16:53,638 --> 00:16:54,973
(BEEPS)

215
00:16:57,475 --> 00:16:59,436
Hello. Hello, hello.

216
00:16:59,519 --> 00:17:01,938
- Jack.
- Jack.

217
00:17:04,816 --> 00:17:06,693
How's it going, Lewis?

218
00:17:07,652 --> 00:17:09,779
How's life at the sharp end?

219
00:17:10,613 --> 00:17:15,160
Must be run off your feet catching all them
criminals from behind the desk.

220
00:17:16,453 --> 00:17:19,914
I don't need to be on the streets
to make arrests, Jack.

221
00:17:19,998 --> 00:17:23,251
There's an abundance of criminals
amongst the police keeping me busy,

222
00:17:23,334 --> 00:17:24,836
you know that.

223
00:17:25,295 --> 00:17:27,964
- Tiring work, is it?
- (LIFT BELL PINGS)

224
00:17:41,269 --> 00:17:42,896
(LIFT BELL PINGS)

225
00:17:45,732 --> 00:17:47,484
Excuse me, yeah?

226
00:17:48,985 --> 00:17:50,403
Bye for now.

227
00:17:52,822 --> 00:17:54,407
(WHISPERS) Wanker.

228
00:17:55,408 --> 00:17:57,744
Grow up, Jack. He's not stupid.

229
00:17:59,329 --> 00:18:01,206
Don't give him a reason to look up your skirt.

230
00:18:01,289 --> 00:18:04,459
As long as he ain't looking up your skirt.

231
00:18:19,015 --> 00:18:20,266
Come on.

232
00:18:24,062 --> 00:18:25,814
(LIFT BELL PINGS)

233
00:18:29,484 --> 00:18:30,735
You go left and I'll go right.

234
00:18:30,819 --> 00:18:34,989
We wouldn't want anyone to think
we're banging each other, would we?

235
00:18:38,493 --> 00:18:40,870
- Aye, aye.
- ELLIS: All right, guv?

236
00:18:41,621 --> 00:18:43,289
- What you got?
- Sign.

237
00:18:43,373 --> 00:18:44,958
Lovely.

238
00:18:45,041 --> 00:18:47,627
Me and Regan went down to QTZ today.

239
00:18:47,710 --> 00:18:49,295
What's QTZ?

240
00:18:49,379 --> 00:18:52,799
- It's a private bank in Trafalgar Square.
- Never heard of it.

241
00:18:52,882 --> 00:18:56,136
The reason you've never heard about it
before is 'cause it's private.

242
00:18:56,219 --> 00:18:57,387
Funny.

243
00:18:57,470 --> 00:19:01,599
Anyway, Regan wants you to go down there
and put the place under observation.

244
00:19:01,683 --> 00:19:03,476
- Why me?
'WhY "Of you?

245
00:19:12,277 --> 00:19:13,903
Morning, Sweeney.

246
00:19:16,072 --> 00:19:18,700
Good job yesterday. Top drawer.

247
00:19:20,076 --> 00:19:21,578
Got a friend with me here today.

248
00:19:21,661 --> 00:19:26,499
I know it's hard enough what we do
without being observed as we do it,

249
00:19:26,583 --> 00:19:28,084
nevertheless,

250
00:19:28,168 --> 00:19:32,255
I'd like you to give a warm welcome
to Detective Ivan Lewis from Internals,

251
00:19:32,338 --> 00:19:35,175
who I know some of you already know.

252
00:19:35,258 --> 00:19:38,428
So no larking about.
Give him what he needs, okay?

253
00:19:38,845 --> 00:19:40,430
Thanks, Haskins.

254
00:19:41,222 --> 00:19:44,642
- Jack, nice to see you again.
- How you going?

255
00:19:44,726 --> 00:19:48,771
I'll make this brief.
I'm not here looking for scalps.

256
00:19:49,772 --> 00:19:53,902
All right? I'm not here to shut you down.
I'm just here to observe.

257
00:19:54,652 --> 00:19:59,199
Observe how you operate and, if need be,
suggest some adjustments to your approach

258
00:19:59,282 --> 00:20:02,493
and maybe make some recommendations
of how to improve,

259
00:20:02,577 --> 00:20:04,704
enhance the unit's success rate.

260
00:20:04,787 --> 00:20:06,331
Success rate?

261
00:20:06,414 --> 00:20:10,543
We've just taken out an armed robbery
with no civilian casualties.

262
00:20:10,627 --> 00:20:13,713
The week before that, a security van attempt.

263
00:20:13,796 --> 00:20:15,340
And all suspects are in custody.

264
00:20:15,423 --> 00:20:18,051
Now, have you got a problem with that?

265
00:20:18,718 --> 00:20:20,345
- No, Jack.
- Good.

266
00:20:21,721 --> 00:20:26,184
Oh, and by the way, um,
people who don't know me call me Regan.

267
00:20:29,187 --> 00:20:30,897
(STIFLED LAUGHTER)

268
00:20:31,689 --> 00:20:33,274
The problem...

269
00:20:34,067 --> 00:20:38,363
The problem is
the significant number of legal cases

270
00:20:38,446 --> 00:20:40,907
that's mounting against your unit.

271
00:20:40,990 --> 00:20:45,912
And these exclusive
and, frankly, exorbitant Sweeney offices

272
00:20:45,995 --> 00:20:48,998
- funded by the tax payer with...
- it's the tax payer we look after.

273
00:20:49,082 --> 00:20:51,542
It causes resentment
in other departments, you know?

274
00:20:51,626 --> 00:20:54,420
- Oh, fuck!
- The problem is the, er...

275
00:20:55,338 --> 00:20:59,092
Methods and tactics you employ.

276
00:20:59,175 --> 00:21:02,053
I mean, there's even talk of baseball bats.

277
00:21:02,845 --> 00:21:06,307
Pick axe handles being used
to attack suspects.

278
00:21:06,391 --> 00:21:11,020
The problem is the collateral damage
that's left in your wake...

279
00:21:11,104 --> 00:21:14,440
The problem is people like you
that don't let us do our fucking job.

280
00:21:14,524 --> 00:21:17,860
- Easy, Jack.
- Oh, I'm being fucking easy here.

281
00:21:19,570 --> 00:21:21,990
Carter, your lot supposed to be somewhere?

282
00:21:22,073 --> 00:21:24,158
Combat training, sir.

283
00:21:24,784 --> 00:21:26,869
Give me five, will ya?

284
00:21:29,414 --> 00:21:31,416
Don't go too far, George.

285
00:21:38,423 --> 00:21:39,549
So what is it then, Lewis?

286
00:21:39,632 --> 00:21:41,134
What do you want to see?
Your name up in lights,

287
00:21:41,217 --> 00:21:43,428
with a medal pinned on you
for bringing down the Flying Squad?

288
00:21:43,511 --> 00:21:45,138
Regan. Leave it.

289
00:21:45,221 --> 00:21:46,889
Yeah, all right.

290
00:21:47,390 --> 00:21:48,641
What are you like?

291
00:21:48,725 --> 00:21:51,686
You wanna be the little man
that brought down the Sweeney?

292
00:21:51,769 --> 00:21:55,898
Is that it? It's people like you
who want to make us obsolete.

293
00:21:55,982 --> 00:21:59,986
'Cause we still do the things
that you can only fucking dream of.

294
00:22:03,114 --> 00:22:05,325
Now, do you wanna take us on?

295
00:22:06,117 --> 00:22:09,787
Well, you can have a go.
I mean, other people have had a go.

296
00:22:09,871 --> 00:22:11,789
Have you got big bollocks?

297
00:22:11,873 --> 00:22:15,710
Have you? You got big fucking nuts?
Let's have a look at them.

298
00:22:18,588 --> 00:22:20,715
No, I don't think you have.

299
00:22:26,429 --> 00:22:28,431
Tell me something, Lewis.

300
00:22:29,932 --> 00:22:32,685
Is your problem with the job or with me?

301
00:22:41,736 --> 00:22:43,029
The job.

302
00:22:43,738 --> 00:22:48,117
It transpires that some of these ingots
went missing from a crime scene.

303
00:22:48,618 --> 00:22:53,915
It's also emerged that
everybody but the Sweeney was searched.

304
00:22:54,916 --> 00:22:56,167
So what?

305
00:22:56,250 --> 00:23:00,046
Tip of an already melting iceberg.

306
00:23:02,757 --> 00:23:05,468
I work on the front line, son. Eh?

307
00:23:06,469 --> 00:23:08,513
Criminals I hunt want me dead.

308
00:23:08,596 --> 00:23:13,434
Day in and day out, I'm undermanned,
under-armed and underpaid.

309
00:23:15,520 --> 00:23:20,108
I fight crime on the street, not from
behind a fucking desk where I can hide.

310
00:23:20,191 --> 00:23:25,530
So do something useful, Lewis,
like catch real fucking criminals.

311
00:23:35,498 --> 00:23:36,666
Regan?

312
00:23:40,378 --> 00:23:42,505
Everyone's got a weak point.

313
00:24:16,038 --> 00:24:19,292
- Everyone on the floor!
- WOMAN: Put me down!

314
00:24:29,886 --> 00:24:30,970
(TICKING)

315
00:24:31,095 --> 00:24:32,763
(WOMAN SCREAMS)

316
00:24:54,368 --> 00:24:56,370
(WHIRRING)

317
00:24:57,538 --> 00:25:01,000
Run, Neil. Run, you little bastard!

318
00:25:01,083 --> 00:25:02,168
Sorry.

319
00:25:18,059 --> 00:25:20,061
(MUFFLED SPEECH)

320
00:25:25,441 --> 00:25:27,109
(ALARM RINGING)

321
00:25:29,153 --> 00:25:32,114
Yes! Fucking number one!

322
00:25:32,782 --> 00:25:34,867
Go on, Neil!

323
00:25:36,494 --> 00:25:37,620
Knock yourself out.

324
00:26:00,393 --> 00:26:02,144
You nasty bastard.

325
00:26:17,994 --> 00:26:19,996
- Any luck, John?
- Nothing.

326
00:26:20,079 --> 00:26:22,164
Well, I need something.

327
00:26:23,583 --> 00:26:26,294
- A little unnecessary, wasn't it?
- Yeah.

328
00:26:26,711 --> 00:26:30,381
- What are you thinking?
- I'm thinking Italian tonight.

329
00:26:31,924 --> 00:26:35,678
- What about this mess? Where do you start?
- I'd ignore that.

330
00:26:36,470 --> 00:26:38,598
The getaway car already found
out by Heathrow.

331
00:26:38,681 --> 00:26:41,142
- Yeah.
- it was torched using phosphorus.

332
00:26:41,225 --> 00:26:43,269
It was stolen out of Manchester
about a week ago

333
00:26:43,352 --> 00:26:45,730
and it was reported, and the plates changed.

334
00:26:45,813 --> 00:26:49,817
Jack, victim was foreign. Natalija Wolscat.

335
00:26:51,277 --> 00:26:55,948
She was working as a temp in a legal firm.
She was only in here buying jewellery.

336
00:26:56,032 --> 00:26:59,535
Ran a check on her.
There's nothing out of the ordinary.

337
00:27:00,453 --> 00:27:02,121
She's a civilian.

338
00:27:03,289 --> 00:27:05,875
- CARTER: Right, that's it.
- All right, guv?

339
00:27:05,958 --> 00:27:07,168
Ta.

340
00:27:07,251 --> 00:27:11,464
The murder weapon was a 9 mm, possibly
a Smithy or a high-powered Browning.

341
00:27:11,547 --> 00:27:14,717
Gonna run a check on the spent cases
now, I'll get back to you ASAP.

342
00:27:14,800 --> 00:27:17,261
But judging by the circumference
of the exit wound,

343
00:27:17,345 --> 00:27:19,597
I'd say they were using dumdums.

344
00:27:19,680 --> 00:27:21,724
- REGAN: They don't mess about, do they?
- Don't fucking mess about.

345
00:27:21,807 --> 00:27:25,936
Guv, I found a shaped charge, what's left of it.

346
00:27:26,020 --> 00:27:30,650
Fucking hell, Ellis. You should be
wearing a glove if you're touching that.

347
00:27:30,733 --> 00:27:33,944
What a stain to have on your soul, eh?

348
00:27:34,028 --> 00:27:38,199
Take someone's life for a couple of
hundred grand's worth of stones.

349
00:27:39,200 --> 00:27:41,827
I mean, you'd just leave the fucking work
and walk, wouldn't you?

350
00:27:41,911 --> 00:27:42,995
Yeah.

351
00:27:47,375 --> 00:27:50,378
Looks like they panicked
when the hold-up alarm went.

352
00:27:50,461 --> 00:27:52,380
Why else would they top her?

353
00:27:52,463 --> 00:27:53,964
Got any ideas?

354
00:27:56,092 --> 00:27:58,135
REGAN: That was blown in 2000.

355
00:27:58,219 --> 00:28:00,304
That was blown the same year.

356
00:28:00,388 --> 00:28:02,848
That was blown the following year.

357
00:28:02,932 --> 00:28:05,142
And that was blown today.

358
00:28:08,145 --> 00:28:11,065
What do you notice
about the shaped charges?

359
00:28:16,779 --> 00:28:19,865
- They're all the same.
- Well done, Grasshopper.

360
00:28:19,949 --> 00:28:21,867
Now, see him?

361
00:28:21,951 --> 00:28:25,287
I gave him his first two sentences
when he was just a teenager.

362
00:28:25,371 --> 00:28:27,790
He robbed a post office
while he was still at school.

363
00:28:27,873 --> 00:28:29,959
He's a fucking torpedo.

364
00:28:33,087 --> 00:28:37,425
Francis Allen. Six years for armed robbery
and attempted murder.

365
00:28:37,508 --> 00:28:41,262
Back behind bars
one week after release for another robbery.

366
00:28:41,345 --> 00:28:44,974
Gets parole. After that the trail goes cold.

367
00:28:45,057 --> 00:28:49,186
He progressed to, er,
running guns for the Provos.

368
00:28:49,270 --> 00:28:50,896
Earned an absolute fucking fortune

369
00:28:50,980 --> 00:28:55,025
supplying breakaway paramilitary groups,
you know,

370
00:28:55,109 --> 00:28:57,737
with small firearms, light weaponry.

371
00:28:57,820 --> 00:29:01,782
He's got links in Eastern Europe,
Chechnya, Russia, Serbia.

372
00:29:01,866 --> 00:29:04,160
By all accounts,
he went to ground in Montenegro.

373
00:29:04,243 --> 00:29:06,662
- So why come back now?
- Don't know.

374
00:29:08,873 --> 00:29:11,125
Rob a shitty little low-end jewellers?

375
00:29:11,208 --> 00:29:12,460
Hmm.

376
00:29:12,543 --> 00:29:15,880
He's either done all his beans and gone skint,

377
00:29:15,963 --> 00:29:20,176
or an opportunity came his way
and he simplyjust couldn't say no.

378
00:29:20,259 --> 00:29:22,553
Well, let's find him and ask him.

379
00:29:22,636 --> 00:29:24,930
Shake a few trees, see what falls out.

380
00:29:25,014 --> 00:29:27,850
And get Simmonds
to go down Hatton Garden,

381
00:29:27,933 --> 00:29:29,935
see if anyone's tried to fence that bit of tom.

382
00:29:30,019 --> 00:29:31,729
- I'm on it.
- Oi!

383
00:29:31,812 --> 00:29:34,940
I'll pick up the new motor,
flop on a few grasses.

384
00:29:35,024 --> 00:29:37,234
Someone's got to know if he's come back.

385
00:29:37,318 --> 00:29:38,527
You look excited.

386
00:29:38,611 --> 00:29:42,114
Yeah, Francis Allen, guv.
Looks like he's come out of retirement.

387
00:29:42,198 --> 00:29:43,282
I need a word.

388
00:29:43,365 --> 00:29:46,368
- I'm jogging on.
- Regan! I said I need a word.

389
00:29:47,495 --> 00:29:48,537
Now.

390
00:29:50,289 --> 00:29:51,540
Yes, guv.

391
00:29:55,211 --> 00:29:56,545
What's up?

392
00:29:58,589 --> 00:30:01,300
You're playing with a straight bat,
aren't you, Jack?

393
00:30:01,383 --> 00:30:02,468
What?

394
00:30:03,052 --> 00:30:06,388
Reassure me that Lewis and his boys
have got nothing on you.

395
00:30:06,472 --> 00:30:08,849
Nothing that can come back and haunt us.

396
00:30:08,933 --> 00:30:10,351
Nothing, no.

397
00:30:13,521 --> 00:30:17,066
His team are taking it more seriously
than I anticipated.

398
00:30:24,114 --> 00:30:26,700
- No.
- Good.

399
00:30:26,784 --> 00:30:29,787
All right, nail your boy for the robbery.
I'm sure this'll be forgotten about.

400
00:30:29,870 --> 00:30:31,288
- Can I splice now?
- Yeah.

401
00:30:31,372 --> 00:30:32,581
Lovely.

402
00:30:40,756 --> 00:30:44,051
- What do you know about Allen?
- He's a slag.

403
00:30:44,134 --> 00:30:47,555
- You close?
- Nah, I gave him his first bit of porridge.

404
00:30:47,638 --> 00:30:50,933
Thought it would be a matter of time
before I saw his fucking face again.

405
00:30:51,016 --> 00:30:54,687
See, cats like Allen, they can't help theirself.

406
00:30:54,770 --> 00:30:56,438
You look excited.

407
00:30:57,398 --> 00:30:59,275
Sorry, it's your tits.

408
00:30:59,775 --> 00:31:02,611
They don't stick out as much as your belly.

409
00:31:04,446 --> 00:31:06,907
What you saying? I gotta lose a bit of weight?

410
00:31:06,991 --> 00:31:09,952
As long as you don't lose your charm as well.

411
00:31:13,038 --> 00:31:18,127
I suppose I could, erm,
lose a couple of kilos for you.

412
00:31:18,752 --> 00:31:20,546
Oh, I'm touched.

413
00:31:20,629 --> 00:31:23,007
- I wish I fucking was.
- You're about to be.

414
00:31:23,090 --> 00:31:24,717
- Yeah?
- Yeah. Here we go.

415
00:31:24,800 --> 00:31:26,886
Oh! Eyes on the road.

416
00:31:34,935 --> 00:31:38,355
- How do you wanna play this?
- Very low key. No trouble.

417
00:31:38,439 --> 00:31:40,649
- Members only.
- Move.

418
00:31:40,733 --> 00:31:42,526
I said, members... (SCREAMS)

419
00:31:42,610 --> 00:31:44,445
We're the Sweeney, son.

420
00:31:44,528 --> 00:31:47,489
Get out of the fucking way
or else I'll break your legs.

421
00:31:49,074 --> 00:31:50,409
Listen up!

422
00:31:50,993 --> 00:31:53,495
Now, calm down, we're not here for drugs.

423
00:31:53,579 --> 00:31:57,124
- What do you want, Regan?
- Not you, you fucking grass.

424
00:31:58,292 --> 00:32:01,503
Fucking hell, Regan. Who dug you up, then?

425
00:32:02,254 --> 00:32:05,591
- What do you want?
- Francis Allen. Where is he?

426
00:32:06,300 --> 00:32:09,345
Leave it out. He ain't been about for years.

427
00:32:09,428 --> 00:32:10,971
You know that.

428
00:32:11,722 --> 00:32:14,016
Well, maybe he just came back.

429
00:32:15,017 --> 00:32:16,602
What do you know about a jewellery robbery?

430
00:32:16,685 --> 00:32:19,021
Innocent girl got one in the back of the nut.

431
00:32:19,104 --> 00:32:20,648
Ring any bells?

432
00:32:22,524 --> 00:32:24,818
Would you like me to jog
your fucking memory?

433
00:32:24,902 --> 00:32:28,155
Leave it out, Regan.
You got nish, and you know it.

434
00:32:28,238 --> 00:32:31,867
Why don't you take
this fucking little drat and piss off?

435
00:32:32,368 --> 00:32:34,036
Well, I'm gonna enjoy this
a lot more than you are.

436
00:32:34,119 --> 00:32:37,122
Yeah, you think you're gonna enjoy what?
What...

437
00:32:37,206 --> 00:32:38,707
Fucking witch!

438
00:32:40,834 --> 00:32:42,127
(GROANS)

439
00:32:42,211 --> 00:32:45,047
Nobody takes liberties on my patch.

440
00:32:45,130 --> 00:32:50,177
If I find out you or any one of these slags
know about Allen and his bit of work,

441
00:32:50,260 --> 00:32:54,515
I'll hit you so fucking hard,
you'll wish you were already in prison.

442
00:33:02,356 --> 00:33:04,733
What a fucking world this is.

443
00:33:05,734 --> 00:33:08,237
- What you looking at?
- Hiya.

444
00:33:13,534 --> 00:33:16,328
I don't understand. Why would someone
tell you where our man is,

445
00:33:16,412 --> 00:33:17,663
and no one wants to talk to me?

446
00:33:17,746 --> 00:33:19,498
What? Am I losing my touch here?

447
00:33:19,581 --> 00:33:22,751
What can I say? I just come about it
from a different angle than you, that's all.

448
00:33:22,835 --> 00:33:24,837
- You know, ask them nicely.
- REGAN: Oh, <i>fuck!</i>

449
00:33:24,920 --> 00:33:26,755
Anyway, my new mate here...

450
00:33:26,839 --> 00:33:27,881
- You all right, mate?
- Just bring me up.

451
00:33:27,965 --> 00:33:29,967
Just on the phone, one sec.

452
00:33:30,050 --> 00:33:33,512
He reckons our boy Allen's got
a little bolt-hole in the countryside.

453
00:33:33,595 --> 00:33:36,682
Little anonymous gaff
in the middle of nowhere.

454
00:33:36,765 --> 00:33:38,892
I reckon we should get down there, soon as.

455
00:33:40,352 --> 00:33:44,773
<i>REGAN: Report to me anything you see.
Do not come off of Channel 6.</i>

456
00:33:46,066 --> 00:33:48,152
<i>Do not compromise our play.</i>

457
00:33:48,986 --> 00:33:53,615
This is Francis Allen we're dealing with.
He's a very capable and dangerous man.

458
00:33:53,699 --> 00:33:56,952
He has killed and he will kill again.

459
00:33:59,997 --> 00:34:01,457
(REGAN SIGHS)

460
00:34:01,874 --> 00:34:03,792
Where the fuck are you?

461
00:34:10,591 --> 00:34:12,926
CARTER: Been here fucking hours.

462
00:34:17,473 --> 00:34:19,767
Do you think he's even in there?

463
00:34:19,850 --> 00:34:22,978
Well, we'll know one way or the other,
won't we?

464
00:34:23,687 --> 00:34:27,066
He's really got under your skin,
hasn't he, this one?

465
00:34:29,985 --> 00:34:32,738
I can't have animals running about,
killing innocent girls

466
00:34:32,821 --> 00:34:35,616
and thinking they can get away with it,
George.

467
00:34:35,699 --> 00:34:37,576
Not while I'm Sweeney.

468
00:34:39,369 --> 00:34:42,039
(SIGHS) Fuck me.

469
00:34:43,957 --> 00:34:45,918
Guv, can I ask your advice on something?

470
00:34:46,001 --> 00:34:48,712
Yeah, go on, knock yourself out, Ellis.

471
00:34:50,672 --> 00:34:54,259
What would be the best way
of asking Lewis out on a date?

472
00:34:58,847 --> 00:35:00,641
- Lewis?
- Yeah, Nancy.

473
00:35:01,934 --> 00:35:06,105
Got a fierce crush on her.
Been thinking about asking her to dinner.

474
00:35:07,356 --> 00:35:09,608
I wouldn't bother if I was you, Ellis.

475
00:35:09,691 --> 00:35:13,904
Well, I fancy her loads and it looks like
her marriage is going down the shitter, so...

476
00:35:13,987 --> 00:35:18,367
Listen, that's a work colleague of ours
you're talking about here, yeah.

477
00:35:19,409 --> 00:35:21,620
Stop being so unprofessional.

478
00:35:22,162 --> 00:35:25,415
Oh, who cares? I'm nuts about her.

479
00:35:25,499 --> 00:35:27,042
Ellis, shut it.

480
00:35:32,506 --> 00:35:34,591
I just really wanna fuck her.

481
00:35:34,675 --> 00:35:36,135
Oh, fucking hell.

482
00:35:36,218 --> 00:35:38,345
And how would you feel
if you ever got the chance, Ellis?

483
00:35:38,428 --> 00:35:41,390
Oh, Jesus. I'd be up on the back of her
like a Jack Russell with two mickeys.

484
00:35:41,473 --> 00:35:43,809
- Oh, nito. Nito!
- (BANGING ON VAN DOOR)

485
00:35:43,892 --> 00:35:45,394
It's Simmonds.

486
00:35:46,728 --> 00:35:48,397
Oi, oi, saveloy!

487
00:35:48,897 --> 00:35:50,399
Where's Wextru?

488
00:35:50,482 --> 00:35:52,192
You sent him to stick a bank
under observation.

489
00:35:52,276 --> 00:35:53,944
Fuck the bank, I want him here.

490
00:35:54,027 --> 00:35:56,155
What about if Allen comes?
I want the whole team here.

491
00:35:56,238 --> 00:35:59,825
- George, get on the blower.
- Here, americano, two sugars.

492
00:36:00,117 --> 00:36:03,495
And an organic soya latte for you, guv.

493
00:36:03,579 --> 00:36:04,830
Oh.

494
00:36:04,913 --> 00:36:09,042
Soya? Since when did you start
drinking fucking soya?

495
00:36:09,877 --> 00:36:11,003
Oh, fuck me.

496
00:36:11,086 --> 00:36:12,838
She got you on the healthy milk now,
has she?

497
00:36:12,921 --> 00:36:14,715
- Who's that?
- No one.

498
00:36:15,007 --> 00:36:18,719
Is it that serious? Is it fucking soya serious?

499
00:36:19,303 --> 00:36:22,890
(SIGHS) Well, judge for yourself.
She's coming to dinner.

500
00:36:24,808 --> 00:36:28,020
I will have the prawn cocktail for starters.

501
00:36:28,437 --> 00:36:33,859
Then beef lasagne, some chips
and some garlic bread, please. Eating for two.

502
00:36:34,568 --> 00:36:38,655
Oh, um, I'll have the deep-fried brie to start

503
00:36:38,739 --> 00:36:42,117
and then the um, oh, roast loin of pork

504
00:36:42,201 --> 00:36:46,038
and a side of chips.
Can I get some mayonnaise with that as well?

505
00:36:46,121 --> 00:36:48,540
I will have... What's a whitebait?

506
00:36:48,624 --> 00:36:51,877
Them little tiny little fishes
with little miserable looks on their faces...

507
00:36:51,960 --> 00:36:54,087
- Yes, darling.
- ...we had in Greece?

508
00:36:54,171 --> 00:36:57,633
I like them. We had them in Greece.
I'll have some of them.

509
00:36:57,716 --> 00:37:00,761
I'll also have rigatoni and meatballs.

510
00:37:00,844 --> 00:37:03,347
Can I have escalope?
Veal escalope on the side.

511
00:37:03,430 --> 00:37:05,098
God, I'm starving.

512
00:37:06,683 --> 00:37:10,771
A bit of garlic bread, I think. Yeah.
What are you having?

513
00:37:14,858 --> 00:37:15,984
Um...

514
00:37:20,906 --> 00:37:23,492
I'll have the pear and walnut salad.

515
00:37:24,493 --> 00:37:25,869
All right.

516
00:37:26,536 --> 00:37:27,996
Cheers, mate.

517
00:37:34,836 --> 00:37:38,340
- Did you tell Jack yet, darling?
- No.

518
00:37:38,966 --> 00:37:41,802
George has applied for a promotion to DS.

519
00:37:43,178 --> 00:37:45,138
They're hearing it, too.

520
00:37:45,597 --> 00:37:47,015
Marvellous.

521
00:37:50,686 --> 00:37:53,021
How's Neil doing at school, Meg?

522
00:37:54,773 --> 00:37:56,316
Piss off, Jack.

523
00:37:56,984 --> 00:38:00,279
You never asked about him before.
Anyone would think you cared, mate.

524
00:38:00,362 --> 00:38:01,905
Just enquiring.

525
00:38:01,989 --> 00:38:04,783
So George tells me you're married, Nancy?

526
00:38:05,242 --> 00:38:07,619
Yes. But Jack's a better fuck.

527
00:38:14,167 --> 00:38:15,961
That's a good one.

528
00:38:16,044 --> 00:38:20,340
I'm only joking. Just that, you know,
I'm in the final stages of a marriage.

529
00:38:20,424 --> 00:38:24,594
The only thing keeping us together
is the roof over our heads. So...

530
00:38:46,867 --> 00:38:50,203
Fuckin' hell. No danger of you and me
getting it on tonight, is there?

531
00:38:50,287 --> 00:38:52,289
I'm trying here. I'm fucking trying.

532
00:38:52,372 --> 00:38:54,166
You might lose it before you get me into bed.

533
00:38:54,249 --> 00:38:57,169
I've got more chance of losing a stone.

534
00:39:10,640 --> 00:39:13,643
If you was looking at what I was looking at,

535
00:39:13,894 --> 00:39:16,271
you'd know why I was so excited.

536
00:39:32,287 --> 00:39:33,580
CARTER: Sure it was Allen?

537
00:39:33,663 --> 00:39:37,042
WEXTRU: Yeah. He pulled up
in a Range Rover and went in with a suitcase.

538
00:39:37,125 --> 00:39:39,294
CARTER: Could be the jewels.

539
00:39:50,555 --> 00:39:51,973
Positive ID.

540
00:39:52,766 --> 00:39:54,643
Guess who just woke up.

541
00:39:58,480 --> 00:40:01,066
- We've gotta fucking go now, Carter.
- Wait.

542
00:40:01,149 --> 00:40:05,529
Listen, Jack, we're gonna miss the boat
on this one if we don't go now.

543
00:40:05,612 --> 00:40:06,822
Hold up.

544
00:40:07,656 --> 00:40:09,032
Who's this?

545
00:40:10,742 --> 00:40:15,163
<i>REGAN: Nobody move.
Unidentified vehicle approaching.</i>

546
00:40:15,997 --> 00:40:19,418
Roger that.
We're in position and we're ready to move.

547
00:40:21,420 --> 00:40:23,547
That's gotta be them, innit?

548
00:40:24,005 --> 00:40:26,007
It's the rest of the firm.

549
00:40:27,592 --> 00:40:28,927
Move into position.

550
00:40:29,010 --> 00:40:33,348
<i>Remember, this lot don't mess about,
so hit 'em hard and fast.</i>

551
00:40:33,849 --> 00:40:35,851
<i>Dominate and pacify.</i>

552
00:40:36,393 --> 00:40:39,271
I've got a fuckin' hard on, I'm telling you.

553
00:40:42,858 --> 00:40:46,361
Simmonds, with me. Ellis, along the wall.
Come on.

554
00:40:57,747 --> 00:40:59,332
Armed police!

555
00:40:59,416 --> 00:41:01,168
Go, go, go, go!

556
00:41:08,008 --> 00:41:09,509
Get up, you...

557
00:41:12,846 --> 00:41:14,764
Ellis, one coming your way!

558
00:41:15,599 --> 00:41:18,226
- Don't fucking move!
- Go, fuck off!

559
00:41:54,054 --> 00:41:58,975
Carter, in pursuit of Allen!
Get in the gardening van and cut him off!

560
00:42:01,102 --> 00:42:03,104
Can you hear me? George?

561
00:42:04,189 --> 00:42:05,440
Fuck it!

562
00:42:21,164 --> 00:42:22,707
Oh, fuck!

563
00:42:37,305 --> 00:42:39,432
(CARTER LAUGHING)

564
00:42:43,270 --> 00:42:45,605
Where was you?

565
00:42:47,566 --> 00:42:49,776
- (BUZZING)
- (GROANS)

566
00:42:49,859 --> 00:42:51,528
(CARTER LAUGHING)

567
00:42:56,491 --> 00:42:58,201
Put your trousers on. You're nicked.

568
00:42:59,160 --> 00:43:01,746
I'm gonna rub you right up.
You're gonna get plenty of porridge, son.

569
00:43:01,830 --> 00:43:03,748
Keep fucking moving.

570
00:43:05,709 --> 00:43:08,336
Keep your fucking head round that way.

571
00:43:32,235 --> 00:43:36,573
- Do you want a cigarette?
- I don't want fucking nothing from you, mate.

572
00:43:40,285 --> 00:43:45,123
Look, Freddy, I'm sure your whole life
you've been told not to talk to the police.

573
00:43:45,206 --> 00:43:49,502
You live by a code.
Honour amongst thieves and all that.

574
00:43:49,586 --> 00:43:52,047
Believe it or not, I respect that.

575
00:43:52,839 --> 00:43:55,884
But, you see,
your code's already been broken.

576
00:43:56,384 --> 00:44:00,138
'Cause armed robbery is one thing
and murder is another.

577
00:44:01,056 --> 00:44:05,435
You know, I ain't got a clue
what you're talking about.

578
00:44:05,518 --> 00:44:06,895
I was at a barbecue.

579
00:44:06,978 --> 00:44:08,063
Bang!

580
00:44:12,400 --> 00:44:16,655
I wonder how it would really feel
to be shot in the head. Point blank.

581
00:44:18,073 --> 00:44:20,992
One minute
you're going about your business,

582
00:44:21,910 --> 00:44:25,455
buying a present for a friend, the next...

583
00:44:25,538 --> 00:44:27,165
- Bang!
- ...nothing.

584
00:44:28,041 --> 00:44:31,753
Gone. A full stop on an ordinary life.

585
00:44:34,297 --> 00:44:37,467
A bit funny, innit,
you all meeting round Allen's this morning?

586
00:44:37,550 --> 00:44:40,178
I told you. I was at a barbecue, gavver.

587
00:44:40,261 --> 00:44:42,889
- Bollocks.
- Why don't you check the shopping bags?

588
00:44:42,972 --> 00:44:45,558
You think I carry fucking pork chops around
with me for the fun of it?

589
00:44:45,642 --> 00:44:47,769
Listen to me,
I went round there for a barbecue.

590
00:44:47,852 --> 00:44:50,563
Bollocks.You went round to Allen's house
for your lick of the lolly.

591
00:44:50,647 --> 00:44:54,693
I've got a bag full of peppered steaks
and sausages out there. Go and have a look.

592
00:44:54,776 --> 00:44:56,820
What the fuck happened to you, Allen?

593
00:44:56,903 --> 00:44:59,989
I used to think you was a bit of a player
a few years ago.

594
00:45:00,073 --> 00:45:04,202
Now you're turning over
two-bob jewellery shops.

595
00:45:05,912 --> 00:45:07,664
And killing punters.

596
00:45:08,164 --> 00:45:10,875
- You the trigger man, then?
- No comment.

597
00:45:10,959 --> 00:45:13,294
You like killing innocent women?

598
00:45:14,963 --> 00:45:17,549
She was only buying a present
for a fucking friend, you scum!

599
00:45:17,632 --> 00:45:18,800
Twenty-three years old.

600
00:45:20,510 --> 00:45:25,223
Shaped charge like that is only available
from an industrial builders' merchants.

601
00:45:25,306 --> 00:45:28,017
Oh, and you need a ticket for that.

602
00:45:29,978 --> 00:45:33,481
It's, um, a specialist skill set.

603
00:45:37,318 --> 00:45:42,490
Only someone with a criminal
or military history would be capable.

604
00:45:43,158 --> 00:45:44,743
Oh, and you weren't in the army, was ya,

605
00:45:44,826 --> 00:45:48,037
'cause I stuck you in the fucking shovel?
(CHUCKLES)

606
00:45:50,832 --> 00:45:52,917
- Come here.
- What's up, man?

607
00:45:54,002 --> 00:45:55,420
You see, Mr. Guilty Murderer,

608
00:45:55,503 --> 00:45:58,465
I'm the kind of person, I want to see
those responsible brought to justice,

609
00:45:58,548 --> 00:46:01,134
but, you, you're the kind of person,

610
00:46:01,217 --> 00:46:05,805
if you had any information on someone
like that, you'd keep it to yourself.

611
00:46:17,525 --> 00:46:19,903
The wrist. May I?

612
00:46:23,865 --> 00:46:25,617
Knock yourself out.

613
00:46:36,044 --> 00:46:38,046
Do you know what that is?

614
00:46:39,005 --> 00:46:41,424
It's a watch mark tan line.

615
00:46:42,550 --> 00:46:43,802
Know why?

616
00:46:48,723 --> 00:46:50,850
'Cause I've been in the sun.

617
00:46:52,268 --> 00:46:53,353
So?

618
00:46:53,436 --> 00:46:56,397
So you can sit there
and say anything you want about me

619
00:46:56,481 --> 00:46:58,316
and that bit of work,

620
00:46:59,317 --> 00:47:01,402
you can tell me it's my MO,

621
00:47:02,904 --> 00:47:05,448
how it could have only come from me,

622
00:47:07,867 --> 00:47:13,665
fingerprints, DNA, shaped charge.

623
00:47:13,748 --> 00:47:14,833
Yeah.

624
00:47:15,917 --> 00:47:18,920
There is one fact you're overlooking, Regan.

625
00:47:19,003 --> 00:47:20,255
Oh, what's that?

626
00:47:20,338 --> 00:47:22,882
One piece of undeniable evidence

627
00:47:22,966 --> 00:47:26,177
that anyjury in the land
will chuck out of court.

628
00:47:27,095 --> 00:47:28,263
Go on.

629
00:47:30,098 --> 00:47:31,766
I was on my yacht,

630
00:47:33,977 --> 00:47:35,603
lying in the sun.

631
00:47:38,606 --> 00:47:41,150
You're gonna have to do better than that, son.

632
00:47:41,234 --> 00:47:44,904
Why don't you ask your sidekick
to bring my mobile phone in here?

633
00:47:44,988 --> 00:47:46,322
Please.

634
00:47:51,077 --> 00:47:54,163
George? Bring this slag's mobile in, will you?

635
00:47:56,457 --> 00:47:58,084
I know it's you.

636
00:47:58,710 --> 00:48:00,670
When I put you away, it will be for so long,

637
00:48:00,753 --> 00:48:04,966
next time you come out,
you'll be walking on fucking sticks.

638
00:48:06,885 --> 00:48:08,136
Maybe.

639
00:48:16,477 --> 00:48:18,813
Go on, dig an 'ole for yourself.

640
00:48:46,466 --> 00:48:52,180
It's me, on board my yacht.
Moored off the coast of Montenegro.

641
00:49:01,731 --> 00:49:04,734
The time and date's at the top of the screen.

642
00:49:05,944 --> 00:49:07,195
Hmm.

643
00:49:07,278 --> 00:49:10,198
- But you saw that, didn't you, Regan?
- Yeah.

644
00:49:15,995 --> 00:49:18,122
<i>HASKINS: Regan, quick word.</i>

645
00:49:19,415 --> 00:49:21,417
I'll be right there, guv.

646
00:49:29,467 --> 00:49:31,260
Keep your nut on him.

647
00:49:31,970 --> 00:49:36,140
You seem like a smart man, Francis.
You shouldn't underestimate me.

648
00:49:37,141 --> 00:49:39,227
I ain't no one's sidekick.

649
00:49:42,897 --> 00:49:44,357
What you got?

650
00:49:45,900 --> 00:49:47,694
The electronic strip on his passport

651
00:49:47,777 --> 00:49:51,489
confirms he was out of the country
at the time of the robbery.

652
00:49:51,572 --> 00:49:55,076
He re-entered the night Wextru saw him
with a suitcase.

653
00:49:57,495 --> 00:49:59,914
I think you've got the wrong man.

654
00:50:00,832 --> 00:50:03,459
Anyone could have carried his passport.

655
00:50:03,543 --> 00:50:06,462
You know what he's capable of.
It's a move, guv.

656
00:50:06,546 --> 00:50:08,381
It doesn't look like a move from here.

657
00:50:08,464 --> 00:50:11,926
And you know we only have him in custody
for 24 hours.

658
00:50:12,385 --> 00:50:15,096
I just need one more little piece
of evidence to tie him to the crime.

659
00:50:15,179 --> 00:50:17,056
Get it quickly, Regan.

660
00:50:17,390 --> 00:50:20,059
You don't charge him by 10:00 a.m. tomorrow,
he's a free man,

661
00:50:20,143 --> 00:50:22,770
and you're sitting in a pile of shit.

662
00:50:44,292 --> 00:50:47,086
I'm sick of sneaking about in the shadows.

663
00:50:48,296 --> 00:50:50,840
I want you to leave him.
I want you to live with me.

664
00:50:50,923 --> 00:50:53,509
What? Here in a Holiday Inn?
It's not that easy.

665
00:50:53,593 --> 00:50:55,428
I'll get a gaff.

666
00:50:58,306 --> 00:51:02,560
We can set up shop together, you and me.
I mean, we're good together.

667
00:51:05,146 --> 00:51:07,231
You make me feel, um...

668
00:51:10,318 --> 00:51:11,527
Hungry-

669
00:51:18,159 --> 00:51:19,911
Just think about it.

670
00:51:22,955 --> 00:51:25,583
Come, get back into bed, Jack.
You're stressed.

671
00:51:25,666 --> 00:51:29,045
Nah. I've got this slag in a cell.

672
00:51:30,838 --> 00:51:32,131
I know he's fucking playing me.

673
00:51:32,215 --> 00:51:35,718
I just can't link him to the crime,
but I know he done it.

674
00:51:35,802 --> 00:51:36,928
I know, Jack.

675
00:51:37,011 --> 00:51:39,430
- I just want to put him away.
- I know, Jack.

676
00:51:39,514 --> 00:51:42,558
- I need to fucking put him away.
- I know, Jack.

677
00:51:49,607 --> 00:51:51,859
(HELICOPTER ROTORS WHIRRING)

678
00:52:03,996 --> 00:52:05,289
CARTER: Who is it?

679
00:52:05,373 --> 00:52:08,042
It's the Pope. Who do you think it is?

680
00:52:12,713 --> 00:52:14,715
What's wrong with you? Don't you sleep?

681
00:52:14,799 --> 00:52:16,968
Put your clothes on, George.

682
00:52:22,014 --> 00:52:24,600
Three armed males enter the premises.

683
00:52:25,101 --> 00:52:27,145
There's one driver outside.
One holds the door.

684
00:52:27,228 --> 00:52:30,106
Two clear the premises
and work the counters.

685
00:52:30,189 --> 00:52:33,359
Shaped charge blows the safe.

686
00:52:33,442 --> 00:52:36,195
They're in and out in under two minutes.

687
00:52:37,488 --> 00:52:39,240
There's one victim.

688
00:52:40,575 --> 00:52:42,702
An innocent girl
who was just buying a fucking present.

689
00:52:42,785 --> 00:52:45,079
I mean, what's that all about?

690
00:52:46,789 --> 00:52:50,168
Two hundred grand's worth of stones
and tom gone.

691
00:52:50,251 --> 00:52:52,753
- What have we got?
- We've got Allen.

692
00:52:52,837 --> 00:52:55,256
Yeah. Only for a couple of hours.

693
00:52:56,215 --> 00:52:57,925
(SIGHS)

694
00:52:58,467 --> 00:52:59,969
Play it again.

695
00:53:02,430 --> 00:53:04,390
- That's it.
- Wait. I've gone back too far.

696
00:53:04,473 --> 00:53:06,559
Fuck it. Leave it, let it play.

697
00:53:06,642 --> 00:53:10,438
Two come in, clear the place.
Shaped charge the fucking...

698
00:53:13,941 --> 00:53:15,234
Where's my fucking glasses?

699
00:53:15,318 --> 00:53:17,695
Has anyone checked her phone records
to find out who she's talking to?

700
00:53:17,778 --> 00:53:19,739
Yeah, Simmonds is on it.

701
00:53:23,576 --> 00:53:26,037
It's funny how,
a few seconds after she hangs up,

702
00:53:26,120 --> 00:53:28,247
the place gets knocked over.

703
00:53:32,960 --> 00:53:34,295
Watch.

704
00:53:39,008 --> 00:53:41,844
Why turn back? They got what they came for.

705
00:53:41,928 --> 00:53:44,055
He didn't need to kill her.

706
00:53:46,933 --> 00:53:49,310
He's done it for another reason.

707
00:53:50,811 --> 00:53:53,356
He's killed her for another reason.

708
00:53:55,066 --> 00:53:57,109
It wasn't just a robbery.

709
00:53:58,402 --> 00:54:00,154
It was an execution.

710
00:54:07,286 --> 00:54:08,412
- REGAN: <i>Guv?</i>
- Yeah.

711
00:54:08,496 --> 00:54:11,290
Allen killed the girl to cover something up.
Weren'tjust a robbery.

712
00:54:11,374 --> 00:54:14,752
Look at the CCTV.
He murdered her for another reason.

713
00:54:14,835 --> 00:54:18,130
We've run a check on her mobile phone.
She's got one number in her address book.

714
00:54:18,214 --> 00:54:20,466
<i>- It's a pay as you go.
- HASKINS: Let me guess, it's disconnected?</i>

715
00:54:20,549 --> 00:54:23,010
Yeah. It's already dead.

716
00:54:23,094 --> 00:54:26,889
- HASKINS: Where are you?
- We're on our way to the victim's house now.

717
00:54:26,973 --> 00:54:30,226
You've got two hours, Regan.
After that, he's gone.

718
00:54:30,768 --> 00:54:33,938
<i>And Lewis has got all he needs
to put the bite on you.</i>

719
00:54:34,021 --> 00:54:35,356
(RINGING)

720
00:54:40,278 --> 00:54:42,363
I'm Officer Carter from the Flying Squad.

721
00:54:42,446 --> 00:54:44,615
We're investigating the murder
of Natalija Wolscat.

722
00:54:44,699 --> 00:54:47,034
We believe she was renting a room here.
Is that correct?

723
00:54:47,118 --> 00:54:49,912
- I've already spoken to the police.
- Not to us, you haven't.

724
00:54:49,996 --> 00:54:52,290
- It's still early in the morning.
- So what?

725
00:54:52,373 --> 00:54:56,544
- Have you seen this man?
- No. You got police ID?

726
00:55:11,392 --> 00:55:14,562
She came over from Serbia several years ago.

727
00:55:14,645 --> 00:55:16,814
She's working as a temp, right?

728
00:55:16,897 --> 00:55:18,899
Who's that? Family?

729
00:55:18,983 --> 00:55:22,028
Well, quite a few of them.
They came over here once.

730
00:55:22,111 --> 00:55:23,654
Did they?

731
00:55:26,115 --> 00:55:27,908
- Boyfriend?
- Brother.

732
00:55:31,287 --> 00:55:32,538
George.

733
00:55:33,414 --> 00:55:34,623
George?

734
00:55:36,584 --> 00:55:39,420
Take a look at this. I ain't got my bins.

735
00:55:45,926 --> 00:55:48,179
Who's the man in the picture?

736
00:55:51,766 --> 00:55:53,309
He came to the house recently.

737
00:55:53,392 --> 00:55:55,895
- How recently?
- Weeks.

738
00:55:57,146 --> 00:56:00,941
What's his name? Think. What's his name?

739
00:56:01,317 --> 00:56:02,818
I don't know.

740
00:57:03,170 --> 00:57:07,508
(WHISPERING) Fuck it. The wrong man.

741
00:57:12,638 --> 00:57:13,848
Fuck.

742
00:57:29,488 --> 00:57:31,157
You're free to go.

743
00:57:32,616 --> 00:57:35,703
- What are you talking about?
- Leave it, George.

744
00:57:39,081 --> 00:57:41,167
(EXHALES) Please.

745
00:57:43,502 --> 00:57:46,922
Law states you've still got 15 minutes
to question me.

746
00:57:47,798 --> 00:57:49,800
Don't you want to use it?

747
00:57:49,967 --> 00:57:51,177
Please.

748
00:58:09,111 --> 00:58:10,946
I can only apologise.

749
00:58:16,243 --> 00:58:21,415
The ramifications of your careless actions
are gonna have severe repercussions, Regan.

750
00:58:23,918 --> 00:58:25,211
Are they?

751
00:58:30,674 --> 00:58:34,970
Simmonds. Show this dog off the premises.

752
00:58:42,520 --> 00:58:46,941
Let's go for a walk. I ought to throw you
out the fucking window, given the chance.

753
00:58:51,529 --> 00:58:54,031
I think I've found your weak point.

754
00:58:55,241 --> 00:58:58,744
No, you've found my glasses.

755
00:59:01,247 --> 00:59:03,499
It's where I found them that matters.

756
00:59:03,582 --> 00:59:05,376
Don't push me, Lewis.

757
00:59:05,793 --> 00:59:08,879
Not when I need a throat
to get my hands around.

758
00:59:10,130 --> 00:59:13,926
- Are you threatening me, Regan?
- No, I'm not threatening you.

759
00:59:16,971 --> 00:59:18,347
(CHOKING)

760
00:59:19,473 --> 00:59:22,726
We were wrong. You stay away from me.

761
00:59:29,608 --> 00:59:31,860
(COUGHING AND GASPING)

762
00:59:46,917 --> 00:59:49,128
He's under a lot of pressure.

763
00:59:49,211 --> 00:59:51,505
It's about to get a lot worse.

764
00:59:51,839 --> 00:59:54,174
Well, I apologise on his behalf.

765
00:59:54,592 --> 00:59:58,345
- I heard you applied for promotion, Carter.
- Yeah.

766
00:59:58,887 --> 01:00:01,932
You've got an impeccable record.
You know that?

767
01:00:02,016 --> 01:00:07,313
Misdirected adolescent
turns his back on crime after a family tragedy.

768
01:00:09,023 --> 01:00:12,192
Accelerates through basic at Hendon
with honours.

769
01:00:14,903 --> 01:00:18,616
A guy like you could be
running the Sweeney in a few years.

770
01:00:26,540 --> 01:00:29,209
Makin Trebolt, you slag.

771
01:00:31,587 --> 01:00:34,923
Right. This is our man. Makin Trebolt.

772
01:00:35,007 --> 01:00:37,676
He's a Serb, ex-paramilitary.

773
01:00:38,260 --> 01:00:42,640
Wanted for robbery
across Switzerland, Italy, and France.

774
01:00:43,390 --> 01:00:45,476
Got an eye for killing witnesses.

775
01:00:45,559 --> 01:00:48,729
We believe he killed the girl
to cover his tracks.

776
01:00:50,064 --> 01:00:54,068
What she saw and what she heard
we still don't know,

777
01:00:54,151 --> 01:00:55,986
but we will find out.

778
01:00:57,071 --> 01:00:59,573
- Have you got that?
- ALL: Yes, guv.

779
01:01:00,658 --> 01:01:01,742
Good.

780
01:01:07,456 --> 01:01:11,460
Mate, you look like shit.
You should go home and get some sleep.

781
01:01:14,463 --> 01:01:17,591
Why didn't I see it coming, George?
Am I fucking losing it or what?

782
01:01:17,675 --> 01:01:20,094
Look, we all thought it was Allen.

783
01:01:21,095 --> 01:01:22,846
Don't worry about it. Go and get some rest.

784
01:01:22,930 --> 01:01:25,182
- You're no good to us like this.
- Guv?

785
01:01:25,265 --> 01:01:29,436
That private bank on Trafalgar Square
that you pulled Wextru off of.

786
01:01:29,770 --> 01:01:33,440
Well, a member of staff
has just triggered a hold-up alarm.

787
01:01:34,608 --> 01:01:35,609
It's Trebolt.

788
01:01:35,693 --> 01:01:37,695
Right. Everyone down in the compound
under a minute!

789
01:01:37,778 --> 01:01:40,531
Check your weapons, your vests.
Armed robbery in progress!

790
01:01:40,614 --> 01:01:44,118
Do not inform any other unit.
I don't want to spook him.

791
01:01:44,201 --> 01:01:46,203
With me. Armed robbery.

792
01:01:46,286 --> 01:01:47,913
- Is it Trafalgar Square?
- Yeah.

793
01:01:47,996 --> 01:01:51,750
Same bank Natalija Wolscat worked at
up until two weeks ago.

794
01:01:56,338 --> 01:02:01,301
Guv? I fucked up. You were right.
Allen had nothing to do with it.

795
01:02:01,885 --> 01:02:03,762
<i>The man we're after is Makin Trebolt.</i>

796
01:02:03,846 --> 01:02:06,765
<i>There's a robbery in progress
at the private bank we pulled away from.</i>

797
01:02:06,849 --> 01:02:08,392
<i>HASKINS: Regan, stand down.
That's an order.</i>

798
01:02:08,475 --> 01:02:09,852
We're less than three minutes away.

799
01:02:09,935 --> 01:02:12,271
<i>HASKINS: I'm ordering you to stand down,
Regan, do you hear me?</i>

800
01:02:12,354 --> 01:02:15,816
Stay away.
Lewis made an official complaint about you.

801
01:02:16,150 --> 01:02:18,569
Don't give him an opportunity
to close us down.

802
01:02:18,652 --> 01:02:20,571
You hear me, Regan? Stand down.

803
01:02:22,990 --> 01:02:24,074
Fuck!

804
01:02:29,329 --> 01:02:31,707
I've thought about what you said.

805
01:02:33,667 --> 01:02:35,085
I'll do it.

806
01:02:36,503 --> 01:02:38,213
I'll come with you.

807
01:02:41,216 --> 01:02:43,427
Come here. Come here.

808
01:02:49,516 --> 01:02:51,101
Keep hold of it.

809
01:03:09,453 --> 01:03:11,914
Get off the fucking street.

810
01:03:15,042 --> 01:03:18,045
Armed police! Get on the floor!

811
01:03:18,128 --> 01:03:22,758
CARTER: Armed police! Get on the floor!
REGAN: Get on the fucking floor!

812
01:03:23,717 --> 01:03:25,177
(HORN BLARES)

813
01:03:25,260 --> 01:03:27,971
CARTER: Get on the fucking floor!
Get on the fucking floor right now!

814
01:03:28,055 --> 01:03:30,474
Get on the fucking floor!

815
01:04:00,128 --> 01:04:02,214
(SHOUTS IN SERBIAN)

816
01:04:04,174 --> 01:04:06,051
(CAR ALARM WAILING)

817
01:04:21,775 --> 01:04:22,901
Move!

818
01:04:32,536 --> 01:04:34,705
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)

819
01:04:52,764 --> 01:04:53,849
Move!

820
01:05:20,876 --> 01:05:22,169
(SCREAMS)

821
01:05:59,081 --> 01:06:01,583
- Get down on the fucking floor!
- Go!

822
01:06:07,965 --> 01:06:09,466
(WOMAN SHRIEKS)

823
01:06:29,319 --> 01:06:30,654
Fuck it!

824
01:06:32,030 --> 01:06:33,031
Fuck!

825
01:06:34,408 --> 01:06:36,493
(SHOUTING)

826
01:06:37,202 --> 01:06:39,413
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)

827
01:06:46,670 --> 01:06:49,256
- Police! Get on the ground!
- Get down!

828
01:06:49,715 --> 01:06:51,258
(ALARM RINGING)

829
01:06:57,931 --> 01:06:59,725
<i>HASKINS: Regan,
don't make this worse for yourself.</i>

830
01:06:59,808 --> 01:07:02,436
<i>Abandon your pursuit. That's an order!</i>

831
01:07:03,603 --> 01:07:05,230
(SCREAMING)

832
01:07:28,170 --> 01:07:29,254
Go!

833
01:07:29,838 --> 01:07:32,174
Ellis, take the right-hand door!

834
01:07:53,862 --> 01:07:55,155
Stay there.

835
01:08:01,119 --> 01:08:02,996
- (WOMAN GASPS)
- Stay in your fucking room.

836
01:08:03,080 --> 01:08:04,956
- Get down. Sit.
- Stay down.

837
01:08:15,592 --> 01:08:17,302
(GUNSHOTS)

838
01:08:31,566 --> 01:08:33,443
- You all right?
- Yeah.

839
01:08:33,527 --> 01:08:35,612
Well, get yourself out of the way.

840
01:09:15,277 --> 01:09:16,528
Fuck it.

841
01:09:17,779 --> 01:09:18,822
Go!

842
01:09:34,880 --> 01:09:36,006
Fuck.

843
01:10:25,055 --> 01:10:26,556
(CLATTERING)

844
01:10:26,640 --> 01:10:27,849
Fuck!

845
01:10:42,781 --> 01:10:44,115
(RATTLING)

846
01:11:07,013 --> 01:11:08,265
Fuck it!

847
01:11:35,500 --> 01:11:36,710
Nancy?

848
01:11:43,383 --> 01:11:44,884
(MUFFLED CRIES)

849
01:11:47,387 --> 01:11:49,055
(ENGINE STARTS)

850
01:11:53,893 --> 01:11:55,478
(ENGINE REVVING)

851
01:11:55,895 --> 01:11:58,815
Get out of the fucking car! Get out!

852
01:12:00,900 --> 01:12:02,610
(TYRES SQUEAL)

853
01:12:09,576 --> 01:12:11,077
(SCREAMS)

854
01:12:35,060 --> 01:12:36,394
(CLICKING)

855
01:12:48,615 --> 01:12:50,700
(GUNSHOT)

856
01:12:53,453 --> 01:12:54,871
(DOOR SLAMS)

857
01:12:55,455 --> 01:12:56,956
(TYRES SQUEAL)

858
01:13:16,935 --> 01:13:19,896
<i>Several people,
including a female police officer,</i>

859
01:13:19,979 --> 01:13:24,567
<i>have been shot dead
after a bank robbery went disastrously wrong</i>

860
01:13:24,651 --> 01:13:26,945
<i>in London's most famous square.</i>

861
01:13:27,028 --> 01:13:30,281
<i>The armed gang stole around £9 million</i>

862
01:13:30,365 --> 01:13:33,576
<i>in various
high-denomination foreign banknotes.</i>

863
01:13:33,660 --> 01:13:38,581
<i>The gang, thought to be behind a number
of high-profile robberies across Europe,</i>

864
01:13:38,665 --> 01:13:42,669
<i>evaded capture,
despite a dramatic pursuit by police.</i>

865
01:13:42,752 --> 01:13:43,795
<i>Although it is thought</i>

866
01:13:43,878 --> 01:13:47,507
<i>one of the men suffered
a serious gunshot wound to the neck.</i>

867
01:13:47,590 --> 01:13:51,678
<i>Police also want to question
Serbian national Makin Trebolt</i>

868
01:13:51,761 --> 01:13:56,182
<i>in connection with the robbery,
as well as the murder of Natalija Wolscat,</i>

869
01:13:56,266 --> 01:13:59,769
<i>who was killed earlier this week
in another armed raid.</i>

870
01:14:00,353 --> 01:14:04,065
<i>MALE REPORTER: Zora Suleman reporting
from Trafalgar Square.</i>

871
01:14:06,025 --> 01:14:07,193
Janet?

872
01:14:10,780 --> 01:14:12,323
(CLEARS THROAT)

873
01:14:30,550 --> 01:14:32,302
Sorry for your loss.

874
01:14:35,889 --> 01:14:37,223
I'm sorry.

875
01:14:40,059 --> 01:14:42,228
I'm gonna destroy you, Regan.

876
01:14:43,938 --> 01:14:47,775
I'm gonna make sure
you never work in the police force again.

877
01:14:48,443 --> 01:14:52,113
I'm freezing your bank accounts,
I'm freezing your assets, your home,

878
01:14:52,197 --> 01:14:53,781
your whole life.

879
01:14:57,243 --> 01:15:00,246
I hold you alone responsible
for what happened,

880
01:15:03,082 --> 01:15:04,501
for my wife.

881
01:15:07,128 --> 01:15:08,838
You're a dinosaur.

882
01:15:11,049 --> 01:15:12,592
You're extinct.

883
01:15:14,969 --> 01:15:18,598
And there's no place for a man like you
in our community.

884
01:15:23,436 --> 01:15:27,524
Your unit's suspended
pending further investigation.

885
01:15:27,607 --> 01:15:32,612
If you approach any witnesses
or suspects associated with this case,

886
01:15:32,695 --> 01:15:35,448
I'll have you arrested
and remanded immediately.

887
01:15:35,532 --> 01:15:37,867
I'm assigning a team to monitor you
around the clock,

888
01:15:37,951 --> 01:15:40,370
so you think about making a move,

889
01:15:42,288 --> 01:15:43,915
you think again.

890
01:15:45,542 --> 01:15:47,627
Because I'm gonna be there.

891
01:15:50,046 --> 01:15:52,340
I want your gun and your badge
until the investigation's over.

892
01:15:52,423 --> 01:15:54,467
Your mobile phone as well.

893
01:16:18,491 --> 01:16:21,119
If I didn't believe in the law, I'd...

894
01:16:25,498 --> 01:16:29,043
The next time I see you,
I won't show the same restraint.

895
01:17:08,499 --> 01:17:11,878
What are you doing here?
I thought you was in hospital.

896
01:17:11,961 --> 01:17:13,630
You thought wrong.

897
01:17:14,422 --> 01:17:16,674
You coming? Come on. Let's go.

898
01:17:17,717 --> 01:17:21,721
- Go where?
- Trebolt.

899
01:17:22,013 --> 01:17:24,265
The unit's been suspended, you know that.

900
01:17:24,349 --> 01:17:26,392
So just me and you, then.

901
01:17:27,185 --> 01:17:28,227
No.

902
01:17:29,646 --> 01:17:32,690
- Haskins has ordered me to stay away.
- Did he?

903
01:17:36,361 --> 01:17:39,364
I can't risk my job. I can't.

904
01:17:39,739 --> 01:17:41,991
Not with Megan the way she is.
You know I can't.

905
01:17:42,075 --> 01:17:43,993
- Lose your job?
- Yeah.

906
01:17:44,077 --> 01:17:46,579
You wouldn't have a fucking job
if it weren't for me.

907
01:17:46,663 --> 01:17:50,750
You'd still be a two-bob thief
on the estate sticking brown up your...

908
01:17:50,833 --> 01:17:53,461
I worked fucking hard to be in this squad.

909
01:17:53,544 --> 01:17:57,465
You may have shown me the fucking door,
but I'm the one had to walk through it.

910
01:17:57,548 --> 01:18:00,343
You think I ain't hurting?
You think I ain't fucking hurting?

911
01:18:00,426 --> 01:18:02,720
I lost a valuable fucking member
of my team today.

912
01:18:02,804 --> 01:18:07,058
It don't matter how I feel,
'cause I weren't the one was fucking her!

913
01:18:09,519 --> 01:18:11,938
Why didn't you protect her, Jack?

914
01:18:14,524 --> 01:18:16,693
She should have been protected.

915
01:18:16,776 --> 01:18:17,860
Fuck!

916
01:18:25,118 --> 01:18:26,911
I was stuck in a car.

917
01:18:28,037 --> 01:18:30,623
I couldn't move. I couldn't help her.

918
01:18:30,790 --> 01:18:32,792
What could I fucking do?

919
01:18:34,669 --> 01:18:39,340
I can't live like this. I just need your help.
I'm on the fucking ropes here.

920
01:18:48,307 --> 01:18:50,059
We're being watched.

921
01:18:50,184 --> 01:18:52,520
- Where?
- On the roadside.

922
01:18:59,402 --> 01:19:00,611
(SIGHS)

923
01:19:03,448 --> 01:19:04,824
Hello, son.

924
01:19:06,451 --> 01:19:07,827
Come here.

925
01:19:08,995 --> 01:19:11,164
- Got a mobile on you?
- Yeah.

926
01:19:11,247 --> 01:19:13,791
Well, get your mobile
and take a smudge of me.

927
01:19:13,875 --> 01:19:15,334
Go on, then.

928
01:19:15,418 --> 01:19:16,919
What happened to your face?

929
01:19:17,003 --> 01:19:18,588
(CAMERA CLICKS)

930
01:19:19,714 --> 01:19:23,176
Give that to Harry. Tell him to meet me here.

931
01:19:25,136 --> 01:19:26,846
In the Crow's Nest.

932
01:19:31,309 --> 01:19:33,352
I want a gun and a badge.

933
01:19:37,857 --> 01:19:40,693
I've never asked you for anything, George.

934
01:21:09,532 --> 01:21:11,534
It's a bad business, this.

935
01:21:12,118 --> 01:21:15,204
They played me, Harry.
Made me look fucking ordinary.

936
01:21:15,288 --> 01:21:17,790
Well, there's nothing ordinary about you, pal.

937
01:21:17,874 --> 01:21:22,461
- Where did it all go so fucking wrong?
- You didn't. But they didn't either.

938
01:21:23,379 --> 01:21:26,674
- Who told you about the bank?
- A friend of a friend.

939
01:21:27,675 --> 01:21:30,386
Some Eastern Bloc trigger man
with loose lips.

940
01:21:30,469 --> 01:21:33,681
More chance of finding a bit of class
in Deptford.

941
01:21:35,474 --> 01:21:36,601
Here.

942
01:21:41,522 --> 01:21:44,066
That's very good. You got the yogga?

943
01:21:46,569 --> 01:21:48,946
This is all I could lay my paws on.

944
01:21:49,030 --> 01:21:51,532
Ah. That'll do.

945
01:21:52,909 --> 01:21:54,911
Yeah. I stuck a 9-mil in one of 'em.

946
01:21:54,994 --> 01:21:57,455
He won't be getting far
with an untreated gunshot wound.

947
01:21:57,538 --> 01:21:59,498
I need you to do me a favour, Harry.

948
01:21:59,582 --> 01:22:04,086
I need you to check hospitals, like Bupa
clinics, vets, and quacks, that sort of thing.

949
01:22:04,170 --> 01:22:05,713
Find 'em, Jack.

950
01:22:07,340 --> 01:22:08,799
Yeah, I will.

951
01:22:28,444 --> 01:22:29,946
(MAN MUMBLING)

952
01:22:35,993 --> 01:22:37,745
Who's Makin Trebolt?

953
01:22:40,247 --> 01:22:43,292
I told Carter. I don't talk to the police.

954
01:22:43,376 --> 01:22:45,878
I ain't the fucking police no more.

955
01:22:45,962 --> 01:22:47,964
Now, who's Makin Trebolt?

956
01:22:48,714 --> 01:22:50,675
What's his connection to Allen?

957
01:22:50,758 --> 01:22:52,760
I told you in the cells.

958
01:22:53,386 --> 01:22:55,513
I went to Allen's for a barbecue.

959
01:22:55,596 --> 01:22:59,558
- Wrong fucking answer.
- No, no, don't! (SCREAMS)

960
01:23:06,148 --> 01:23:09,568
He paid me... He paid... Allen paid me!

961
01:23:09,652 --> 01:23:11,529
- He paid me.
- For what?

962
01:23:11,737 --> 01:23:14,490
To take his passport out of the country.

963
01:23:16,325 --> 01:23:19,870
- Where is he now?
- I don't know.

964
01:23:20,413 --> 01:23:22,790
- I said...
- God! Please!

965
01:23:22,873 --> 01:23:25,418
- Where the fuck is he now?
- Oh, fuck!

966
01:23:26,377 --> 01:23:29,005
I can't tell you, 'cause I don't know.

967
01:23:38,180 --> 01:23:43,853
Now, you tell him I'm coming after him.
I'm fucking coming after all of them.

968
01:23:55,614 --> 01:23:56,991
MAN: Regan!

969
01:23:58,034 --> 01:24:01,495
We've got orders to search you.
Now empty your pockets.

970
01:24:04,415 --> 01:24:05,791
Come here.

971
01:24:06,709 --> 01:24:07,793
Fuck!

972
01:24:08,169 --> 01:24:09,879
(GROANS)

973
01:24:11,297 --> 01:24:13,966
Yeah, that's the language
you understand, isn't it?

974
01:24:14,050 --> 01:24:16,594
I'm arresting you
on suspicion of witness intimidation.

975
01:24:16,677 --> 01:24:18,554
- You have the right to remain...
- You ain't a fucking man!

976
01:24:18,637 --> 01:24:20,014
You bastard!

977
01:24:22,933 --> 01:24:24,185
Cuff him.

978
01:25:38,968 --> 01:25:41,303
The promotion you applied for...

979
01:25:43,430 --> 01:25:45,683
I'm not in the market no more.

980
01:25:47,393 --> 01:25:50,563
You wanna waste your time
with false loyalties,

981
01:25:51,772 --> 01:25:54,692
or be of real value to your community? Hmm?

982
01:25:56,193 --> 01:25:59,989
Redundant camaraderie or fulfilled potential?

983
01:26:00,072 --> 01:26:02,283
It's a simple choice, Carter.

984
01:26:04,994 --> 01:26:07,580
This is my direct line and my mobile.

985
01:26:08,038 --> 01:26:12,418
You call me when you're ready to become
the man you're capable of being.

986
01:26:44,241 --> 01:26:46,577
I know what I'd do if I was you.

987
01:26:47,745 --> 01:26:52,499
My inmates are so excited about your arrival
we had to lock down the wing.

988
01:26:54,543 --> 01:26:58,005
Funny to think
on the outside people look up to you,

989
01:26:58,088 --> 01:27:00,925
but in here you're my most hated prisoner.

990
01:27:01,175 --> 01:27:03,510
You make sex cases look popular.

991
01:27:04,970 --> 01:27:08,098
Truth is, you should be on the rule in seg,

992
01:27:09,350 --> 01:27:12,811
not on normal courtyard exercise,
for your own safety.

993
01:27:14,230 --> 01:27:16,440
But we haven't got the space.

994
01:27:17,024 --> 01:27:21,320
So you'll have to stay on the open wing
till we can transfer you.

995
01:27:22,529 --> 01:27:24,281
All right. Open up.

996
01:27:24,823 --> 01:27:27,243
(INMATES SHOUTING IN BACKGROUND)

997
01:27:33,499 --> 01:27:35,542
(INMATES BANGING ON DOORS)

998
01:27:40,422 --> 01:27:42,591
(INMATES SHOUTING)

999
01:28:14,707 --> 01:28:16,041
Here he is.

1000
01:28:25,884 --> 01:28:28,887
- How's the leg, Harry?
- It still bloody hurts.

1001
01:28:31,056 --> 01:28:33,517
Tell my friend here what you know.

1002
01:28:34,685 --> 01:28:39,273
Got a call this afternoon,
asking if I could treat a gunshot wound.

1003
01:28:40,065 --> 01:28:41,358
For cash.

1004
01:28:43,110 --> 01:28:45,821
- Do you know where he is?
- I sure do.

1005
01:28:46,655 --> 01:28:48,907
I operated on him an hour ago.

1006
01:28:49,742 --> 01:28:52,161
Pulled this from his collarbone.

1007
01:28:53,078 --> 01:28:56,081
- What's his condition?
- Shot.

1008
01:28:59,585 --> 01:29:00,794
Regan did it.

1009
01:29:00,878 --> 01:29:04,423
There's a taxi cab office
on the next street along.

1010
01:29:05,049 --> 01:29:08,886
But in the back they sell crack and heroin.

1011
01:29:09,845 --> 01:29:12,348
He's recuperating in the apartment.

1012
01:29:15,726 --> 01:29:18,020
I wouldn't go in there blazing.

1013
01:29:19,521 --> 01:29:21,065
He's not alone.

1014
01:29:23,984 --> 01:29:26,278
- Bernard.
- Take care, Harry.

1015
01:29:56,392 --> 01:29:57,976
(PHONE RINGING)

1016
01:30:00,104 --> 01:30:02,689
- Mini Cabs.
- Yes, I'm with a dozen or so friends,

1017
01:30:02,773 --> 01:30:04,983
and we need to get into Soho.

1018
01:30:05,150 --> 01:30:09,238
Could you tell me how many drivers
you have at base at the moment?

1019
01:30:13,158 --> 01:30:16,203
Neil? Neil. It's Uncle Jack.

1020
01:30:17,121 --> 01:30:19,581
Listen, I need to speak to Daddy, kid.

1021
01:30:19,665 --> 01:30:21,542
He's gone, Uncle Jack.

1022
01:30:21,625 --> 01:30:22,835
Well, where is he?

1023
01:30:22,918 --> 01:30:24,211
<i>NEIL: I don'I' know.</i>

1024
01:30:24,294 --> 01:30:27,673
Listen, Neil, I gotta talk to him.
Get a message to him from me.

1025
01:30:27,756 --> 01:30:28,799
It's very important.

1026
01:30:28,882 --> 01:30:31,093
Allen never left the country.

1027
01:30:32,177 --> 01:30:34,430
Funny place to bump into each other.

1028
01:30:34,513 --> 01:30:36,390
- Gotta laugh, eh?
- Yeah.

1029
01:31:38,410 --> 01:31:39,661
Where is he?

1030
01:31:39,745 --> 01:31:42,581
- (SPEAKING SERBIAN)
- Where the fuck is he?

1031
01:31:44,374 --> 01:31:46,418
At home with your wife.

1032
01:31:58,597 --> 01:32:00,098
(SCREAMS)

1033
01:32:59,992 --> 01:33:01,660
Fucking hell!

1034
01:33:10,419 --> 01:33:11,670
(SCREAMS)

1035
01:33:12,296 --> 01:33:14,047
You've been busy, ain't you, mate?

1036
01:33:14,131 --> 01:33:17,467
Nice little diversion you set up, yeah,
when you saw we was onto the bank.

1037
01:33:17,551 --> 01:33:20,304
Very clever. Almost pulled it off as well.

1038
01:33:20,387 --> 01:33:23,348
Just one thing you didn't take into account.

1039
01:33:24,266 --> 01:33:25,726
Me, you cunt.

1040
01:33:26,143 --> 01:33:30,314
Now, I'm gonna ask you a question.
You answer it if you want to live.

1041
01:33:30,397 --> 01:33:32,274
Where's Trebolt going?

1042
01:33:38,030 --> 01:33:39,948
I ain't fucking about with you, mate!

1043
01:33:40,032 --> 01:33:41,783
A friend of mine is over there on your wall,

1044
01:33:41,867 --> 01:33:43,869
he's in a spot of bother
and I ain't about to let him down,

1045
01:33:43,952 --> 01:33:47,789
so you better tell me what the fuck
I want to know or I will shoot you.

1046
01:33:47,873 --> 01:33:50,584
- Answer me! Where's he fucking going?
- (SPEAKING SERBIAN)

1047
01:33:50,667 --> 01:33:53,462
In English, motherfucker.
I don't speak your language.

1048
01:33:53,545 --> 01:33:55,631
- Home.
- How's he getting there?

1049
01:33:55,714 --> 01:33:57,674
- Boat
- What boat? Where?

1050
01:33:59,468 --> 01:34:01,553
<i>Gravesend. Pegasus.</i>

1051
01:34:02,429 --> 01:34:04,806
<i>Gravesend. The Pegasus.</i>

1052
01:34:06,475 --> 01:34:08,894
That wasn't too difficult, was it?

1053
01:34:12,981 --> 01:34:14,858
This is for Nancy.

1054
01:34:14,941 --> 01:34:17,402
Drop the gun! Drop the gun!

1055
01:34:19,237 --> 01:34:22,491
- Calm down. I'm police.
- Don't talk! Just drop the gun!

1056
01:34:22,574 --> 01:34:25,077
I'm Officer George Carter
from the Flying Squad.

1057
01:34:25,160 --> 01:34:26,662
Keep your hands behind your head!

1058
01:34:26,745 --> 01:34:29,581
Go in my pocket and you will find my badge.

1059
01:34:34,252 --> 01:34:36,254
Lower your weapons, boys.

1060
01:34:39,424 --> 01:34:43,970
Got a report that an IC1 was seen
assembling a firearm in a nearby vehicle.

1061
01:34:47,766 --> 01:34:50,602
Gotta say I'm disappointed it was you, Carter.

1062
01:34:50,686 --> 01:34:53,021
Yeah, well, it weren't gonna be Regan, was it?

1063
01:34:57,359 --> 01:34:58,985
There's your man.

1064
01:35:26,638 --> 01:35:29,474
Haskins. You can't shut up shop now.

1065
01:35:32,477 --> 01:35:34,938
I told you, I know where Trebolt's at,
I know where he's going.

1066
01:35:35,021 --> 01:35:37,774
I just annihilated four geezers
to get you that information

1067
01:35:37,858 --> 01:35:39,151
and you don't even wanna hear it!

1068
01:35:39,234 --> 01:35:40,902
Take it easy, Carter.

1069
01:35:40,986 --> 01:35:44,406
I just got you off the hook
and it won't happen again.

1070
01:35:45,115 --> 01:35:46,992
I'm all out of favours.

1071
01:35:47,576 --> 01:35:52,205
You can take all your intelligence
down to the NCI when they interview you.

1072
01:35:53,957 --> 01:35:55,625
Haskins, come on!

1073
01:35:56,626 --> 01:36:00,756
You're just gonna leave Jack in prison?
Locked up like a criminal?

1074
01:36:02,841 --> 01:36:04,593
What about the Sweeney?
What about Regan? Come on.

1075
01:36:04,676 --> 01:36:08,430
You're starting to sound a lot like him.
And you're better than that.

1076
01:36:08,513 --> 01:36:11,183
You got a big future ahead of you
if you can just keep your bloody head down.

1077
01:36:11,266 --> 01:36:13,518
- Don't patronise me.
- I'm not.

1078
01:36:14,060 --> 01:36:15,729
Look at the way he's ended up.

1079
01:36:15,812 --> 01:36:18,440
Is that what you want?
To become like Regan?

1080
01:36:18,523 --> 01:36:21,276
You know fuck-all about what I want,
what's best for my future.

1081
01:36:21,359 --> 01:36:22,944
I'm my own man.

1082
01:36:23,403 --> 01:36:26,198
I didn't join the police
to be some constable out on the beat

1083
01:36:26,281 --> 01:36:28,158
or to sit behind a desk.

1084
01:36:28,241 --> 01:36:30,869
I became police to be in the Sweeney.

1085
01:36:31,828 --> 01:36:35,707
So if there's no Sweeney,
there is no Officer George Carter.

1086
01:36:38,001 --> 01:36:39,878
Oi, come here, Carter.

1087
01:36:40,170 --> 01:36:42,255
Carter! I'm talking to you!

1088
01:36:44,716 --> 01:36:46,218
<i>What's Pegasus?</i>

1089
01:36:50,597 --> 01:36:53,141
It's the name of Allen's boat. Why?

1090
01:37:41,940 --> 01:37:44,609
Pig, it turns out you've got a friend.

1091
01:38:03,962 --> 01:38:05,171
Oi, oi.

1092
01:38:05,964 --> 01:38:08,425
How the fuck did you manage that?

1093
01:38:10,927 --> 01:38:12,596
I couldn't believe it,
they had fucking pictures.

1094
01:38:12,679 --> 01:38:15,265
Hundreds of pictures of us. They've been
watching us the whole fucking time.

1095
01:38:15,348 --> 01:38:16,683
We walked right into this.

1096
01:38:16,766 --> 01:38:19,185
Trebolt blew the safe in the jewellers
to make it look like Allen,

1097
01:38:19,269 --> 01:38:22,397
'cause he knew we'd go after him.
That's why it was so easy to find him.

1098
01:38:22,480 --> 01:38:24,774
We had him cuffed in a cell
and we let him walk.

1099
01:38:24,858 --> 01:38:28,361
I knew Francis Allen was involved.
We had him on a fucking plate.

1100
01:38:28,445 --> 01:38:30,947
- (MOBILE PHONE RINGS)
- it's Haskins.

1101
01:38:31,531 --> 01:38:32,741
I'm listening.

1102
01:38:32,824 --> 01:38:35,160
<i>HASKINS: The Pegasus has already entered
British waters.</i>

1103
01:38:35,243 --> 01:38:37,996
<i>Repeat, Allen's boat is already here.</i>

1104
01:38:39,205 --> 01:38:42,042
<i>And, Jack? I'm sorry.</i>

1105
01:38:57,599 --> 01:38:59,476
(GULLS CRYING)

1106
01:39:01,561 --> 01:39:03,021
(SHUSHES)

1107
01:39:30,632 --> 01:39:32,425
- You all right?
- Yeah.

1108
01:39:33,718 --> 01:39:35,470
Well, let's have it.

1109
01:40:09,629 --> 01:40:11,423
You go to the front.

1110
01:40:21,599 --> 01:40:23,643
<i>(WOMAN SPEAKING ON RADIO)</i>

1111
01:40:48,710 --> 01:40:50,754
(BOAT CREAKING)

1112
01:41:03,892 --> 01:41:05,143
Fuck me.

1113
01:41:05,852 --> 01:41:07,270
(GROANING)

1114
01:41:19,032 --> 01:41:23,578
I knew you'd take the bait, Regan.
All I had to do was dangle a carrot.

1115
01:41:24,871 --> 01:41:27,165
- (SCREAMS)
- Fucked

1116
01:41:28,500 --> 01:41:30,585
- Mug!
- You're such an easy target.

1117
01:41:30,668 --> 01:41:33,338
I'm gonna blow your fucking brains out.

1118
01:41:34,297 --> 01:41:36,132
(SPEAKING SERBIAN)

1119
01:41:44,265 --> 01:41:45,767
(GROANS)

1120
01:41:51,189 --> 01:41:53,233
Fuck. George!

1121
01:42:20,510 --> 01:42:22,554
George, cover me!

1122
01:42:26,224 --> 01:42:27,475
(GROANS)

1123
01:42:58,006 --> 01:42:59,632
(CAR HORN BLARES)

1124
01:43:16,649 --> 01:43:18,776
(CAR HORNS BLARING)

1125
01:43:55,146 --> 01:43:56,814
Move, move, move!

1126
01:44:08,743 --> 01:44:10,745
(TYRES SQUEALING)

1127
01:45:16,352 --> 01:45:18,354
(GROANING)

1128
01:45:18,646 --> 01:45:20,732
(ENGINE CHOKING)

1129
01:45:36,914 --> 01:45:38,708
(ENGINE STARTS)

1130
01:46:22,126 --> 01:46:23,378
(GUNSHOT)

1131
01:47:07,672 --> 01:47:09,173
You're nicked.
