SILVERLAKE ANIMAL RESCUE
That one.
Here boy.
You're heavy.
And slobbery.
There.
You're a good boy!
You're my good boy!
5 YEARS LATER
Hello!
Honey, I don't have much time!
Daddy?
Are you okay?
Something's came up at work, honey.
Daddy is not gonna be home for a while.
I don't understand.
You can't go back to the house Penny, okay?
What's happening?
It's alright. You won't be alone.
You have Bolt.
I've altered him.
He can protect you now.
~ BOLT ~ Subtitles by Darkopal
Thank you, which of course, is wonderful news.
Everything is positioning nicely.
There he is, doctor Calico!
Any luck getting our guest to spill his guts?
Oh, his guts will spill.
One way or another.
Never! I'll never talk.
Daddy!
You're beginning to irk me profesor, I'm irked.
And that will not do. As the package arrived...
...I think it might make our dear friend a bit more communicative.
I'm sending an agent to pick it up.
Gorgeous! Have him bring it to me on the first flight.
Bolt, let's go!
We only need the girl!
- What? - Where is Calico?
I'm not talking to you.
Bolivia, Bolivia, Calico is in Bolivia!
Near lake Rogaguado!
Lake Rogaguado? I should have known!
Come on Bolt, let's go.
Bolivia!
There is a flight leaving in 10 minutes.
Bolt, zoom zoom!
Bolt, dispatch!
Puppy!
LOCK
Good boy!
Airport!
Bolt, speak.
Okay, okay...
Good job, buddy.
Mission accomplished!
That's a keeper!
It's alright tough guy, you caught them all.
Don't worry Bolt, you've saved the day again.
Good boy!
Airport!
Bolt, speak.
Boom mike!
- We got a boom mike. - That's a boom mike.
That's sloppy.
The dog could've seen that. He could've seen that!
Uh, who cares if the dog sees a boom mike?
Forgive me for answering a question with a question,...
...but who are you?
Mindy Parker, from the network.
Of course. Let me ask you, Mindy from the network...
What do you see here?
- Uhh... the dog? - "The dog" she says.
Oh, Mindy. Poor, poor Mindy.
Am I missing something?
You're missing everything, Mindy.
You see a dog. I see an animal that believes...
...with every fiber of his being, every fiber...
...that the girl he loves is in mortal danger.
I see a depth of emotion on the face of that canine the likes of which...
...has never been captured on screen before.
Never, Mindy from the network.
We jump through hoops to make sure Bolt believes everything is real.
It's why we don't miss marks. It's why we don't reshoot.
And it's why we most certainly do not let the dog see boom mikes!
Because, Mindy from the network,...
...if the dog believes it,...
...the audience believes it.
Wow. Okay, you want reality, here you go chief.
The show's too predictable.
The girl's in danger, the dog saves her from the creepy english guy, we get it.
There's always a happy ending.
And our focus groups tell us 18 to 35 year olds are unhappy.
They're not happy with happy.
So maybe you should, I don't know,...
...spend a little less time worrying about the dog's method acting,...
...and more time figuring out how to stop 20 year olds in Topeka...
...from changing the channel.
Because if you lose so much as half a rating point,...
...so help me, I will fire everyone in this room, starting with you!
How's that for real?
There. Perfect.
You saved me again, Bolt.
It's okay, it's nothing.
No more bad guys.
Do you want some food, Bolty? Huh? Are you hungry?
You've got them, Bolt, no one is gonna hurt me.
Bolt, look at me. I'm fine, see?
Come here buddy, come here!
Go, get it Bolt! Go, get it!
Yeah, that one is no funny either.
Well, what we have here?
Your old buddy, Mister Carrot!
Oh, Bolt!
You know I have to go.
Yeah, you are my good boy.
And there she is, my little superstar!
Let's get to that "Teen" vogue cover shoot.
Mam, I wanna take Bolt home for this weekend.
- Well, I... I'm... - Oh, that be nice. That be great.
That would. A little girl and her dog.
Nothing better that.
So I can bring Bolt home?
As your friend, I say yes, absolutely...
...but as your agent, I have to remind you. This is Bolt's world.
He has to stay right here. Okay, let's go.
But he never gets to be a real dog.
And it will be only for the weekend and I just once...
What? You know what? It's a fair question. Let's do this, let's put a pin in it.
Pin in, there you go. Now, let's let that hang there a little bit...
...and then we'll address that when we thought things through, okay?
Good enough for everybody? Smiles all around!
Let's get out of here. Come on.
I don't need to think it through. I wanna take Bolt home.
Look at this face! I have a little girl at home,...
...love of my life. I would do anything for her.
And I would trade her for you in a heartbeat!
True story.
That reminds me, uh, we need to begin over to wardrobe.
Let's go.
- I need every... - I... I just...
So, the dog thinks this is all real?
Oh, yeah. Hear new. Guy never leaves the set.
It's unbelievable. Whenever I get a chance this is the perfect way to unwind.
I like to start with an evil laugh.
Hello, hairballs!
You may have one today Bolt, but in the end...
...we will get your little Penny.
Not likely cat. For you've choosen to follow the path of evil,...
...ultimately we'll destroy you, along with your fiendish puppet master.
- Wow! - I know. Okay, watch this.
She is a goner, dog. But green-eyed man has a plan...
...and soon he will execute it.
Yeah and then he will execute her!
Nice!
I would super bark you both back into the hole you crawled out of...
...but I need you alive...
...because I got a little message for you to take back to your green-eyed man.
You tell him, his old friend Bolt said he...
Is it long?
- Is what long? - The message.
Is it a long message? Because I have a horrible memory.
Yeah, I'll make a brief, all right? You tell him I said, I'm gonna...
You know what? Why don't we do this?
You remember the first half of the message and then I remember the second.
And then we can pass it on green-eyed man together.
I don't care how the message is translated, alright?
Just do it, okay? Tell the green-eyed man, that I will not sleep,...
...I will not rest until my Penny is safe from his evil clutches.
You tell the green-eyed man, I'll...
Way too many words! I was like, "what?", and then I was like "huh?"...
...and then "I got a little bored". Some about clutches?
Anyway, I'll do my best! Ciao!
By the way, huge fan, love it, love you, gotta go. Thank you!
Get back here, you... You sick! Revolting, low some little...
Dogs!
Cats!
I'll never let them get you, Penny!
You ready, Bolt?
Let's widen out camera three.
Ready four! Go four!
And... driver.
Thanks, Larry.
Alright Scooter, right the grade. Ready on to propel bars.
And track with them!
Calico's super computer.
If we can access it...
...we'll find and learn where they're keeping my father.
The weapon is hot.
"Heat vision" time.
Bolt, stare!
Now!
Nice move.
Come on, come on!
Such devotion... It brings tears to my eyes!
Calico!
Your father's discoveries could be a great use to our organization.
I'm sure, he will be more commutating...
...now that I've got his "lucky Penny"!
Bolt!
World domination is waiting my grasp!
How did your focus groups feel about the end of this?
You asked for unhappy 18 to 35 years olds,...
...I give you unhappy 18 to 35 year olds.
Bolt, it's okay Bolt. I'm fine.
Guards, stop her!
- Hey, hey! - Bolt!
- Hold on! - Listen to him.
- He needs to know I'm okay. - No, you're not okay.
You've been kidnapped by fiendish Doctor Calico.
At least that is what the dog needs to think but...
...just imagine, close your eyes and imagine how excited he'll be...
...when he saves you, tomorrow. OK?
But he's gonna be freaking out all night. Please, just let me...
Wait a second. What's that behind your ear?
Is that a... Yes, it is! It's a pin!
Let's do this. Let's take the pin and put it in this conversation.
And we will not take it down, no m'am, until this matter is resolved.
- But I just... - What's that reminds me up?
The DVD release junket. Let's get going. It's a big push.
I want to go with a modern looks.
Alright, okay. Let's give her some air. Let's not crowd the talent.
I've been working on my evil laugh. Is there an evil laugh like...
Like that?
Okay, here is the thing. You're not ready for the evil laugh.
You could do a chuckle, like a mildly upset chuckle...
...after my evil laugh. Listen to mine.
Hey Bolt!
Climbing here!
Bolt, come back!
I'm too late.
- Bolt, help! - I'm coming Penny!
Bolt, help!
Hold on, Penny. Hold on!
Penny!
Bolt! Here, Bolt!
Okay, Bolty, okay! Stay cool! You're cool, Bolty!
The green-eyed man!
Penny! Penny!
Penny!
Target acquired!
It ends here!
Penny!
Penny! They moved her.
There is no time for formalities, brothers.
My person is in danger and I... I...
- Wow! What're you doing? - Oh, I'm sorry.
- You wanna sniff mine first? - What?
- Not from around here, are you? - Hey, stop it!
- What? - This is serious.
Hey, there. Are you lost sweety?
Hey, wait!
Why can't I bend these stupid bars?
Oh, buddy!
You got your head stucked pretty good, huh guy?
Hey guys, come here. Check this out! He's got his melon stucked.
Yup, that is one stucked melon.
Hey, hey buddy, take it easy! Slow down.
I will not take it easy, because I'm missing my person.
Hey buddy, relax. Like this, turn and pull. Turn and pull.
Forget about it, you'll be out no time.
What are these things? They're weaken me.
- Polystyrofoam packing peanuts. - Styrofoam?
This has a "green-eyed man" written all of it!
Have you seen the man with a green eye?
You know, I gotta say something, if I could say something here.
You look familiar. Joey, look at this guy's mug.
Yeah, you know, I could've sworn I've seen this guy before.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I gotta tell ya, I never forget a face.
- He never does. - Oh, yeah, yeah.
- Never. - Yeah, he's really good with the faces and such.
Listen, listen! The man with the green eye. Tell me what you know, birds!
- I know this dog. - Yeah, yeah, me too!
I gotta remember, it's gonna kill me. Hold on.
No, I don't know. I, I, I thought I know.
Hey, you ever hang out down on 14th Street with a stray named Kelvin?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. Kelvin, the Labrador. - What?
You gotta gimme something here, cause this is redonkulous.
Absolutely redonkulous!
Capisch redonkulous! Ya know what that means?
You pigeons are useless.
I need someone on the inside, someone close to the green-eyed man.
- A cat. - Oh, a cat?
Yeah, a cat. When I find him...
When I find him, I'm gonna make that cat wish never born.
I think we know just the cat.
Right on time, Saul. Come on in.
Okay, Saul, nice work. Let's find some mustard next time. Okay, babe?
Yes, Mittens. Thank you, Mittens.
Is that an everything bagel, Ted?
- Attaboy! - Good day, Mittens.
Louie!
What is this?
It was a slow week. I mean, that's half of what I got.
You hear this, Louie? I'm starving here.
And when the old stomach starts talking, it ain't talking to me.
- It's talking to... the claws! - Not the claws! Please!
I'm holding these bad boys back as best as I can, but the thing is it's not up to me.
The stomach got a direct line to these babies,...
...and I'm picking up a lot of chatter!
So, I'll talk to the claws, but in exchange...
...next week, all your food comes to me. - But that's not our deal!
I bring you half, you give me protection! That's our deal.
Yeah, well, the deal just expired. Now, get lost.
Mark my words, Mittens.
One day, someone's gonna stand up to you! Someone's gonna teach you a lesson!
Yeah, I'm really scared now.
You should be!
Aaah! Okay! You...
Where is she?
- Who? - You know why I'm here!
Okay, okay! Look buddy, I don't know what you're getting at, but...
Come on, Mittens. Just tell the guy where she is.
- Tell the dog, make him happy. - Yeah, yeah, come on, Mittens! Tell him!
Joey, Vinnie, Bobby, my boys!
Would you tell the crazy canine that he's got the wrong cat?
- You got her, pal! - That's her!
- She's the one! - That is definitely the right cat!
Looks like we're gonna do this the hard way.
Whoa! Aaah! Are you crazy, man?
Hey Joey, do we go to far on this?
You kidding? This is the best day in my life.
You work for Ben and Bart, who work with the man green-eye.
They take him Penny. Where is she?
- I don't know what you're talking about. - This is becoming tiresome cat...
...in fact, I feel a yawn coming on.
Okay, okay, I'll talk, I'll talk. I know where Penny is.
Yeah, they have her.
Yes, the men in black and the guy, the guy with the blue eyes.
Blue eyes?
Oh, green! Yes, green! The one green eye.
You just can't stop lying, can you cat? It's in the genes. This is gross.
I know, it's disgusting, I disgust myself.
Hollywood?
But if you put me down, I'll show you where she is.
You know, I hope you appreciate the risk I'm taking here.
Every bone in my evil cat body is telling me...
...not to betray the trust of the green-eyed man.
Okay, this is a top, top secret map...
...of the entire earth!
Now, we're over here, by the green lady with the big torch.
And my boss has Penny locked up...
Right, right over... Here, here! By the waffle with the sun glasses!
Now all you need to do is get from here to there.
Well, I told you where you find her, so if you'll just untie me, I'll be on my way.
I'll release you cat, when we found Penny.
Excuse me? That wasn't the deal! We had a deal!
Your deal just expired.
She said that to me, not 10 minutes ago.
The irony!
Perfect.
Hmm... padlock.
Listen Cujo, I got some pretty wicked claws under these mitts,...
...do not, I beg of you do not make me bring out these bad boys!
It gets ugly!
- What are you doing? - Stay back!
If I stare at the lock really hard, it'll burst into flames and melt.
Now I'm concerned on a number of levels.
- Easy, watch! Watch it those! - I'm good. We gotta go.
Intruders!
Hey! Slow down you screwy borrowed of mind...
- Oh, boy, this thing is heavy. - Hey, hey! Put it down.
I forgot the keys.
I'll be right back.
Hey, lucky Penny.
Thanks. Now move your butt.
Okay, just upon your left. Yeah. I got... No, I got, I got mine.
You got it?
It's on tipping my tongue. I know that dog.
I'm telling you, Joey. Bobby, you guys looking at me like, you don't know. I'm telling you...
...I know this dog. I've seen him somewhere.
You remember it tonight, when you're perching.
Alright, that's... That's will happen.
- I've got some good news! - Really?
Yes, I do. I just booked you, on the tonight show's "main guest"!
That's right. That, I mean...
...which means just absolutely nothing, if Bolt is still missing.
It's not even a good news, like whatever, so up tonight show. Who cares? I don't care.
It's okay, baby.
- He must be so scared. - Scared? This is Bolt we're talking about.
He's not scared of anything.
I bet Bolt would want you to the tonight show.
It is...
I just... or maybe not.
Bolt loves you very much sweety. And you're here.
He couldn't have gone far.
Welcome to Ohio. So much to Discover!
So, if you got super powers, I guess that would make you, what...
...like some kind a super dog? - That information is classified.
Oh, come on! Like, what's your best power?
You go to move. How about flying? Can you fly?
Don't be silly, I can't fly.
Okay, okay, fine. If you don't have any powers,...
...you don't have any powers. What's it to me?
- I have super bark. - A super bark? Wow, you're kidding me?
What exactly this one do with the super bark?
I really can't talk about it. It's classified.
I suggest you pipe down and take me to Penny.
You're awfully attached to this Penny character, huh wags?
- She is my person. - Oh, please. She's a person.
And if you ask me, the only good person is a...
Styrofoam!
Tag and roll!
Tag and what?
What? What is this red liquid coming from my paw?
It's called blood, hero!
- Do I need it? - Yes.
So if you want it to keep inside your body where it belongs,...
...you should stop jumping off trucks doing eighty on the interstate!
Yeah, well, normally I'm a tad more indestructible. Must have been the...
Styrofoam! That stuff, it weakens me!
- What are you doing? Put that down! - Alright, that's it. I've had with you.
Untie me, pooch or I'm gonna... I'm gonna... Uhmm... I'm gonna seriously wound you!
I'm gonna seriously wound you with this styrofoam!
Are you mad? You don't know the power of styrofoam!
Oh, you bet on that, baby. And I'm about to unleash it!
- The power of the styrofoam! - No!
Alright, cat. Okay, you win. I'll untie you.
That's a weird push to put a piano!
- Are we gonna have any more problems, cat? - No, no, no. No more problems.
I'll take you to Penny.
Ah! What is that?
- What? - That!
Okay, you have two seconds to tell me what you've implanted in me, cat!
Poison? A parasite? Poison? Wait, I just said that, didn't I?
See, I'm all discombobulated! I can't think straight!
Oh, I don't believe this. You're hungry!
- Where is the antidote? - Okay, okay! Alright!
There's your antidote...
Food!
Alright! Who wants burgers?
- I'll take one. - Me too!
Watch this!
Go on, use the dog face. This gonna be beatiful.
You know, beg. Do the dog face!
What? The dog face? What is that mean?
Figures, I'm tied to the one dog on earth who doesn't know how to beg, huh.
Okay, if you want the food...
...the antidote, you're gonna have to do exactly what I say.
No, not likely. You're a degenerate creature of darkness.
Yeah, yeah, granted but that's it.
All I'm asking you to do is just tilt your head a little.
You could do that, can't you? Come on.
- More, more... - This is stupid.
No, no. Come on. Work with on this. Please, you're almost there.
Oh, boy!
Okay, try the other way.
There you go! Tilt up! Down. Now, a little smile. Lose the smile.
Drop your left ear. Your other left. Okay, the other way was better.
Now, drop them both. Hold it right there.
And ever so slightly, look up.
Soup is on, baby!
Here you go.
Yes!
Oh, look at you, you little guy!
Here you stupid cat!
...what really happened. And why is that matter to you?
- Because I'm involved. - With rich?
- With James. - If you and James are romantic...
...I wanna know all about it. - What? So you can...
Come undone!
You gonna get stop that leaking!
Go Larry, go Larry, go Larry! Stop!
It really does help and it really releases the serotonin and...
Hey, man! This time we'll do it my way!
Well, hello puppy. Did you come for some of grandma's butter bean dumplings?
You wait right there.
Look at you. You're quite a little actor, huh?
I haven't eating like this in ages.
Hey, look! My stomach distended. How great is that!
Yeah, well. Don't get used to it. We gotta keep moving.
But this place is a gold mine. What's wrong with you?
Every week, new RVs bring us new suckers, who bring us new food.
Look around! It's perfect.
Do my eyes deceive me? Is this some apparition I see before real?
Or could it be? My hero!
Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh! Oh, my gosh!
You're Bolt, the super dog. You're fully awesome.
Wait a minute. You know this dog?
- Oh, I do. He is fully awesome! - Ah, yeah, yeah. We've established that.
- Who are you? - I'm Rhino.
Rhino, the hamster?
Well, you know, my ancestry isn't all hamster. I'm 1,16% wolf...
...with a yellow wolverine and there is some...
But that beside the point!
We have before us a legend. Bolt, the super dog!
You can outrun speeding missiles, and burn through solid metal with his heat vision.
And best of all, he can obliterate large structures with his super bark!
Wait a minute, you've seen the super bark?
- Have you been observing me? - Oh, yeah. I watch you all the time.
- That's incredible. - Oh, it's nothing, really.
But I'm always so vigilant! No one can avoid my detection!
- You are a phantom. - Ah, if you say so...
Oh, hey! Check it out!
Take a gander at this Bolt action. Scary, huh?
- It's like, we're twins. - Yeah, scary.
- So, where is Penny? - She was kidnapped by the green-eyed man.
Kidnapped? This is terrible! She could be in grave...
Grave danger. I know. But I've captured this cat.
An agent of the green-eyed man, I presume!
You presumed correctly. She is taking me to Penny.
You! You are a vile vermin.
How did you sleep at night? Penny is the most wonderful person ever.
She loves Bolt and he is awesome. And you're a monster!
How dare you disrupt their relationship with your evil!
- Die! Die! - Whoa! Whoa!
I can take her Bolty.
- Die! Die! - Easy, easy, Rhino. Easy.
You're right, we need her alive.
We?
Yes. Bolt, I can be a valuable addition to your team.
- I'm listening. - I'm lightning quick.
I have razor sharp reflexes and I'm a master of stealth.
Plus, I'll keep the cat in check.
- The road will be rough. - I have a ball.
- There is no turning back. - I guess I have to roll with the punches.
- Easy won't be a part of the equation. - Promise.
Gotta warn you, going into the belly of the beast, danger in every turn.
- I eat danger for breakfast. - You're hungry?
- Starving. - Welcome aboard.
Hey, can we talk for a second?
I don't know what's going on here but I'm just a little bit concerned...
...about the numbers of lunatics on this trip.
- My limit is one. - He is coming with us.
But I...
Move it prisoner, we're losing daylight.
I agree.
Now, we need to find a fast set of wheels.
I've got a better idea. Follow me!
Okay, so what we do here is we give the target a quick fly over...
...we adjust the trajectory and land dead center. Am I missing anything, Rhino?
Just the knowledge that every minute spent in your company becomes...
...the new greatest minute of my life!
No, forget it! How do you say, "No way, I'm doing this" in crazy?
- Calm down, cat. You're with me. - That's the problem.
Oh, would you be relax?
Every time you get this on the "magic box", it was awesome!
Magic what?
You know, "magic box", people stare at.
Wait a minute! Is this "magic box" have moving pictures on it?
Yeah and Bolt's pictures are the best.
Bolt's pictures? Of course! He's a former...
Oh, no! Oh, no! No, wait, wait! Bolt, guys! Hear me out!
- Let it begin! Let it begin! Let it begin! - Wait, you're not a super he...
What are you doing?
Mittens!
Mittens, take my paw. I need you alive.
Yeah, of course! Stay away from me!
- Squeeze my paw, I'll save you! - No, you won't. You're not really a...
Bolt!
Saboteur!
Ah! Ouch! You moron!
- Stop it! I'm trying to help him. - Help him? Yeah, right.
Don't worry Bolt! I'll stop her.
I can't hold it.
- Let it go, you monster! - Bolt!
The real world hurts, doesn't it? But you wouldn't know about that, would you?
Get down here cat. We don't have time for this.
I'll get a ladder.
Look, genius. You're a part of a TV show.
You know what that is, television? It's an entertainment for people.
It's fake! Nothing you think is real as real!
That's has preposterous!
Think about it Bolt. Since you got lost, none of your powers are working, aren't they?
For the first time you're hungry, you're bleeding.
I mean, do you really think that you were born with a birthmark...
...in the exact shape of a lightning bolt?
It's my mark of power, cat!
It's the mark of a make-up artist, dog!
You're ridiculous! Now, get down here!
No.
Mittens, so help me, I will super bark you out of that tree.
Yeah, go nuts. Let's see how that works out for you.
You leave me no choice.
Oh, the super bark. Scary, scary!
Yeah, that's really really super.
It's not true. This is not true.
Wow, that one felt really super.
Wait! No, it didn't.
Okay, okay. I get the idea, you can stop now.
That's enough! Seriously dog, stop! I'm not kidding.
Would you stop?
Okay, fine. You're the super dog. Bolt, be quiet, please.
Bolt, we gotta run!
- Bolt! - Come here.
ANIMAL CONTROL OFFICER
LOST DOG - BOLT
He is white with a lightning bolt on his side. REWARD! Please help me get my friend back.
Look who we found young lady! It's Bolt!
- They found him! - Bolt!
Isn't that right you little puppy dog?
That is not Bolt.
Well, that depands on how you look at it.
You know, when I was little, I want a bicycle for my birthday...
...but my parents got me a baseball glove. So...
You know what I did? I pretended that baseball glove was a bicycle.
And I rode it to school every day.
True story.
- It's not him. - I think it's him. I do.
Thank you.
Look kid, it's time we are honest with you.
If we don't get back in the production, people are gonna lose their jobs.
- Good people with families. - But Bolt is still out there.
- And I... - I know, we feel for you.
And the last thing we wanna do is ask a little girl to make a grown up decision.
But it's come to that, we need you to move on.
We need you to let Bolt go.
It must be made of styrofoam!
No, no! No, no, no! Please, it can't end like this!
Stop worrying cat. I'll get us out of here.
You can't, Bolt. You got nothing.
No super strength, no super bark.
And no heat vision.
Listen to me, okay? We've been taking to a place...
...where humans go animal shopping, alright?
And this is what humans do. They always pick the cute ones.
The ones that look like you, Bolt.
But the rest of us never come back out.
I said, I'll get us out of here, alright?
My hero!
Ring, ring. Who is it? Destiny!
I've been expecting your call.
Oh, would you give it up already? You're liquefying, whatever brains you have left.
I can not be contained in any container.
You quitter! Watch this!
I did it! I'm back!
That styrofoam is a wicked stuff.
Totally awesome! There is no truck that I know that can keep Bolt and Rhino!
Rhino, what are you doing here?
Oh, nothing. I was enjoying an evening stroll and thought that I'd just...
...pop the hatch on hack that containment unit!
- You... You opened the door? - Yes, I did.
That's... That's great, Rhino.
Yeah, that's... That's really good.
Alright, let's go get the prisoner back.
I... I can't do it.
What did you say?
- I can't. - What... Who are you?
Rhino, you're just... Just a little...
- You are Bolt. - But I'm not...
Who single handedly destroyed the green-eyed man's under sea labs?
Me, but...
And who foiled his plan to infiltrate the Olympics with gymnastic cyborgs?
- Who, Bolt, who? Who? - Me, but none of them...
You! You can, Bolt. Because, all over this planet...
...there are animals who feel like they can't.
Like a little hamster, who once spent his days in a RV park.
Dreaming of the day when he too would save a little girl from danger and be told:
"You did it! You did it, Rhino! You saved the day."
They need a hero, Bolt!
Someone, who never mind what the odds, will do what's right.
They need a hero to tell them that sometimes the impossible...
...can become possible, if you're awesome!
Well, you're right about one thing, Rhino.
Mittens does need a hero.
I guess I'll have to do.
Such modesty! Now, who is going to save that cat?
- Me. - Who? Tell me who?
Me.
I'll get my ball.
ELMWOOD COUNTY ANIMAL SHELTER
Over there.
There it is.
This will be just like the time, you infiltrated Calico's R.D. cover base!
It's not gonna be exactly like that, Rhino.
We're gonna have to do things a little differently.
Oh, stealth mode!
ADOPT A PET WEEK
- Good night, Ester. - Good night, Lloyd.
Lloyd?
Lloyd Spoon, you jump out and scare me, and I'm gonna pepper spray ya again!
I swear it, it's like I work with toddlers!
Threat nullified.
I feel alive!
There's a guard.
I'll snap his neck.
We need to get away him from that door.
- Ball! - Ball?
Ball! Ball! Ball! Ball!
Oh, come... I'm just... I'm read... I'm just... Oh, god! Just quiet down!
Mittens?
Bolt!
- What are you doing here? - I'm busting you out.
You came all the way back here, for me?
Yeah.
But how did you... I mean... You don't have any super powers.
- I know. - Really?
- Yeah. - Wow!
- Crazy day for you, huh? - It's been a lot. Yes, it has.
- Are you ready for this? - No.
Me neither.
Hey, hey, hey! What is twisting your giblets?
Hey, wait! Where did you get that hamster?
Give it, give it.
Hey, wait!
Initiating escape!
Lloyd, block the door! Block the door! Block the door! Block the door!
Super bark! Super bark!
Sweet Sister Francis! What did you do my new truck?
You hold that back later!
Oh, sally Ester!
- Both you boys need serious help! - Spicy eyes!
- We need a ride. - I've got a big one.
You're welcome!
I can't believe it! My whole life, I wanted to see a real live super bark.
You are legendary!
Mittens...
If... If I don't chase bad guys, then what am I?
I mean... What...
Don't worry about it. Being a regular dog,...
...is like the greatest gig in the world, okay?
Look, I'm gonna let you in, on a little secret, okay?
A little known cat secret.
You know why we hate dogs?
Because we wanna be dogs, we have dog complexes.
But... But what are dogs do?
Slubber, sleep, chase tails, chew shoes.
You don't exactly need a master's degree.
You know, most dogs living in a place like this.
And uhm... Well, I don't know, they do things like...
Out of this? But... But...
- And this is your dog bowl. - What is?
This! The entire floor! It's the ground, goes to the hound.
How cool is that?
And on cold nights, this and a ball of yarn...
Oh, it doesn't get better than that.
You... You seem to know a lot about this places.
Yeah, I did my time in one of these, but I'm more be an alley cat at heart, you know?
Sprung out first chance I got, never looked back.
Rhino is awesome! He is so awesome!
He is... He is beyond awesome. He... He is "be awesome"!
He is... Uh!
I... I am "be awesome".
I think it's about time I introduce you to a regular dog piece d'resistance.
- Get your head out. - Why?
Just do it.
This... This is awesome.
And stick your tongue out!
This is totally awesome! Why don't you try it?
No, thanks. It's really a dog thing.
# I have got so much to give,
# I swear I do.
# I may not have nine lives,
# but this one feels brand new.
# Yes Ive lived a good one.
# I have tried to be true.
# There are some things I never realized,
# till I met you.
# How the wind feels on my cheeks,
# when Im barking at the moon.
# There is no home like the one youve got,
# cuz that home belongs to you.
# Here I come
# back to you.
# There is no home like the one youve got,
# cuz that home belongs to you.
# Well I was in trouble, bad.
# I was so confused.
# I may not see in color babe,
# but I sure can feel blue.
# I have been a lot of things,
# they may not all be true.
# My experience was so mysterious,
# till I met you.
# Now the sun may rise in the east,
# but Im barking at the moon.
# There is no home like the one youve got,
# cuz that home belongs to you.
# Here I come
# back to you.
# There is no home like the one youve got,
# cuz that home belongs to you.
Hey Bolt, wake up.
Come on, I've got a surprise for you.
Okay, okay, no picking.
Alright. Now, open them.
Bask in the glow, baby!
Just let me give you the grand tour, okay?
This one, this one is mine. And this one is all yours.
- Mittens, I... - Oh, I found this really soft pillow thing for you.
And get this! I found some styrofoam and I stuffed it inside...
...which I thought both kind of creative and ironic. You know what I mean?
- Mittens, I don't think that... - Check it out!
Total privacy and completely sound proof!
- Yeah, well, I don't think that I... - Okay, I lied. It's not sound proof.
- But, you know... - Mittens, I can't stay here.
- What? - We're one waffle away from Penny.
You still going back to her?
Mittens, she is my person.
Ouch! Ouch! Ear, ear!
Look at me, Bolt. I'm real.
Now, how about this, huh? Is that real?
Is this look real to you? Or that? Is that real? Or that?
How about that, Bolt? She is an actress.
- She is just pretending. - Not Penny.
There is no Penny. She is fake.
No, you're wrong. She loves me.
No, no Bolt. That's what they do, okay?
They act like they love you. They act like they'll be there forever.
And then one day, they pack up all their stuff and move away,...
...and take their love with them.
And leave their declawed cat behind to fend for herself!
They leave her...
...wondering what she did wrong.
I'm sorry Mittens, but...
Penny is different.
Then go.
- Mittens, I... - Get out of here, Bolt!
I never should take a pitty on you.
- Oh, Mittens... - Just get out of here, Bolt!
You take care of Mittens.
That meat lover's pizza is not loving me back at all!
- Hey there, Rhino. - Morning, cat.
- Where is Bolt? - He is... Uh...
- He's gone. - Bolt left?
Yeah, but he... Uhm... He instructed me to tell you, that he... Uhm...
He had to face the green-eyed man alone.
- Where are you going? - To Bolt.
But he doesn't need us anymore.
Trust me, I've seen that a million times before.
In the cold, dark night before the battle when the steely fangs of evil...
...are sharpened and posed to strike...
...the hero must go and face his greatest challenge alone.
But if Bolt's taught me anything,...
...it's that you never abandon a friend in a time of need!
When your team mates in trouble, you go.
Whether they ask or not, you go!
Not knowing if you're coming back dead or alive...
He went the other way.
...you go! Knowing how deep the shrapnels gonna pierce your hide, you go!
Penny!
No way! Wow! Bolt! I'm really a big fan of yours, brother.
I'm Blake. This is my partner, Tom. Tom, say what's up.
- What's up? - Wow!
Oh, no!
And this is our personal assistant, Billy...
...who is supposed to wait up on the wire.
Bolt, I've been admired you such a long time and there is something I always wanted...
...to tell you if I ever get a chance to meet you. And now...
Okay Billy, that was horrifying what you just did.
Why don't you make yourself useful? Go, get me some bread crumbs. Whole grain. Go!
Whole-wheat is not the same thing as whole grain, Billy!
- Not the same, Billy! - Do not come out with whole-wheat!
Or pumpernickle Billy!
- Okay guys, but I really gotta get going. - I know. I know you're a busy dog.
But if you got a second, we'd love to pitch you an idea for your show.
Tom's better pitching. I'll let him taking from here.
Tom has got the spotlight.
Wait for it!
- Aliens. - Holy snap!
- Aliens? - Audiences love aliens.
Holy crap!
- It'll be huge man, huge! - You can't touch us!
I love it. I'll tell you what, if you guys can help me find Penny,...
...the girl from the television show...
...I'd love hear more about this aliens idea, but on the way.
- We got a nibble! - Don't freak out.
This is how you blew with Nemo.
We open exterior outer space scenery.
Calico comes for your Penny.
And then you squish him.
And as the tractor beam is pulling Penny toward to alien mother ship...
...we fade to black.
And we have a great pop song for the end credits.
Talk your people. We're ready to move on this.
He's so on board!
There it is!
The most terrifying place on earth!
At long last, we've arrived at he belly of the beast.
The lair of the green-eyed man!
Rhino, hold up!
Hold up!
What, what is the problem? I'm... I'm pumped!
Listen, this may be really hard for you to understand...
...but you see, sometimes things aren't what they seem to be...
...and sometimes when you think something is really real and it's not,...
All of my training has prepared me for this moment.
Die! Die!
Prepare yourself, foul man-beast! I will eat your pancreas...
...with your spleen and then I will rip your liver out of your...
You're so cute with your little whiskers.
Oh, I had a hamster just like you when I was a kid.
Bolt!
Bolt! You're okay!
Oh, you came back!
Bolt, I thought I've lost you.
You're my good boy.
Good boy.
Okay, people. Let's move to stage 7 and do it for real.
- I miss him. - I know, honey.
I do too.
First positions, please!
Okay, hold still a little sweetie.
15, take 1. Mark.
And action.
Ah, Professor.
I'd like to thank you for granting us an access...
...to that labyrinthian mind of yours.
You know I'd never do such a thing.
Unless it was only way to save your little girl's life!
- Penny! - Daddy!
Bolt! Here, Bolt!
Your dog is nowhere near...
Get that dog!
Go! Go, go!
It's okay, boy. Come here.
Fire! Fire! Fire! It's fire!
Hey Wags!
Mittens? What are you doing here?
Long story, short I was tied to a delusional dog and dragged across the country...
...but that is not important now. The real question is,...
...what are you doing here and why aren't you in there?
You were right about her, Mittens.
She, uh, well... it wasn't real.
No Bolt, it is real.
I was in there just now, I saw her face after you left.
She's broken hearted.
She doesn't want just any dog, she loves you.
She's your person, Bolt, and you are her dog.
- Bolt, you just gonna have to trust me on this. - Mittens, be quiet!
- No, you need to hear this! - No, no, seriously, be quiet!
What is it?
Penny!
- Help! Please, help! Help! - Hold on!
Please!
Oh, my gosh! The stage!
Yeah, you better run!
- I'm on your six. - What are we do?
Just make sure I get inside that building!
Bolt?
- Is anyone still in there? - I don't know.
Coming through!
- It's a good day to die! - Not on my watch, rodent!
Bolt!
I knew you'll come back.
Bolt, zoom zoom!
Bolt...
Bolt, just... just go on and out.
Go.
It'll be okay.
You're my good boy.
I love you.
Have you seen my daughter? Has anyone seen my baby?
- Did you hear that? - Yeah.
Quiet! Everyone be quiet!
It's the super bark!
- It's coming from over there! - Come on, let's go, go!
Over here! We found them! They're here! We found them!
Alright, we got a RG coming through people! Make it hole!
For your own safety, stay away from the building!
- Bolt. - Sweetie!
You're okay! Oh, you gotta be okay. You're gonna be just fine.
- She is stable. - We're gonna take her to the hospital...
...just to be safe.
I'm so, so, so sorry does happened.
I can't imagine, what you must feeling.
No mother should ever have to go through something like this, but I...
...promise you, we're going to make this work for us.
I'm talking cover stories, production deals, executive producer credit...
This is so great!
We quit!
No, no, wait! Let's not make any rush decisions.
Let's put a pin on it.
I'm afraid your injuries far more severe...
...then we've previously thought, my dear.
We have to completely reconstruct your face.
Have a look.
At least Calico won't be able to recognize me.
Calico!
Bolt!
What?
Aliens!
That is totally unrealistic.
- Absolutely "redonkulous". - You could say that again.
Oh! Oh, yeah! Right there! Right there! Over!
Yeah, that's the spot.
Hey, silly doggy!
That's a keeper.
You wanna go play outside, huh? You wanna go play outside?
Let's go!
- Is that dog look familiar? - Nope. I've never seen him before in my life.
# There is no home like the one you've got,
# cuz that home belongs to you.