With every sun comes a new day.
A new beginning.
A hope that things will be better
today than they were yesterday.
But not for me.
My name's Eep.
And this is my family.
The Croods.
If you weren't clued already,
by animal skin
and sloping forehead,
we are cavemen.
Most days we spend in our cave.
In the dark.
Night after night, day after day.
Yep. Home sweet home.
When we did go out,
we struggled to find food
in a harsh and hostile world.
And I struggled to survive my family.
We were the last ones around.
There used to be neighbors.
The Gorts, smashed by a mammoth.
The Horks, swallowed by a sand snake.
The Erfs, mosquito bite.
The Throgs, common cold.
And the Croods.. That's us.
The Croods made it,
because of my dad.
He was strong,
and he followed the rules.
The ones painted on our cave walls:
Anything new is bad.
Curiosity is bad.
Going out at night is bad.
Basically, anything fun is bad.
Welcome to my world!
But this is a story about how
all that changed in an instant.
Because what we didn't
know, was that our world
was about to come to an end.
And there were no
rules on our cave walls
to prepare us for that.
You're supposed to
wait for my signal, Eep.
Eep?
We've been in that cave forever.
Three days is not forever.
It is with this family.
Eep, will you come down here?
You're being so... so dramatic.
No, no, no, Sandy, come back here!
Remember the signal.
Good girls wait for the signal.
Ugga! / As soon as I get Sandy, I'll go
back in, and you can give the signal.
No. But you're already out now.
I am waiting for the signal, Dad!
Never mind, Thunk.
Just come out.
But if you don't give me the signal,
how do I know you're my dad?
The signal isn't so you know it's me. It's
so you know I wasn't eaten by an animal.
Then why is the
signal an animal noise?
I mean, doesn't that
just confuse things?
I'm still waiting
for the signal.
Mom, we're ready to leave!
Mom?
Still alive!
It's still early.
And you're still fat.
Breakfast formation!
I want to see some real
caveman action out there!
We do this fast. We do this loud,
we do this as a family,
and never not be afraid!
Yay! Breakfast..
Who's up?
We'll flip for it.
- Call her in the air.
- Heads!
Tails. Thunk's in.
Positions!
Okay.
Thunk, go!
Come on, Thunk.
Way to go! Take it to the cave!
Release the baby!
Get 'em, Sandy, go!
Get them, Mom!
Old lady down!
Eep, avenge me!
Thanks.
- Eep!
- Heads up!
Hey, Dad, can we eat now?
Just wait til we get home.
Eep, put on the brakes!
Eep!
Who's hungry?
Good one, Dad.
Here you go, Thunk. Drink up.
- Sorry, dad.
- Looks like fast food tonight!
That's all right. I ate last week.
Two knuckle warning!
Go, go, go, go.
Come on, come on.
Darkness brings death.
We know this.
The moon is full.
Bath night.
- Run for your life!
- You too, Mom.
I don't want to lose
my protective layer.
Mom, you've got ants.
See? Sandy doesn't fuss.
- Is she still out there?
- You know she hates the cave, Grug.
Please come back tomorrow.
How can she not like the cave?
It's so cozy.
It is a little dark, right?
It's not that dark.
Eep!
Eep?
Come on, I gotta close the cave.
Eep!
Okay! Okay!
Come on.
Eep! Come down!
- That was too close!
- I was watching. I was fine.
- What were you doing up there, Eep?
- I don't know.
- What were you looking for?
- Nothing.
- Well then, why did you go up there?
- I don't know!
Why don't you know?
Stop looking for things!
Fear keeps us alive, Eep.
Never not be afraid.
What's the point of all this?
- What was that?
- I mean, why are we here?
What are we doing this for?
No one said survival is fun.
Nothing is fun.
- Would you come down here?
- Grug? - Eep? - Yes?
- Off! - Yes. Okay...
- Off!
I just don't see why she needs
her own ledge.
That's all. That's what this is about.
She's working through some things
and needs some her own space.
What things? How long
is this going to take?
Really? I mean, she already
doesn't listen to me. Hey!
See? She's listening.
If she wants to survive,
she has to follow our rules.
- How about a story? Eep loves those.
- That's a good idea.
- How about a story, huh?
- Yeah, tell us a story.
Okay. Can I borrow that? Thank you.
Eep! Your old favorite!
I haven't played with
that thing in years.
Tonight we'll hear the
story of Krispy Bear.
A long time ago, this
little bear was alive.
She was alive because
she listened to her father
and lived her life in routine
and darkness and terror.
So she was happy.
But Krispy had one terrible problem.
She was filled with...
..curiosity.
- Grug!
- Yes, yes.
And one day, while she was in a tree,
the curious little bear
wanted to climb to the top.
What? / And no sooner had she
climbed to the top,
she saw something new and..
- ..died!
- Just like that?
Yes! Her last moments of
terror still frozen on her face.
Same ending as every day.
I get it, Dad. I get it. I will
never do anything new or different.
Good man, Thunk.
All right, everyone sharpen your teeth
and let's pile up.
- Air..
- You talk?
I'm person, like you.
Sort of... like you.
Okay, okay. Hey, hey, hey, hey.
Could you, could you mind not..
That tickles.
Hey, hey, hey. Hey!
Quiet! I am not
supposed to be out here.
- Eep's gone.
- What? Grug!
Stay in the cave.
Wow, you're really strong.
- No! It's mine!
- Please.. - No! No!
- But it is dying! - I caught it.
- I can fix it. Please...
Please. I hate the dark.
Come on, come on...
It does what you tell it?
Well, yeah, sort of.
- Sun?
- No, no. Fire.
- Hi, Fire.
- It's not alive.
But you said it was dying.
- Sorry. Uh..
- It comes from where you came from?
- No. No, I make it.
- Make some for me.
- Okay! - Make! It doesn't
come out of me. - Make!
Make! Make it!
You do this a lot.
Are you dead?
Can I have your fire if you're dead?
Hey, those are cold!
You think?
Listening shells, activate.
I concur. Tiger girl, we
need to leave immediately.
I don't even know you.
- I'm Guy.
- Guy?
And this is Belt. Cook,
conversationalist, navigator.
Also keeps my pants up.
- What are 'pants up'?
- Who are you?
Eep.
Let me clarify, Eep.
The world is ending.
- What?
- I'm calling it... "The End."
- How do you know?
- I've seen it. It's coming this way.
First, the ground is gonna shake.
Then it breaks open.
Everything falls in.
Fire. Lava. I don't mean to
sound too dramatic, but...
Believe me, everything we're standing
on, all this right here, will be gone.
We've got to get to high ground.
I know a mountain.
That way.
It's our only chance.
Come with me.
- I can't.
- Okay. Okay.
Here.
If you survive, call me.
Thank you.
Hello?
Hey!
Dad!
Are you hurt?
What took you?
Nothing. I left on my own.
- You.. what?
- Dad, let me explain.
You never let me talk.
You're grounded.
- Eep!
- Mom!
Grug! What happened?
You know what, I am so mad right now
that I can't talk to her.
- Eep?
- You'll never believe it.
I found something new.
- New?
- New is a big problem.
Wait. Wait. / Eep, stay inside
the family kill circle.
- It wasn't bad.
- New is always bad.
- No. He was nice.
- What? Excuse me? He?
Well, I thought he was a warthog,
but then he turned into a boy.
Strange. Usually it’s the reverse.
Eep’s got a boy hog!
Eep’s got a boy...
There was a boy. Watch, okay?
I'm gonna call him.
What is wrong with you?
- It was dangerous.
- It was beautiful!
You want to see dangerous? Here!
- Ow! My sniffer!
- Okay, Eep, that’s it.
We’re going back to the cave and you’re going
to stay in there until you’re older than...
- You know.. her!
- What?
You can't keep me inside forever!
He said this would happen.
Get to the cave!
Go!
Look out!
Stop!
- Is everyone okay?
- Yes.
Grug, the cave. It’s gone.
No..
You really need to see this.
- We should go there!
- No. No.
No one is going anywhere.
What else did that boy say?
Come on, Gran!
Just go. Go! Go!
One, two, three, four, five...
Six.
- Where are we?
- I don't know. I'm not sure.
Down. In a lower place.
But, one thing’s for sure, we
can't go back the way we came.
Sandy? What is it?
No, no. Wait.
Come back, Sandy.
We can't be out in
the open like this.
We need a cave.
Now step where I step
Okay. Stay quiet.
Hopefully nothing big
knows we’re here yet.
Wait!
Okay.
So Dad, just to be clear, are we
looking for the exact same cave?
Okay. If it was me... I was throwing this
out there. If it was me choosing the cave,
I would go with a smaller cave.
Wait!
- Dad?
- I’ll take care of this.
All right, Dad, get 'em!
Go get ’em!
Hah! I’m loving this.
Dad, I got this. Just stop
running to their fists!
Grug, when you’re done,
we should get going.
That’s right! You
can't get past this!
Climb! Climb! Climb!
Move!
Cave! Go! Go!
Come on, hurry up!
Let’s go! Come on!
Hey, look! This cave
has a tongue! Awesome!
Okay. That's one, two,
three, four, five...
Six. / And seven, if we’re
counting Chunky the Death Cat.
He’s scared of the dark!
Wait, we’re scared of the dark.
Kill circle!
Eep!
- Cavies!
- Cavies?
Cavemen! Stand back!
They’re practically animals.
- See their bony, sloping foreheads?
- Yeah!
- The huge primitive teeth?
- Yeah?
The excessive body hair?
- That one’s even got a tail!
- Yeah.
All right. Close your eyes. I’m
going to have to take their lives.
No! It won't help.
They’re my family.
What?
- The sun is in his hands!
- No, no, it’s fire.
- Where did it come from?
- He made it.
- Make some for me!
- It doesn't come out of him.
Make! Make it!
You know, you’re a
lot like your daughter.
Oh, great, now he’s broken.
Oh, it’s a baby sun!
Whoa! Hey! Stay back!
We don't know what it wants.
Now we’ll all sit here and
wait for the sun to come back.
And tomorrow we’ll find a new cave
and pretend today never happened.
Isn't this fun, Eep?
Eep, don't touch him!
Goodness knows where he’s been.
Dad, Sandy’s hurting fire!
Sandy! No! Fire is not a plaything.
- What a cute little guy.
- Hey, stay back!
No, no, no, wait!
It likes me! Hey! It’s biting me!
Thunk! Try hiding from
it in the tall, dry grass!
Stop, please! I’m only nine!
It’s biting me!
Fire babies!
- Hi.
- So, your dad, he’s trying to kill me.
Yeah. But I won't let him.
Hold on, son, come back!
It won't stop.
Stop touching me!
Get out!
Eat up, babies!
Die!
I win!
They’re not so scary
once you get to know them.
- Who are you people?
- Oh, I’m sorry. We’re the Croods!
And you are?
- Uh, Guy?
- Hai, Guy.
Looks like magic!
And smells like food.
No, don't eat it, it's new!
Still alive!
Come on, keep eating!
Hey, where's Guy?
Going somewhere?
The Mountain. High ground.
End of the world, remember?
That already happened.
It destroyed our cave.
No. That was just the beginning
of the end.
The end of the end is still coming.
Eep!
Drop it.
We can't let him go!
What if we don't find
a cave before sunset?
What if it takes a few days?
What if the birds come back?
We need his fire, dummy!
Fine. You’re staying with
us until we find a cave.
What? No, I’m not! Don't
make me part of this!
Stay here if you want, but let me go.
I’ve got a dream, a
mission, a reason to live!
Not anymore!
Umm, I’ve got an idea.
Let’s go to that Mountain!
- It's too far.
- Dad really has his heart set on a cave.
There are caves on that Mountain.
Have you been there?
It's a mountain. Mountains are
safe. Mountains have caves...
..water. Sticks.
Mom, did you hear that?
I can get my own stick!
Yes! Sticks. And caves. Caves and
sticks. Crazy sticks. Let's go!
Quiet!
That thing is weird.
No. No. No. It's okay, Sandy.
That's just a belt.
I’ve made a decision. We’re
going to.. that mountain!
Don't ask me why.
It’s just a hunch.
- It just feels right.
- I don't know, Grug.
We’ve never really walked that far.
I don't think my feet can do that.
I’ll never live long
enough to get there.
Let's do it.
Oh, come on, just think.
Our whole family, packed together
on a long, slow trip across country?
Days and nights with just each other?
We’ll tell stories. We’ll laugh.
We’ll become closer as a family.
Get her off! Get her off!
If you’re not ready to challenge her,
then don't look her in the eye.
Could you keep your big giant
arms on your side of the trail?
Isn't this fun? We’re taking
our first trip together.
Stop shoving, or I will
pull out your tongue!
Do you want me to turn
this family around? Do you?
Because I will turn this
family around so fast!
- Dad, I gotta go!
- Come on, you can hold it.
- I don't think so.
- Sandy, take that out of your mouth.
- I don't touch it.
- Gran!
I still gotta go!
- Fine, just look around and make it fast.
- Quit it!
- Something bit me!
- I don't blame it!
- Dad, can I take a turn carrying him?
- No.
- How about now? - No!
- Now? - No!
- Now?
- I can do this all day long.
No, no, no, and still no!
I’m not dying on an empty stomach.
Grug, we’re all pretty tired!
- We’ll eat when we get there.
- It's taking too long!
I'm grabbing a snack.
Don't do that! He will cut you.
That's not food, he's a pet.
- My pet.
- What's a pet?
An animal you don't eat.
We call those children.
No man should have a pet.
It's weird. And wrong.
- It's, it's food!
- No, no, please!
Not that. That!
Food fixes everything. All right,
show me your hunting face.
Not you! You're still grounded.
Come on, Thunk.
My feet hurt.
- You look tense.
- I'm not tense.
Angry girl wants to do what
they're doing.
I wasn't ready.
Hang on, Thunk. I'm coming.
Why are you doing this?
- What are they doing?
- Hunting.
You stay away from me!
No, seriously, what are they doing?
You’ve got a ton of eggs.
Just make another egg!
Now you’re just rubbing it in.
There. Who is hungry for scorpion?
What happened to
the egg and the bird?
You know, we lost 'em.
But when the bird stepped on me
and pushed me into the ground,
the scorpion grabbed a hold of me, and
you know, one thing led to another
and here we are, eating him.
- So, win-win.
- Not enough.
- Not enough. I need more. I need more!
- Oh, look at that.
She’s not gonna eat me, right?
You’re too skinny. If she was
going to eat anyone, it would be...
Mom! She locked her jaw!
I could use stick!
Get her stick!
Stay away! You sick old monster!
Hurry! Put the stick in her mouth!
Hold her still. Use a rock.
Would you just hit her legs?
Why are you rolling away?
I just want something to eat!
You had bug for
dinner. Plenty of bug!
Please! I'll let you help me hunt.
- Really?
- Don't wait on me!
Tell my story.
- Okay.
- What do you call this?
- A trap.
- What does it do?
Well...
How long have you been alone?
So what do we do?
How's your acting?
You're good at this.
- Sorry. No. Okay.
- Excuse me.
- That’s my arm!
- Okay, I'm moving it...
- It didn't step on your trap-y thing.
- Yeah, I noticed!
Where's Eep?
She's awesome.
- Eep!
- Dad, no!
It’s an avalanche of flavor!
Looks like we won't
have any leftovers.
What are leftovers?
You know, when you have so much
food to eat you have some left over.
Well, we never have that much food.
Grug, how about a story?
That’s a good idea.
How about a story, huh?
Yeah, a story! Tell us a story!
Once upon a time there
was a little tiger
who lived in a cave with her family.
There were a lot of rules,
but the big, simple one
was to never leave the cave at night.
And the door was so heavy, you’d
think it would be easy to remember.
- So easy to remember!
- I know.
But while everyone was asleep,
- ..she went out anyway.
- No! - Yes!
And no sooner than she
did her cave was destroyed
and everyone had to go
on this long, sucky walk,
with some weirdo they met,
and died!
The end.
I did not see that coming.
Twist ending!
My stories never end like that.
Yes! Two stories in one night!
Okay, but it won't
be as good as Grug’s.
Once upon a time, there
was a beautiful tiger.
She lived in a cave with
the rest of her family.
Her father and mother told her:
"You may go anywhere you want,
but never go near the
cliff, for you could fall."
And die.
Good story.
But when no one was looking,
she go near the cliff.
For the closer she came to the edge,
the more she could hear,
the more shecould see,
the more she could feel.
Finally she stood at the very edge,
and she saw a light.
She leaned out to touch it.
- And she slipped.
- And she fell.
And she flew.
Where did she fly?
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow?
A place with more suns in
the sky than you can count.
- It would be so bright.
- A place not like today, or yesterday.
A place where things are better.
Tomorrow isn't a place.
It's, It's, It's..
- You can't see it!
- Oh, yes. Yes, it is. I’ve seen it.
That’s where I’m going.
Well, we are going to
shut our eyes and sleep.
And when we wake up,
we’re going to find the place
that has everything we want.
- Tomorrow?
- A cave.
That was too close.
It almost caught us.
- I was watching. We were fine.
- We gotta move faster.
Do you people have any other
speed aside from 'wander'?
- I’ll take 'shamble' at this point.
- Hey, um, do you have a minute?
- How did the tiger fly?
- I only share when I’m outside the log.
- I’m funny that way.
- Leave this to me.
Hey, Thunk, you have
a spider on your face.
Oops.
He's loose!
Do not step on those
weird, pointy rocks!
You mean these rocks?
- Do not step on these rocks!
- Step aside, girl.
Hello? Nobody's listening!
No one is listening!
You cannot walk on those!
Come back here now!
Well, there goes out
chance for survival.
And our log!
Okay!
Jumping doesn't help. I mean, just
briefly, but it doesn't get any better!
Okay. Do not walk on your hands.
The hands do not help at all!
I can help you, but we're going to
have to make a few changes around here.
The log ride is over.
Drop the log.
Now kick it away.
Farther.
- Really?
- Okay, smart Guy.
Now what?
Good fish, good fish.
Okay, now you can look.
- I love them! Where are my feet?
- They're still there.
Okay.
- You're really heavy.
- Really?
Thank you.
Hey, wait!
Whoa!
Okay, she's up. We're good.
I'm good.
These shoes are great!
Where do you get these ideas?
I'm calling it a brain.
I'm pretty sure it's
where ideas come from.
Dad, I don't have a brain.
We've gotten along just fine
without brains until now.
Cavemen don't need brains.
We have these.
That's I'm talking about!
Ideas are for weaklings!
Now let's get to that mountain!
- Wow, I love those.
- Good fish, don't eat my feet.
How did the tiger fly?
She jumped on the sun
and rode it to Tomorrow.
No, no, no, no!
Hi, Dad!
Bye, Dad!
- You've seen rain before, right?
- We don't get out much.
- Eep, looks dangerous.
- Ugghh..
Dad, you say that about everything.
- Careful.
- Really? Okay.
No, no, no! Not cool!
Not cool!
The bear says: "Your cave?
I've been dumping my
bones here since last week."
- That's a funny story!
- It's not a story, it's a joke.
- What's a joke?
- You know, just making something up,
to make you laugh.
- Here you go. - Thanks.
- One for you, and this one's for you...
Okay. Okay. That's enough.
I don't see why the kids
need their own shells.
So if anyone gets in trouble,
we can call the others.
Wait, you're saying we should split up?
We can try more paths at once.
- It's the fastest way through.
- The Croods stick together.
- Your way isn't safe.
- They can handle it.
- We can do it, Dad.
- No, no, no, no, no.
It’s my job to keep you
safe. I’m still in charge,
and we are not splitting up.
Except for you two.
And that's final.
Hello? Hello? Is everyone all right?
- We're okay, Grug!
- Dad? I'm freaking out a little bit.
Just tell me what to do. Just what
do I do? What do I do right now?
- Stay where you are! I'll find you.
- No! Too slow.
Everybody, keep moving
forward and we'll get out.
Dad?
Yeah. Okay.
Remember, never not be afraid.
You can do this!
It's gonna be okay. It's gonna
be okay. I'm gonna pass out.
Sandy! Sandy!
Give me another one.
You dropped these.
Come with me.
Here, boy, catch!
Gran?
Mom?
Grug?
I'll go get him.
Oh, good boy.
Who's my good boy?
You are. Yes, you are. Look at you.
You need a name? You want a name?
I'm gonna call you Douglas.
Can you do tricks?
Roll over.
Come on, Douglas. Roll over.
Good boy, Douglas!
I was in love once.
He was a hunter.
I was a gatherer.
It was quite a scandal.
We fed each other berries.
We danced.
Then my father smashed him with a
rock and traded me to your grandfather.
Croods, get down here!
Grug, they're okay.
Guy's with them.
Oh, Guy's with them.
Oh, okay.
Well, thank you, thank you for
bringing me that interesting Guy update.
Oh, okay. I'm gonna go up,
..and why don't you join us when
you stop being a big drag!
Sleep pile?
How about a story, huh?
Anyone?
And then Thork said:
"Know it, I drew it."
I know it was hard for
you to bring us along, but,
they had the best days in their lives.
Thank you for that.
I wanna show you something.
More suns in the sky
than you can count.
Every sun that crosses our
sky comes to rest up there.
- Tomorrow.
- That’s where we’ll be safe.
I’m going with Guy.
No, not my little girl.
- Come with us.
- I can't go without Grug.
Well, that makes one of us.
Count me in!
Really? Mom?
Now?
Grug has no idea how to protect
us. In fact, he has no ideas at all!
No. That's not true. What
about that one time he.. uh..
- He..
- Oh, face it.
If he actually had
an idea of his own,
I'd have, I'd have a heart attack and die!
- Grug?
- Dad? - Dad!
He's a big guy. How can he
just disappear like that.
Hey! Hey, wait. Let's ask that
ugly lady if she's seen Dad.
- I haven't seen him.
- Whoah!
- What are you doing?
- Yeah. Wow. I was up all night.
'Cos I got all these ideas kept coming to me.
- Is that a snake?
- Belt! New and improved!
It's even self-tightening.
What is that on your head?
It's called desperation.
I call it a 'rug'. Rhymes with Grug.
And this one, I call it
a 'ride'. Rhymes with Grug.
That doesn't rhyme.. / It's gonna
get us places faster than shoes.
Yeah! Try to keep up!
I wish I had a 'ride'.
Painting is a thing of the past.
I call this a 'snapshot'.
Let's do it again.
I think I blinked.
I call them 'shades'.
The sun doesn't hurt my eyes anymore.
- Where do you get these great ideas?
- Since I don't have a brain,
they're coming from my stomach, down deep
below, and then up again into my mind.
Grug, we have to keep moving.
See, I got ideas. I got thoughts.
Like this. I call it a 'mobile home'.
Isn't that something?
- I'm calling this one a 'lifterator'.
- Mom?
It's.. I know. It's bad.
I almost feel sorry for him.
No, I don't.
What are you trying to do, Grug?
I thought if I could
have ideas like Guy,
uh, maybe Eep would listen to me.
Maybe she wouldn't
want to go with Guy.
Oh, Grug. Is that
what this is all about?
And I also thought it would
kill your mother, so...
you know, win-win.
We're here!
Cave! Everyone inside! Come on!
Hurry up! Let's go! Let's go! Go! Go!
No!
- No more caves, Grug.
- What?
We're gonna jump on the sun and
ride it to Tomorrow with Guy!
Wait, wait, so you're
all going to do this?
Thunk?
Sorry, Dad.
You have to stop
worrying for all of us.
It's my job to worry.
It's my job to follow the rules.
- The rules don't work out here!
- They kept us alive!
That wasn't living! That was just..
Not dying! There's a difference.
Ugga, everyone, you
have to listen to me!
We'd be dead now if
we'd listened to you!
We have to follow Guy now.
- Guy..
- Guy, run!
This is pointless!
We've running out of time!
Everything is collapsing. You are
being irrational and counterproductive.
Big words anger me!
- Keep talking!
- Countermeasures!
Remember how you were this morning?
You changed,
remember? Idea man.
Modern man.
- I am a caveman!
- No, no, no, wait!
No! What is this stuff that
save you from my punches?
- Tar.
- No! - Please..
- No! I have to get back to them!
- You have to stop...
- ..struggling!
- No! - Grug, stop!
No one gets out of this.
Believe me.
I know.
- Your..?
- Family.
Yeah.
Sorry.
I was little when it happened.
The last thing my
parents told me was,
"Don't hide. Live."
"Follow the sun. You'll
make it to Tomorrow."
You followed the light.
My daughter is a lot like you.
No. She's like you.
She loves you but
always forgets to say it.
Just like you forget to tell her.
I guess I was just busy
keeping them all alive.
It's okay. That's what dads do.
That's right, and we
can't do that from here.
We need one of your ideas.
Come on, you can do it.
Belt! Emergency Idea
Generator, activate.
Ooh, I've got it.
- Wow!
- Yeah. I know, but,
he's doing the best with
what he has. Let's go.
There he is.
Belt, I want romance,
drama, sincerity.
Move me.
Okay, he sees us! That's our cue.
Now work it!
He's not coming over. I don't think
out puppet looks scared enough.
Scared? I’ll show you scared!
Hand me those acting sticks!
Hold on!
Yes! You did it!
- Grug!
- Dad!
Hey! We're okay!
Yeah. We're okay.
Grug, your call.
Take us to Tomorrow.
Hurry! Come on! We're gonna make it!
- You were right!
- There, there it is!
The sun! We can do it!
We can ride it to Tomorrow!
Run!
I don't, I don't understand. The
sun was right here! It was right here!
We have to go back to the cave!
Hurry!
Hurry, hurry, stay together! Let's
keep moving. Move! Move, move!
Everybody hold my hand! Thunk, let's go!
Go, go, go! Let's stay together!
Let's..
Grug, what's wrong with you?
Grug, we'll die if we stay here!
Grug, listen to me.
We've to get back to that cave.
No more dark.
No more hiding.
No more caves.
What's the point of all this?
To follow the light.
I can't change,
I don't have ideas.
But I have my strength.
And right now that's all you need.
No! We don't know what's over there!
Maybe nothing. It's too risky!
It's a chance.
I'll take that chance.
You know, I wanted to throw you away
ever since I met you.
- That's a joke, right?
- What's a joke?
He made it!
He made it.
- Okay, Thunk. Your turn.
- You're not coming, are you?
When you make it, so will I.
You did good.
Dadda.
- Gran..
- No mush, just throw me.
Wait! You surprised me today.
Lunkhead.
Still alive!
- Time to go.
- No! I have too much to say to you.
I need to fix everything,
and I don't have time.
I can fix it.
This works good.
What do you call it?
I was thinking of calling it, a 'hug',
because it rhymes with Grug.
But you can change it if you want.
No, no, I like hug.
I love you.
I..
Dad..
- I'm scared.
- Never be afraid.
There! I see him.
Hey! Hey, I did it!
Stay back! Stay back!
They're in trouble. Hang on!
I'm coming!
How do I get across?
I gotta think.
What would Guy do?
What would I do?
Hold this.
I.. have..
an.. idea!
Run!
Yes!
Douglas?
Hey, I know that guy!
Hold on!
It's not safe here.
I'll tell her.
I've never had to tell him.
Eep, if your dad were here,
he would tell you to...
Get out of the way!
Wow, you sound just like him.
- Dadda!
- He did it!
He's riding the sun.
- But.. not very well.
- Everybody out of the way!
Grug!
Where's the danger?
Who blew their shell?
I love you, too!
One, two, three, four,
five, six, and..
Seven.
And a half.
And eight.
- Nine..
- Douglas! Dad, you saved him!
Well, boy's got to have a pet.
Turns out I'm a cat person.
Uh.. No!
You really need to see this.
We should go there.
Yes! Coming through!
This is me.
My name is Eep.
And this is my family, the Croods.
If you weren't clued
by sunbathes and pets,
we're not exactly cavemen anymore.
Let's do it again.
I think I blinked.
Our world is still
plenty harsh and hostile.
But now we know the
Croods will make it,
because we changed the rules.
The ones that kept us in the dark.
And because of my dad, who taught
us that anyone could change.
Release the baby!
Well, sort of...
So from now on,
we'll stay out here,
where we can follow the light.