The Blind Side 2009
There's a moment of orderly silence
before a football play begins.
Players are in position, linemen are frozen,
And anything's possible.
Then, like a traffic accident, staff begins to randomly collide.
From the snap of the ball to the snap of the first bone
Is closer to four seconds than five.
One mississippi.
Joe Theismann, the redskins quarterback
Takes the snap and hands off to his running back.
Two mississippi.
It's a trick play, a flea flicker,
And the running back tosses the ball back to the quarterback.
Three mississippi.
Up to now the play's been defined
by the what the quarterback sees.
It's about to be defined by what he doesn't.
Four mississippi.
Lawrence Taylor is the best defensive player in the NFL
And has been from the time he stepped onto the field as a rookie.
He will also change the game of football as we know it.
...and we'll look at it with the reverse angle one more time.
And I suggest if your stomach is weak you just don't watch ...
Legendary quarterback Joe Thiesmann
never played another down of football.
Now, y'all would guess that more often than not
The highest paid player on an NFL team is the quarterback.
And you'd be right.
What you probably don't know is that more often than not
The second highest paid player is, thanks to Lawrence Taylor,
A left tackle.
Because, as every housewife knows,
The first check you write is for the mortgage
But the second is for the insurence.
And the left tackle's job is to protect the quarterback
From what he can't see coming. To protect his blind side.
The ideal left tackle is big, but a lot of people are big.
He is wide in the butt and massive in the thighs.
He has long arms, giant hands and feet as quick as a hiccup.
This is a rare and expensive combination
The need for which can be traced to that monday night game
And Lawrence Taylor.
For on that day he not only altered Joe Theismann's life,
But mine as well.
Mr. Oher?
Do you understand..? Do you know why I'm here?
To... investigate?
Yes. To investigate.
I'm here to investigate your odd... predicament.
Do you find the odd? Your predicament?
Michael?...
Iono.
Can I... can I leave now?
No. You can't.
# strange face, with your eyes #
# so pale and sincere #
# underneath, you know well #
# you have nothing to fear #
# for the dreams that came to you #
# when you were young #
# told of a life where #
# spring has crawled #
# you would seem so frail #
# in the cold of the night #
# when the armies of emotion #
# go out to fight #
# but while the earth #
# sinks to its grave #
# you sail to the sky #
# on the crest of a wave #
They say you the coach.
Bert Cotton.
Tony Hamilton, but everybody just calls me big Tony.
Hey, big Mike! Check it out.
Not even locked!
White people are crazy.
I promises my mama boo, on her deathbed
That I'd get my son Steven outta public school
And into a church school.
I appreciate that, Tony. But I'm not involved with admissions.
This figured maybe I'd come to talk to you,
Seeing as you might need some players.
What kind of sport is he playing?
Anything with a ball. Boy's good, too.
Classes start in a week.
It would have to be for the next semester.
I know, what you're thinking, coach. But,
look here, I got money, alright?
See I'm mechanic at wilson's auto t'other side of town.
Look, what if somebody drops out or moves?
Could they get in then?
"They?" you only mentioned one son.
That's right, Steven. But there's another boy.
- Another boy?  - Yeah.
Big Mike.
Sleeps on my coach from time to time.
It's a bad deal. You know, his mama's on the crack pipe.
He ain't got nobody else.
He just wanted to come along for the ride.
- They're here? - Yeah.
The little one is Steven
And the big one...
Big Mike.
Swish!
Mike!
Come on!
Mother of god....
Steven Hamilton's paperwork looks acceptable to me.
And I believe he would do fine.
- but this other kid... - Big Mike.
Michael Oher gives us no reason to believe it,
Based on his record, that he would be successful here.
How bad could it be?
We're not exactly sure how old he is due to lack of records.
He has a measured iq of 80. Which is 6th percentile.
His grade point average begins with zero.
Zero-point-six.
Everyone passed him along
They gave him d's so they could hand
their problem off to the next school.
It's a brave kid.
For wanting to come here.
For wanting a quality education.
An education denied him by the poor
quality of the schools he's attended.
I tell you most kids with his background
Wouldn't come within two hundred miles of this place.
Coach Cotton, we understand your interest
in this young man's athletic abilities.
Now, he wouldn't be able to play sports
until he got his grades up anyway.
Forget sports!
Look at the wall.
Christian.
We either take that seriously or we paint over it.
You don't admit Michael Oher because of sports,
You admit him because it's the right thing to do.
Class, this is Michael Oher and he's new here
So I expect you all to make him feel welcome.
Mike, just take any empty seat.
This is a quiz based on the information you learned last year
In your science curriculum.
Don't worry. It's not gonna be graded.
I just want to see how much information we need to hit again.
Just answer whatever you know.
Thank you.
- Can I leave now? - Yeah.
Take your book.
Why should he always stay in our home?
- He's gonna eat all our food. - This is not true.
I try to be Christian abot the son, alright?
Let somebody else be Christian about this kid.
You want me to throw him out on the street like some dog?
Let somebody else take over the responsibility!
Should I throw him out on the street?
He's here all the time. I just want to be with you!
Alright. Alright.
You win. I'll take care of it.
I don't care if Patrick Ramsey approved the chair.
He's the NFL quarterback
not Martha frickin' Stewart.
Because there's a difference between
Bunny Williams and a la-z-boy.
No. See, when MTV cribs comes to his house
He's gonna be showing off his home theatre
All I'm gonna see is a brown barca-lounger.
No. No, listen to me. I'm the designer, my name's on it.
Deliver what I ordered! alright? Thank you.
- What'd I miss? - Collins has just got a dig.
It's a girl's volleyball, mom. You didn't miss anything.
- Come on Collins! move your feet! come on! - Good job, Collins!
Go!
Collins, we're gonna wait for you outside.
But don't double condition in the shower, you have homework!
I'm going over to Cannon's to study.
SJ! SJ, do not go to the girl's locker room again.
Come here! SJ, come here!
Well, the big kid's been here for a month
He's still not cutting in my class.
Why does admissions do this?
I mean, it's not fair to us or the boy.
Just setting him up to fail.
I don't think, he has any idea what I'm teaching.
And how would you know if he did? He won't even talk.
- He writes. - His name. Barely.
He thew this in the trash can.
I look, and I see white everywhere
White walls, white floors, and a lot of white people.
The teachers do not know I have no idea
of anything they are talking about.
I do not want to listen to anyone, especially the teachers.
They are giving homework and
Expecting me to do problems on my own.
I have never done homework in my life.
I go to the bathroom, look in the mirror and say,
"This is not Michael Oher."
He entitled it "White walls."
How's the spelling?
Hi.
Smile at 'em.
And that let them know you're their friend.
You're big Mike, right?
I'm Sean. But everyone calls me SJ.
It's for Sean Junior,
My father's name is Sean. Sean Tuohy.
He was a basketball star at Ole Miss, point guard,
Now he owns like a million Taco Bells.
Maina'.
- Who's that SJ? - Big Mike.
Get you feet off my dash.
Thank you. Put on your seatbelt!
Big Mike?
Mike, I got a call from someone at the police departement.
Do you remember the story in the papers while back about...
A man who fell off an overpass?
No one knew who he was and or he jumped, or...
Umm... anyway he... he passed away.
Mike, the man was your father.
They've been looking for somebody to notify and they...
They found your name on our registry.
I'm really sorry, son.
You were close to him?
When's the last time you saw him?
Iono.
- He knows it! - Who knows it and what is he know?
The material. Michael Oher. I gave him this test verbally.
- That even allowed? - A C?
- On how big a curve?  - He's been listening all along.
It's amazing what he's absorbed. Trust me.
He's listening to you, too.
Now, his reading level is low
And he's got no idea how to learn in the classroom.
I'm not saying he's going to pass but Big Mike is not stupid.
What, mom?
- Good job. - Yes?
Good job. Hey, I got a question for you.
Go.
There was a little girl about two rows back.
What was her name?
- oh, that was Kinsey. - Kinsey. Yeah.
I saw your little indian feathers get all ruffle up.
Yeah. She's nice.
SJ, don't let this go to your head but I've thought you were
very convincing in the role of...
- Indian number three. - Yes.
I tried out for the chief but they gave it to Andy Sung.
I can't be sure, but I think there was
some multi-cultural bias thing working.
Or maybe they just thought he'd make a better chief.
Dad, he's like Chinese.
Yeah. You're Irish.
And if you weren't the chief, how did you get that headdress?
Dad, I'm gonna need a few more of those free Quesadilla tickets.
And where does the acorn fall?
Hey, don't laugh too hard. The quesadilla saved our ass.
Don't use the a-word.
What is he wearing?
It's freezing.
What's his name again?
Big Mike.
Where's he going?
Hey, Big Mike! Where you headin'?
Gym....
Go ahead.
Turn around.
Big Mike... stop the car.
Big Mike.
Hey, my name is Leigh Anne Tuohy.
My kids go to Wingate.
You said you're going to the gym?
The school gym's closed.
Why were you going to the gym?
Big Mike?! Why were you going to the gym?
Because... it's warm.
Do you have any place to stay tonight?
Don't you dare lie to me.
I've seen that look many times.
She's about to get her way.
Come on.
SJ, make room.
Get in the car.
Come on.
- Where are we going?  - Home.
Oh no! That's my favourite part.
So cute.
How'd the dork do in the school play?
Umm... okay.
Collins, you know Big Mike from the school?
I'd give you the guest bedroom but it's full of sample boxes.
And the sectional in the family room
slides apart when you sleep on it.
At least that's what Sean says.
Mr. Tuohy sleeps on the coach?
Only when he's bad. Alright.
The powder room's right there
and we'll be upstairs if you need us.
Alright? Right.
Sleep tight, honey.
- Was this a bad idea?  - What?
Don't lie there and pretend like you're
not thinking the same thing as me.
Fine, tell me what you're thinking
so I know what's supposed to be on my mind
How well do you know Big Mike?
In case you haven't noticed he doesn't have much to say.
What's the big deal? It's just for one night, right?
It is just one night, right? Leigh Anne?
You don't think he'll steal anything, do you?
I guess we'll know in the morning.
Well if you hear a scream call the insurence adjustor.
Mike?
Big Mike?!
Big Mike!
You're gonna make me walk the whole way?
Alright then.
Where are you going?
Iono.
Well, are you spending thanksgiving with your family?
- Come and get it, childs! - Yeah, baby!
SJ
SJ!
Come on!
We have a ramble turkey.
Everyone thank your mother for driving
to the store and getting this.
- Thank you, mama. - Thank you, mama.
Limp football.
Eat all you want.
Come on.
Hustle, hustle! We got to get back to the game.
Oh yeah!
- Don't take my space. - You rush us, SJ.
- SJ, sit down. - Come on.
- No. - That's just fantastic.
Oh, y'all forget the potato salad!
- How's Ole Miss doing? - They're kicking butt.
Sean, salad.
- Thanks, mom. - Oh, good. Thanks, mama.
Yeah, mama.
- Come on! - Come on!
He wants to be bet.
- Hey! Mom! - Whoa.
But it's thanksgiving.
- Why are we in here?  - Shhh!
Shall we say a grace?
Heavenly father. We thank you for all
the many blessings on this family.
We thank you for bringing us a new friend.
And we ask that you look after us in this holiday season
that we may never forget how very fortunate we are.
- Amen. - Amen.
- SJ, the score? - Up by ten.
Collins, can you pass me the green beans, please?
Don't pick it with your fingers just take a spoon. Okay.
- SJ! Elbows!  - Sorry.
So, Big Mike. You like to shop?
Because tomorrow I think I'll have to show you how it's done.
I got clothes.
You "have" clothes.
And an extra t-shirt in the plastic bag does not a wardrobe make.
I have clothes.
Fine, let's go get 'em. Just tell me where I'm going.
Alright. Tell me everything I need to know about you.
Who takes care of you? A mother?
Do you have any mother? A grandmother maybe?
Tell you what, Big Mike.
We can do this the easy way,
or we can do it the hard way.
You take a pick.
Fine.
Tell me just one thing I should know about you.
Just... just one.
I don't like to be called big Mike.
Okay.
Tell you what, from now on, to me, you're Michael. Okay?
So... Michael, where we headed?
Right?
Savi. Savi, give it to me...
She's just the ...
- Hey, B.J.  - Hey.
- That's nice - Yo. Check it.
- Yay. - S7.
- For real. - Yeah.
You like that?
Do you know 'em?
Man, I got no idea.
It's where your mother lives?
- Let's go get 'em. - No. Don't get out.
Who's going to help you carrying your clothes, Michael?
Don't get out of the car.
No way.
Oh, that's Big Mike, man.
Oh, Big Mike is in the house!
Big Mike! Where you been?!
And who's that fine thing that driving you around like Ms. Daisy?
Hey, Dave.
You need to let me buy you new snickers,
Man. I'll take care, you know.
I run this over here and the whole village, baby. Got it?
Look at that.
Hey. Hey, D. Watch this.
They always go for the wing. Watch this.
Dear snowflake.
You like that? Yeah.
She wasn't home.
Well, we can come back.
She prolly moved to a nicer place.
I've lived in Memphis my whole life
And never been anywhere near here.
You're going to take care of me, right?
I got your back.
Just follow me yo.
Here we go.
Oh, we also got a parole for the ladies.
But everything we got that'd fit him is right here.
This is it?
If this is all you got,
why's it say "big and tall" on the sign?
Big and tall. You need "bigger and taller."
- Howl, if you need me. - Thank you.
You see anything, you like?
Hey. I got a just what you're looking for.
Well, one thing I know about shopping is
That if you don't absolutely love
it in the store, you won't wear it.
The store is, where you like it best.
So before you choose something think of yourself wearing it
and say to yourself, is this me?
No.
What about this one?
This isn't atrocious.
Alright, well, you go look over there I go look over here.
Who would imagine this many clothes are plastic?
Good lord... what is this made of?
That's the one?  That's the one you like?
Alright then.
Have a great day. Learn something!
Don't get your panties in a wad.
The best part about Paris was the food.
They use sauce like we use gravy.
I had to join a gym the day I got back.
Any of y'all spent much time on the other side of town?
Where exactly are you talking about?
Alabama Street... Hurt village.
Hurt village, that sounds like a threat.
You're not far off.
I think it might "hurt" me to go there.
It'd hurt your reputation to go there.
Well actually I'm from there but didn't mind hard work
And look where I am now.
Eating an eighteen dollar salad.
And it's a little soggy to be honest.
Leigh Anne? What is this sudden interest in the project?
Is this another one of your charities?
Wait. A project for the projects.
Oh, that's catchy. Money would raise itself.
Okay. Count me in, leigh anne.
Sj, you have two more minutes on that playbox thing, alright?
Oh, mom!
Michael, do you want to stay here?
Because... if you want to stay here... for awhile longer...
I can find some time to figure out a bedroom for you.
Because look at this, you've practically
ruined a ten thousand dollar coach.
You want to stay here, Michael?
I don't want to go anyplace else.
Well alright then.
SJ, you'd better be off that playbox.
That wasn't two minutes.
Good night Mrs. Tuohy.
I see on the admission that we're Michael's contact
for medical emergencies?
Sean wrote that in last week.
We needed contact number
and the ones listed weren't in service.
Sean. Love that man.
What's this?
The state makes schools measure for
career aptitude in eight grade.
And this just came with his file.
What does it say about Michael?
Spatial relations - third percentile.
Ability to learn - fifth percentile.
It's funny though. He tested in the
98th percentile in one category.
- Which one? - "Protective Instincts."
So over here we have a desk. Chest o'drawers.
You have a night stand, a light, and alarm.
Sean says all the pro athletes use futons
if they can't find a bed big enough.
So I got you one of those
'cause frame was heinous.
It's not about to let that in my house.
But I got you something nicer.
- It's mine?  - Yes, sir.
What?
Never had one before.
What? A room to yourself?
A bed.
Well, you have one now.
Okay. Define osmosis.
I think I know what.
It's when water passes through the barrier.
That's basically right, Michael. Very good.
Name the combatants in the battle of Waterloo.
I know that one. Umm...
The little guy, Napoleon... he was on one side and...
- ...and Duke's on the other. - Duke of Wellington.
Yeah. And the Duke of Wellington and Russia or something.
Prussians.
Enough with the rugby shirts.
You look like a giant bumble bee.
That Taco Bell, KFC catty corner,
the Long John Silver's on the next block...
You own all of 'em?
Yeah. We've got like hundreds.
Eighty five.
Is that why Mr. Tuohy don't have to go to work?
Ho! Ho! Hey! I'm working even when I'm not working.
What?
And y'all eat at those places for free?
All you want. It's awesome.
What do y'all do with the leftover food? From the restaurant?
Well, we have to throw some of it out,
what's already been cooked.
- That's too bad.  - Yeah. I'd rather sell it.
Seems like you could give it away or something?
- You should check into that, daddy.  - Alright, I will, SJ.
How come we ain't eatin' at one of your restaurants tonight?
Because tonight is a special occasion.
What?
I talked to coach Cotton and
He said that Michael's grades had improved enough
that he can go out for spring football in March.
Isn't that great?
Oh, man! You are gonna crush some people!
- Hey, guys. How you doin'?  - Great. Thank you.
I've got a design book I need to get.
Sean, go check on our reservation.
They're gonna seat us right away. Can't you wait after dinner.
Might be closed by then! Come on, SJ.
- Please. - I need some new magazines.
Michael, come on. Come on.
Collins! Collins!
Collins. Come on! Your dad's already pilled.
- Lets' go. Come on.  - Over here.
Remember this one, mom?
You read it to us like thousand times.
"And he gnashed his terrible teeth
and he roared his terrible roar."
I always liked this one.
Oh, Ferdinand... Me too.
Michael, your mama ever read either one of those books to you?
No?
It was a good steak.
- Thank you, daddy. - Thank you for lovely dinner, papa.
Here we go.
Michael?
Who was that boy you were talking to, at the restaurant?
Marcus.
Marcus. And he works there?
Yeah.
How do you know him?
He's my brother.
Well, we'd really like to meet him someday.
Would that be okay with you?
I don't know where he stays.
When's the last time you saw him?
When I was little maybe.
"Once upon a time in spain, there was a
little bull and his name was Ferdinand.
All the other little bulls he lived with would run and jump
and butt their heads together,
but not ferdinand.
He liked to sit just quietly and smell the flowers.
He had a favorite spot out in the pasture under a cork tree.
It was his favorite tree
and he would sit in its shade all day and smell the flowers."
- Good night.  - Good night.
What?
Why are you smiling?
I don't know. I'm just happy. Really happy.
Does this happiness have anything to do with Michael?
No.
It has everything to do with Michael.
Happy's good.
You know what I think we should do?
We should start a charity for kids like Michael.
Okay.
- Maybe fund a program at Wingate. - Sure.
Lord knows that school could use a little color.
Michael's like a flying and milking that place.
Are you listening to me?
I try to concentrate on one... thing... at a time.
You knew I was multi-tasker when you married me, right?
- I sure did.  - Alright. Okay.
Okay. Tuohy family. Big smiles everyone!
And, one , two, three...
Michael! Michael come over here and get in the next one.
Come on. Come on. Come over here.
Oh, come on.
It's not like I'm gonna put it on the Christmas card.
Okay, let's scootch in a little tighter.
That's good.
Really big smiles.
Okay, one, two three... Say rebels!
Rebels.
I got it.
- Who's winning? - Tennessee.
- Who are they playing? - Clemson.
Your mom roots against Tennessee no matter who they're playing?
Oh, yes, I do. With gusto.
She can't stand Tennessee.
Collie-bell, I thought you were going to your boyfriend's?
I thought of hanging around here today.
I like that.
Hey, baby. There's a couple of messages on the machine
but I didn't check 'em.
Alright.
Hey, Sean, hey, Leigh Anne, it's cousin bobby. Happy new years!
Listen, I've had about five cold ones...
Of course you had.
I'm just gonna go ahead and ask.
You know there's a colored boy in your Christmas card?
What?
You just looked teeny-tiny next to him. Right?
Like Jessica Lange and King Kong.
Hey, does Michael get the family discount at Taco Bell?
Because if he does Sean's gonna lose a few stores.
He's a great kid.
Well, I say make it official and just adopt him.
He's gonna be eighteen in a few months.
Doesn't really make much sense to legally adopt.
Leigh Anne, is this some sort of white guilt thing?
What will your daddy say?
Umm... before or after he turns over in his grave?
Daddy's been gone five years Elaine,
Make matters worse you wear at the funeral.
Remember? You wore Chanel and that awful black hat.
Look, here's the deal.
I don't need y'all to approve my choices, alright?
But I do ask you to respect them.
You've no idea what this boy's been through.
And if this is going to be some running diatribe
I can find an overpriced salad a lot closer to home.
Leigh Anne, I'm so sorry. We didn't intend to...
No. We didn't really.
I think, what you're doing is so great...
to open up your home... to him.
Honey, you're changing that boy's life.
No.
He's changing mine.
That's awesome for you, but what about Collins?
What about Collins?
Aren't you worried, I mean, even just a little?
He's a boy, a large, black boy,
sleeping under the same roof.
Shame on you.
I've got this.
Be honest with me, okay?
Is Michael being here making you uncomfortable?
They're stupid kids, who cares what they say.
What kids?
At school.
They're juvenile.
And what do they juvenile kids say?
It's really not worth repeating.
And don't worry about SJ, he likes all the attention.
He introduces Michael as his big brother.
- What about you? - It's fine.
I mean, you can't just throw him out on the street.
I can make other arrangements.
- Hi, Mike.  - Hi.
- Need a push?  - Yeah.
Higher, Mike! Higher!
Higher!
Don't look down. Don't look down!
- Where are you going?  - Collins?
Quit looking at me like that.
I mean, we study together at home.
You know how much those things weigh?
This kid's gonna make us all famous.
Easy, Bert, man. It's only the spring.
He hasn't even been through his first practice yet.
No. He's a player.
Ready.
Get down, son. Get down in your stands.
In your stands!
Go!
Mike! son!
You fall off the block and then you
wanna shuck-shuck the blocker.
Right? Shuck it! alright? Let's go!
How's he doing?
Doesn't quite have the hang of it yet.
Hey, Mike. Son...
Shuck the blocker. Don't hold him!
No! no! no! no! no! no! no! no! no! no.
Balloons! There are balloons!
Guys, quit looking at the balloons. Everybody.
Most kids from bad situations can't wait to be violent
and that comes out on the field.
This kid, he acts like he doesn't want to hit anyone.
He's Ferdinand the Bull.
- What?  - Nothing.
I thought sure he was gonna be a player.
I can't believe I used up my chiefs to get him in school.
I thought you said it was your Christian duty?
Look, Bert. He's never played before.
And he won't this fall if he doesn't improve a lot before then.
Who dad made him Bert Bright?
Unbelievable!
Oh, God bless me.
This is your summer workout sheet.
Now, first it says to warm up and get loose.
Go ahead, get loose.
Are you loose?
Okay, next is five one hundred yard runs
to stretch out your legs.
Let's go home, play some video games.
Look, everybody at Wingate is expecting
you to be a star football player.
You don't want to let them down, do you?
I don't know.
What about dad and mom?
'cause you see, in our family everyone's an athlete.
Dad was a basketball star,
Collins plays volleyball and runs track.
And me, as you know, I do it all.
And mom... mom was a cheerleader,
which doesn't exactly count but don't tell her I said that.
- Okay?  - Okay.
Okay.
...Fifty, fifty one,
Fifty two, fifty three...
Come on and get it! Go, go, go, go, go!
Come on. Five seconds left in the game!
Just like! Just like!
High knees, high knees, high knees! Baby.
Run like the wind!
Go, Michael, go!
...Ninety eight, nine,
One hundred.
Move your feet! Move your feet! Come on! Come on! Come on!
Go. There you go.
Get on the tackle! Come on! Come on! Come on!
Come on, Michael!
Mrs. Tuohy?
I hear "Mrs. Tuohy" I look over my shoulder for my mother-in-law.
Call me Leigh Anne or Mama or almost anything else.
- Can you help me get something? - What?
Driver's licence.
Why do you need a driver's licence
When you don't even have a car?
Michael, why do you want a driver's licence?
Something to carry. With my name on it.
There's nobody named Michael Oher in the system.
Another last name perhaps?
Look, I will sign something that says he lives with us
And we'll pay for all the insurence;
whatever it takes, okay?
What's it gonna take?
- You wanna do what?! - You heard me.
Shouldn't we at least talk about this?
What do you think we're doing?
And don't act like I'm going behind your back.
I know you put us down as
Michael's medical contact at school.
There's a huge difference between paying for broken arm
And being legally responsible for someone.
I mean the kid we barely know.
That's another thing.
We need to find out more about his past.
He won't talk about it. He's like an onion,
You have to peel him back a layer at a time.
Not if you use a knife.
What if we took him to a child psychologist or something?
- Do you really expect Big Mike - "Michael"
You really expect Michael to lie down
On a couch and talk about his childhood
Like he's Woody Allen or something?
I mean, Michael's gift is his ability to forget.
He's mad at no one and he really
Didn't care what happened in the past.
You're right.
Excuse me?
"You're right?"
How'd those words taste coming out of your mouth?
Like vinegar.
At least promise me you'll think about it.
Alright.
"Alright" you'll think about it or
"Alright" we should do it?
Is there a difference?
Just tell Gerald to hold on the
Chiffonier and I'll get by after while.
You don't... I got to call you back. Bye.
Excuse me.
I'm not cutting, I'm just asking.
Let me tell you something, alright?
We've been sitting around here for over an hour
And when I look around and all I see
Is people shooting the bull and drinking coffee.
Who runs this place?
Well, I'd have it in shape in two days,
I can tell you that.
I'd bet you would. How can I help you?
- Oh, he was first. - No, you go ahead.
- I think I want to hear this - Me too.
I do not appreciate the attitude.
Ma'am, now you can tell me what you want
Or I'll make sure you wait all day.
Now how can I help you?
I'd like to become a legal guardian.
Lord help that child.
There's very little on Michael.
Most of his files have been lost.
- What is in there?  - A few case notes.
This one describes an incident where
Officers forcibly removed Michael
From Denise Oher's care when Michael was seven.
Quite a scene evidently. They had to split up the kids.
And it's far from the worst.
Where is she? His mother?
I don't know, if you find her
Will got a bunch more files we could add to.
How many kids does she have?
At least a dozen, probably.
If not more. With her drug arrest record
My guess would be she can't even remember.
May I see that?
So we'd need her permission, right?
No. Michael is a ward of the state.
Just apply and get a judge to sign off on it.
So you would just give him away
Without even telling his mother?
Mrs. Oher?
Hi.
- You from the state? - No.
My name is Leigh Anne Tuohy
And your son Michael lives with me.
And my family.
How's my boy? How's big Mike?
He's fine. He's doing really well.
We might have some wine in the kitchen, if you...
Oh, no, no, no. That's really kind.
When did you last see Michael?
I don't know.
How many foster kids you got living with you?
Oh, I'm not a foster parent to Michael.
We were just helping him out.
- State don't pay you nothing? - No.
And you feed him? You buy him clothes, too?
Well, when I can find them in his size.
You a fine Christian lady.
Well I try to be.
This is all really nice what you're doing,
But don't be surprised if one day you wake up and he gone.
- What do you mean?  - He's a "runner."
That's what the state called him after they took him from me.
Every foster home they sent him to,
He'd slip out the window at night and come looking for me.
No matter where I was that boy would
Come find me, take care of me.
I've had some health problems.
Mrs. Oher, was Michael born under a different name?
Proctor. That was his daddy's last name.
- Where is he?  - Ain't seen him since he left.
And when was that?
Week after was Mike born?
Do you have his birth certificate?
It's alright. I'll figure it out.
Mrs. Oher, you'll always be Michael's mama.
Would you like to see him?
No. Not this way.
It's Williams.
His last name's Williams.
Couldn't even remember who the boy's father is.
The color is better, the graphic is bright. It's awesome!
Michael, we have something we'd like to ask you.
What?
Leigh Anne and I, we...
We'd like to become your legal guardians.
What's that mean?
What it means is, that we want to know
If you'd like to become a part of this family?
I kinda thought I already was.
Well alright then.
Right here.
We got a couple of steps.
- Watch your big foot. - One more.
One more. There we go.
Alright. Take off the belt.
Well, that's the one you want it, didn't it?
Here. Here you go. Go ahead. Take it for a ride. Go.
- Can I go too? - Yeah.
Michael? Be careful.
Shotgun!
- He wanted a truck?! - Michael thinks he's a redneck.
Come on, Michael!
Okay. See, you're the ketchup,
Here at left tackle. On the weakside.
The first play is simple. "Gap."
Now, see, dishes means you're going
To block whoever is in front of you,
Or on your inside shoulder
If you're not covered by a defender.
Now, I'll be the running back and you
Show me what you're supposed to do.
Ready.... hike!
You block him, you hit him,
Quarterback will hand it off, he gets the ball and...
Open lane to the end zone. All there is to it.
What's going on here?!
Player spice just scored.
We're going through the playbook.
Michael got move to offense.
Yeah. Well, when you're done, please,
Put the players back in the spice cabinet.
- Thank you. - No problem.
Oh, actually, Mom, we were kinda waiting for you.
You see, the new madden game came out
And me and Michael wanted to go get it.
I can't, baby. I've got a meeting in ten minutes
But he can drive!
He can drive us.
Oh, yeah. That's what I'm talking about.
What do you know about this?
I already know all about this!
Alright, show me something.
I'll tell you something, alright?
I'll start it. Follow my leads.
- Ready? - Yes.
# next days function, high class luncheon #
# food is served and you're stone cold munchin' #
# music comes on, people start to dance #
# but then you ate so much you nearly split your pants #
# A girl starts walkin, guys start gawkin' #
# Sits down next to you and starts talkin' #
# Says she wanna dance cus she likes the groove #
# So come on fatso and just bust a move #
# If you want it, you've got it #
# If you want it baby you got it #
This is not a 40,000 dollar oushak, Omeed.
You're crazy, Leigh Anne!
The borders have different width. They've been altered.
We'll give you seventeen tops, alright?
Hello?
Hey, hey, Ma'am. Ma'am, you can't get in.
Those are my kids. Those are my kids!
Oh my God!
- It will be okay.  - Where are they?
I'm so sorry! I'm so sorry. Oh my God!
- Michael, you okay? - I'm fine. SJ!
- Michael, you're alright? - Go help SJ!
I'm so sorry, so sorry!
Excuse me, Ma'am?
SJ  SJ
SJ! SJ!
- Mom? - Yes, baby?
Do you think the blood will come out of my shirt?
Yes, I think the blood will come out of your shirt.
Ma'am, an airbag deploys at 200 miles an hour.
Your son's too small to sit in the front seat.
But he's okay, right?
Busted lip, bruised face.
Usually when someone his size gets the airbag
It's fractured faces, a broken neck.
Maybe worse.
Like the air bag was coming for him then changed direction.
Quite defective or something like that.
Your son's very, very lucky.
No idea. I called the insurence. He's fine. He's fine!
I'll talk to you later. I got to go. Bye.
SJ's fine.
He is. He's actually enjoying all the
Attention he's getting back there.
Hey, Michael. Could happen to anyone,
Alright? It's not your fault.
Honey, look at me.
Michael, what happened to your arm?
I stopped it.
Let's go!
Oher! you've got a hundred pounds on Collis
And you can't keep him out of our backfield?
Hold your block until the whistle blow. Hold it!
Alright, let's go!
What's with the camera?
Michael always does better when he
sees what he's supposed to be doing.
- Holding ... left tackle. - Michael! Come on!
Oher? Come here, Son.
You got to hold it. Hold it inside here, between the tits.
You got it?!
Would you look at me, Son.
If you grab 'em outside here like this
without horse colour thing, you just did,
We're going to get flagged and I'm gonna get pissed.
You hear me?
Alright, let's go!
Baby, watch my stuff, alright?
Okay.
Well at least he'll look good coming off the bus.
They'll be terrified 'til they realize he's a marshmallow.
Looks like Tarzan, plays like Jane.
Gimme a minute, Bert.
We're in the middle of practice, Leigh Anne!
You can thank me later.
Come.
Michael,
Do you remember when we first met
We went to that horrible part of
town to buy those dreadful clothes?
And I was a little bit scared and you told me not to worry about,
Because you had my back. Do you remember that?
Yes, Ma'am.
And if anyone tried to get to me,
you would have stopped them, alright?
And when you and SJ were in that car wreck,
What did you do to that airbag?
- I stopped it. - You stopped it.
You stopped it.
This team is your family, Michael.
You have to protect them from those guys.
Okay? Listen.
Okay.
Tony here is your quarterback, alright?
You protect his blind side.
When you look at him, you think of me.
How you had my back. How you have his.
Okay? Alright. Tony, go back.
Alright.
Oomaloompah here is your tailback.
When you look at him, you think of SJ,
How you never let anyone or anything to hurt him.
You understand me?
Alright. Go back.
- You got it? - What about Collins and Mr. Tuohy?
Fine. They can be on the team too.
Are you gonna protect the family, Michael?
Yes, Ma'am.
Good boy. Now, go have some fun.
Yelling at him doesn't work, Bert. Doesn't trust men.
In his experience they pretend to care about 'til
they disappear.
Wanna little play?
SJ, you're gonna wanna get this.
Okay.
Come on, Mike!
Alright. Michael! come on!
- Yes! Michael! - Alright! Way to go!
Yes!
Good boy.
Okay. What'd you say to him?
Should get to know your players, Bert.
He tested 98 percent in protective instincts.
I said you could thank me later.
It's later, Bert.
So much for home field advantage.
You ever seen so many rednecks in one place?
Nascar, not even close.
Crusaders! Get ready for forty eight minutes of hell!
You have fat ass.
Hey, back on the field.
Let me go. Hold on. Listen up! Listen up!
Don't let 'em get inside your head. Now, keep your focus.
- You ready? - "Yeah"
- Alright. Let's go! - "Go"
- Come on! - Michael!
Damn, that ain't fair!
They got big ole' black bear playing for 'em!
- What is this, a circus? - Right.
Eyes forward, SJ! Sticks and stones.
Sticks and stones! Come on!
- Alright!  - Alright! Good start!
Let's go o! let's go!
Here we go. Look at this big bull we got right here.
Coming after you! Coming after you!
All night. All night.
Don't let him get through, Oher! Come on, Son!
Boy! All night long, fat ass! all night long!
I got you, boy. All night long!
That's my boy!
- it's alright, Michael! - It's alright. Come on!
- Let's go! - Take it off. Come on!
Here we go! Round two, baby! Round two!
- Switch! Switch! - Get it! Get it! Get it! go!
Oher, don't let them get the inside gap zone!
Come on! Use your head!
What is Bert doing? Nothing.
Hey, fat boy. We're not done yet.
All game long, boy! All game long!
Alright. Alright.
Go!
Pass! Pass! Pass!
Stop! Oh!
Why another pass, Bert?
Hey! Where you going, fat boy?
Better stay out of my field.
You are not welcome here! This is my field!
Sixty six, get beck to your own bank.
Bert! Be quiet! Bert!
Hello?
Enough with the trick plays, Bert. Run the dang ball.
You heard it. Run the dang ball. Run it.
Wait a minute, did he just hanged up the phone?
- No, I think he lost service. - He did not lose service.
That's my boy, Jimmy! number 66!
Kicking that blue guy's ass.
Hey crotch mouth!
Yeah, you!
Zip it or I'll come up there zip it for ya!
Sticks and stones?
You know what, SJ? Just turn forward.
Just take up the camera and keep shoot. Come on.
Lock it!
It's alright. Alright. Alright. We come back.
Go!
Come on! Get him!
Gone. He's gone.
Unbelievable. Three plays. Three plays.
Where were we... 4.3?
Come on.
Baby, me and you. Me and you, baby. One more time.
Here we go!
Alright, we got to cut back! We got to cut back!
Come on. Let's go!
Black piece of crap!
Raf! Are you gonna do something about this?!
He just kicked my boy in the head and cussed him!
Thank you!
Unsportsmanlike conduct... wingate! Fifteen yards!
What?!
You shut up, or you'll get another fifteen.
This young man plays for my team. My team!
And I will defend him like he's my own son.
Against you or any other redneck son of a bitch!
Don't worry, coach. I got your back.
Alright then.
Come here, Son. Come here.
Try "gap."
- "Gap?" - "Gap."
Alright, gun rip, 47 gap, on and on.
Ready?
Coach ain't here to protect you now, is he?
Ready!
Team is your family, Michael.
Go!
Go back, go back! Block them all!
We got to hold! We got to hold!
Oh god!
- Run, Michael! - SJ!
- Michael! - Run, Michael! Run!
Go!
- Go, Mike! - Go, Michael.
Touchdown!
Yo! Deliverance! You see number 74?
Well, that's my son.
Way to go big bro!
- Dead ball foul. - Now what?!
- Was he holding! - No.
- Did he hit after the whistle? - I don't believe so.
So what is the flag for?
I dunno... excessive blocking.
You're kidding me.
Sorry, coach. I stopped when I heard the whistle.
Where were you taking him, Mike?
To the bus. That was the time for him to go home.
Attaboy, Michael Oher. Attaboy! Go get 'em.
Go get 'em, Crusaders!
Rub the heads! Rub the heads! Alright! Let's go!
Go!
Stay!
Red, 41! Red, 41!
Tom Lemming recruiting, please hold...
Tom Lemming recruiting, please hold....
Coach Saban wants his monthly recruitment update fedex.
Does he really think getting it one
day early is gonna give LSU a leg up?
Hey, have you filled all the slots for the army all star game?
Yeah, why?
You might want to open one up.
What did I tell you?
I want him. I want him bad.
Y-e-l-l! Everybody yell! Say, everybody yell!
Y-e-l-l! Everybody yell!
Nice kick this time, Collins. Nice job.
What in the world?
Alright. Y'all keep practicing. Remember point your toes.
One, two, three, one!
One, two, three, two!
One, two, three, three!
You okay, Son?
Shoot, man, Fulmer's here. I might as well go home.
What to say, fellas? How's doing your life?
I came all the way from Knoxville, to see for myself.
Hey, Coach. We drove from Clemson, nine hours!
Coach Fulmer, it's a real honor.
Coach Cotton, my pleasure.
I watched your program. You've done really well.
I don't think there is any question
that you'll be at the next level soon.
Oh, well, you know, we do all we can, all we got.
Is that Michael? Is that O'hair?
It's Oher.
Like a paddle in a boat. Oher.
You think we might see some drills?
Perhaps... I think all the coaches would appreciate it.
- Yeah? - Oh, yes, Sir. You bet.
Listen up, fellas! New board drill!
Big Mike, Jay Collis.
Best on best. Right here.
Let's go! Come on! Come on!
On my whistle, men!
Coach, thank you.
- Where are you going, coach? - Back to South Carolina.
You tell to Michael Oher, if he can qualify with his grades...
Clemson wants him.
Yeah. Good luck with that, Brad!
Coach, you've done a great job with this young man.
Oh, well he was little rough when we first got him
But we, you know, coached him up a little bit.
Hello, Mom.
Did you know that to be eligible for a division one scholarship
Michael's gonna need to make it a 2.5 gpa?
Really?
His ACT is low and I don't see him doing
Any better if he retakes it right there.
- What's his gpa now?  - 1.76.
Oh, that's not too bad, when you consider where he started.
He's gonna make it all A's this year.
I'm serious. And that might not even be enough.
So he goes to junior college?
Most inner city kids that go to JC drop out in the first year.
His shot at the pros would go out the window.
Pros?
Are we even sure he's gonna get college offers?
Michael, Nick Saban from LSU.
I'm looking forward to you're coming down and visit us sometime.
Gready. I'm Lou Holtz form South Carolina.
I'm call...
We're very interested in having Michael
Over to Knoxville for a visit.
Phil Fulmer, from Tennessee?
There's twenty more among there.
And these things right here. Fifty of 'em.
Any of those from Ole Miss?
No, they're not gonna start recruiting
Until they hire a another coach.
Does make any difference unless Michael makes his grades.
So, what are we going to do?
I understand you applied for a teaching position at Wingate?
I won't religious enough for 'em.
I'm a spiritual person, Mrs. Tuohy,
but I have certain, shall we say... doubts.
Oh, I appreciate your honesty, Miss Sue.
What's the situation with Michael?
He needs to be better in school.
Obviously. Why the big push?
Well, he's in line for football scholarship
If he gets his grades up.
Is he considering Ole Miss?
He'd better be.
- I'd love to work with him. - Well, when'd you like to start?
Mrs. Tuohy... umm... there's something you should know about me.
I don't usually tell many people, but
It's something you feel should be aware of
Before you hire me.
What is it?
I'm a democrat.
Okay.
- I don't understand it. - Yet.
You don't understand it yet.
- how big is your head, Michael? - Big.
And what's in there?
- A brain. - A brain.
It's full of knowledge
Like a file cabinet with maps;
And shortcuts for figuring things out.
You'll get there, Michael Oher
Because I'm to help you use those
maps and reach your destination.
Like Sacagawea helped Lewis and Clark.
Sacagawea?
We'll get to that. And the history books have it wrong,
All you need to know is I'll get you there.
Do you believe me?
You trust me, Michael?
Yes, Miss Sue.
Try it again.
Now, what's the next one? Read that to me.
Hey, what is it? As first, we have to find the constant.
Now, where is the constant?
Good. See?
Who'd thought we'd have a black son before we knew a democrat.
- Doorbell! - I got a guest.
Coach, how are you? Come in.
- Sean Tuohy. - Sean.
- Nick Saban. Nice to meet you. - Nice to see you. Pleasure.
I appreciate the opportunity to come in your home.
- That's my daughter, Collins. - Hi. Pleasure to meet you.
- and you must be Leigh Anne. - that would be me, Coach Saban.
- nice to meet you. - me too.
Please, call me Nick.
With an incredible home. The windsor valances are a nice touch.
Oh, thank you. You obviously have an excellent taste.
Well we appreciate the quality. And recognize it when we see it.
Michael, why don't you come over here and say hello to Coach Saban.
Hello, Michael. Nick Saban.
- Nice to meet you. - Nice to meet you.
- And you must be sj. - That's me.
Michael, why don't you and Nick go into the living room to talk?
Can SJ come?
Absolutely. We'll recruit the both of you.
Alright.
I find him extremely handsome.
Yeah, I'm right here, Leigh Anne.
Yeah, I know.
So Michael, we'd like to get you down to LSU for visit.
We've got a great thing going there right now,
You have an opportunity to be successful as a person, as a student
And an opportunity to be a part of
The next national championship team with LSU.
So what do you say? You'd like to commit to a visit?
- Can I ask a question?  - Sure.
My brother and I are very close.
And so... I'm very afraid that if he goes off to school,
I might not get to see him.
- So ... - Go on.
I guess I was just wondering how much access I'd have to him.
Well, SJ, you'd have total access to Michael.
But better than that, in his first game at tiger stadium,
We would like for you to lead the team out of the tunnel.
- What do you think about that? - Sounds good.
Come on in!
Gready. I'm Lou Holtz. The university of South Carolina.
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Nice to meet you. Come and in.
Michael!
Hello. I'm Tommy Tuberville. Albany university.
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Nice to meet you. Michael!
Howdy, houston nutt. University of Arkansas.
Leigh Anne Tuohy. Very nice to meet you.
- Ole Miss cup, huh? - Michael!
Oh, come on. You know this.
It's logical.
I guarantee you come to the university of South Carolina
Will be the smartest decision you've ever made.
We want you, we need you, but the other thing is,
Mike, you need us.
Knoxville is a tremendous place to live and...
I know there's lions, there's tigers, there's bears...
Hey, there's only one razorback in the world.
...and not only that, you'd look great in gamecock red!
What's in if for me?
Sj, I'd get you a hawkhat, and for whole family a hawkhat.
Are you telling me, that's the best you can do?
SJ, you remind me of me as a boy.
Coach, help me, help you.
I can get you a gamecock headdress. And with real feathers.
What you got for me, Phil?
SJ, I've been thinking a lot of about that and one of the things
That think will be special for both
of us is we'll walk arm in arm
To center of union stadium at the first ball game,
And we'll do the coin toss together.
How's that sound?
Coach Fulmer, a pleasure doing a business with you
My pleasure, SJ. Could be sure, buddy.
Congratulations on gettin' hired.
Thank yew, ma'am. Ole miss is my dream job.
You're coming a little late to the party but we're diehard rebels
So I'm gonna give you a frickin' road map.
- Alright? - Got it.
LSU is out. Everybody knows Saban's going to the nfl.
I don't wanna name names,
but on Michael's first two recruitment trips
Somebody took him to the titty bar.
- That's terrible.  - Tell me about it.
He'll have nightmares about for a weeks.
So when he comes to visit
I want you to feed him Italian. He likes fettucine alfredo
And I want you to take him to a movie - not chainsaw massacre
Because he'll just cover his eyes - and get him to bed by ten.
- You got it?  - Yes'm.
- Alright. - What about Tennessee?
It breaks my heart but they're still in the hunt.
Fulmer made sj a sweet deal.
I heard the kid can really pepper the gumbo.
He's his daddy's boy.
- You ready?  - Lets' do it.
Alright.
Mike, do you like to barbecue? I tell you what, mike.
You can go to the gas station and get best barbecue,
You've ever got in your life.
It's a wonderful place to live, fried catfishes,
All the good food that we love to eat
But it's not good for us as football players,
You'd have to be aware, mike. I promise.
And for you, SJ, this is what I can do.
At ole miss we have the grove by the stadium.
We walk it before every game, in front of thousands of people.
It is a sacrad ritual. And I'm in front.
Seen it a thousand times.
Ever seen it from the front of the line?
Next year, you and me; leading the team.
Tennessee offered to let me run on the field and flip the coin.
I'll throw in a sideline pass.
Have you decided yet, Michael?
No, Miss Sue.
But you like Tennessee?
It's a good school.
Not at academic level of ole miss,
But they have an outstanding science department.
You know what they're famous for?
They work with the fbi
To study the effects of the soil on decomposing body parts.
What's that mean?
Well when they find a body,
the police want to know how long it's been dead.
So the fine fox at Tennessee help them out.
They have a lot of body parts.
Arms and legs and hands - form hospitals and medical schools.
And you know where they store them?
Right underneath the football field.
So, while it's fine and dandy,
there're 100,000 fans cheering for you,
The bodies, you should be worried about are right underneath the turf
Set to poke up through the ground and grab you.
But it's your decision where you wanna play ball.
Don't let me influence you.
All the other teachers are on board,
I don't know, what your problem is.
I'm sorry.
I will not give a student a grade he, or she, doesn't deserve.
Well, Michael needs a b.
What is he have to do to "deserve" that?
Right now is Michael doing c minus, d plus work.
His best chance at improving is with the written essay
At the end of the year.
It counts a third of his grade.
Well that's it. We're sunk.
Why don't you write about "Great Expectations"?
You're a lot like Pip.
I mean he was poor, he was an orphan
and someone kind of found him.
You should be able to relate to that.
Fine, let's go through the reading list.
But you're gonna have to pick one, Michael.
"Pygmalion"...
"A tale of two cities"..... "The charge of the light brigade"...
"half a league, half a league, half a league onward"
I love that one.
He loves it.
Why don't you do this and I'll watch basketball?
Okay.
"all in the valley of death rode the six hundred."
They named LSU's stadium death valley because of this story.
Alfred, lord tennyson has writing about
LSU in Ole Miss.
- You're kidding? - No. It's a great story.
It's a poem.
"forward the light brigade!"
It's like the offense.
"charge for the guns he said."
That's the end zone.
"into the valley of death rode the six hundred."
"forward the light brigade!
Was there a man dismay'd?
Not tho' the soldier knew someone had blundered."
Someone made a mistake?
Yeah, their leader, their coach.
But why would they go ahead if they knew he messed up?
"theirs not to make reply, theirs not to reason why,
theirs not to reason to die,
Into the valley of death rode the six hundred."
They're all gonna die, aren't they?
Yeah.
That's really, really sad.
I think you just found something to write about, Michael.
Courage is a hard thing to figure.
You can have courage based on a dumb idea or mistake,
But you're not supposed to question adults,
Or your coach or your teacher
Because they make the rules.
Maybe they know best
But maybe they don't.
It all depends on who you are, where you come from.
Didn't at least one of the six hundred guys
think about giving up.
And joining with the other side?
I mean, valley of death that's pretty salty stuff.
That's why courage it's tricky.
Should you always do what others tell you to do?
Sometimes you might not even know why you're doing something.
I mean any fool can have courage.
But honor, that's the real reason you
either do something or you don't.
It's who you are and maybe who you want to be.
If you die trying for something important
Then you have both honor and courage
And that's pretty good.
I think that's what the writer was saying.
That you should hope for courage and try for honor.
And maybe even pray that the people
telling you what to do have some, too.
Kevin Lynn.
- Good job. - Excuse me.
Matthew Nicols.
2.52
2.52.
Michael's final GPA.
Got it off Paul's computer.
Jamie North.
He did it, Sean. He did it!
Baby, you've been broken to the principal's computer?
Michael Oher.
Where in the world did you find a baby picture of Michael?
Scanned it off an internet ad for a toddler boutique.
Congratulations, mike.
Michael, our greetings.
Way to go, bro!
Alright, that's enough. Young man...
I think I need a proper hug.
- Alright. You're gonna be staying in Deaton Hall - Where is it?
109. It's right there. And you're gonna be on a meal plan
So you're gonna be eating all the way here in Johnson Commons. Right there.
Johnson commons has all you can eat self-serve ice cream.
As much as you want?
Yes, that's how mama put on her freshman ten.
Stop it!
Hello?
This is Mrs. Tuohy.
He just want ask you a couple of questions, Michael.
You have nothing to hide.
Ms. Tuohy? Mr. Oher?
My name is Jocelyn Granger
and I'm the assistant director Of enforcement for the NCAA.
Please, call me Leigh Anne.
So, let's do this. Shall we?
Ms. Tuohy, if you wouldn't mind
I'd prefer to speak with Michael alone.
- And how long is that gonna take? - Awhile.
Go, mike. Okay? Go.
Michael? Michael! I'll be waiting for you in the lobby, alright?
I don't know, Sean. I just have a bad feeling about this one.
This woman is tough, tough... hold on.
The client wants what?
Were you aware that coach Cotton is accepting a job at Ole Miss?
No.
And that this job offer came after you signed with them?
Sean Tuohy, your legal guardian went to Ole Miss.
He played basketball.
And Mrs. Tuohy went to Ole Miss as well.
She was a cheerleader.
Is this safe to say that Ole Miss is their favorite school?
Did they like any other universities?
What about, say Tennessee?
No. They can't stand Tennessee.
- And your tutor... - Miss Sue.
Miss Sue. Miss Sue is an Ole Miss grad, too.
Miss Sue ever tried to persuade you to attend Ole Miss?
Did you know that the Tuohys make generous donations to Ole Miss?
That even Miss Sue makes donations?
That the Tuohys, they have a condo in Oxford
so they can attend as many athletic events as possible?
That, in fact, Sean and Leigh Anne Tuohy
are by our definition... "boosters."
Mr. Oher.
Mr. Oher?
Do you understand... do you know, why am I here?
To... investigate.
Yes. To investigate.
I'm here to investigate your odd... predicament.
Do you find it odd? Your predicament?
Michael?...
Iono.
Can I... can I leave now?
No. You can't.
- What do you want, ma'am?  - I want the facts!
- I need the truth.  - I didn't lie!
And I want to know what you think about all this.
Think about what?!
The NCAA fears that with your recruitment a door might be opened
That boosters from lots of schools in the south
will become legal guardians for young athletes without means
And funnel them to their alma maters.
I'm not saying I believe it and I'm not saying I don't,
But there're many people involved with this case
who would argue that Tuohys they took you in,
- They clothes you, they fed you. - No.
- They paid for your private education, - No.
- They bought you a car, - No!
- And paid for your tutor, - No.
All as part of a plan
to insure that you play football for the university of Mississippi.
Michael! We're not finished.
It's not available. Just like I told you three months ago.
So why don't we go with the canvas.
The low napa, it's a beautiful---
Oh, I'll call you back. Bye.
Michael. So what happened?
- Why'd you do it?  - What?
All along you wanted me to go to Ole Miss.
Of course, I did. We love Ole Miss!
Why did you do this for me?
- What?  - Everything!
Was it for you or was it for me?
Was it so I would go to school where you wanted?!
Was it so I would do what you wanted?!
- Michael, no... - That's what she thinks.
Is she right?
Michael, honey,
I need for you just listen to me, alright?
Don't you dare to lie to me.
I'm not stupid!
Michael?!
Michael, of course, you're not stupid.
Michael?! Come on.
I should have followed him.
You had no way of knowing he'd disappear.
Was he right?
What he said about us?
Leigh Anne, be reasonable.
We gave clothes to a boy who had one pair of shorts.
We gave him a bed.
To hell with the NCAA,
I'd do it again tomorrow.
What about all the rest of it
All the stuff we did to make sure that he got a scholarship?
A scholarship at Ole Miss.
He could go whenever he wanted, he knew that.
Oh, did he? Did you ask him?
'Cause I sure as I know I never did.
Come here.
Am I a good person? Not a joke. Not rhetorical.
You're the best person I know.
Everything you do, you do for others.
And why is that?
I have not a clue.
But you obviously get some sort of sick satisfaction out of it.
- Sean... - Yeah?
What if he never comes back?
Oh, shit!
Big Mike? Hey, get your ass in here, man.
I'm looking for my moms.
Your mama? Yeah, I seen dee dee around.
As a matter of fact...
Oh, yeah. She usually stop by for a taste around this time.
But I tell you what. Why don't you just come inside
I'll get you a forty
and we're gonna chop it up like real fo,
Just 'til she get here.
Come on, man. Nobody gonna bite you, man.
Hey! Big Mike! Man, go down there and have a seat.
Hey, baby, gimme a couple of cold beers from the refrigerator!
Sit down, man. Big Mike.
- What?  - I'm so glad to see you.
Yeah. You lookin' good. Too, you lookin' fit.
I heard you playin' little ball.
But you know that rich kid football
ain't like the public school league.
Niggers packing knives in their socks.
Hey, I played little ball myself.
Back in the day, you know that, alright?
Yeah, I heard.
A quarterback. Up there at MLK.
- Thank you, baby.  - What about you, Dave?
You still playing ball over at JC?
- Naw. - No, man.
Dave no longer a student.
He with me now!
As a matter of fact... look, I can open a spot for you, too.
I got tired of going to class.
People are tryin' tell me what to do.
Well, in that case, Dave, look here...
Turn it up, like that little bit of bitch!
Bitch!
Hey, man. Don't mess with D, man.
I heard you stayin' on the other side of town.
Yeah, that what dee dee said.
Said you got a new mama now.
- Yeah?  - Oh yeah!
- She fine too.  - Yeah. She fine.
She got other kids?
She got a daughter?
You tap that?
Yeah, you taped that! Yeah, yeah, yeah!
Big Mike!
Big Mike got his white babes!  He looks innocent.
Hey, Big Mike!
You should enjoy 'em, man.
Hey, where you going?
Going to wait my mom to the apartment.
Hey, man, just don't go away now.
Hey, sit down, man.
I'm just trying to find out little
bit about your fine white sister.
Because I like me some mommy/daughter action.
Shut up.
Shut up? Who the hell is you telling to shut up?
I will bust and cap your fat ass.
And then drive east and pay a visit to your cracker mom!
And her sweet little daughter.
Mama!!!!!
He gone, snowflake.
Michael was here?
Yeah, but you tell him, I'll be seeing him around.
Or he gonna get this.
So Michael was here?
Last night. He come by here.
Sneaked me then run off.
Yeah. Tell him, sleep with one eye open.
You hear me, bitch?
No, you hear me, bitch!
You threaten my son you threaten me.
You so much as cross downtown you will be sorry.
I'm in a prayer group with the D.A.,
I'm a member of the NRA.
And I'm always packing.
What you got in there, a .22?
A saturday night special?
And it shoots just fine, all the other days, too.
- Michael?! - Mama?...
You think the police is gonna come and get me?
I'd imagine the last thing they want at Hurt Village
is bunch of cops snooping around.
I swore I'd never ask this,
but how'd you get out of there, Michael?
When I was little and something awful was happening
My mama would tell me to close my eyes.
She was tryin' to keep me from
seeing her do drugs or other bad things.
And then when she was finished or the bad things were over
She'd say, "now when I count to three, you open your eyes
And the past is gone, the world is a good place,
And it's all gonna be okay."
You closed your eyes.
You know, when I was driving all over kingdom come looking for you
I kept thinking about one thing.
Ferdinand the Bull.
I know I should have asked this a long time ago, Michael.
Do you even wanna play football?
I mean do you even like it?
- I'm pretty good at it.  - Yeah, you are.
Sean and I have been talking and...
Michael, if you're gonna accept the football scholarship.
We think it should be to Tennessee.
And I promise that I will be at every game cheering for you.
- Every game?  - Every game.
But I will not wear that gaudy orange. I will not.
It is not in my color wheel and I'm not gonna wear it.
So you want me to go to Tennessee?
I want you to do whatever you want.
It is your decision, Michael. It's your life.
What if I want to flip burgers?
It's your decision; it's your life.
Okay.
Okay, what?
I'm sorry I left the other day.
- You were pretty upset. - You ask a lot of questions.
I'm just trying to get to the bottom of this.
But all questions you asked were about why everybody else
wanted me to go to Ole Miss.
Okay...
Not once did you ask why did I want to go there.
Alright, fine, Michael...
Why do you want to go to Ole Miss?
Because it's where my family goes to school.
It's were they've always gone to school.
College is going to be different experience for you, Michael.
SJ, stop it.
- There are lots of distractions. - Have a fun.
There's gonna be some nimrod in the dorm
who wants to play video games all night,
Or goof on the internet.
Just have fun.
And you will spend a lot of time at practice, which means...
Which means you have to
be very dedicated to your studies, alright?
SJ, if you don't stop it right---
- Come here. - No.
Relax, mama.
I just got back from the library.
I reserved a private cubicle for the semester.
Here's your class schedule and our study hall hours.
Now, if y'all don't mind
I'm gonna go move into my new apartment.
- Thank you, Miss Sue. - "Thank you, Miss Sue"
Yeah, yeah, yeah....
Let's see what you've got. College's writing,
Good, psychology, math lab...
It's gonna be good. Just...
I do not know why. A lot of good classes.
You'll have a lot of fun.
SJ
SJ!
Michael Oher, you listen to me, alright?
I want you to enjoy yourself, but if
you get a girl pregnant out of wedlock.
I'll crawl in the car, drive up here to Oxford
and cut off your penis.
She means it.
- Yes ma'am.  - Alright
Now, 78's gonna be a parking lot.
So we should be going. Or everyone...
Say the goodbyes, alright? Here.
Bye, baby.
- Thank you, mama. - You're welcome.
Why'd she always do that?
She's an onion. Michael.
You have to peel her back one layer at a time.
I'll be back.
What?
What, Michael?
I need a proper hug.
I read a story the other day about a boy from the projects.
No daddy, in and out of foster care.
He'd been killed in a gang fight at hurt village.
In the last paragraph they talked
about his superb athletic skills
And how different his life might have been
if he hadn't fallen behind and dropped out of school.
He was twenty-one years old the day he died.
It was his birthday.
That could have been anyone.
It could have been my son, Michael.
But it wasn't.
And I suppose I have god to thank for that.
God and Lawrence Taylor.
One Mississippi.
The New England Patriots have traded the twenty third pick
to the Baltimore Ravens.
And with the twenty third pick in 2009 NFL draft
The Baltimore Raven select...
Michael Oher. Offensive tackle, Mississippi.