OCD from engine 35. On scene at 902 Sunnyvale. Six-story, center hallway--
I.C. from engine 35. Need additional backup.
I.C. from engine 35. We need additional manpower now!
An elderly woman is trapped. We need another line up here.
We got Captain Brewer's team checking in.
My grandmother can't walk! She's trapped!
We'll handle it.
Gordy, we got people trapped at both ends of the hall.
Heads up. Let's do it.
Take care.
Please!
Help me!
l can't walk!
-Get me a baby ladder for this hole. -Don't even think about it!
-You guys stay back! l'm going in! -Gordy, goddamn it!
Gordy! Get that last wall on the fifth floor!
l.C. from fire 1028! Floor collapsing!
Captain Brewer's fallen through! l need help.
This is engine 28.
Help me, please! Somebody, help me!
l can't breathe.
-Put on my mask. -Thank you.
Get your ass over here and steady that ladder!
All right, get that woman out!
All right. lnhale, okay? You got it. Come on.
-You'll be okay. -Steady that ladder! Here we go!
-We have a burn victim coming down! -l got one coming down!
Take it easy with her. Take her down.
Then we'll put a piece in here.
And we got it. Look at that. Wait till Mommy sees that.
We have to put the stand on now, okay? Here we have the stand.
The blue goes to blue.
We put it right in here. You see this one's blue here?
Hold the wings stable.
Good. There we are. Look at this.
-Looks good. -Good morning.
-Good morning. -Mom, look what we made.
-Matty, that is so cool. -Show your mommy. Come on.
lt must have taken hours.
Since 4 a.m. He was already up when l got home.
-He has a sore throat. -He should see Dr. Bob.
Want to see my lKobe Bryant slam-dunk?
Sweetie, l don't think you should be jumping around.
Bubble, bubble, toil and trouble.
Matt is going to be clean on the double.
Dr. Bob can see him at 1 1 :30, but l have to be at the hospital.
-l can take him. Can you pick him up? -All right.
Yeah, great. 1 1 :30 is fine. Thank you so much.
-Now you're clean. -Come on, little buddy.
Come on, you're all clean. Oh, you're so slippery. Let's go.
l told you that doctor would make you feel better. Want a hot dog?
-How are you? -Good.
-What can l do for you? -Two hot dogs, a soda.
-What you want to drink? -Orange juice.
Okay, two hot dogs.
Here we go, bud.
lt's late. Where's Daddy? He should have been here by now.
Stay right around in here, okay, honey?
Officer.
Excuse me, officer.
l'm just going to pick up my kid.
lf you don't mind, it's just going to be a minute, okay? Thanks.
-There he is! -Where?
-Well done. lt's all because of you. -That's my job, sir.
This way.
Hi, Daddy.
Hello.
See? l told you he'd be here.
No!
ETA on those units!
Get Gilly, Perry, Copeland up here now.
The agent in charge is coming. l want paperwork in 10 minutes.
Gordy, we'll need to start an lV line.
l need to get him to the hospital. We can't get this glass out.
Device functioned after a motorcade arrived.
Targets: Colombian officials, American intelligence.
Guy on the phone is Brandt. ClA, works Colombia.
The other guy is Shrub. Undersecretary of State, Latin American affairs.
-Not a scratch on him. -Surveillance cameras?
-We're pulling the video now. -Where's L.A.P.D. on this?
They know it's ours. They're helping.
-What's the body count? -Two dozen injured. Nine dead...
...including ClA, American and Colombian military, a mailman...
...a nurse and her little boy. That's the father over there.
Gordy, we need to get you on a gurney.
Call our contacts. l want to know who's responsible by the day's end.
-Phipps, counter-terrorism. -Peter Brandt.
-l need to talk to him. -Not today.
Get the undersecretary to his hotel.
-lKeep me informed. -Right.
Okay, l'll talk to you then. Someone in your caravan was a target.
-Terrorism. Everyone's a target. -Shovel that on the press, not me.
-l need to know what you know. -When you get clearance.
l won't tell that dad the killer got away due to protocol.
Tell him what you want. We're done talking until you're cleared.
Excuse me, nurse. Excuse me. Gordon Brewer, please.
-Jack. -How you doing?
Hey, Gordy.
-How is he? -Could have been worse.
The glass missed his femoral artery by a hair. He was lucky.
Let me say, the full resources of the United States...
... will be employed to make clear...
...that we do not tolerate attacks on our city.
That said, we must fight the temptation...
...to make hasty policy decisions we may come to regret.
We can't allow an anonymous criminal...
...to unravel our partnership with Colombia.
Who was the specific target?
Hey, buddy. How you doing?
-I won't speculate. -What will the president do about it?
-He 's meeting with the Joint Chiefs. -Was the State Department warned?
What do we know?
The president's coming on soon. l doubt he'll say anything new.
Turner says the bomb was hidden in a police motorcycle.
-They don't know who triggered it. -l saw a cop.
l saw him.
Gordy, get back here! Goddamn it!
-Goddamn it, come here! Slow down! -l saw him.
You're not going anywhere!
Any problems, go through Shrub's office over at State.
That's right. Yes, he's one of us. He can handle it.
ls Beckett there? Or Moyers? He could help.
Skin of his teeth, that guy. Classic agency mold.
Get a copy of every visa on a Colombian passport.
-Everyone's covering up for him. -That's why they're called spooks.
Bastards. They must have used some kind of liquid explosive.
lf you'll follow me, sir.
l just want to help. Used to be with Bomb and Arson.
Right this way, sir. l'll take you to Agent Phipps.
Gordy Brewer is here.
-The fireman? -Yeah. Says he talked to the cop.
We appreciate you coming down.
We know this guy. His name is Claudio Perrini.
We think he's a terrorist called El Lobo. The Wolf.
Definitely the guy l bumped into.
l talked to him. l told him l was picking up my son.
The son of a bitch smiled at me.
The bomb may have been triggered by a cell phone.
-Did he have one? -l don't know.
How long between the time you saw him and the explosion?
Five seconds. Maybe 10 at the most.
-That's enough time to make a call? -Maybe.
This could be tough to watch, sir.
l was late.
They shouldn't have been there.
-They shouldn't have. -No, the bomber shouldn't have.
Peter Brandt, ClA, Latin American section. He was one of the targets.
l'm sorry for your loss. lf there's anything l can do for you....
l promise, one way or the other, we'll catch that son of a bitch.
How do l get ahold of you?
We're not at all separated from one another. We all run the same course...
...and will find one another again.
We won't be apart, for we live for Christ.
Now, we are united with Christ as we go to him.
We shall all be together in Christ. Amen.
-This is Gordy. -Anne.
-And Matthew Brewer. -Leave us a message.
Mr. Brewer, my name's Ken Barnett with Lateline.
We'd love to get you in the studio to hear you tell your story...
...in your own words.
If that's something that interests you, please call us at 552- 12--
Now back to Rick Garcia with more on the bombing in Los Angeles.
I'm at the State Department, where the counter-terrorism headquarters...
...received a videotape from El Lobo, or The Wolf...
...a Colombian terrorist who is responsible...
...for at least 7 bombings, including the most recent in Los Angeles.
On behalfof the people of Colombia...
...I claim responsibility for the bombing in Los Angeles.
The bombing was an act ofself-defense againstAmerican war criminals.
As long as America continues its aggression in Colombia...
... we will bring the war home to you.
And you will not feel safe in your own beds.
Colombia is not your country.
Get out now. Sangre o libertad.
For more, JenniLuz in Los Angeles.
I'm with Mr. Ortiz Dominguez of the Latin American Solidarity Committee...
...a group sympathetic to the Army of Colombian Liberation.
Sir, you've characterized the ALC as freedom fighters.
Isn't the bombing herejust a brutal act of terrorism?
The Wolfonly brought to the U.S. what the U.S. has brought to Colombia.
The killing ofinnocentpeople like Anne and Matt Brewer is terrorism.
Their deaths are regrettable.
It's called collateral damage.
Ortiz, you want the call? CNN is holding. Washington Post's on the line.
-Am I the only one here? -Agent Crosby will relieve you soon.
New York Times is on one.
Put them on hold. That's my position. l already told you this.
-Why should l change it? -Collateral damage, huh?
-Who the fuck are you? -l'll give you collateral damage.
Stop that!
lt looks like the fireman. Move in. Go now! Go!
You want collateral? Right here.
-What are you doing?! -Want collateral damage? Here.
What are you doing?!
-Where's The Wolf?! -l don't know!
-Tell me where The Wolf is! -Put the bat down!
-Fuck you! -Take him down!
l don't know!
Turn it off.
Come on.
Just relax, Mr. Brewer.
-l have to cuff you. -l'm Agent Collins with the FBl.
Bring your wrist right here, sir.
Take it easy. You'll be all right.
Just relax. lt's gonna be all right.
l can't imagine what you're feeling right now...
...but you can't take the law into your own hands.
l think you already lost him.
He's long gone. Otherwise, he wouldn't have sent you that tape.
-Am l under arrest? -No.
We convinced Mr. Ortiz to drop the charges.
The truth is, we're pretty sure The Wolf is back in Colombia.
-l find this questioning offensive. -You are the reason this has occurred.
You went to the Colombian consulate with a plan to attack the guerrillas.
Then they tried to blow you up.
-Senator, if you intend to argue-- -Mr. Brandt, l'm not arguing.
l am telling you, your mission in Colombia is terminated immediately.
With all due respect, senator...
...that is the worst thing you can do now.
This isn't for discussion.
Peace talks are being arranged between Colombia and the guerrillas.
This is insane. You can't negotiate with terrorists!
These guerrillas don't want peace. All they want to do is sell cocaine.
Senator, Peter Brandt has had a great deal of experience--
Spare me, Douglas.
Brandt has failed. All he's done is bring the war home to American soil.
That is completely unacceptable, and you know it.
You have 72 hours to pull your operatives out of Colombia.
-Have you any questions, Mr. Brandt? -None at all.
Damn it, Pete! Come here!
Why call them Senate intelligence hearings? They're all imbeciles.
l'm going back to Colombia and kill them all.
We've been here before. You know the drill.
This will blow over.
For now you're being reassigned here to l-TAG.
You can find this animal, Pete.
Just do it via satellite. All right? You're okay.
l'm sick of this crap. Get the plane ready. We're leaving tonight.
Another guy's claiming he's The Wolf.
-So? -He asked for you by name.
And he knows unreleased details about the bombing. Take it over here.
-Who's this? -You're tough to reach.
-I tried for the last three weeks. -Brewer?
You've been busy finding the man who killed my family?
Right?
l understand you're anxious. We'll keep you posted.
Tell me the truth, Brandt. You owe me that much.
-You're not going after him. -The truth?
The Colombian government's trying to negotiate peace with the guerrillas.
We can't go in the guerrilla zone. So bottom line is...
...justice for your wife and son isn't a priority.
-Colonel. -Peter, good to see you.
l wasn't expecting you back.
l won't hand the country over to a third-rate Che Guevara.
-How are my boys? -They're dying to get in the field.
-On furlough from the psych unit? -lsn't this it?
-l need to talk to you. -Okay.
-Gordy, how you doing? -Come in.
Meet a friend of mine, Ed Coonts.
-l'm sorry about your loss. -Thank you.
Ed spent two years as a military adviser down in Colombia.
He can help you.
l see you're doing homework.
Well, if l don't do it, it seems no one else will.
You'd have to be freaking cracked to go there.
You can't even land in Colombia...
...without a State Department stamp on your passport.
You can bet you were on their restricted list...
...five minutes after that bombing.
Oh, yeah. Well, Panama.
Back door into Colombia. You have been doing some homework.
Let's say you managed to get into the country without getting killed...
...you'd need a pass to get into the guerrilla zone.
They're sure not going to give you one.
Well, let's say l got one.
lt would take them about two seconds to realize you're not Juan Valdez.
And they'd shove your head up your ass...
...and bowl you off a cliff.
Are you going to help me or not?
Tell me your plan.
I'll cross the border through the Darien Gap.
I understand thejungle is hard to patrol.
I can make it to Valencia in one day.
Then it's 200 miles to the guerrilla zone.
I can pay someone to drive me to Mompos.
I don't think so. Approach the wrong person, you're a dead man.
Next to drugs, kidnapping gringos is the mostprofitable business.
Get on a bus as fast as you can.
-Mompos? -Si.
If you make it to the bus, you're doing all right.
-Thanks for your advice. -lt's only good advice if you take it.
-Que pasa? -Up ahead. Roadblock.
-Who are they looking for? -Anyone not like them.
His passport was found in his backpack when he escaped one of our roadblocks.
-He's committing suicide. -Only two ways he can go:
Upriver or on the road through Mompos.
lf we know he's here, the guerrillas know.
Or they will soon. l want you to make sure of it.
All right.
l give you 1 2 hours before we find your fireman facedown in a pit.
Sure would show Washington you can't negotiate with terrorists.
Los Angeles was a great success.
Finally, the hypocrites want to negotiate.
Americans hide behind family values. False ideals.
They've forgotten the reality of war. Not like us.
They found his passport. He's coming to Mompos.
Excellent. Take a fireman from Los Angeles.
When America hears the story, they cry rivers of tears.
Capture him. We hold him for ransom, and they will pay.
Two teams. One at the harbor, one in town. Find him and bring him to me.
lf they don't pay...
...we kill him.
All roads end in Mompos.
The only way into the guerrilla zone from there is upriver.
How do l go upriver in that?
No one goes upriver. Not without a pass.
You said I need a pass to get in.
Tell me how to get one.
You may be able to buy a pass from a local.
God help you if you ask the wrong one.
Look, this is where Ipretty much run out ofgood advice.
Thanks. I'm going to figure it out.
What are you doing?
ls the boy okay?
Yeah, he's okay. But l don't need any help.
l was just concerned about the boy.
Sorry. You are very kind.
He gets so excited. l have trouble keeping up.
He couldn't wait to get to the festival.
This carnival, he loves.
-l'm Selena. -Gordy.
This is my son, Mauro.
Gordy.
Friend.
All right. Better get going. Nice to meet you. Bye-bye.
Mr. Brewer.
You have to come with me. You're on my list.
-What's this about? -You're here illegally.
No, l'm not. My passport was stolen.
See those guys over there?
They're guerrillas!
Hey, no, seriously, captain.
l appreciate you guys taking me without a reservation.
l know how crowded it gets in here.
You know, l'd tip you, but your chief took all my money already.
-You gave away my favorite cell. -Put him next to the American.
That's not nice. Why'd you do that? Because he's bigger than l am?
Why are you doing this to me? l thought we had an understanding.
You're calling me a pervert?
l like you too.
Sean Armstrong. Public lewdness. At least, that's what they call it.
But l was just standing there. She was doing all the work.
Are you just quiet, or did somebody confiscate your tongue?
-Gordy Brewer. -Do l know you?
l doubt it.
So, what are you innocent of, huh?
l'm an illegal alien.
You goddamn gringos. You come down here and steal all the jobs.
Half the country wants to kidnap you. Half wants to kill you.
No one gives a shit about us Canadians.
Death squads kill the guerrillas. Guerrillas kill the military.
Peasants are killed by everybody.
But we Canadians, flies on the wall.
Hey, man. Don't even look at them unless you can kill them.
-They're all guerrillas, aren't they? -l did not say that.
That's what you meant.
You work the guerrilla zone. That's how you know.
-Can l move to a different cell? -Doing what?
l fix and sell heavy machinery. You satisfied?
Sell me a pass so l can work the zone.
Stick a sock in it. l'm just a wrench for hire.
lf anyone found out what l do, l'd be an organ donor.
My pass is not for sale.
-Thanks a lot. -Don't mention it.
Give me a list of everybody they picked up.
The guerrillas were after Brewer when the policia showed up.
Everyone we need in the same jail.
We should put this fireman on the payroll.
Seat belt.
l think we got some company coming.
Mompos Jail is under attack by guerrilla troops.
Get a team outside the jail and two squads to clear the building.
Copy.
Goddamn it, l can't believe this shit!
What about the fireman?
Claudio, they're coming! We have to go!
Let him burn in hell!
Shit! We're gonna fry! We're gonna fucking fry!
That's using the old noggin! That's using the noggin!
Yeah! Fuck America!
Good. That's good, baby. That's good! Get me out of here!
Let's play This Is Your Life. l want your pass.
lt's my livelihood! You'd let me die here?
l thought we were friends! lt's my livelihood!
You'd let me die here?
That's the last thing that will happen to you.
First, the air's gonna heat up in here to 451 degrees.
Your pass will explode, your socks will ignite, your fingernails will melt.
All right, all right! Shit! Here you go!
lt's yours, all right? Take it.
Now get me out. Get me out of here, please! Come on!
Witnesses heard prisoners call for El Lobo. He was here, boss.
He was into our hands and they let him walk out?
What good's a tower if nobody's watching?
The fireman isn't here.
No kidding. The fireman escaped the fire?
Look around. With any luck, Gordy Brewer's dead.
l'm sorry l had to scare you.
Hey, l know when it's time to retire.
You weren't gonna let me burn.
What's this for?
For your retirement fund. And for additional information.
Tell me what l need to know.
Get back to the harbor.
The guy who takes me upriver, his name's Omar. He'll set you up.
ln San Pablo, ask for Felix Ramirez.
Say you're my replacement. Say that l was arrested for something raunchy.
Good luck. You'll need it.
Who did this?
The guerrillas. They think these people help the paramilitaries.
Put your hands up! And hold up your pass!
l replace Armstrong.
-You are not Armstrong. -That's for damn sure.
Felix?
Heinrich Beckmann, his replacement.
Says you, buddy. This is a serious breach of protocol.
l put in the papers, and this is what l get?
lt's like ordering a pizza.
Ask for Canadian bacon, you get German sausage.
lf you don't want me to fix your engine, l'll go back home.
Come on, come on. Don't be such a sauerkraut.
What happened to my man Armstrong? Maybe you brained him for his pass.
Armstrong was arrested yesterday.
He was caught screwing the police chief's daughter.
That's Armstrong. Double-dipping whore. l love that guy.
-l wish l were him. -l still can't let him through, Felix.
lf my generator isn't fixed, l can't pay my taxes.
l can't pay, your boss will make some cuts.
Now, it could be your salary, and it could be your throat.
l'll let you marinate on that, okay?
Bring him back here first thing in the morning.
Danke.
Beckmann.
Don't forget your pass.
Your English is good for a German guy.
Thanks. When did you learn yours?
Oh, man, l been to New York, Chicago, Miami.
L.A. for a little bit. l want to go back someday when l'm a big shot.
l can't be begging some corporate asshole to put my CD on.
l want to cut an album, man.
lt's kind of hardcore campesino rap. Want to hear a little taste?
lf l have to.
With that attitude, it won't be a lot of fun. Here you go.
Guerrilla thrilla Take me to Manila
What do we got? Smooth like vanilla
Hottie, eenie-minie-mo Tell the CIA to go
They gotta get out, you know
-What do you think, man? -Great. l think you'll be a winner.
-Are you serious? -You're in the wrong profession.
l can't believe this. That's exactly how l feel.
-All right, here. Put this on. -What's this for?
For your protection. You don't wanna know how to get where we're going.
lt won't be more than 1 5 minutes.
Okay, we're here, baby. Don't get funky on me.
Peekaboo.
So, what do you think? Pretty snazzy, right?
-Where are we? -My place.
-lt smells here. -Profits, baby, profits.
-This is a cocaine plant. -l know.
Just because l'm brown and down doesn't mean l work for minimum wage.
lf l don't do it, Bolivia will. Bolivia don't, China will.
lf China don't, America will do it. Actually, they are doing it.
Jesus! l want to put you in my next video.
lt's the diesel generator. l should let it cool down...
...but it's drugonomics. l can't crank it out fast enough.
Those Silicon Valley geeks must e-mail it to each other.
-That the one? -Yeah.
Armstrong was a magician with that.
-Don't worry. l'll make it work. -Let's hope so.
He told me his name was Heinrich Beckmann.
Heinrich Beckmann?
He had a hat on. l didn't recognize him.
l made a mistake.
No! Please, Claudio! Listen to me, please!
Claudio!
ln the struggle for liberation...
...there is no room for mistakes.
Discipline is everything.
Discipline and punishment.
Find him. And no mistakes.
Come here whenever they want and barge in. l'm not a puppet.
-l thought l was paid up for the month. -Where's the mechanic?
Calm down, dog. You losing faith in me, man?
l got everything under control.
l got him working his ass off. Germans are like cyborgs.
You seem tense. Need some R and R?
You got pull, you can get me a new generator.
Heinrich, l got some friends for you.
My bad. l said if he fixed that gasket, he could take five.
He's probably in the latrine.
He's probably buffing the helmet.
Besides, he can't blend in. He's this big Neanderthal--
We'll get some rum, we'll hang out--
What the hell was that?!
Get the mangueras! Get the pumps! Save the kilos, come on!
l'll work it out. l'll cut my losses, pay whatever it takes.
l'll pay you three times the amount. l'll work it out.
No! Stay back there!
Stop! Stay back!
Claudio!
No! Stop!
Rest now.
Who are you?
l'm his wife.
Get out.
The fireman, huh?
The coward who kills women and children.
You Americans are so naive.
You see a peasant with a gun on the news, you change the channel.
But you never ask, "Why does a peasant need a gun?"
Why? You think you're the only ones who can fight for independence.
lndependence to do what? To kill my wife and my son?
l remember your face from Los Angeles.
That was the face of a man who saved lives.
Well, your face has changed.
You think your wife and son would recognize you now?
l remember your face too.
The smile...
...just before you killed them.
You're gonna pay for that.
Well, it seems we're both willing to kill for a cause...
...so what's the difference between you and l?
The difference is...
...l'm just gonna kill you.
Estaban!
-Why do you want him alive? -He saved my life and Mauro's.
What is the purpose?
He's the enemy. lf they don't pay tomorrow, l'll kill him.
-Claudio, don't do this. -Don't argue with me.
-lt's not the right way! -Don't tell me what to do! Come back!
This is a satellite photo of San Pablo last night.
We got a large heat-and-light anomaly consistent with an explosion.
Two minutes later, building blows up. We got guerrillas, some down.
We have a big man down on the street, a woman and child.
And this guy. This guy gives the orders.
l can't believe it. Brewer found the son of a bitch.
A little later, an ALC convoy arrives. Everyone loads up.
They travel two minutes upriver. They stop here.
An ALC base camp.
We'll insert a platoon here. Use air support to box in the rear.
We'll come in through the treetops. Only 20 minutes.
Washington will know.
We got a wounded American being tortured. This is a rescue mission.
-We go in at dawn. -Roger that.
Why are you taking care of me?
Because you saved my son.
And your husband killed mine.
When l first met Claudio, he was a teacher.
lt was in Guatemala.
Sophia, our daughter, was born there.
The guerrillas were all around us, but they left us alone.
One night, soldiers came to our village.
They were led by American advisors.
We crawled into the fields, but they threw grenades.
Sophia, our baby girl...
...she was hit.
She bled to death in Claudio's arms.
Mauro was orphaned that night, so l took him in.
Claudio joined the guerrillas.
And now he's a man consumed by hate and driven by rage.
Just like you.
l'm not like him.
Not yet.
What about you? lf you keep working with him, you are no better than him.
-What would you have me do? -Help me stop him.
lt's too late.
l'm trusting you with my life.
And my son's.
What are you saying?
Claudio went to Washington to plant a bomb.
l can't be a part of it anymore.
They'll protect us, won't they?
lf they won't, l will.
Now!
Let's go.
Son of a bitch.
Eighth squad's on the way down.
Come on.
Hold your hover.
Insertion's under way.
Let her go!
Target out. Setting her up.
We have to go upriver. There's a minefield over there.
lKeep firing! lKill them all!
-Stay low. -We're trapped.
Got them in the clearing Firing away.
-Copy that. -It's confirmed. LZ is secure.
Let's go.
Looks like an officer.
Get down!
lKeep your eyes open!
Stand down!
What we've got here is a great American.
Goddamn you, Brandt. l was your excuse to kill all these people.
You're here to murder a man, right? l'm trying to save a country.
-lKeep its poison off our streets. -By killing innocents?
l fight terrorists with terror.
What terrorists? The Wolf isn't even here!
He's gone to Washington to blow up another building!
What do you mean? Where?
l'll tell you as soon as l'm on a jet heading home.
And they'll come with us, because this is his wife and his son.
She's the only one that can identify the target.
l appreciate it. Thank you.
Mr. Secretary, this just came in.
All right, NSA, ClA, Southern Command, they're at your disposal.
Washington Surveillance Command will assist with our search.
Stay on station. Be ready.
We got an audio-encoded e-mail. lt's authentic.
Run it.
My last warning went unheard.
The American people willpay for this mistake in blood.
A bomb has been placed in your capital city.
By the time you hear this message, it will be too late for you to find it.
And many of your citizens will die.
Their needless sacrifice is the price of your ignorance.
There will be no mercy.
There's no place you can hide.
We 'll continue to strike until the American public...
...finally realizes the price of this war...
...is one they cannot afford.
Get out of Colombia now.
Sangre o libertad.
Good to see you with all your fingers and toes.
This is Selena Perrini.
-Agent Phipps. This is Agent Dray. -How do you do?
-We'd like to get started. -Sit.
Good luck.
-Something to drink? -Water, please.
All right, David, let's get ready.
We've assembled pictures of buildings with columns as you've described.
We'll go through them.
lf you see anything familiar, please give us a nod. Here we go, David.
These are photos of this building from different angles. Here's the facade.
Did he describe any activity in this building?
-No, he didn't discuss anything. -Ms. Perrini.
This is the same building, different angles.
-Can you zoom in on that? -l can't tell.
-Take a look at this entrance. -That's not it.
Can you zoom in on that?
-How about this one? -No, that's not it.
Does this look at all familiar?
-lKeep going. -l don't know.
You two make quite a team. Fireman and the refugee.
Sounds like a TV show.
And you could play the asshole.
All right. We're gonna let everybody know.
Secretary Ramsey's coming over.
Wait. Go back. Go back. There.
-This one. -That one?
-Familiar? -lt's this picture.
Union Station. You got that?
-Yes. -Here's another shot of it.
ls that it?
Go back two and zoom in on the entrance.
Look at this one, here's the entrance.
Oh, my God, l think so.
Eyeball footage from every station's camera in the last 24 hours.
David, let's go back on that, please.
Let's go! Go, go, go! Pick it up!
Don't get up.
Selena, Secretary of State Barbara Ramsey.
We understand the sacrifice you're making here.
Thank you.
-The fireman's over here. -Peter!
Madam Secretary, sir, l think we got something.
Dave, the file's in your active bin.
lt was taken off one of the Union Station monitors 13 minutes ago.
-What is it? -First photograph:
Man behind the trees with a briefcase.
Second photograph: goes behind the trees, briefcase is gone.
Punch in on that.
On the face.
Yeah, that's him.
Tell our team the location of that camera.
lt's almost rush hour.
Good afternoon, this is Shrub. Yeah, very urgent.
Thank you. He's coming on line.
Yes, we've identified the target.
l'll be leaving shortly.
l saw him over there.
No media statement at all.
l'll cover here.
You did the right thing.
-l hope so. -No, l'm sure of it.
Look, it's something you had to do.
Right now, l don't feel very good about anything.
l'm sorry about that.
Look, everything will be all right.
Excuse me. Can you show me to the restroom?
Sure. Follow me.
Are you all right?
He's gonna be fine with me.
Why don't you go ahead?
Mr. Brewer, l just want to express to you my sympathy.
As long as America continues its aggression in Colombia...
... we will bring the war home to you.
And you will not feel safe in your own beds.
Colombia is not your country.
Get out now. Sangre o libertad.
Sangre o libertad.
Oh, my God.
Where's he going?
Don't open it!
You should wipe your nose off with that.
Selena!
Stop her!
Open up the door! Open up!
Open up the door! Open up now!
Everybody, clear out the room! There's a bomb in here!
Give me the toy. Under the table.
-What are you doing? -There's a bomb!
Get back! Get back! Get back!
-Get the secretary out of here! -Close it down!
-Take care of the boy, okay? -l will.
Please evacuate andproceed to the exit.
Attention, this is not a drill.
Move out of the way! Go!
Exit using stairwells only. Do not use the elevator.
This is not a drill. Do not use the elevators.
lt's not working. Go back to the controls.
lt's over!
lt's never over.
So when are you going to kill me?
Now!
-lt's over. -For you, sir, l hope that's true.
-Where's the boy? -Right here, sir.
The first terrorist attack on our capital....
Secretary of State Ramsey escaped unharmed.
--discovered a vehicle in an underground garage...
...loaded with explosives.
--confirmed the death ofa security official.
The bomb was placed by Colombian terrorist, The Wolf.
The White House announced that the president will award Gordon Brewer...
...the Medal of Freedom, the highest decoration a civilian can receive.
Despite efforts to contact him, Brewer remains unavailable for comment.