It's cold.
Where should we go?
Anywhere, just make it quick.
It's ready.
Over here!
It's over here.
Someone must've fallen
from the roof.
Suicide?
I don't know.
Let's go check it out.
Someone died
and you wanna wa'tch?
Let's go see it later.
Excuse me.
What are you doing?
Hurry up.
Do you know where
Lee Eun-yi lives?
Forgive me for entering
your home without permission.
But I need to be careful
about new hires.
I checked your resume
and references and so on.
But I wanted to see for myself
how you lived.
Please don't misunderstand.
Not much of a talker, are you?
I heard you have
a small apartment in Pyung-taek?
Yes, I had to rent it out.
You went over everything
with Mrs. Cho?
You're here
on her recommendation.
We appreciate your help.
No, ma'am.
Thank you.
It's huge, isn't it?
It is quite large.
It's because there are
two of them in there.
You didn't tell her?
Mrs. Cho...
I told you not to do that again.
Oh, twins are no problem.
I'll work out
the terms again, ma'am.
Should fit you perfectly.
Don't let them see you
in anything else.
It's nice, but...
I never wore anything like this
at work before.
Madam's underwear
is in her bathroom
you should hand wash it.
When you get that big,
you pee just by sneezing.
Look in the laundry basket,
please.
You're Nami, right?
I'm the new nanny, Eun-yi.
I told you
a new maid was coming today.
I know.
Aren't you going to go
greet your mother?
After I change
and wash my hands.
I can do it myself.
- Then call me if you need me.
- Okay.
- Should I close the door?
- Yes, please.
Do you like the new maid?
She likes me a lot.
- Did she say that?
- No.
Then how do you know?
I can see it in her face.
It's all going to be
thrown out.
We might as well eat it.
Are you insane?
I'm sorry.
He's here.
She's new, sir.
She'll be here for a while.
This is Lee Eun-yi,
she took care of
Hyun's baby brother for 3 years.
She's divorced and living alone.
Ah, do you have any children?
Have a seat, please.
Go tell Mom
there's no need to come down.
I'll be right up.
Okay.
I'm Goh Hoon.
Nami's father.
Lee Eun-yi, sir.
I don't have anything to say
in particular.
But you'll be raising my kids...
and cooking the food I'll eat.
You're an important person.
I should greet you properly.
Madam?
Would you send up
a bottle of red wine?
He calls you madam?
Sometimes.
When he feels like it.
Take it up to him.
Were you grouchy
all day again?
I can't even breathe.
And my stomach's so itchy.
You exercise too much.
I need to be healthy
for a natural delivery.
You know, the doctors say
that won't be easy.
Of course they say that.
A C-section is easier for them.
They'll do as I tell them.
You sure you can handle it?
Of course.
I'm the mom.
Ms. Lee used to be an
early childhood education major.
What does that have to do
with actually raising kids?
I guess.
She seems kind of childlike.
That's good.
She'll get along with the kids.
Eun-yi?
Yes?
You're still awake?
Can you leave the door
open a little?
This much?
More please.
Thank you.
Who's playing?
Black pepper.
Two times.
Take it.
The Beethoven sounded nice.
Bye.
- Breakfast, please.
- Yes, ma'am.
Me, too.
Breakfast, please.
Yes, ma'am.
That's too hot.
I think Mr. Goh is back, ma'am.
I should clean the washroom.
My fingernails tomorrow, please.
Yes, ma'am.
Try it.
If you want more,
stop by my father's house.
Drink, it's good.
Much better!
You brought your swimsuit,
right?
Gotcha!
You're a good swimmer.
You're floating!
Up you go.
It's so cold...
Mmm, hot water!
You know why I'm not getting
a C-section, baby?
I'm going to have
4 or 5 children.
I don't get why your brother's
wife stopped after two kids.
That's for common people who
have to struggle to raise them.
Not so deep.
I think we should stop.
What a shame...
I'll use my mouth.
Is that you, Nami?
Come on down.
Drink up.
Let me see.
Pull off the blanket.
God, I love this smell.
Suck it.
"The Second Sex"
That'll be all.
Ms. Lee?
Thank you.
Bye, honey.
Not so hard.
Your eyes seem so desperate
to find your baby.
Your eyes, pure like diamonds
and sharp like sapphire.
Now, shed your tears
into the lake.
I will take only your eyes.
Then I will bring you
to the other side of the lake
to your baby.
The young mother sighs
in desperation.
If I can only save my baby
from death...
Of course
I will give you my eyes.
The mother starts
shedding tears into the lake.
Look at the picture.
I love how
you're such a nice girl.
You're not bad-tempered,
you're polite to me.
I learned that from Father.
He said
to treat people politely.
It may seem like
a sign of respect,
but it's really
putting myself first.
You're lucky to have a father
who teaches you things
like that.
Open the door wide tonight,
please.
Yes, Miss.
It's so late.
You don't have to do that.
Congratulations on your son.
Thank you, sir.
You must be tired.
I'm fine, sir.
I'm going to cum.
Can I do it inside you?
Please don't.
Then let me cum in your mouth.
Yes!
Not now.
Suck it hard when I put it in.
What?
Suck it like a straw.
I'll try.
I'm so scared.
What are you scared of?
I'm terrified.
Now, in your mouth!
- Where is it?
- Here!
Take it.
You!
Let's eat.
Wow.
They're kicking hard.
You're impatient to come out?
You two are so lively!
They're moving around.
You get up in the morning
and think of
what you have to endure...
...and damn
it makes your gut hurt.
But what can you do?
Just breathe in deep,
and transform into a cold stone.
Sorry I can't be warmer to you.
This job is R.U.N.S.
What?
Revolting, ugly,
nauseating, and shameless.
I wasted my whole life
in this place.
How long do you plan to do this?
I like this job.
You got a man?
You're still in good shape.
Aren't I?
I still got it, huh?
Are you dating or not?
Out there
the world's full of men.
But no one's
really worth my time.
That's true.
She used to eat
the stinkiest kimchi...
But now she won't even touch it.
She can't keep her food down.
And her breasts seem swollen.
I know how sharp you are.
So I asked her off guard,
but she doesn't have a man.
I'm pretty sure of it, ma'am.
So she doesn't even realize
she's pregnant yet?
Well, she's kind of
on the slow side...
Slow?
Really?
What do you think she'll do
when she finds out?
Slow, or naive...
She's not completely stupid,
but she won't pull any tricks.
She's pure-hearted.
Like Dostoyevsky's Idiot?
Your daughter got mad at me
for coming here.
Like she can do anything
without me.
I heard your son
got appointed to prosecutor.
Truly amazing, huh?
Thank you.
It's all thanks to you.
What do you mean?
It's a personal triumph for you.
A personal triumph.
Your boss came in naked
and you didn't even resist?
I was naked, too
and waiting for him!.
Are you out of your mind?
So, is it any different
with a rich man?
He finished with that.
Guess it is different.
Are you going to keep
working in that house?
Yes.
Isn't it uncomfortable
being around his wife?
It's like
nothing really happened.
But it did happen.
You can't change that.
Bye, Mom.
I won't be coming anymore.
Why call in someone else
to do the cleaning?
Just have her do it bit by bit.
She won't be too busy
until the twins are born.
That damn thing!
My god, Mom!
Stay calm, don't panic.
Mom, do something!
Don't move!
Ma'am?
Please grab my leg.
Grandma! Hurry!
Nami, you stay still.
Mom!
Are you crazy?
Shut up
if you don't know anything.
She just has
a slight concussion.
But she feels pain in her pelvis
so we'll do some tests.
She fell
from the second floor?
She's very lucky.
Your husband's fucking her,
and she's pregnant.
That's a fact.
The possibility that the baby's
not your husband's?
Zero.
So you pulled that shit
in front of Nami?
I can't believe you.
What shit?
That was just an accident.
Yes?
She has a concussion
bruised pelvis,
and some abrasions.
They're all pretty minor.
She just needs
a couple days rest.
That's not
what I want to know.
The doctor
didn't mention that.
And she didn't
discharge any blood.
Tough as a weed, that girl...
The doctors did all that testing
and didn't find out
she's pregnant?
It's still too early to tell,
ma'am.
You sure you didn't
make a mistake?
Fine! Calm her down
and come back.
I heard Hoon's going abroad
on business.
Just hold on for tonight.
I'll take care of everything
before he gets back.
Mother, I want to be alone.
With a rich husband, cheating
is just part of the package.
Hae-ra's mother says
she's really sorry.
She says to rest up
and not worry about anything.
It must've been heavy.
Your consolation payment.
You know this is how that family
solves any problems, right?
Convenient for them.
And not bad for us either.
Get some rest.
Mrs. Cho!
Do you still see me
as that helpless little
high school girl?
Of course not, ma'am.
In that case
how dare you gossip
about my husband
behind my back to outsiders?
Outsiders?
How am I an outsider?
Mom!
My deepest apologies, ma'am.
It won't happen again.
Hello, Mother.
Hi.
- Hae-ra is edgy.
- These days she always is.
I don't see
the young maid today.
I sent her to the hospital.
She's not feeling well, sir.
This late?
They admitted her
for the night.
Oh, really?
She'll be back tomorrow, sir.
Mrs. Cho?
Why are you chattering on
this late at night?
With that annoying
voice of yours.
And why does it take you hours
to pack a suitcase?
Is it because you're old?
I am the mother...
...of a prosecutor
of the Republic of Korea!
Revolting, ugly,
nauseating, and shameless!
R.U.N.S.
R.U.N.S!
- Here's Ms. Lee Eun-yi.
- Thank you.
We didn't notice it at first.
See this?
The fertilized egg
implanted in your womb?
You're pregnant.
Looks like about four weeks.
It's a blessing to be pregnant.
Be brave.
Was it your boss?
You'll spend all your savings
giving birth
and raising the baby.
But I guess savings are meant
to be spent in times like this.
Maybe there's some sort of
government support?
Is it your boss' baby?
I mean, he's rich and all.
Have you ever had an abortion?
You should pack up
and get out of that house now.
Abortion or not.
Then what?
You can think about that later.
Your baby's not going anywhere.
Thank you.
There are obstetrics tests
listed on the hospital bill.
Now she knows she's pregnant.
Let's see what that bimbo
tries to pull.
What did he see
in that cheap, common slut?
I should've pushed her
from someplace higher
and ended things.
Damn it.
I'm sorry, Eun-yi.
I can't believe
I made a mistake like that.
You understand, right?
Yes, ma'am.
Your friend got you
some herbal medicine?
I should've done that.
No, I'm fine, ma'am.
I'll be up again soon.
I'm late for work.
Bye.
Drink that lying down.
Go on. Lie down.
How could that bastard
do this to me?
In my house, with the bitch
who washes my underwear.
You made her wash
your underwear?
No need for you to resent Hoon.
From the day he was born,
he had everything
he ever wanted.
Whatever he saw
if he wanted it, it was his.
No matter what.
All the men
in that family are like that.
Look at your mother-in-law.
She suffered through such awful
things because of those guys.
Normal people
can't even imagine it.
But she endured it all
to become who she is today.
And look at her now.
Everyone worships
the ground she walks on.
You'll be like that, too.
And your children
will be like Hoon.
That's what both
you and I want, isn't it?
Let him sleep around
all he wants.
Later, you can enjoy yourself
and live like a queen.
You know...
This house is kind of scary.
Why?
Last night...
What about last night?
Had a nightmare?
I think I'd better
quit working here.
Then pack up now and go.
But until they find
someone else...
Look.
No one in this family will care
that you're gone.
Just go.
But I should tell them...
Just cut the bullshit
and leave.
What if she shows up one day
with her baby?
You think a few million dollars
would solve the problem?
She'll hinder you for life,
and be a thorn in the side
of Nami and the twins, too.
You should deal with it now.
Make her get rid of it
before it's too late.
Come in.
Sit down.
I'm sorry to say this.
But something came up.
What is it?
It's a family matter.
What are you doing?
I said, what are you doing?
I treated you
humanely and nicely.
Didn't I?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
About what?
I'll see myself out.
Stay right there, please.
I apologize.
For what?
Mother?
Sit up straight.
Let's go get an abortion.
Then you can take this
and leave.
Then we'll all go back
to living in peace.
That's a $100,OOO check.
That thing inside you,
it's nothing.
You can just cut it off,
like a cyst.
Think wisely.
But how did you all know?
I'll give you a few days,
but you won't get yourway,
eVer.
She's been so affectionate
to the kids in my stomach.
So her own kid...
She won't give up the baby
for all the money in the world.
Never.
Stupid!
Imbecile!
I should've
thought of Madam...
I did a horrible thing.
It's her husband
who should've thought of her.
Did the hospital tell them
I am pregnant?
If you want more money, ask.
They'll pay.
And forget the baby.
Look.
Do you really want to
have this baby and bring it up?
I'm not sure.
Why'd you just stand still
and let her slap you like that?
I'm sorry.
Don't be sorry!
Damn!
You're still awake?
You sleep first, tonight.
I'll watch over you.
I'm sorry.
About what?
Grandma pushing the ladder
on purpose.
I saw it.
It was an accident
because of the vacuum cleaner.
You're a good person.
I feel bad.
"Herbal medicine"
- Mrs. Cho!
- Yes?
Tell her to move
out of this room.
Pardon?
Put her in your room
and keep an eye on her.
Why did you move to this room?
A new nanny will come.
Why?
Are you sick?
It's not that.
There's a baby
inside my tummy, too.
Is it a boy or a girl?
I hope it's a girl like you.
I'm not sure yet.
It's still too small, right?
Nami...
Yes?
Nami?
Your mother's waiting.
Bye, Eun-yi.
I hope you deliver safely.
- Where were you?
- Never mind.
Keep an eye on that woman.
Yes.
What a relief!
Liberation!
Madam Cho?
I'm having this baby.
Go ahead.
Hello, Mother.
Thank you for being here.
Right on time
despite being so busy.
Go on in.
Let's eat.
They even took my cell phone.
Sit.
What do they think
they can do to my baby?
These people are scary.
I'm scared something awful
might happen to you.
Bravo.
Well done, my sweetie.
Thank you, honey.
Get some rest.
I'll go change and come back.
Son of a bitch.
That's enough, okay?
Stop there.
After these precious angels
were just born...
My stomach.
I don't need anything.
Damn bitch.
How dare she!
What are you doing there?
I was feeling
under the weather.
Wanna join me?
As you wish...
Were the twins born?
What's wrong with you?
I'm pregnant.
But the ladies of the house
found out everything.
They really smacked me around.
They said they'd give me
$1OO,OOO if I have an abortion.
But I'm having this baby.
What are you doing in there?
Get out of there, now!
I know you don't even
think of me as human.
But this baby is yours!
No! Don't do this!
No, baby!
I'll just disappear quietly
and live with my baby.
I couldn't hurt anyone,
and I don't need money.
You're the father.
This is your baby, too.
Calm down, Ms. Lee.
Let's have the baby, okay?
Thank you, Mr. Goh.
Sorry for getting pregnant
from someone like you.
She was squirming
in such pain,
I gave her a shot
of something strong.
Good work.
The men in this family
are really something.
- See you.
- Bye.
Pack her things
and send her out.
Don't let her back here, ever.
Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Goh wants to see you.
- Me?
- Yes.
- He saw her?
- Yes, ma'am.
Is the baby dead?
Completely?
Oh, it seems she fooled around
and came in pregnant.
Why do you even care?
Ma'am!
I'll ask the questions.
The baby's completely erased?
Yes.
She said it was my baby.
Who says?
She'd say anything to try
to rip some money off us.
If it wasn't mine
why go through all the trouble?
Did you slip her some poison?
It wasn't me.
Then who was it?
Your daughter?
Sorry.
It was me.
Are you completely insane?
This is a real shock to me.
It's my child.
How dare you think
you can do that?
Who has the nerve!
Look.
Is it not my child
if your daughter
doesn't give birth to it?
Is that it?
No, course not.
Did you get a signature?
Just do it.
It's an emergency.
Isn't that woman outside
her mother?
No.
It's no one.
It was probably Hae-ra
who did it.
Scary people.
Probably why they're so rich.
Nami said...
She saw her grandmother push me
from the second floor.
She apologized,
and said she felt sorry for me.
Kids don't lie.
But I didn't even know
I was pregnant then!
I did.
Nothing goes on in that house
without me knowing.
I knew everything.
When you came home
from the hospital,
your baby's fate was decided.
Even if I hadn't told them...
I'm sorry.
I'm ashamed.
But a woman like me...
...it's in my bones.
Take this and find someone nice.
You'll be fine
you have a good heart.
I'm going to get revenge.
I know.
Anyone would want to.
No! However small
I have to do something!
Damned world has been
so cruel to me.
You poor thing.
I'll apologize for them.
Happy?
Their daughter, Nami...
She was genuinely nice to me.
Stop thinking about it.
I wanted to have a pretty
little daughter like her.
A girl who's kind to me.
Wipe those thoughts
from your head.
I smell like the restaurant
don't I?
No.
Go to sleep.
And forget it ever happened.
R.U.N.S., R.U.N.S.
We haven't done it for ages.
You're unclean.
Me?
Put your hand
on your heart and think.
All right.
Still, tell me when you're ready
for our 4th and 5th kids.
Ms. Lee!
What the hell
are you doing here?
"What the hell
are you doing here?"
- Leave the baby alone.
- "Leave the baby alone."
- Go, go!
- I'm going!
- Honey!
- "Honey!"
What's going on?
She's crazy!
Mrs. Cho?
How did that bimbo get in here?
Who let her in?
Kick her out, now.
Call the men
if you can't do it alone.
I quit.
I'm leaving this house, now.
What's this all of a sudden?
I'm already packed to go.
Where do you get the nerve?
Chase that crazy bitch out
before you go!
Never shut up, do you?
From now on, if you want
something do it yourselves.
I quit.
What are you doing, Mrs. Cho!
What the hell are you doing?
You really want to
live like this?
This is what these people
are like.
Just ignore her.
Eun-yi!
Nami, how have you been?
Okay.
What about you?
You must be so happy to have
two angelic little brothers.
It's so-so.
What about the baby
inside your tummy?
My baby?
It died.
Why?
Eun-yi?
Don't do it.
Walk out of here with me.
I can't get it
out of my head...
what happened here.
It's so horrible...
I can't take it anymore.
That's why.
Ms. Lee.
I apologize for what happened.
I'll settle with you as needed.
You know me.
Nami.
Thank you for everything.
I'm sorry to you,
and the twins.
Don't forget me!
Promise!
What's she doing?
Fire!
Let's get out of here!
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday
My precious girl
Happy birthday...
Subtitles by Merah