Paramount News brings you a special coverage
of Princess Ann's visit to London,
the first stop on her much-publicized goodwill tour of European capitals.
She gets a royal welcome from the British,
as thousands cheer the gracious young member
of one of Europe's oldest ruling families.
After three days of continuous activity and a visit to Buckingham Palace,
Ann flew to Amsterdam,
where Her Royal Highness dedicated the new International Aid Building
and christened an ocean liner,
then went to Paris,
where she attended many official functions
designed to cement trade relations
between her country and the Western European nations.
And so, to Rome, the Eternal City,
where the princess' visit was marked by a spectacular military parade
highlighted by the band of the crack Bersaglieri regiment.
The smiling young princess showed no sign of the strain
of the week's continuous public appearances,
and, at her country's embassy that evening,
a formal reception and ball in her honor
was given by her country's ambassador to Italy.
Her Royal Highness.
His Excellency, the Papal Nuncio, Monsignor Altomonte.
Sir Hugo Macy de Farmington.
- Good evening, Sir Hugo.
- Good evening, Your Royal Highness.
His Highness the Maharajah of Khanipur
and the Rajkumari.
I'm so glad that you could come.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, madam.
Friherre Erick af Massinsjarna Bergenskiold.
Prince Istvan Barlossy Nagyavaros.
How do you do?
Lhre Hoheit der Furst und die Fursten von und zu Luchtenstichenholz.
Sir Hari Singh and Kmark Singh.
The Count and Countess Von Marstrand.
Good evening, Countess.
Good evening.
Señor e Señora Joao de Camoes.
Hassan El Din Pasha.
How do you do?
I hate this nightgown.
I hate all my nightgowns, and I hate all my underwear, too.
My dear, you have lovely things.
But I'm not two hundred years old.
Why can't I sleep in pajamas?
Pajamas!
Just the top part.
Did you know there are people
who sleep with absolutely nothing on at all?
I rejoice to say that I did not.
Listen.
Ann, your slippers.
Please put on your slippers and come away from the window.
Your milk and crackers.
Everything we do is so wholesome.
They'll help you to sleep.
I'm too tired to sleep. I shan't sleep a wink.
Now, my dear, if you don't mind, tomorrow's schedule, or "schedule,"
whichever you prefer. Both are correct.
8:30, breakfast here with the embassy staff.
9:00, we leave for the Polinari automotive works,
where you'll be presented with a small car.
Thank you.
Which you will not accept.
No, thank you.
10:35, inspection of food and agricultural organization,
will present you with an olive tree.
No, thank you.
Which you will accept.
Thank you.
10:55, the New Foundling Home for Orphans.
You will preside over the laying of the cornerstone.
Same speech as last Monday.
Trade relations.
Yes.
For the orphans?
No, no, no, the other one.
Youth and progress.
Precisely.
11:45, back here to rest. No, that's wrong.
11:45, conference here with the press.
Sweetness and decency.
1:00 sharp, lunch with the Foreign Ministry.
You will wear your white lace and carry a bouquet of
- very small pink roses.
- Very small pink roses.
3:05, presentation of a plaque.
Thank you.
4:10, review Special Guard of Carabinieri...
No, thank you.
- 4:45, back here to change...
- How do you do? Charmed.
...into your uniform to meet the...
- So happy...
Stop!
- Good heavens!
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
It's all right, dear. It didn't spill.
I don't care if it spilled or not.
I don't care if I drowned in it!
My dear, you're ill.
I'll send for Dr. Bonnachoven.
I don't want Dr. Bonnachoven! Please let me die in peace.
You're not dying.
Leave me!
- Leave me!
- It's nerves. Control yourself, Ann.
I don't want to!
Your Highness!
I'll get Dr. Bonnachoven.
It's no use.
I'll be dead before he gets here.
She's asleep.
She was in hysterics three minutes ago, Doctor.
Are you asleep, ma'am?
No!
I'll only disturb Your Royal Highness a moment.
I'm very ashamed, Dr. Bonnachoven.
Sudenly, I was crying.
To cry, a perfectly normal thing to do.
It's most important she be calm and relaxed
for the press conference, Doctor.
Don't worry, Doctor.
I'll be calm and relaxed.
I'll bow, and I'll smile.
I'll improve trade relations, and...
There she goes again. Give her something, Doctor, please.
Uncover her arm, please.
What's that?
Sleep and calm.
This will relax you and make Your Highness feel a little happy.
It's a new drug, quite harmless.
There.
I don't feel any different.
You will. It may take a little time to take hold.
Just, now, lie back.
Can I keep just one light on?
Of course.
Best thing I know
is to do exactly what you wish for a while.
Thank you, Doctor.
The General! Doctor, quick!
I'm perfectly all right.
Good night, ma'am.
- Good night, ma'am.
- Good night, Doctor.
Bet 500.
500. How many?
One.
I'll take one.
Three.
Foolish boy.
Two for papa.
500 more.
Without looking.
500, and I'll raise you 1,000.
Two pairs.
I got three shy little sevens.
A nervous straight. Come home, you fools.
Look at that. 6,500.
Not bad. That's 10 bucks.
One more round,
and I'm going to throw you gents right out in the snow.
Say, what is this?
I got to get up early.
Date with Her Royal Highness,
who will graciously pose for some pictures.
What do you mean, early? My personal invitation says 11:45.
Couldn't be anything to do with the fact that you're ahead?
It could.
It works out fine for me. This is my last 5,000,
and you hyenas are not gonna get it. Thanks a lot, Irving.
Yeah, see you at Annie's little party in the morning.
- Ciao, Joe.
- Yeah, ciao.
Good night, Joe.
All right, a little seven-card stud.
Okay with me.
So happy.
How are you this evening?
Hey, hey, hey.
Hey, wake up.
Thank you very much. Delighted.
Wake up.
No, thank you.
Charmed.
Charmed, too.
You may sit down.
I think you'd better sit up.
You're much too young to get picked up by the police.
- Police?
- Yep. Police.
2:15 and back here to change. 2:45...
You know, people who can't handle liquor shouldn't drink it.
"If I were dead and buried and I heard your voice
"beneath the sod my heart of dust would still rejoice."
Do you know that poem?
What do you know?
You're well-read, well-dressed,
snoozing away in a public street.
Would you care to make a statement?
What the world needs is a return to sweetness and decency
in the souls of its young men and...
Yeah, I couldn't agree with you more, but...
Get yourself some coffee. You'll be all right.
Look, you take the cab.
Come on, climb in the cab and go home.
- So happy.
- You got any money?
Never carry money.
That's a bad habit.
All right. I'll drop you off. Come on.
It's a taxi!
Well, it's not the Super Chief.
Where are we going?
Where do you live?
Colosseum.
Now, come on. You're not that drunk.
You're so smart. I'm not drunk at all.
I'm just being very happy.
There, now, don't go to sleep again. Come on.
Where are we going?
- Okay.
- Look, now, where do you want to go?
Where shall I take you?
Where do you live?
Come on. Come on. Where do you live?
Come on! Where do you live?
Colosseum.
She lives in the Colosseum.
Is wrong adress.
Now, look, signore, for me, it is very late night.
Wife. I have three bambino, three bambino.
You know bambino?
My taxi go home. I go home, too. Together.
Via Margutta 51.
Here is Via Margutta 51.
I am very happy.
1,000 lira.
One, two, three, four mille.
Okay.
For me?
Okay, okay. Now, look.
- Take a little bit of that...
- Yeah?
Take her wherever she wants to go.
Good night.
- No, no, no, no.
- All right, look.
As soon as she wakes up, see,
she'll tell you where she wants to go, okay?
My taxi is not for sleep.
My taxi. No sleep. Understand? You understand?
Look, pal. This is not my problem, see?
I never see her before. Okay.
Is not your problem. Is not my problem.
What you want? You don't want girl, yeah?
Me don't want girl.
Police! Maybe she want girl.
Okay, okay, okay.
So happy... So happy...
I ought to have my head examined.
Is this the elevator?
It's my room.
I'm terribly sorry to mention it, but the dizziness is getting worse.
Can I sleep here?
That's the general idea.
Can I have a silk nightgown with rosebuds on it?
I'm afraid you'll have to rough it tonight, in these.
Pajamas!
Sorry, honey, but I haven't worn a nightgown in years.
Will you help me get undressed, please?
Okay.
There you are. You can handle the rest.
May I have some?
No.
Now, look...
This is very unusual.
I've never been alone with a man before,
even with my dress on.
With my dress off, it's most unusual.
I don't seem to mind.
Do you?
I think I'll go out for a cup of coffee.
You'd better get to sleep.
No. On this one.
So terribly nice.
These are pajamas. They're to sleep in.
You're to climb into them. You understand?
Thank you.
And you do your sleeping on the couch, see, not on the bed.
Not on the chair, on the couch. Is that clear?
Do you know my favorite poem?
You've already recited that for me.
"Arethusa arose From her couch of snows
"In the Acroceraunian mountains."
- Keats.
- Shelley.
You just keep your mind off the poetry and on the pajamas.
Everything'll be all right, see?
- It's Keats.
- Now, I'll be...
It's Shelley. I'll be back in about 10 minutes.
Keats.
You have my permission to withdraw.
Thank you very much.
- Well?
- No trace, Your Excellency.
Have you searched the grounds?
Every inch, sir, from the attics to the cellar.
I must put you on your honor not to speak of this to anyone.
I must remind you that the princess is the direct heir to the throne.
This must be classified as top crisis secret.
- Have I your pledge?
- Yes, sir.
Very well.
Now we must notify Their Majesties.
Oh.
So happy.
The pleasure's mine.
Screwball.
Holy smoke! The princess interview.
11:45.
Hi, Joe.
- Good morning, Joe.
- Hello, honey.
Mr. Hennessy has been looking for you.
Thanks a lot, hon.
Come in!
You've been looking for me?
Just coming to work?
Who, me?
We start our days at 8:30 in this office.
We pick up our assignments...
I picked mine up last night.
- What assignment was that?
- The princess. 11:45.
You've already been to the interview?
Sure. I just got back.
- Well, well, well, all my apologies.
- It's all right.
- This is very interesting.
- No, just routine.
Tell me, tell me, did she answer all the questions on the list?
Well, of course she did. I've got them right here somewhere.
Don't disturb yourself. I have a copy here.
How did Her Highness react to the idea of a European federation?
She thought it was just fine.
She did?
Well, she thought that there'd be two effects.
Two?
The direct and the indirect.
Remarkable.
Naturally, she thought that the indirect would not be as direct as the direct.
- That is, not right away.
- No, no, no, no.
Later on, of course, well, nobody knows.
Well, well, well, that was a shrewd observation.
They fool you, you know, these royal kids.
They've got a lot more on the ball than we suspect.
How did she feel about the future friendship of nations?
Youth.
She felt that the youth of the world
must lead the way to a better world.
Original.
By the way, what was she wearing?
You mean, what did she have on?
That's usually what it means.
What's the matter? Is it a little warm in here for you?
No, no. I just hurried over here, that's all.
Naturally, with a story of these dimensions.
Did you say she was wearing gray?
No, I didn't say that.
Well, she usually wears gray.
Well, it was a kind of a gray.
I think I know the dress you mean. It has a gold collar.
That's the one. That's the one, yeah.
I didn't know exactly how to describe it, but that's...
I think you described it very well,
in view of the fact that Her Highness
was taken violently ill at 3:00 this morning,
put to bed with a high fever,
and has had all her appointments for today canceled in toto!
In toto?
Yes, Mr. Bradley, in toto.
It's certainly pretty hard to swallow.
In view of the fact that you just left her, of course.
But here it is, Mr. Bradley,
all over the front page of every newspaper in Rome.
All right, all right, I overslept. It can happen to anybody.
If you only got up early enough to read a morning paper,
you might discover little news events,
little items of general interest
that might prevent someone in the future from getting immersed
in such a gold-plated, triple-decked, star-spangled lie
as you have just told me.
If I were you, I would try some other line of business,
like mattress testing.
Is this the princess?
Yes, Mr. Bradley, that is the princess.
It isn't Annie Oakley, Dorothy Lamour, or Madam Chiang Kai-Shek.
Take a good look at her.
You might be interviewing her again someday.
Am I fired?
No, you're not fired.
When I want to fire you, you won't have to ask.
You'll know you're fired!
The man's mad.
Giovanni, it's Joe Bradley.
Now, listen carefully. I want you to hurry up to my place
and see if there's somebody there asleep.
Say, Mr. Joe, I look.
You wait.
Mr. Joe?
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah. Tell me. Tell me.
Giovanni, I love you. Now, listen.
Yes, Mr. Joe?
A gun?
No!
Yes, a gun, a knife, anything,
but nobody goes in and nobody goes out.
Okay.
You still here?
How much would a real interview with this dame be worth?
Are you referring to Her Highness?
I'm not referring to Annie Oakley, Dorothy Lamour or...
How much?
What do you care? You got about as much chance as...
I know, but if I did, how much would it be worth?
Just a plain talk on world conditions might be worth 250.
Her views on clothes, of course, would be worth a lot more, maybe 1,000.
- Dollars?
- Dollars.
I'm talking about her views on everything.
The private and secret longings of a princess.
Her innermost thoughts,
as revealed to your Rome correspondent
in a private, personal, exclusive interview.
Can't use it, huh?
I didn't think you'd like it.
Come here.
Love angle, too, I suppose?
Practically all love angle.
With pictures.
Could be. How much?
That particular story will be worth five grand to any news service.
But tell me, Mr. Bradley, if you are sober,
just how you are going to obtain this fantastic interview.
I plan to enter her sickroom disguised as a thermometer.
You said five grand? I want you to shake on that.
And you realize, of course, Her Highness is in bed today
and leaves for Athens tomorrow?
Yep.
Now, I'd like to make a little side bet with you.
500 says you don't come up with the story.
What are you looking at that for?
I just want to see what time it is.
- Huh?
- What day it is.
It's a deal!
Now I'd like you to shake.
Let's see, you're into me for about 500 now.
When you lose this bet, you'll owe me 1,000.
Why, you poor sucker, I'll practically own you.
You have practically owned me for a couple of years now.
But that's all over.
I'm going to win that money,
and with it, I'm gonna buy me a one-way ticket back to New York.
Go on, go on, I love to hear you whine.
And when I'm back in a real newsroom, I'll enjoy thinking about you,
sitting here with an empty leash in your hands
and nobody to twitch for you.
So long, pigeon!
Hey, Joe. What you know?
Is everything okay, Giovanni?
Nobody she's come. Nobody she's go.
Absolutely nobody.
Swell. Thanks a lot.
Giovanni...
How would you like to make some money?
- Money?
- Yeah.
That's the stuff. Now, look, I've got a sure thing.
Double your money back in two days.
Double my money?
Yeah, well, I need a little investment capital
to swing the deal.
Now, if you'll just lend me a little cash...
You owing me two months' rent,
and you want me to lend you money?
- Yeah.
- No.
Tomorrow you'll be sorry.
Your Highness?
Your Royal Highness?
Yes, what is it?
Dear Dr. Bonnachoven...
Sure, yes, well, you're fine. Much better. Is there anything you want?
So many things.
- Yes? Well, tell the doctor.
- So...
Tell the good doctor everything.
I dreamt, and I dreamt.
Yes? Well, what did you dream?
I dreamt I was asleep in the street, and a young man came.
He was tall and strong, and he was so mean to me.
He was?
It was wonderful.
Good morning.
Where's Dr. Bonnachoven?
I'm afraid I don't know anybody by that name.
Wasn't I talking to him just now?
Afraid not.
Have I had an accident?
No.
Quite safe for me to sit up?
Perfect.
Thank you.
Are these yours?
Did you lose something?
No.
Would you be so kind as to tell me where I am?
Well, this is what is laughingly known as my apartment.
Did you bring me here by force?
No, no, no. Quite the contrary.
Have I been here all night, alone?
If you don't count me, yes.
So I've spent the night here with you?
Well, now, I don't know that I'd use those words, exactly,
but from a certain angle, yes.
How do you do?
- And you are...
- Bradley. Joe Bradley.
Delighted.
You don't know how delighted I am to meet you.
You may sit down.
Thank you very much.
What's your name?
You may call me Anya.
Thank you, Anya.
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- What time is it?
- About 1:30.
1:30! I must get dressed and go!
Why? What's your hurry? There's lots of time.
No, there isn't, and I've been quite enough trouble to you as it is.
Trouble?
You're not what I'd call trouble.
I'm not?
I'll run a bath for you.
There you are.
Here we go now.
There you are. That does it.
Give me a little slack, will you?
Irving! Why don't you answer the phone?
Look, this is Joe.
Irving, can you get over here in about five minutes?
No, I can't come now, Joe. I'm busy.
No.
Joe, I'm up to my ears in work.
Go and get into your next outfit, will you, honey? The canoe.
What kind of a scoop, Joe?
Look, Irving, I can't talk over the telephone.
One word in the wrong quarter,
and this whole thing might blow sky-high.
It's front-page stuff. That's all I can tell you.
It might be political or it might be a sensational scandal.
I'm not sure which, but it's a big story.
It's got to have pictures.
But I can't come now, Joe. I'm busy...
I'm busy now, and I'm meeting Francesca at Rocca's in a half an hour.
Don't understand.
There you are.
I was looking at all the people out here.
It must be fun to live in a place like this.
Yeah, it has its moments.
I can give you a running commentary on each apartment.
I must go.
I only waited to say good-bye.
Good-bye? Why, we've only just met.
- How about some breakfast?
- I'm sorry. I haven't time.
It must be a pretty important date to run off without eating.
It is.
Well, I'll go along with you, wherever you are going.
That's all right, thank you. I can find the place.
Thank you for letting me sleep in your bed.
That's all right. Think nothing of it.
It was very considerate of you.
You must have been awfully uncomfortable on that couch.
No. Do it all the time!
- Good-bye, Mr. Bradley.
- Good-bye.
Go right through there and down all the steps.
Thank you.
Well, small world.
Yes. I almost forgot. Can you lend me some money?
Yeah, that's right. You didn't have any last night, did you?
How much was it that you wanted?
Well, I don't know how much I need. How much have you got?
Well, suppose we just split this 50-50? Here's 1,000 lira.
1,000? Can you really spare all that?
It's about $1.50.
Well, I'll arrange for it to be sent back to you.
What is your adress?
Via Margutta 51.
Joe Bradley.
Good-bye. Thank you.
Double my money, eh?
You tell me why double my money that way?
Tomorrow, tomorrow.
Yeah, tomorrow.
What a wonderful hair you have.
Just cut, thank you.
Just cut?
Well, then, cut so?
Higher.
Higher?
Here?
More.
- Here?
- Even more.
Where?
There.
There?
Are you sure, miss?
I'm quite sure, thank you.
All off?
All off.
Off.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Yes.
Off!
Off.
That's a nice little camera you have there.
It's nice.
You don't mind if I just borrow it, do you?
- Miss Weber!
- Bring it right back.
- Just for a couple of minutes.
- No.
Let go. It's my camera.
You musician, maybe?
You artist?
Painter?
I know. You model.
Model.
Thank you.
It's perfect.
You be nice without long hair.
Now is cool. Cool?
Yes. It's just what I wanted.
Now, why you not come dancing tonight with me?
You should see. Is so nice.
Is on a boat on the Tiber, the river by Sant'Angelo.
Moonlight, music, romantic.
Is very, very... Very!
Please? You come?
I wish I could.
But your friend, I not think they recognize you.
No, I don't think they will.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
After 9:00, I will be there, dancing on river.
Remember, Sant'Angelo.
All my friends...
If you come, you will be most pretty of all girl.
Thank you.
- Good-bye.
1,000 lira.
No money.
I'm sorry. I've really no money.
Look.
I'm sorry.
Well, it's you.
Yes, Mr. Bradley.
Or is it?
Do you like it?
Yeah. Very much.
So that was your mysterious appointment.
Mr. Bradley, I have a confession to make.
Confession?
Yes. I ran away last night,
from school.
What was the matter?
Trouble with the teacher?
No, nothing like that.
Well, you don't just run away from school for nothing.
I only meant it to be for an hour or two.
They gave me something last night to make me sleep.
I see.
Now I'd better get a taxi and go back.
Well, look, before you do,
why don't you take a little time for yourself?
Maybe another hour.
Live dangerously. Take the whole day.
I could do some of the things I've always wanted to.
Like what?
You can't imagine.
I'd like to do just whatever I like the whole day long.
You mean, things like having your hair cut, eating gelato?
Yes, and I'd like to sit at a sidewalk cafe and look in shop windows,
walk in the rain.
Have fun, and maybe some excitement.
- Doesn't seem much to you, does it?
- It's great.
Tell you what.
Why don't we do all those things together?
Don't you have to work?
Work? No. Today's going to be a holiday.
But you don't want to do a lot of silly things.
Don't I?
First wish, one sidewalk cafe. Coming right up.
I know just the place. Rocca's.
What will the people at school say when they see your new haircut?
They'll have a fit.
What would they say if they knew I'd spent the night in your room?
Well, I tell you what. You don't tell your folks, and I won't tell mine.
It's a pact.
Well, what would you like to drink?
Champagne, please.
Champagne?
And cold coffee for me.
Must be quite a life you have in that school.
Champagne for lunch.
Only on special occasions.
For instance?
The last time was my father's anniversary.
Weding?
No. It was the 40th anniversary of the day he got his job.
Forty years on the job. What do you know about that?
What does he do?
Well, mostly you might call it public relations.
Well, that's hard work.
- Yes, I wouldn't care for it.
- Does he?
I've heard him complain about it.
Why doesn't he quit?
Well, people in that line of work almost never do quit,
unless it's actually unhealthy for them to continue.
Well, here's to his health, then.
You know, that's what everybody says.
It's all right?
Yes, thank you.
What is your work?
I'm in the selling game.
Really? How interesting.
What do you sell?
Fertilizer.
Chemicals. You know, chemicals.
Stuff like that.
Irving! Well, am I glad to see you!
Why? Did you forget your wallet?
Pull up a chair, Irving. Sit down with us.
Aren't you going to introduce me?
Yes. This is a very good friend of mine, Irving Radovich. Anya, Irving.
- Anya...
- Smith.
Hiya, Smitty.
Charmed.
Hey, anybody ever tell you you're a dead ringer for...
Well, I guess I'll be going.
No, don't do anything like that, Irving. Sit down. Join us. Join us.
Well, just till Francesca gets here.
Tell me, Mr. Radovich, what is a ringer?
Waiter?
It's an American term,
and it means anyone who has a great deal of charm.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Cousins.
Mr. Bradley's just been telling me all about his work.
I'd like to have heard that.
What do you do?
I'm in the same racket as Joe, only I'm...
I'm awfully sorry, Irving.
- What are you...
- I'm sorry.
Look, I can take a hint. I'll see you around.
Your drink's just here.
Yeah, here's your drink right now, Irving. Take it easy.
I'm sorry about that. Sit down. That's a good fellow.
Have a... That's a boy.
You're...
You're twisting my arm, you know.
Just be a little more careful not to spill.
Spill? Who's been doing the spilling?
You.
- Me?
- Yeah.
Where did you find this loony?
You're okay. Here's to you.
Here's hoping for the best.
If it wasn't for that hair, I'd swear that...
Thanks.
You slipped, Irving. You slipped, you almost hurt yourself that time.
I slipped? I almost hurt myself?
- Joe, I didn't slip!
- You've got a bad sprain there.
Never mind I got a bad sprain, Joe.
We'd better go in here and get it fixed up.
- Yeah, I'd like to...
- Will you excuse us for a minute?
Yes, of course. I'm so sorry.
- Come here, pal.
- Joe, now wait a minute.
What are you trying to do now? Take your hands off me.
- Have you got your lighter?
- What's that got to do with it?
- Have you got it?
- Yeah, but what are you trying to do?
Listen, what would you do for five grand?
- Five grand?
- Okay, look.
She doesn't know who I am or what I do.
Look, Irving, this is my story. I dug it up. I've got to protect it.
She's really the...
Your tintypes are gonna make this little epic twice as valuable.
- "The princess goes slumming."
- You're in for 25% of the take.
- The take's five Gs.
- Minimum. Hennessy shook hands on it.
- That's $1,500.
- It's $1,250.
Okay. Now you shake.
Okay, now lend me 30,000.
30,000? That's 50 bucks. Are you gonna buy the crown jewels?
She's out there now drinking champagne that I can't pay for.
We've got to entertain her, don't we?
Joe, we can't go running around town with a hot princess.
Do you want in on this deal or don't you?
This I want back Saturday.
Okay. Now where's your lighter?
Let's go to work.
Better now?
- Your ear.
- My ear?
Yeah. Joe fixed it.
Would you care for a cigarette?
Yes, please.
You won't believe this, but it's my very first.
Your very first?
No smoking in school?
Your first cigarette.
There. The gizmo works.
Well, what's the verdict? Okay?
Nothing to it.
That's right. Nothing to it.
I'll stretch my legs a little here.
I'll pick this one up, Irving.
Yeah. You can afford it.
Well, what shall we do next? Shall we make out a little schedule?
Not that word, please.
I didn't mean a work... School schedule.
I meant a fun schedule.
Yes. Let's just go.
Well, how about you, Irving? Are you ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
Francesca!
- This is...
- Smitty.
She's a grand girl, Irving. Grand.
Five grand, Irving.
- Joe!
- Where are you going now?
Honey, I gotta work. I'll call you tonight.
Look at those men!
They were supposed to be inconspicuous.
You asked for plain clothes.
Hey!
Stop! Come back here!
- Let me take this...
- No, no. Let it go. I can do it.
Yeah.
I'm going straight from now on.
American News Service? What did he mean?
Well, you know, you say you're with the press,
you can get away with anything.
Going to church to get married on a scooter, that's a hot one.
Joe's a wonderful liar.
Congratulations. Congratulations.
You don't have to look so worried. I won't hold you to it.
Thank you very much.
You don't have to be too grateful!
Okay, I won't.
I'm a good liar, too, aren't I, Mr. Bradley?
The best I ever met.
Thank you very much.
Say...
Come with me.
The mouth of truth.
The legend is that if you're given to lying and put your hand in there,
it'll be bitten off.
What a horrid idea.
Let's see you do it.
Sure.
Hello.
You beast!
It was perfectly all right! You never hurt your hand!
I'm sorry. It's just a joke.
You never hurt your hand.
I'm sorry. You okay?
- Yes.
- All right. Let's go.
Look out!
I'll park at the corner.
What do they mean, all these inscriptions?
Well, each one represents a wish fulfilled.
It all started during the war when there was an air raid right out here,
a man with his four children was caught in the street.
They ran over against the wall right there for shelter
and prayed for safety.
Bombs fell very close, but no one was hurt.
Later on, the man came back and he put up the first of these tablets.
Since then, it's become a sort of a shrine.
People come, and whenever their wishes are granted,
they put up another one of these little plaques.
Lovely story.
Read some of the inscriptions.
Make a wish?
Tell the doctor?
Anyway, the chances of it being granted are very slight.
Well, what now?
I've heard of a wonderful place for dancing on a boat.
You mean, the barges down by Sant'Angelo?
Yes, couldn't we go there tonight?
- Why not?
- Anything you wish.
And then at midnight, I'll turn into a pumpkin
and drive away in my glass slipper.
And that'll be the end of the fairytale.
Well, I guess Irving has to go now.
I do?
Yes, you know, that big business development of yours
that you have to attend to?
Oh, the development.
Yes, can't afford not to take care of that.
Yeah. I'll see you later, Smitty.
- Good luck with the big development.
- Thanks.
Two, please.
Hello.
Mr. Bradley, if you don't mind my saying so,
I think you are a ringer.
A what?
Oh!
Thanks very much.
You've spent the whole day doing things I've always wanted to.
Why?
I don't know. It seemed the thing to do.
I've never heard of anybody so kind.
It wasn't any trouble.
Or so completely unselfish.
Let's have a drink at the bar.
There you are!
I look for you a long time. I think maybe you not come.
Off... All off!
It's nice without, isn't it?
Cool.
Very, very good.
This is Mr. Bradley.
I, Mario Delani.
Old friends?
Yes. He cut my hair this afternoon. He invited me here tonight.
Well, what did you say the name was?
Delani. Mario Delani.
Mario Delani. I'm very glad to know you.
Me, too.
May I enjoy myself... The pleasure... Do you mind?
No, no. Go right ahead.
Thank you.
- Did I miss anything?
- You're just in time, pal.
Who's Smitty dancing with?
The barber.
Cut her hair this afternoon. Made a date for tonight.
The princess and the barber.
What is it?
August.
Thank you!
Bye.
Your Highness.
You'll dance quietly towards the entrance.
There is a car waiting.
- No.
- Your Highness, please.
You've made a mistake.
Let me go. Will you let me go?
Mr. Bradley! Let me go, will you? Mr. Bradley!
Let go!
You...
Hit him again, Smitty!
- Joe, here are my car keys.
- The police. The police. Come on.
The other side of the bridge.
All right?
Fine. How are you?
Fine.
Say, you know, you were great back there.
You weren't so bad yourself.
I guess we'd better get Irving's car and get out of here.
This is The American Hour from Rome,
continuing our program of musical selections.
Everything ruined?
No. They'll be dry in a minute.
Suits you.
You should always wear my clothes.
It seems I do.
I thought a little wine might be good.
Shall I cook something?
No kitchen. Nothing to cook. I always eat out.
Do you like that?
Life isn't always what one likes.
Is it?
No, it isn't.
- Tired?
- A little.
You've had quite a day.
A wonderful day.
This is The American Hour from Rome,
broadcasting a special news bulletin in English and Italian.
Tonight, there is no further word
from the bedside of Princess Ann in Rome,
where she was taken ill yesterday
on the last leg of her European goodwill tour.
This has given rise to rumors that her condition may be serious,
which is causing alarm and anxiety among the people in her country.
- The news can wait till tomorrow.
- Yes.
May I have a little more wine?
I'm sorry I couldn't cook us some dinner.
Did you learn how in school?
I'm a good cook.
I could earn my living at it.
I can sew, too, and clean a house and iron.
I learned to do all those things.
I just haven't had the chance to do it for anyone.
Well, it looks like I'll have to move
and get myself a place with a kitchen.
Yes.
I shall have to go now.
Anya...
There's something that I want to tell you.
No, please.
Nothing.
I must go and get dressed.
Stop at the next corner, please.
Okay.
Here?
Yes.
I have to leave you now.
I'm going to that corner there and turn.
You must stay in the car and drive away.
Promise not to watch me go beyond the corner.
Just drive away and leave me,
as I leave you.
All right.
I don't know how to say good-bye.
I can't think of any words.
Don't try.
Your Royal Highness, 24 hours, they can't all be blank.
They are not.
But what explanation am I to offer Their Majesties?
I was indisposed. I am better.
Ma'am, you must appreciate that I have my duty to perform,
just as Your Royal Highness has her duty.
Your Excellency, I trust you will not find it necessary
to use that word again.
Were I not completely aware of my duty to my family and my country,
I would not have come back tonight,
or, indeed, ever again.
And now, since I understand we have a very full schedule today,
you have my permission to withdraw.
No milk and crackers.
That will be all, thank you, Countess.
Is it true? Did you really get it?
Did I get what?
The princess story. The exclusive. Did you get it?
No, no, I didn't get it.
What? But that's impossible.
Have a cup of coffee or something?
- Joe, you can't hold out on me.
- Who's holding out on you?
- You are.
- What are you talking about?
I know too much.
First you come into my office
and ask about an exclusive on the princess.
Next, you disappear.
Then I get the rumor from my contact at the embassy
that the princess isn't sick at all and she's out on the town.
What kind of a newspaperman are you?
You believe every two-bit rumor that comes your way?
Yeah, and a lot of other rumors
about a shindig on a barge down by the river
and the arrest of eight Secret Service men
from a country which shall be nameless.
And then comes the news of the lady's miraculous recovery.
It all ads up.
And don't think by playing hard to get you'll raise the price of that story.
A deal's a deal.
Now, come on, come on, where is that story?
I have no story.
- Then what was the idea of...
- Joe!
- Man, wait till you see these.
- Irving...
Hiya, Mr. Hennessy. You got here at the right time.
- Wait till you get a look...
What's the idea?
What do you mean charging in here and spilling things all over my place?
Who's spilling?
You did. I spoke to you about that once before.
Don't you remember?
Joe, look at my pants.
Yeah, you'd better come in here and dry them off, Irving.
Nuts to that.
- Hey, did you tell him about Smitty?
- Irving...
Smitty?
- Mr. Hennessy...
- Irving...
Wait till...
There you go again, Irving.
Joe.
- All right, save that till later.
- Listen...
You're here early, anyway. Why don't you go home and shave?
Shave?
Yeah, or else keep quiet till Mr. Hennessy and I are finished talking.
Hey, what kind of a routine is that?
What are you two guys up to? Who's Smitty?
He's a guy that we met. You wouldn't care for him.
What am I supposed to look at?
No, just a couple of Irving's dames. You wouldn't like them.
Maybe you would.
Don't change the subject. When you came back into my office yesterday...
Yeah, I know, yesterday at noon, I thought I had a good lead,
but I was wrong.
That's all there is to it. There is no story.
Okay.
She's holding the press interview today. Same time, same place.
Maybe that's one story you can get.
And you owe me 500 bucks!
Take it out of my salary, 50 bucks a week.
Don't think I won't.
Hey, what gives?
Have we had a better offer?
Irving, I don't know just how to tell you this, but...
Wait till I sit down.
Well, in regard to the story that goes with these,
there is no story.
Why not?
I mean, not as far as I'm concerned.
Hey, the pictures came out pretty well. You want to have a look at them?
How about a blowup from a negative that size?
- That's her first cigarette.
- Oh, yeah. At Rocca's.
Hey, the mouth of truth.
Oh, you want to know the caption I had in mind there?
"Barber cuts in."
Well, here's the one I figured would be the key shot for the layout.
"The wall where wishes come true."
Joe, that's good.
Lead off with that, then follow up with the wishes.
I dug that up out of the file.
"Princess inspects police."
Yeah.
"Police inspects princess."
How about it?
- Joe, I got a topper for you.
- Pretty good...
Wow!
- Is that a shot?
- What a picture!
Is that a shot, Joe?
"Bodyguard gets body blow."
Yeah. No, how about this?
"Crowned head."
I get it! That's... Joe, you got...
She's fair game, Joe.
It's always open season on princesses.
You must be out of your mind.
Yeah, I know, but...
Well, look, I can't prevent you from selling the pictures if you want to.
- You'll get a good price for them.
- Yeah!
You going to the interview?
Are you going?
Yeah. It's an assignment, isn't it?
Yeah.
I'll see you.
It ain't much, but it's home.
Ladies and gentlemen, please approach.
Her Royal Highness.
Your Royal Highness, the ladies and gentlemen of the press.
Ladies and gentlemen,
Her Royal Highness will now answer your questions.
I believe at the outset, Your Highness,
that I should express the pleasure of all of us
at your recovery from the recent illness.
Thank you.
Does Your Highness believe that federation would be
a possible solution to Europe's economic problems?
I am in favor of any measure
which would lead to closer cooperation in Europe.
And what, in the opinion of Your Highness,
is the outlook for friendship among nations?
I have every faith in it,
as I have faith in relations between people.
May I say, speaking for my own press service,
we believe that Your Highness's faith will not be unjustified.
I am so glad to hear you say it.
Which of the cities visited did Your Highness enjoy the most?
Each in its own way...
Each in its own way was unforgettable.
It would be difficult to...
Rome.
By all means, Rome.
I will cherish my visit here in memory as long as I live.
Despite your indisposition, Your Highness?
Despite that.
Photographs may now be taken.
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you very much.
I would now like to meet
some of the ladies and gentlemen of the press.
Hitchcock, Chicago Daily News.
- I'm so happy to see you here.
- Thank you.
Scanziani, de La Suisse.
Klinger, Deutsche Presse-Agentur.
Maurice Montabre, Le Figaro.
Sytske Galema, De Linie, Amsterdam.
Jacques Ferrier, Ici Paris.
Gross, Davar, Tel Aviv.
Cortes Cavanillas, ABC, Madrid.
Lampe, New York Herald-Tribune.
- Good afternoon.
Irving Radovich, CR Photo Service.
How do you do?
May I present Your Highness with some commemorative photos
of your visit to Rome?
Thank you so very much.
Joe Bradley, American News Service.
So happy, Mr. Bradley.
Moriones, La Vanguardia de Barcelona.
Stephen House of The London Exchange Telegraph.
Good afternoon.
De Aldisio, Agence Presse.