Name is aword by which a person is spoken of.
When a person's profession
becomes his nick name£¬
people will forget his original name.
My nick-name is the King of Adventurers.
I am a novel writer and an adventurer.
My student and I lost our way during an adventure.
We walked three days and nights in adesert.
We hadn't drunk any drop of water.
Although we were very tired£¬
we hadn't gone asleep.
On the third day£¬we were almost exhaused£¬
we saw one thing.
Who are you?
- What are you moving?
- Move harder!
What's that?
Can you answer my question?
I am not responsible for answering questions.
Who can answer me then?
The one who is inside the ox.
He is studying the stomach of the ox
Is there anybody inside the ox?
What kind of ox?
This is a golden ox! It's hard to get one.
Golden ox? It's dark in color!
Move away! Don't block my way!
Go!
He doesn't know this is a preciousantique!
Accident happens!
What kind of accident?
Help!
It's running over us!
Get lost! Be careful£¬
the golden ox is Iosing control.
Run! Escape!
Don't hurt anyone£¬it's dangerous.
Get up!
You always dream of gold!
I have just fallen asleep!
I told you not to go to karaoke that often.
Which new song is named Golden Ox?
You are not like me£¬
I only need to sleep three hours a day.
You are so young but you are so weak!
Yeah£¬ like you! Sleep only three hours a day!
Look at you!
You are so ugly looking.
The article is ready.
The Idea Box is empty.
Can't think anything?
You know.
Love problem again?
Monica again?
Affection is like an apple.
No matter how tasty is it£¬
you have to shit at last.
Eat another one!
I do hope so.
What a shit is£¬ like Adam£¬
one apple has already given me too much trouble.
How dare I eat another one?
I hate eating apple.
What a waste! You haven't bitted.
It's good to eat more apples£¬ remember!
Mr Chow£¬ the boss is looking for you.
What for?
He comes back that early!
Just go on typing your articles!
I've finished!
So what?
- Chow Si-kit!
- I know
What do you know?
93 stories of the novel
"King of Adventurers" have been issued.
Still 7 stories have not yet been written.
I am glad you know it.
I know.
What else do you know?
We can't catch the publishing schedule againl
According to our contract£¬
we will publish 100 stories a year.
Now£¬ three months has passed.
- Then...
- I know!
You know everything£¬
so should I keep my mouth shut?
You know? I have great loss!
I know you are having great loss.
I know.
Kit£¬ you can't do anything to amend
the relationship between you and Monica.
How can your career be affected?
For a man£¬ career is his life.
Doesn't it worth for a woman like this?
Mr Lo£¬ your call£¬ it's from Monica.
Hi£¬ Monica£¬ did you have a sound sleep?
Have you eaten the medicine
which I introduced to you?
Should I go out first?
I am just chatting with your hubby.
I love to talk to you instead.
I am his employer only!
We are different£¬ we are friends.
So£¬ we can talk something affectionate.
You are flattering me.
In fact£¬ there is difference.
How bad is the contract.
Mr Chow£¬ you should learn from Headmaster.
After saying goodbye to his wife£¬
he remarried in Mainland China
A Philipino maid cheated all him money.
Later£¬ he knew a girlfriend£¬
he promised to pay her debt to loan sharks.
But£¬ she brushed him off.
He then went to bar to court girls.
But£¬it was a stool pigeon.
Now£¬ he owes others much money! What a poor guy.
But he keeps on writing!
He writes in the Ieft£¬ in the toilet£¬
by left hand£¬ and then right hand!
He never stops!
In fact£¬ the torture of life
is the food of a creator.
Monica is giving you money!
Sorry£¬ I don't need such kind of money!
It breaks my heart.
I am not that lucky to spend such kind of money!
Chow Si-kit.
Monica dated you to have a meeting
tonight to talk about the divorce.
Keep an eye on him£¬or he will fight.
OK£¬ I will follow him.
Where?
By the way£¬I won't divorce.
What do you want?
Just pretend nothing has happened.
Impossible!
I know I don't know how to please you.
When you knew me£¬ you knew this very well.
I can't pretend as another guy.
Right£¬ you can't pretend as another one.
Please be straight to the point.
I am too straight forward£¬
But you are even worse than me.
Since we don't have babies£¬
it'll be wise for us to separate.
You are so selfish!
We work from day and night.
We need to work over night sometimes.
You too!
You can't blame me only.
Not exactly!
- Hi.
- Monica
Movie star.
You like such kind of playboy?
Monica wants a divorce£¬
this is Mr Chan£¬ the lawyer.
He is an expert in divorce malter.
How are you£¬ Mr Chow?
I wrote the paper for Monica.
Please take a look.
You love such kind of greasy guy?
In fact£¬ l like your style£¬ with wisdom.
But you don't like me.
Are you learning from me£¬
or do you want to court me?
I bet both sides£¬ any outcome will be fine to me.
You can't make money by gambling£¬ yoo know?
Otherwise£¬ the Royal Jocky Club
won't be that sinful£¬
that's why they do so many charity deeds.
What's so funny?
I don't have money to pay you.
Lawyer fee?
Don't worry£¬ I'll introduce
you to write TV script.
You can earn much more than writing novels.
Since the audiences love watching stars only.
My divorce is none of your business.
Monica helps me to invest£¬
her business is my business too.
Her divorce is my business too!
Don't mix up divorce with stocks.
Think it over£¬ Iam Ieaving now.
Monica£¬ you haven't eaten yet.
I will have some food with you.
Waiter£¬ give me a bottle of volka.
Chung Fat-pai!
I won in one mahjong game once£¬
why do you still mention it?
Please help£¬ we will drop him here and leave.
Don't close the door please.
Please let him spend one night here.
Hurry up!
No problem£¬ it'll be quick!
It's poor to be a man like this!
What's that?
Idea Box.
But nothing is found inside.
Usually£¬ he puts his ideas there.
But now£¬ they are all gone£¬
so he doesn't know how to write the story!
So poor!
- Let me try.
- How?
The box is the key point of it.
Since there isn't anything inside!
What does that mean?
Let's find out the ideas for him.
Come on.
Do you know where he ends in the last story?
Yes£¬ I do.
In the last story£¬
the golden ox lost control.
Right at such critical moment.
Smart and handsome
King of Adventurers appears.
Look£¬ he is so smart Iooking!
Master.
You've finally shown up.
- Shing
- He goes crazy.
He uses the golden ox to run people over.
Don't panic!
Thank you¡­
You ruined my ox£¬ you are in deep shit now!
Look£¬ you're in great trouble too.
Why don't you tie them up?
You fools solved the danger
cause by the golden ox.
The Kingg of Adventurers intended
to have a lunch with his student.
Right at that moment.
The lunch had already been arranged.
King of Adventurers£¬
the Security Consultant General Lone£¬
wants to meet you in his office.
General Lone?
Isn't he Uncle Lone?
You know the answer already.
He is a high official now£¬ isn't he?
So£¬ you can't despise anyone.
This lunch must be very important.
Have biscuit.
Uncle Lone has a best salary£¬
your life is more simple
My salary hasn't been paid yet£¬
please be considerate.
I asked you to come here for the
scripture of no words and its box.
You are an adventurer and an archaeologist£¬
expert in finding the lost antiques.
we hope you'd bring back
the scripture &its packing box.
What scripture and box?
Why do you need my master's help?
We learn this scripture and
its box from a mysterious legend.
The scripture with no words
is related to the future of people.
The box is the key to find the scripture.
It's known that£¬ the last appearance
of it was in the end of Ching Dynasty.
The boss of the Salt Gang
got it from lamas of Tibet£¬
It' s said£¬ because of the massacre£¬
the sand turned red within half mile.
I admire you so much!
Now£¬ the archaelogists
of Japan found a letter in agrave£¬
it's believed that by which
we can find out the box.
Where is the letter now?
It's kept inside the safe
of the Japanese Embassy in Shanghai.
So£¬ we are going to be spy.
Lone said the lelter is
inside the Japanese Embassy.
Why should we come to a club?
Nut! Isn't the embassy your home?
How can you search as you want?
We have to find away to get in.
King of Adventurer knows very well that£¬
the only one who can go
freely to the Japanese Embassy£¬
is a guy called Chung Fat-pai£¬
the Japanese gives him face£¬
for he is a famous triad head
who loves wine so much!
Chung Fat-pai.
I won in a mahjong game£¬
why do you still mention it?
I can tell he is avery important person.
Such kind of place is heavily guarded!
Do you want to drink with me?
If not£¬forget it.
Come on£¬ bring all good wine here for us.
Are you scared?
I am training my fellows.
You know my background!
I don't want to forget my past.
I want you to do one thing for me.
OK.
To steal a letter from the Japanese Embassy.
What kind of letter is it?
I know they have invited you to a party.
Can you bring us along with you?
Sure! But let's drink first.
King of Adventurers wants
Chung to help him sneak into the Embassy.
He intends to cut the electricity£¬
and steals the letter in the dark.
So no one will know who is the thief.
What a wonderful idea!
What a scene!
I haven't smelt such strong perfume.
Without it£¬ it's hard to disguise as a woman!
Can we go in like this?
By the way£¬ just copy me.
Don't seduce anyone.
I would beat whoever courts me.
This is Mr Chan£¬ a banker in Shanghai.
How are you?
How do you do?
This is my wife£¬ my 1st concubine.
4th£¬ 5th£¬ 6th£¬ 7th£¬ 8th£¬ and 9th concubine.
Check where the switch room is.
After cutting the electricity£¬
we would act accordingly.
Have one£¬ it's great.
So many food!
- Oh! Beautiful lady.
- Hi
May I have a dance with you?
I am married.
- Oh£¬ sorry.
- You had it coming
Don't go too far from me£¬ keep contact.
One after another! So mean are they!
Don't just care of drinking£¬
come and dance with me.
I want to have a drink too.
Pal£¬ where is the main switch?
I beg your pardon.
Pardon?
Pal£¬ do you know where is the main switch?
It should be in the switch room.
Switch room.
Keep an eye on him.
Can I take you home tonight?
That guy gets drunk.
He must have partners£¬ come with me.
My perfume is over because of his strong breath!
- Tow him aside.
- Alright
Kiss£¬ baby!
so many people are watching the switch room.
- Since we are so happy...
- What'lI we do?
Get some ice to cooI down first.
Stay!
Miss...You are seen!
Here.
Let me help you!
King of Adventurers has never imagined!
In this party£¬ he would meet a woman£¬
who makes a hero
lose his mind!
He knows£¬ his freezed heart is going to melt.
Fire! Tum off the switch!
- It's really dark
- Bullshit
It's perfect!
Keep on playing music£¬ let's dance in the dark.
This is the study room£¬ the letter will be right here.
Old practice£¬ I am looking for the letter£¬
and you£¬ get a way out.
Clean up£¬ don't leave any clues behind.
It's you!
Sorry to wet you.
I want to go to toilet£¬
but I have gone a wrong way.
Now£¬ I am going out£¬ don't be surprise!
No...
you¡­ were a woman!
This is my hobby!
Sometimes a man£¬sometimes a woman.
How about you? Do you have such habit?
No£¬ I am a woman£¬ I need not pretend as a woman.
I know£¬
you are a very attractive woman!
I love seeing you dress like a man.
Wholeheartedly?
Yes£¬ wholeheartedly.
Two guests are knocked out!
The music stops.
- Go and search separately.
- Yes
Don't wander off.
Stop hiding!
Your prefume is so horrible!
I know you are here!
Hi£¬ I won't put on perfume next time.
Still next time?
Dong! The first round is over.
Catch him!
You know how wonderful is my Lightning Fists?
Are you alright?
It trembles a lot!
But it helps digestion.
What a sharp tongue!
Alright£¬ once more.
Hit the waist£¬ hit the neck.
Hit the right foot£¬ hit the left foot.
Hit the stomach£¬ hit your temple
Hit your heart!
Save it£¬ just talk to my gun.
Talk to my pen.
Don't come over.
If only I move my pen£¬
the gun will talk to him.
Drop the gun!
My autograph!
King of Adventurers?
I'll remember you!
Miss Cammy£¬ remember my name£¬ King of Adventurers£¬
Cheer up£¬ since the remaining time of your life£¬
will be linked with mine£¬ yours sincerely£¬
King of Adventurers.
From that moment£¬ she watched him
jumping through the window£¬
in fact£¬ he has entered her heart.
King of Adventurers and Shing went away like wind£¬
and that moved her heart!
So£¬ she decided to stay with
the King of Adventurers for her life?
Kidding! How come the woman will be so nice to me?
Don't create danger for me.
This woman should act like this.
I thought you would stay here tonight.
Can you say something nice?
Are you crazy? You hit me at short range
I'm sorry£¬ General
Go to check the letter quickly.
Cammy whom King of Adventurers saw that night...
was a hard hearted
woman instead.
No one could imagine that£¬
she is a beautiful but dangerous woman£¬
like poisonous candy.
In Shanghai£¬
she operated a clubhouse for killings.
This merciless evil bitch!
She uses men as experiment.
You were fat when you came
why are you so thin now?
Are you taking drugs?
No£¬ but I got thin because
you took me as an experiment.
So£¬ you are useless now.
You'd better go to hell.
Get ready the gas.
No!
I don't want him to die that soon.
I haven't given him enough torture!
You slept with him£¬
that's why you are merciful now?
You are wrong.
I want to test the capacity
of human body.
And I want to test how strong one's mind will be.
Why do you use man?
Since Iam a woman.
I have no reason to let you know my weakness.
- There are many kinds of men.
- I think you have no say here.
I am a man too!
Our target
should be a self confident man.
That's hero!
I am self confident too.
I mean King of Adventurers.
Only the one who is over confident
would keep on adventuring.
And we can kill our enemy at the same time.
What a good idea!
I am now asking you to get him back.
I am no match for him.
Just bull shit!
First£¬ kill his friend General Lone.
He left Xian by train yesterday.
He will arrive Shanghai this day.
The letter was stolen two days ago in our Embassy.
If it is taken by the King of Adventurers£¬
it's possible that he would
give this letter to Lone by hand.
Over there.
Miss Cammy£¬ you are damn right.
Don't use poisonous gas.
I want to keep his life for another experiment.
If you don't kill him now£¬
I am afraid you would miss a chance.
Yourjob is to carry out the mission.
Why do you raise so many questions?
General Lone is in danger.
When the woman was killing General Lone£¬
in fact£¬ she was breaking
the heart of the King of Adventurers£¬
but this hard hearted woman£¬
after killing General Lone£¬
there is another evil thought in her mind.
In this world£¬
no one can estimate¡­
what damages will be caused by this woman.
- Smoke?
- This is the correct way to write.
- Now start.
- This woman!
She left without saying a word.
- You have to write in this way.
- Chow Si-kit!
You can't ruin such romantic love like this!
How romantic?
I have been tortured like
shit by the woman inside£¬
how can I write romantic things?
You don't understand woman at all.
Don't I? I have married
with this woman for two years£¬
what have I got?
Self abase£¬ and I lost all my confidence!
I can't even work!
How can I trust woman?
I haven't known that women
are so troublesome indeed!
Right! It's shit!
You need not to be self abased.
This is the key of your home.
I've moved out.
Check your belongings.
Or£¬ don't blame me of lossing anything in future.
Isn't this key useless?
Change the lock quickly.
So£¬ you won't suspect me of copying it.
You have never trusted a woman.
Monica
Monica! What are you laughing at?
Isn't it funny?
What are you laughing? Monica!
Monica
What do you want?
You just release yourself by writing!
You are chicken!
But you become a hero in your novel!
Are you a man?
Wonderful! Mrs Chow£¬ you are great.
How can you clap?
Am I a rat? Who are you then?
You bitchy woman! You always seduce men!
We are separated!
I give you face so I keep my mouth shut.
If I don't give you face¡­
So what?
If I don't£¬ I will give you a slap.
The lift is coming£¬
if you want to slap me£¬ be quick.
Beat her¡­
Just go ahead.
It's a great slap.
You slap the air only!
Isn't it funny? Why don't you go home
and slap your own wife?
Enjoy your time!
There is a lift accident!
Which lift?
Monica...
Send her to the hospital!
Where is your damn car? Where is it parked?
Hurry up!
Give me the key.
Does he know driving?
Yes.
Motorcycle.
Do you want him to pay for the loss?
Save that woman first.
Their love has a U turn!
Are you talking about the novel?
Both!
Actually£¬
King of Adventurers misunderstood that woman!
Cammy is poor instead.
Get ready the poisonous gas.
Cammy is down there.
I won't allow any chance for them to fall in love.
Yes.
Run¡­
He is holding a woman£¬
how can he run faster than us?
He will be dead meat this lime!
- After them!
- Yes
You'd better drive.
Don't let them escape.
There is no way out.
Shit! I don't know how to drive a train.
Which button to stop?
According to my information£¬
you don't even know how to drive!
Move! I don't know how to drive a train!
Shit!
Which button can stop the train?
Why do you save me?
I am the person who wants to ruin your mind.
You just want to ruin my mind.
But I am ruining many things now! It's tense.
But I want you to know that£¬
no matter how dangerous out there¡­
I care you most!
You are so silly!
But I always want you to care about me.
Do you know you are selfish to do like this?
Sorry£¬ love is always selfish!
Forgive me.
Cammy¡­
Miss Monica£¬
although you got shock inside the lift£¬
you are alright£¬
you can leave after taking a rest.
Take it to Mr Chow's room?
Yes£¬ I intend to finish the story for MrChow.
Mr Chow and his wife are so funny!
He sent her in the hospital£¬
but he doesn't allow us to tell his wife the fact.
They are having a little argue.
Isn't it funny?
This is romance!
Monica...
Yvonne?
Get up£¬ get up now.
Get Shing back now.
Has he come?
Yes.he is still in the corridor£¬ hurryup!
Why do you leave so quickly?
Have I come? Nuts!
Haven't you? So£¬ why is there a computer?
Why don't you ask the computer? Go now!
Why do you lose your temper?
You looked ugly£¬
and now£¬ you are more ugly£¬ understand?
I hate ugly people.
Can you let me have some love imaginations?
You'd better go to Mr Chow.
He is jealousing.
Shing's left.Why do you laugh?
Hey£¬ Shing!
I know how to write the remaining stories
of the King of Adventurers£¬
Yvonne£¬ mark it down for me.
Shing£¬ type as much as I tell you.
Let's finish the story
as soon as possible!
Although General Lone died£¬
King of Adventurers and Shing
kept on finding out the whereabout of the box.
They could depend on no one¡­
...but themselves.
Why haven't you put on your glasses?
I don't want to see anything.
Did I break your heart?
Did I tell such line?
No such line.
According to the letter
which was stolen from the Embassy£¬
two words were written.
Righteous News.
So£¬ they finally came to this press office.
I think this is the right place!
Pay at once£¬ here is so dangerous!
See the fence!
It doesn't seem to be a press office.
Go in and take a look.
The people ahead£¬ get lost.
Put out the fire!
They are so effective!
I think they have offended many people£¬
so they have to be alert.
For righteousness£¬ you have to sacrifice.
Can you term it as sacrifice
if you are caught after committing crime?
It depends.
For righteousness£¬ you won't be alone.
Even we are abandoned£¬
it can be claimed as atraining.
More abandonments£¬ more strength you'll have.
We have to keep it up.
Not only using one hand£¬ but both hands.
This is the spirit of our newspaper!
Bravo! Headmaster£¬ you are great!
Drag him out£¬
read today's editorial few times to him.
I can't imagine that he used
our paper to wrap the knife.
That means£¬ his gang of territorists
is wrapped by us.
This proves that£¬ we are affecting them.
What a sharp tongue!
We are outsiders£¬ we should not have said so much.
Who are you?
We are here to look¡­
To look forjobs.
But I can't even afford buying your clothes
with one month of my salary.
That's why I have to give up my previous outlook.
From now on£¬ I come here to enrich myself.
Liar!
How do you know I am lying?
We have enough men power here£¬ you'd better go.
He asked us to leave.
Well£¬ let's carry out part two.
Who is the in charge here?
I am£¬ what do you want?
We Japanese send troops to the North East only£¬
we haven't offended you.
Why do you always scold us through your paper?
You can't say this an offence!
So£¬ we have to thank you
for giving us so many bullets!
Now£¬ they are so full
that they need not eat anything!
Let them do it.
Shanghai isn't your zone! Why are you so fierce?
Don't move!
You'd better look for me if there is any trouble!
We don't want to fight.
I am called Headmaster!
Headmaster?
So£¬ you will be in deep shit from now on!
Go.
- Sorry...
- Go!
They are good actors!
Pay now£¬ or our secret will be disclosed!
Becareful! Don't let others see you paying them!
I understand!
That's alright!
Let's call it a day! Return the costumes quickly!
Don't go!
You're good at fighting!
Come and fight with me then!
How dare you block our way?
Beat her¡­
There seems to be an accident!
We don't have enough money
to pay for another fight.
This time£¬ we should pay the overtime charge!
Let me help you.
Listen£¬ stop fighting.
Or£¬ Iwon't be responsible!
I don't want you to be responsible!
Come here for negotiation!
Lislen£¬ be frank!
Don't move!
This is additional£¬ get half pay£¬ OK?
You have done a great job!
I will pay you enough over-time fee.
Hurry up!
The kicks hurt me.
It's time for me to get advantage!
If you have guts£¬ come tomorrow.
I helped you to get rid of them£¬
why don't you take a glance at me?
At least you should say thank you.
Isn't it hard to say thank you?
First love will always fail£¬ let's go.
How do you know it's my first love?
I can tell from your eyes!
How about being a watchman here?
- Sure
- Sure!
Do they look like watchmen?
Better than keeping a dog here!
Master.
Master£¬ two strangers came here
to be watchmen.
Go on.
I don't know their backgrounds.
Don't you think...
And...
Infact¡­
Will they...And¡­In fact they¡­
What do you want to say?
In fact£¬ you needn't mask.
Your work is same as the editor's up there.
Why do you be that tough?
You won't understand.
In this world£¬ the mysterious power
will give people hopes!
So£¬ mysterious power.
Are we looking for troubles
to employ that two guys
be our watchmen?
They dress well£¬
how come they would be a watchman?
But£¬ I employ them.
is to keep an eye on them.
If you kick them away£¬
they may do something behind us!
It sounds reasonable!
Will they come for the box?
You are really smart£¬ beautiful and clever!
Enough£¬ it makes me sick!
How does the box look like?
What is inside?
I haven't taken any look at it.
Why not open it?
No! We can't open it.
I am a descendant of the Salt Gang.
Our ancestors said...
Hand me the box£¬ then I'll let you go.
Stop dreaming! The box is not yours!
If you open it£¬ there will be great trouble!
Lama£¬ cut the crap!
Don't open it!
My dad opened it£¬ thus£¬ he became like this.
It'll be shit! We can't open the box.
It's so dangerous!
If you open the box accidentally£¬
you will be burnt!
But don't worry£¬
I've put the box in a safe place.
This safe place¡­
is a hole right
behind the compose stands!
It's safe£¬
no one is so smart to find out that hole!
By the way£¬ that is a difficult place to find!
That's the stand I mentioned!
Go and take a look!
It's strange! Why there is a hole?
Any snake or insects climbed in?
Luckily the box is still there!
There is a dog.
And a snake!
This dog is so powerful!
So is the snake!
A rat!
- It's so big! Have a look!
- Stop looking!
You stepped on my clothes!
You are so ugly!
What's that?
- Take it!
- No!
Take it!
Give it to me!
Are you alright?
Don't let him discover!
Hide up the box quickly!
You bandits! You are always late!
Why are you that late
Have you brought the excavations
you stole from the royal necropolis?
This is stolen from the 10th grave.
How about the bloody jade?
Isn't it inside the box?
It's a real bloody jade!
This is yours.
Why is there only abag of gold sand?
How about the rest?
You are the descendants from the Salt Gang£¬
are you looking for a mysterious box?
Box? You know where it is?
Stop cheating me!
Have you heard of Righteous News?
That box! I heard that it's kept
inside the press office.
Go!
Don't be that happy£¬ if you cheat me£¬
I'll kill you!
Never mind£¬ I'll wait for you!
Are you going out?
Today isn't a good day£¬ it's not wise to go out!
Master£¬ what's the mailer?
Look outside!
it's raining cats and dogs£¬ nothing special!
What else?
There are many hawkers!
Selling fruits£¬ toys£¬
and paper sacrificial offerings!
Right£¬ there is no reason for him
to sell paper sacrificial offerings here!
That's righl! Call Chung Fat-pai!
Headmaster£¬ the press office
is surrounded by some strangers.
It seems that£¬ we are surrounded by enemies!
We should leave here as soon as possible!
Headmaster£¬ it'll be safe
to be an ordinary people now.
No way! Right at this moment£¬
we need the appearance of a mysterious hero.
To let the power in the dark know that£¬
we£¬ the crime beaters
are picking on them!
Headmaster!
Take the box£¬ no one will pay attention to you.
Don't let others take it.
Masked hero£¬ for something precious£¬
it's not convenient to take it out.
If the bad guys take it£¬
you will regret!
Right£¬ so I've decided to let you keep it.
You'll be wholely responsible!
Be careful!
It's so bright!
Do you know what I am saying?
You want to use me to shift
the attention of those guys out there.
But they are not that easily be cheated.
Headmaster£¬ our electricity has been cut.
They've rushed in.
I'll stop them£¬ you'd better run.
It'll be more dangerous to go out now.
Let's shift their attention.
They just aim at the box.
Let's mask ourselves.
Everyone holds one box.
Then rush out and run into different directions!
Good speech¡­
Masked hero£¬ only you know where the box is.
Be careful.
Pal£¬ I've misunderstood you.
You are on our side instead.
It's not the point!
We have not much time! Let's go out now.
Run!
I know you like mature men.
I am not as mature as my master.
But my master is married.
That'snot my business.
Whether you are married or not£¬
it's not my business either.
Why do you get angry that easily?
We have no time to talk in details.
From now on£¬
whether I have a wife or you have any boyfriend£¬
that concern us too.
Since I want to court you£¬ you know?
Yes.
Have one more kiss.
Damn it!
You are dying£¬ you know?
Everyone holds a box£¬
then run into different directions!
Go.
I am leaving!
Wait¡­
I have something to tell you.
You know what I am going to say?
I know you are a decent girl.
I know you are a foolish man£¬ like shit!
I love to be a pile of shit.
If only a flower is willing to be placed on it.
Take off your mask.
Who is it?
I am called Hung Sing.
S nce my name is scaring£¬
so the people will always tremble
when they read my name...
say£¬ Hung H ng Sing Sing.
What's that bull shit!
Yan Yan£¬ you are no match for him!
Be merc ful!
Same as you! We are the descendants
from the Salt Gang.
Our ancestors discovered a mysterious box.
It can tell our future and history.
Don't be that mean£¬
why not share it?
I'd have a share of it.
Why not open it and take a look.
Mybe£¬ it'll be more suitable for me.
I'd want to know the answer too.
But£¬ you will regret if yoo open it.
You'll regret if you don't open it!
King of Adventurers?
Let me teach you a lesson.
You always bluff others with money!
I am helping your dad to teach you a lesson.
Be a good boy...
Get back your clothe.
It's time for your mom.
Your mom beats you£¬ your auntie beats you£¬
your grandma beats you¡­
You can't even use a gun! So useless!
You are a trash!
You are useless!
I wanna beat you to death!
Why do you stand so far? Dare you come?
I don't think you have so many pens!
Do you want my autograph?
Sign on your grave!
Where can you go?
King of Adventurers£¬ I am a real man£¬
you are no match for me.
Your dream lover£¬ Cammy is my subordinate!
She is mine!
Last time£¬ she was poisoned£¬ and I saved her.
I do hope she would recover soon£¬
to find a man she loves and live happily together.
But that guy will never be you.
You playboy!
Don't bother others like a fly.
And£¬ what did you say?
A real man?
Not you!
I don't mean this£¬ you've misunderstood me.
I am a man£¬ you too.
But you are like shit!
Masked hero£¬ how are you?
I know it's you.
King of Adventurers£¬ you are really capable.
You need not mask and you are so famous!
It seems you are a man
who has been hurt by a woman.
I share the same point of view with you.
Where is Hung Hung Sing Sing?
What for? Do you want to treat him dinner?
No...
When I went out of the press office£¬
I saw your student being caught by his fellows.
I intended to catch Hung Sing
to exchange for your student.
At least£¬ it would reduce much action scenes.
I don't mind fighting.
The first step£¬
I have to find out where
they have kept my student Shing.
Go back first£¬ come on.
Where am I now?
Can you tell me your address?
Or£¬ how can my master find me?
What's that? It stinks.
This is poisonous gas.
Just stop breathing!
Pretend that you are in the water.
About one hour later£¬ the smoke will be over.
But£¬ no one can make it.
Should I get above the water?
Don't step on the net£¬ let me come out.
Master£¬ how come you are here?
I know you are caught for the experiment.
I know you will come.
No big deal! Just a piece of shit!
I'll handle it.
There is no bullet.
But I don't like violence.
That's King of Adventurers.
So fat is he! He must be a wrestler!
Master£¬ I am ready.
So fat!
Watch my Tai Chi Stance!
It's my turn.
Master£¬ please teach me.
How to throw that fatty to the sky?
It's easy£¬ all power is generated from ground.
When a man is in the air£¬
he will be strongly hurt by a slight hit.
Do you understand?
What's that?
You always hide up£¬ why do you ask so much?
That's right.
We still have an hour before we get on the train£¬
get back the box first.
Where is it?
Here.
Let's go.
Hung Hung Sing Sing!
This time£¬ King of Adventurers won't save you.
Since he is saving his student now.
For get about me£¬ get the box and leave.
Headmaster.
Why are you still standing here?
I can't stand too long!
Get the box and don't come back£¬ forget about me.
How can you give the box
to an outsider! I'll get it back.
Hung Hung Sing Sing.
See what is written on it.
Don't open the box.
We cnn't stop him£¬ leave now!
Headmaster.
Come here!
My head swells!
- Headmaster.
- Don't tell who is the masked hero.
Ask King of Adventurers to get back the box.
Headmaster...
Mr Editor!
You've finally recovered.
We are enemies from now on.
I've predicted that.
King of Adventurers has finally separated
with that nasty woman.
It's dark£¬ but King of Adventurers knows that£¬
when the sun rises£¬ another war will be started.
He will keep on finding the box
which can tell fortunes.
Miss Kwan£¬ you can take a walk today.
Doctor£¬ may I know who sent me to the hospital?
It's your husband Chow Si-kit.
But he told me not to tell you a word.
He didn't care his wound when he took you here£¬
but he just asked us to cure you first.
He cares you very much!
Now he is staying in the next ward.
Separtation! Separation at last.
How can he describe that woman like this!
But this woman was really bad!
After Cammy left King of Adventurers£¬
she knew very well that£¬
she was going the same way
with the King of Adventurers.
Their adventure went up to the sky.
The secret of the box is getting closer
and closer to them.
She looked down from the sky£¬
There was only one thing in Cammy's heart.
That's not the box.
But the King of Adventurers.
Do you know where the scripture is?
It seems that£¬ you haven't given me something.
Turn back and take a look.
From the sutra£¬ it's said
the scripture was kept here.
After getting the scripture£¬ you will get the
mysterious power of telling fortune.
Ga Yu Gate?
Tell the control room to make
a direct flight to Ga Yu Gate.
Yes.
Will you hand the scripture
and the box to the Japanese Government?
Or£¬ have you thought of keeping it yourself?
I am not interested to be like Hung Sing.
He didn't know he should put the scripture
inside the box first.
By the way£¬ he doesn't know
whether I read the sutra correctly.
Well£¬ what's the real pronounciation?
When you get the scripture and the box£¬
you'll know it.
Bring me the wine.
If you want to pull off a stunt£¬
this will be your last meal.
Don't scare me£¬ or I will remember anything.
What about the rest?
I'll give you the rest after the thing is done.
Chung Fat-pai£¬ why are you here?
I just take a free ride.
Do you know where I am going?
Wherever you are going.
Still lying!
- Get him.
- Yes
Damn you drunken man!
Why don't you follow our plan?
Bitch£¬ how dare you scold me?
Shut up!
You bitch!
What's the matter?
None of your business£¬
this is the matter between us.
I will be the boss£¬ catch him.
Yes.
Men£¬ catch her.
You're so stupid!
You know£¬ they are all my men.
Wait£¬ Ican disclose my real identity now.
In fact£¬ I am an undercover! I am on his side.
You betrayer! Go to hell.
Open the door¡­
Inform the control tower!
There is betrayer on the plane£¬
we have to fly back.
Yes.
What did you say?
It's you!
- What do you want?
- Don't move!
Now£¬ the plane is under my control.
Surrender!
Bastard! How dare you fool me?
Do I?
You control the plane first.
I can't make it.
Up to you.
At the very beginning£¬
you pretended to be waitress.
And cheated my sympathy.
I just want to help you.
Open the door¡­
- Shut up.
- Shut up
Theyare negotiating.
Have you ever thought of it?
I wanted to save you thus I ran many people over!
Why did I do so?
How about me?
I asked my fellows not to use poisonous gas£¬
for I didn't want to hurt you
That's why Ibroke the relationship
with my fellows. So£¬ take your time.
You know I am coming for the box£¬
why do you fight with me?
I was a waitress.
But you made me become a murderer!
Who dragged me like this? I am forced to do so.
So what? Whenever you lose your temper£¬
you just step out.
Forget everything£¬ let's die together.
We are close friends£¬
for we are common friends
of the King of Adventurers£¬
and you are close friend of him¡­
Don't come over.
Now£¬ we still have three minutes.
If you have guts£¬ just bomb the plane.
Don't you think I haven't?
The bomb is going to explode.
Let's die together.
Bravo!
You fall deeply for each other.
There is nothing to do with us.
We just take a ride.
Now£¬ we are leaving.
So£¬ take your time.
Let's go.
Let's go¡­
What's up?
Can I jump with you?
On the wall.
There is someone up there.
What are you screaming?
Want to apologize? It's useless to wave.
I won't forgive you.
There is someone up there.
Why don't you jump?
I will die with you!
Can you say something else?
Don't come over.
Hung Hung Sing Sing?
Boss£¬ I've got the box for you.
That box.
Master£¬ I said I don't know how to control aplane.
Master£¬ have I improved?
Hung Hung Sing Sing?
Come out.
I've got you in.
Don't panic£¬ I'll protect you.
The plane is going to explode£¬ run now.
The box is out.
Let's jump.
Jump!
How about you?
There is only one parachute.
Let's die together.
Jump or not?
No.
I'll jump.
Wait for me.
Don't be nervous£¬ I'll open it for you.
This story is going to an end.
Let's forget who is right and wrong.
It doesn't matter.
Since you hate me that much£¬
I just want to tell you.
When you see me in future£¬
you must be happier.
You too.
Be careful.
I am not afraid£¬ you would hug me.
Master.
We get a box there.
He always shows up in such moment.
Why are you looking at me? Not this way!
Are we bothering them?
Bother?
Forget it.
It should be somewhere nearby.
How to get the scripture?
There will be an entrance.
We'd get an entrance first.
The sutra is written up side down.
You can tell by rubbing it with a piece of paper.
In other words£¬
the secret of the box£¬
isn't on the surface£¬
but at the bottom.
Check the bricks on the floor.
There are so many bricks on the floor£¬
when can we stop?
We have four persons here.
Check one by one£¬ it won't be very difficult.
Master£¬ see whether this hole is useful or not.
Put it in and test.
Master£¬ is that scripture of no words?
Wait.
See the skulls.
These people died here.
I think£¬ it must be caused by moving the sutra.
I don't want to go on.
It's useless for me to get any scripture.
Let's give up the box and the scripture.
No way£¬ since we have come here.
I will never give up.
No...
He is still alive!
Catch it.
King of Adventurers£¬
I won't let you get what you want.
The scripture!
It's mine.
Catch it!
- so sharp!
- But it's useless.
Run now.
You evil!
King of Adventurers!
Do you want to lock me up?
I wanna chop you to death!
I won't die.
That bastard!
Why did you brush King of Adventurers off
but followed him?
Why do you ask such bull shit now?
She said it's bull shit!
Right£¬ that's none of your business.
None of my business?
Yes£¬ none of your business!
Master.
Pull with me.
Go to hell.
What'll we do?
Make him come here.
The scripture is right here£¬ if you have guts£¬
come get it.
Bingo!
- Let's have a drink.
- Cheers!
Go to hell.
And...
Where is the scripture?
The scripture?
Thisway!
Why do you fight here?
Better go that way.
Hands off me.
Do you know whom have you caught?
Stop! Do you know you are in real danger?
Run! Run!
He is following us! Run!
It's hard to save him!
Three of you are here.
Iam glad you are all safe!
We have fixed him! Wonderful!
Send appreciation to me please.
Run!
Shing!
Hung Hung Sing Sing£¬catch it.
It's on fire.
Go to hell
Open the box.
Remember that rat?
The rat.
The long one inside the compose office.
After the first shine£¬ its form changed.
The second time£¬ it became tiny balls.
Shine on him now.
He will disappear then!
Monica
She isn't called Monica in the novel.
Don't come here.
Honey!
Let Cammy go!
Master£¬ I'll help you.
In this world£¬ what I can't possess£¬
I no one can possess too.
Serve you right.
Don't you think it's only you
who has this in mind?
Hands off£¬ or you will die!
Are they yours or mine?
Forget about it£¬ just put it in your pocket.
Honey!
Open the box and shine on us.
We will then disappear!
No way.
How is Monica?
Let me open it!
Give it to me!
King of Adventurers!
Give me the box.
Hurry up! Or you can't make it£¬
Open it.
You can't hesistate now!
Why do you push me to make a decision?
Only our separation can solve the problem!
Let me do it.
Monica
We have got the box and scripture at last!
But¡­
What's that?
How is it?
Dr. Lo said the scripture
and the box should be put together
to know the future.
In this human world£¬
there is no end and no beginning£¬
the scripture returns to its precious box at last.
Everyone of you will have a wish.
To know one thing in future.
This is funny!
May I know who will be my husband?
You can tell it from the wall behind.
There you can see your wish!
Why it's you!
Why do you react like this?
Can I see the smartest look of mine?
Samescene.
This is your smartest look!
So discouraging!
Don't be so mean£¬ it's destinated to be you.
King of Adventurers£¬ it's your turn.
About future£¬ what do you want to know?
I don't know what should be asked.
Well...
Can I see Monica again?
For many things£¬ hatred comes from love.
And it causes fights and killings too.
In fact£¬ there will be chance!
People control everything.
The one you are looking for£¬
is inside this city.
Monica!
Master£¬ look
Remember£¬
there will be chance anyway.
Value your future!
Where have you gone?
For food.
With a boy or girl?
With my classmate!
You don't know either£¬
please don't ask£¬ I am tired.
A meal made you feel tired?
I'm better now.
I changed the ending of your novel£¬
don't you get angry?
No£¬ it's good.
The girl is quite lovely.
I've signed the divorce paper.
It's your turn.
Why did you sign?
I don't know how to flatter girls.
If I sign and you will be happy¡­
Well£¬ I'll sign it.
Alright£¬ Iwill sign.
Give me the pen please.
I've signed.
I said£¬ you won't sign!
No! I haven't signed.
It'll be effective anytime.
Bring it back!
I can't imagine that we would be seriously hurt.
In fact£¬ the most risky thing in this world
is how to stay with one person without any change.
So£¬ in this city£¬
we always need King of Adventurers!