1
00:00:05,000 --> 00:00:10,000
{\an3}{\pos(360,230)}翻译：薄荷小瑾  嘟嘟矢  章鱼X

2
00:00:10,000 --> 00:00:15,000
{\an3}{\pos(360,230)}校对：木浅薰

3
00:00:15,000 --> 00:00:20,000
{\an3}{\pos(360,230)}总监：somehacker

4
00:00:20,000 --> 00:00:25,000
{\an3}{\pos(360,230)}后期：松子

5
00:01:04,750 --> 00:01:12,210
{\pos(195.5,210.667)}弗兰肯斯坦

6
00:01:42,530 --> 00:01:47,030
1795年的冬天  我被创造出来
I was cast into being in the winter of 1795.

7
00:01:47,040 --> 00:01:49,980
没有灵魂  行尸走肉
A living corpse without a soul,

8
00:01:50,540 --> 00:01:52,570
只是尸块的拼接
stitched, jolted...

9
00:01:52,570 --> 00:01:55,410
是那个疯子的一件作品
bludgeoned back to life by a madman.

10
00:01:55,410 --> 00:02:00,080
被自己成果吓到的他曾试图杀死我
Horrified by his creation, he tried to destroy me.

11
00:02:00,280 --> 00:02:04,860
但我没死  而且再次找到了他
But I survived and found my way back to him.

12
00:02:07,260 --> 00:02:08,620
伊丽莎白
Elizabeth!

13
00:02:08,620 --> 00:02:11,630
我要一命还一命
A life for a life, that's what I wanted.

14
00:02:11,630 --> 00:02:14,560
还的那条命  就是他的新婚妻子
I took that of his beloved new bride.

15
00:02:17,430 --> 00:02:20,100
他追杀我到了极北酷寒之地
He pursued me to the far north.

16
00:02:21,170 --> 00:02:23,440
我不惧严寒
I was immune to the cold.

17
00:02:23,440 --> 00:02:24,980
但他不行
He was not.

18
00:02:53,800 --> 00:02:57,970
我将他埋在了家族墓地
I buried him in his family cemetery,

19
00:02:57,970 --> 00:03:01,480
算是厚葬了他
it was more than he deserved.

20
00:03:01,480 --> 00:03:03,680
我以为这就是结局
I thought it was the end,

21
00:03:04,810 --> 00:03:08,480
其实一切刚刚开始
but it was actually just the beginning.

22
00:03:15,040 --> 00:03:17,300
{\pos(202,170.667)}弗兰肯斯坦

23
00:03:31,640 --> 00:03:34,220
我们等你很久了
We have been waiting for you.

24
00:03:37,210 --> 00:03:39,620
你得跟我们走一趟了
You will come with us.

25
00:04:26,060 --> 00:04:30,140
住手  纳贝里士要活的
Stop! Naberius wanted it brought back alive!

26
00:05:01,900 --> 00:05:04,200
都干掉了
That was the last of them.

27
00:05:06,600 --> 00:05:08,040
你觉得它是什么
What do you suppose it was?

28
00:05:08,770 --> 00:05:10,270
不知道
I don't know.

29
00:05:10,270 --> 00:05:12,640
第一次见到能杀死恶魔的人类
Never seen a human kill a demon before,

30
00:05:12,640 --> 00:05:14,220
而且力量惊人
and with such strength.

31
00:05:16,780 --> 00:05:18,010
很久以来
It's been a long time

32
00:05:18,010 --> 00:05:20,280
北方已经少有恶魔了
since I've seen demons this far north.

33
00:05:20,780 --> 00:05:22,950
它一定有什么特别之处
There must have been something special about it,

34
00:05:22,950 --> 00:05:25,650
让纳贝里士不惜代价的想要得到
something Naberius wanted.

35
00:05:35,630 --> 00:05:37,640
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦
"Victor Frankenstein."

36
00:05:46,470 --> 00:05:49,020
流言是真的
The rumors are true.

37
00:05:51,810 --> 00:05:54,150
它还活着
It's alive.

38
00:05:54,150 --> 00:05:56,120
它还活着
It's alive!

39
00:05:58,990 --> 00:06:00,190
陛下
Your Majesty!

40
00:06:09,060 --> 00:06:11,270
只是个怪兽  陛下
No more than a wild beast, Your Majesty.

41
00:06:11,400 --> 00:06:13,910
杀掉了事算了
Destroy it and be done with this.

42
00:06:18,540 --> 00:06:21,350
你知道原因吧
So, you understand reason.

43
00:06:22,080 --> 00:06:24,550
这是哪  我怎么在这
Where am I? How did I get here?

44
00:06:24,580 --> 00:06:26,880
那些袭击你的东西想要什么
The creatures that attacked you, what did they want?

45
00:06:26,880 --> 00:06:29,580
-我不知道  -它们提到了纳贝里士
- I don't know! - We heard them speak of Naberius.

46
00:06:29,580 --> 00:06:31,350
说他想留它活口
Seems he wants this thing alive.

47
00:06:31,350 --> 00:06:34,260
如果纳贝里士想要它活着
If Naberius wants it alive,

48
00:06:34,260 --> 00:06:36,260
我们就更该杀了它
all the more reason to destroy it.

49
00:06:36,260 --> 00:06:37,320
不
No!

50
00:06:37,330 --> 00:06:38,870
基甸
Gideon.

51
00:07:10,530 --> 00:07:13,400
是"他"  不是"它"
"Him", not "It".

52
00:07:15,230 --> 00:07:19,070
我是莱奥诺拉  夜翼神战团的女王
My name is Leonore, High Queen of the Gargoyle Order.

53
00:07:19,070 --> 00:07:22,310
这是基甸  我最信赖的勇士
This is Gideon, my most trusted warrior.

54
00:07:22,400 --> 00:07:24,100
袭击你的是四个恶魔
You were attacked by four demons

55
00:07:24,110 --> 00:07:27,950
受命于黑暗王子纳贝里士
under the command of a dark prince called Naberius.

56
00:07:28,380 --> 00:07:31,990
幸好阿斐和基茜亚在附近巡视
Fortunately, Ophir and Keziah were on watch nearby.

57
00:07:32,780 --> 00:07:35,480
他们认出了你  将你带了回来
They realized who you were and brought you here,

58
00:07:37,250 --> 00:07:39,450
带回我们的家
to our home.

59
00:07:49,930 --> 00:07:51,930
夜翼神战团是由
The Gargoyle Order was commanded into being

60
00:07:51,930 --> 00:07:53,930
大天使米迦勒所创造
by the great Archangel Michael.

61
00:07:53,940 --> 00:07:57,940
与恶魔战斗是我们的神圣使命
It is our sacred duty to wage war against the demon horde.

62
00:07:57,940 --> 00:08:00,610
撒旦堕落后
666 legions of hell-spawned creatures

63
00:08:00,610 --> 00:08:03,120
释放了666支地狱军队
unleashed by Satan after his fall from heaven.

64
00:08:04,480 --> 00:08:07,220
人类以为我们只是石雕
Humans think of us as mere decoration.

65
00:08:07,420 --> 00:08:08,640
他们不知道
They do not know,

66
00:08:08,640 --> 00:08:11,250
也无法想象身边
nor could they conceive of the brutal, unseen war

67
00:08:11,250 --> 00:08:13,190
无形而残酷的战争
being fought around them every day.

68
00:08:14,460 --> 00:08:16,960
也许有天  这场战争
A war that may one day determine the very fate

69
00:08:16,960 --> 00:08:18,360
将决定全人类的命运
of all mankind.

70
00:08:20,360 --> 00:08:22,430
而你已经卷入这场战争
You have now been drawn into this war.

71
00:08:26,670 --> 00:08:28,750
我不在乎人类的命运
I care not for the world of man.

72
00:08:28,770 --> 00:08:31,420
可以理解  我们听说了你的事
Yes, we've heard the stories of you.

73
00:08:31,770 --> 00:08:35,350
被制造你的人抛弃  无依无靠
Shunned by your human creator, lost and alone.

74
00:08:35,380 --> 00:08:37,520
可是我们欢迎你
You would be welcome here.

75
00:08:38,450 --> 00:08:41,120
在弄清纳贝里士抓你的原因之前
Until we learn why Naberius wants you,

76
00:08:41,120 --> 00:08:43,120
希望你能留在这里
I ask that you stay with us,

77
00:08:43,120 --> 00:08:45,560
圣墙之内很安全
safe within these hallowed walls.

78
00:08:46,890 --> 00:08:48,190
我独来独往
I go my own way.

79
00:08:48,190 --> 00:08:51,830
陛下  它杀了维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的妻子
Your Majesty, this thing murdered Victor Frankenstein's wife.

80
00:08:51,830 --> 00:08:53,600
出于一时激愤
All in the heat of passion,

81
00:08:54,060 --> 00:08:56,660
出于还没人教他控制的情绪
driven by emotions he was never taught to control.

82
00:08:56,660 --> 00:09:00,000
他还没意识到自己多么接近人类
He may be more human than he realizes.

83
00:09:03,670 --> 00:09:06,910
我知道弗兰肯斯坦没有给你取名字
I understand Frankenstein never offered you a name.

84
00:09:07,140 --> 00:09:08,690
我给你取名为
I should like to call you

85
00:09:09,040 --> 00:09:10,520
亚当
Adam.

86
00:09:11,910 --> 00:09:13,480
我向你保证  亚当
I promise you this, Adam,

87
00:09:13,480 --> 00:09:15,630
每个人都有个崇高的追求
each of us has a higher purpose,

88
00:09:15,750 --> 00:09:18,020
只是你的还有待发现
yours has simply yet to reveal itself.

89
00:09:21,720 --> 00:09:23,590
这是战亡的兄弟姐妹们
These are but some of the scapulars

90
00:09:23,590 --> 00:09:25,190
留下的肩衣
of our fallen brothers and sisters.

91
00:09:25,190 --> 00:09:27,430
战斗一直是敌众我寡
We have always been outnumbered in battle.

92
00:09:27,430 --> 00:09:29,870
经过无数恶战
Now, after many hard-fought victories,

93
00:09:29,900 --> 00:09:31,480
我们更在削弱
our ranks have thinned.

94
00:09:31,830 --> 00:09:34,270
然而恶魔却依然强大
Demons, however, remain strong.

95
00:09:35,600 --> 00:09:37,170
为了让你有能力自保
To help you survive against them,

96
00:09:37,170 --> 00:09:40,720
女王命我们送你件武器
the Queen has asked us to provide you with weapons.

97
00:09:43,710 --> 00:09:46,890
只有圣器能降服恶魔
Demons can only be descended by sacramentals,

98
00:09:47,920 --> 00:09:51,720
十字架或是圣水之类
blessed objects such as the crucifix or holy water.

99
00:09:53,020 --> 00:09:56,090
只要刻上夜翼神战团的符号
Any object can be made sacramental by marking them

100
00:09:56,090 --> 00:09:58,100
便可成为圣器
with the blessed symbol of the Gargoyle Order.

101
00:10:01,760 --> 00:10:03,030
什么叫降服
Descended?

102
00:10:03,030 --> 00:10:04,440
恶魔被杀死时
When a demon is killed

103
00:10:04,700 --> 00:10:06,740
灵魂会坠入地狱
its spirit descends to hell,

104
00:10:07,040 --> 00:10:09,240
永世不能脱身
where it remains trapped for all eternity.

105
00:10:09,540 --> 00:10:11,270
夜翼神怎么降服
How do you descend a gargoyle?

106
00:10:11,270 --> 00:10:15,420
我们是光和善的圣体  只会升天
We are sacramental beings of light and good. We ascend.

107
00:10:15,580 --> 00:10:19,280
只有无灵魂的邪恶者才能降服夜翼神
And only at the hands of godless creatures that have no souls.

108
00:10:29,260 --> 00:10:33,090
最好别选这个  又粗又钝
You do not want those. They are blunt and crude,

109
00:10:33,090 --> 00:10:35,430
挥起来又重
and far too heavy to wield.

110
00:10:46,510 --> 00:10:49,950
亚当  你有超人的力量  速度和毅力
Adam, you have strength and speed and stamina

111
00:10:49,980 --> 00:10:53,280
你不该浪费这天赋
far beyond that of any human. You would use those gifts.

112
00:10:53,280 --> 00:10:56,330
既然已卷入战争  就该明确立场
Take sides in a war that you are already a part of.

113
00:11:11,170 --> 00:11:14,010
我才不管他降服了多少恶魔
I do not care how many demons it descended.

114
00:11:14,640 --> 00:11:16,170
你本该让我杀死它的
You should've let me destroy it.

115
00:11:16,170 --> 00:11:18,720
我知道这是冒险
I am not blind to the risks.

116
00:11:19,010 --> 00:11:21,480
可事实是  亚当也有生命
The fact is, Adam is alive,

117
00:11:22,110 --> 00:11:23,840
所有的生命都是神圣的
and all life is sacred.

118
00:11:23,850 --> 00:11:27,550
-它并非人类  -我们也不是  基甸
- It is not human born. - Neither are we, Gideon.

119
00:11:28,820 --> 00:11:30,020
拿着
Here.

120
00:11:32,390 --> 00:11:33,890
锁进密室
Lock this in the vault.

121
00:11:33,890 --> 00:11:36,490
决不能落入纳贝里士之手
It must never fall into Naberius' hands.

122
00:11:36,490 --> 00:11:38,390
它只是本书  陛下
It is but a book, your Majesty.

123
00:11:38,390 --> 00:11:40,000
它  是上帝不再是
It is written proof that

124
00:11:40,000 --> 00:11:43,010
唯一的造物主的证明
God is now no longer the sole creator of man.

125
00:11:54,340 --> 00:11:55,750
亚当
Adam.

126
00:11:56,180 --> 00:11:58,250
无论何时你改变主意
If ever you should change your mind,

127
00:11:58,250 --> 00:12:00,220
永远能在这里得到庇护
you will always find refuge here.

128
00:12:05,350 --> 00:12:09,700
信任是只会犯一次的错
Trusting others is a mistake you only make once.

129
00:12:09,860 --> 00:12:11,730
所以我决定寻找
And so I resolved to seek out

130
00:12:11,730 --> 00:12:14,160
遥不可及的天涯海角
the farthest corners of the earth,

131
00:12:14,160 --> 00:12:15,260
那个人类
where no human,

132
00:12:15,260 --> 00:12:18,530
恶魔  或是夜翼神都无法找到我的角落
demon or gargoyle would ever find me.

133
00:12:18,530 --> 00:12:21,540
年复一年  我已忘却时间
So many years passed, I lost track of time,

134
00:12:21,540 --> 00:12:25,240
可我没有人类的生老病死
yet I did not grow old and die, as humans do.

135
00:12:25,240 --> 00:12:28,650
这正是维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的终级诅咒
Victor Frankenstein's final curse.

136
00:12:29,380 --> 00:12:32,490
我以为纳贝里士的恶魔已忘记我
I thought Naberius' demons had forgotten me,

137
00:12:34,020 --> 00:12:35,660
但我错了
but I was wrong.

138
00:12:40,220 --> 00:12:44,600
于是我将愤怒都发泄在了他们身上
And I unleashed all my rage upon them.

139
00:12:59,710 --> 00:13:02,750
我已躲藏太久
I had hidden long enough.

140
00:13:03,750 --> 00:13:07,290
该轮到我去追杀猎杀我的人了
Now I would hunt those who were hunting me.

141
00:13:09,880 --> 00:13:13,120
我回到久别的地方
I returned to the place I had left so long ago.

142
00:13:14,920 --> 00:13:19,470
人类世界已经变了模样
The human world had changed in the time I had been gone.

143
00:13:20,930 --> 00:13:24,770
但有些东西未曾改变
But some things had not changed.

144
00:13:26,330 --> 00:13:28,740
如果在荒野恶魔都能找到我
If the demons could find me in the wilderness,

145
00:13:28,740 --> 00:13:32,140
那在这儿找到我也只是时间问题
it was only a matter of time before they found me here,

146
00:13:32,140 --> 00:13:36,720
所以我要先发制人
which is why I had to find them first.

147
00:14:14,220 --> 00:14:17,780
纳贝里士在哪
Naberius, where is he?

148
00:14:17,790 --> 00:14:19,560
警察
Police!

149
00:14:21,060 --> 00:14:22,830
放下武器
Put down your weapon!

150
00:15:21,520 --> 00:15:23,290
晚上好  威塞克斯先生
Good evening, Mr. Wessex.

151
00:15:24,420 --> 00:15:27,570
人生从何来  死往何处
Where does life begin and where does it end?

152
00:15:27,690 --> 00:15:29,020
今晚的实验
Tonight's experiment represents

153
00:15:29,030 --> 00:15:30,790
是三年来的工作成果
the culmination of three years of work...

154
00:15:30,790 --> 00:15:32,470
时光稍纵即逝  维德博士
Time is fleeting, Dr. Wade.

155
00:15:32,490 --> 00:15:35,270
所以请别用废话浪费我的
I'd ask that you not waste mine.

156
00:15:36,360 --> 00:15:38,440
启动复活程序
Commencing reanimation sequence.

157
00:15:40,400 --> 00:15:42,740
膜片箝放大器设置完毕
Patch clamp amplifier set.

158
00:15:42,740 --> 00:15:44,470
脉冲发射器已校准
Pulse generators calibrated.

159
00:15:44,540 --> 00:15:46,480
心脏复律除颤器连接右心室
ICD wiring in right ventricle.

160
00:15:46,740 --> 00:15:49,380
输出能量设置为三焦耳
Energy output set to three joules.

161
00:15:49,380 --> 00:15:52,460
实验体心脏处于静止状态
For the record, subject's heart is currently dormant.

162
00:15:54,380 --> 00:15:58,620
开启电流倒计时  三  二  一
Firing current in three, two, one.

163
00:15:58,650 --> 00:16:00,330
就绪  启动
Clear and shock.

164
00:16:05,060 --> 00:16:06,890
身体上部和腿部出现肌肉痉挛
Muscle spasms in the upper torso and legs.

165
00:16:06,890 --> 00:16:07,960
情况良好
Looks good.

166
00:16:07,960 --> 00:16:10,760
左右心室均检测到细胞内电流
Detecting intracellular electrical activity in both atria.

167
00:16:10,770 --> 00:16:11,930
心室检测
We are in the ventricles.

168
00:16:11,930 --> 00:16:13,930
出现一次心房颤动  小心异位
We have an atrial flutter. Watch out for ectopics.

169
00:16:13,940 --> 00:16:16,950
出现不规则异位搏动
Irregular ectopic beats have begun on schedule.

170
00:16:19,410 --> 00:16:22,610
心室纤维性颤动  实验体将停止心搏
Ventricular fibrillation. Subject's going into cardiac arrest.

171
00:16:22,910 --> 00:16:24,580
电能增加至50焦耳
Up the current to 50 joules.

172
00:16:24,580 --> 00:16:25,680
已增加至50
Current raised to 50.

173
00:16:25,680 --> 00:16:27,780
心率突变  除颤无效
The heart rate's spiking. There's no defibrillation.

174
00:16:27,780 --> 00:16:30,350
-电能加倍  -电能增至100
- Double it. - Current set to 100.

175
00:16:30,350 --> 00:16:32,460
脉搏衰弱  特拉
Pulse is fading! Terra!

176
00:16:32,750 --> 00:16:33,850
再加倍
Double it again!

177
00:16:33,860 --> 00:16:35,490
-不行  -我说加倍
- No, I can't! - I said double it!

178
00:16:35,490 --> 00:16:36,590
它会死的
That'll kill it!

179
00:16:36,590 --> 00:16:37,830
它本来就是死的
It's already dead!

180
00:16:38,660 --> 00:16:40,130
200焦耳
200 joules.

181
00:16:40,760 --> 00:16:42,130
拜托
Come on.

182
00:16:43,030 --> 00:16:44,970
活过来
Live.

183
00:17:06,020 --> 00:17:07,890
出现心跳
There's a heartbeat.

184
00:17:10,630 --> 00:17:12,290
转换至生命维持系统
Switch to life support.

185
00:17:12,290 --> 00:17:13,490
生命维持系统正在运行
Life support functioning.

186
00:17:13,790 --> 00:17:15,230
形成窦性心律
Sinus rhythm established.

187
00:17:19,300 --> 00:17:20,570
它在呼吸
It's breathing.

188
00:17:34,250 --> 00:17:36,450
先生  出现点情况
Sir, we have a situation.

189
00:17:40,150 --> 00:17:41,860
你确定吗
You're certain?

190
00:17:42,220 --> 00:17:45,060
不确定  但是它袭击的方式
No, sir. But the way it attacked,

191
00:17:45,060 --> 00:17:47,490
强壮而敏捷  就像夜翼神
strong and fast, like a gargoyle.

192
00:17:47,500 --> 00:17:52,110
降服了七个同伴  我也是勉强逃脱
It descended seven of us. I managed to fight it off.

193
00:17:52,170 --> 00:17:55,070
我好像打伤了它  它好像受伤了
I think I wounded it. I think it's wounded.

194
00:17:56,600 --> 00:18:00,050
它降服了七个恶魔
It descended seven demons,

195
00:18:00,940 --> 00:18:04,150
你却临阵脱逃了?
yet you escaped?

196
00:18:05,010 --> 00:18:06,680
我想您需要得到这个消息
Well, I thought you'd want to hear this.

197
00:18:06,680 --> 00:18:10,560
是吗  你想
Yes, you presumed.

198
00:18:11,390 --> 00:18:13,720
你是在揣测我的想法
You presumed to know what I want.

199
00:18:16,760 --> 00:18:18,930
因为您追寻了它
Well, considering how long

200
00:18:18,930 --> 00:18:20,590
这么长时间
you've been hunting the creature...

201
00:18:20,600 --> 00:18:24,260
所以你就以为我希望你回来报告
And you thought I'd want you to tell me about the creature

202
00:18:24,270 --> 00:18:26,570
而不是直接抓住他
rather than capture it yourself.

203
00:18:26,570 --> 00:18:28,910
二者之间你选了前者
That's the choice you made.

204
00:18:33,210 --> 00:18:35,010
有意思
It's interesting.

205
00:18:40,550 --> 00:18:43,050
永远不要
Do not ever

206
00:18:43,050 --> 00:18:45,920
猜测我的想法
presume to know what I want.

207
00:18:47,460 --> 00:18:49,530
听懂了吗
Is that understood?

208
00:18:50,830 --> 00:18:52,370
饶恕我
Forgive me,

209
00:18:54,400 --> 00:18:57,700
纳贝里士王子
Prince Naberius.

210
00:19:24,160 --> 00:19:25,860
阿斐  你以为
Ophir, if you think...

211
00:19:35,670 --> 00:19:37,650
不
No.

212
00:19:38,440 --> 00:19:39,910
不
No!

213
00:19:40,540 --> 00:19:45,050
什么时候开始最终阶段
When do you begin the final stage?

214
00:19:45,050 --> 00:19:47,680
威塞克斯先生  人类是世上
Uh, Mr. Wessex, our bodies are the most complex

215
00:19:47,680 --> 00:19:49,360
最复杂的生物体
living organisms in the universe.

216
00:19:49,620 --> 00:19:51,890
复活老鼠和
Animating a simple rat is one thing,

217
00:19:51,890 --> 00:19:54,890
复活人类不可同日而语
but a human is still far out of reach.

218
00:19:54,890 --> 00:19:58,530
是吗  你听说过一个叫
Is it? What do you know of a scientist

219
00:19:58,530 --> 00:20:01,170
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的科学家吗
by the name of Victor Frankenstein?

220
00:20:02,300 --> 00:20:04,170
弗兰肯斯坦是虚构的
Frankenstein is a myth.

221
00:20:05,200 --> 00:20:07,170
为了吓唬小孩编出来的恐怖故事
A horror story made up to scare children.

222
00:20:07,400 --> 00:20:09,300
所有的科学家都是怀疑论者  维德博士
All scientists are skeptics, Dr. Wade.

223
00:20:09,300 --> 00:20:10,840
我就会怀疑
However, I would've suspected

224
00:20:10,840 --> 00:20:13,410
也许你这种领域的科学家
that a scientist in your particular field

225
00:20:13,410 --> 00:20:15,480
应该思考一下
would have to wonder if such stories

226
00:20:15,480 --> 00:20:17,580
这些故事是否也有些事实依据
just might have some basis in fact.

227
00:20:17,580 --> 00:20:20,410
18世纪90年代还无法驾驭电力
Well, electricity couldn't be harnessed in the 1790s

228
00:20:20,410 --> 00:20:24,080
更别说导入人类  尸体上了
let alone channeled into a... a human subject.

229
00:20:24,190 --> 00:20:27,190
再说他又去哪了  为何消失
And where did he go? Why did he disappear?

230
00:20:27,190 --> 00:20:29,420
如果他真的复活了一具尸体
If he really animated a human corpse,

231
00:20:29,420 --> 00:20:31,490
为什么不与世界分享此技术
why not share his technology with the rest of the world

232
00:20:31,490 --> 00:20:33,730
来挽救生命  治愈瘫痪呢
to save lives, cure paralysis?

233
00:20:33,890 --> 00:20:37,770
也许他没有你这么品德高尚  博士
Perhaps he wasn't as magnanimous as you are, doctor.

234
00:20:38,170 --> 00:20:39,540
每个科学家都会做记录
Every scientist keeps a record.

235
00:20:39,930 --> 00:20:42,140
哪怕试验最终失败
Even when their experiments end in failure.

236
00:20:42,370 --> 00:20:45,040
至少该有一份实验记录
Look, there ought to be at least a record of his work somewhere,

237
00:20:45,040 --> 00:20:48,340
手绘或者笔记什么的
drawings or a set of notes, something.

238
00:20:48,340 --> 00:20:50,680
没发现的东西
Just because something is yet to be found,

239
00:20:50,680 --> 00:20:52,920
并不是不存在
does not mean it doesn't exist.

240
00:20:54,250 --> 00:20:58,230
但如果弗兰肯斯坦真的存在
But if Frankenstein was real,

241
00:20:58,350 --> 00:21:01,260
如果他真的复活了人类
if he really did animate a human,

242
00:21:01,590 --> 00:21:04,130
研究那个人会有帮助吗
would it help you to study it?

243
00:21:05,060 --> 00:21:07,760
会的  当然
Well, yes, absolutely.

244
00:21:08,360 --> 00:21:09,630
但是  威塞克斯先生
But, Mr. Wessex,

245
00:21:09,630 --> 00:21:11,900
即便是真的  它现在也得200多岁了
it would have to be over 200 years old by now.

246
00:21:11,900 --> 00:21:15,370
估计只剩把烂骨头了
There would be nothing left but a few brittle bones.

247
00:21:15,370 --> 00:21:18,770
他只复活了这么一个  维德博士
It's the first and only one of its kind, Dr. Wade.

248
00:21:18,770 --> 00:21:23,020
谁知道它能活多久呢
Who's to say how long such a subject might live?

249
00:21:36,560 --> 00:21:39,430
我们的战争必隐于黑暗
Ours is a war that must be fought in the shadows,

250
00:21:39,490 --> 00:21:42,560
你不能随意开战
it is not an open battlefield for you to do as you please.

251
00:21:42,560 --> 00:21:43,940
我是在降服恶魔  不是吗
I'm descending demons, aren't I?

252
00:21:43,960 --> 00:21:47,830
别装作你是为了我们或是人类而战
Do not pretend that you are doing this for us or mankind!

253
00:21:47,840 --> 00:21:50,380
你只关心你自己  亚当
You care only about yourself, Adam.

254
00:21:52,070 --> 00:21:53,910
你知道今晚巷子里有个人类被杀了吗
Do you know a human was killed in that alley tonight?

255
00:21:53,910 --> 00:21:55,070
又不是我杀的
I didn't kill him.

256
00:21:55,080 --> 00:21:58,450
可你的行为直接导致了他的死亡
Your actions led directly to his death.

257
00:21:59,410 --> 00:22:00,910
我下次会小心的
I'll be more careful next time.

258
00:22:00,920 --> 00:22:02,980
没有下次了
There will not be a next time.

259
00:22:02,980 --> 00:22:05,540
女王作出决定前  你将被关在这
You will remain here until the Queen decides what to do with you.

260
00:22:05,990 --> 00:22:07,820
你不能把我关在这  莱奥诺拉
You cannot keep me here, Leonore.

261
00:22:07,820 --> 00:22:10,900
我也不能放任你在这座城市肆意妄为
I can hardly risk unleashing you on the streets of this city.

262
00:22:10,930 --> 00:22:14,490
我怎么活是我的事  你别想干预
My life is my own. You will not take it from me.

263
00:22:14,500 --> 00:22:17,530
可你的生命并非上帝赐予
Your life was not granted to you by the grace of God!

264
00:22:17,530 --> 00:22:19,770
你只是个实验产物
It was fabricated in a laboratory!

265
00:22:19,770 --> 00:22:22,940
除非你能理智的使用  否则我别无选择
And until you learn to use it wisely, I will do what I must!

266
00:22:22,940 --> 00:22:24,640
那你和纳贝里士又有什么分别
Then you are no better than Naberius!

267
00:22:29,610 --> 00:22:32,110
我初次见你
When I met you,

268
00:22:32,110 --> 00:22:35,260
第一个反应就是要消灭你
my first thought was to have you destroyed.

269
00:22:36,050 --> 00:22:39,120
可当我看着你的眼睛
But then I looked into your eyes,

270
00:22:39,120 --> 00:22:40,820
你知道我看到了什么吗
and do you know what I saw there?

271
00:22:41,060 --> 00:22:45,330
虽然没有灵魂  却有灵气
Not a soul, but the potential for one.

272
00:22:46,130 --> 00:22:48,900
而现在  那里只有黑暗
Now, all I see is darkness.

273
00:22:54,370 --> 00:22:56,510
我没有别的办法
I know of no other way.

274
00:22:57,810 --> 00:22:59,540
我不是人类
I am not human,

275
00:23:00,470 --> 00:23:02,180
不是夜翼神
nor a gargoyle,

276
00:23:03,480 --> 00:23:05,180
也不是恶魔
nor a demon.

277
00:23:09,520 --> 00:23:11,200
我什么都不是
I am like none other.

278
00:23:19,830 --> 00:23:21,200
阿斐
Ophir.

279
00:23:27,400 --> 00:23:29,900
你打算怎么把这家伙从教堂里弄出来
How do you plan to remove the creature from the cathedral?

280
00:23:29,900 --> 00:23:32,170
夜翼神会全力保护他
The gargoyles will protect it like one of their own.

281
00:23:32,170 --> 00:23:34,370
确实  我正希望如此呢
Yes, I shall be counting on that.

282
00:23:34,710 --> 00:23:37,110
牺牲会很惨重  但这是必须的
Our casualties will be high, but necessary.

283
00:23:37,110 --> 00:23:39,680
朱利尔  我的军团里
Zuriel, none of my legions

284
00:23:39,680 --> 00:23:43,280
没有比你更优秀的指挥官
ever had so worthy a commander as you.

285
00:23:43,280 --> 00:23:46,620
他们还会为谁更心甘情愿地
Would they have sacrificed themselves so bravely,

286
00:23:46,620 --> 00:23:49,990
牺牲自己呢
so willingly for anyone less?

287
00:23:50,560 --> 00:23:54,130
你知道这对他们来说意味着什么
You know what this could mean for them.

288
00:23:54,130 --> 00:23:56,270
不要忘记
Do not forget.

289
00:23:56,600 --> 00:24:01,270
去  把弗兰肯斯坦的怪物给我带来
Now, bring me Frankenstein's monster!

290
00:24:18,120 --> 00:24:20,130
恶魔们正在教堂外集结
Demons are gathering outside the cathedral.

291
00:24:20,320 --> 00:24:22,360
-有多少  -50个左右
- How many? - Fifty or so.

292
00:24:51,190 --> 00:24:53,890
以上帝之力  使汝坠入地狱
By the power of God, descend into hell,

293
00:24:53,920 --> 00:24:55,830
撒旦及其所有恶灵
Satan and all evil spirits.

294
00:25:26,620 --> 00:25:28,160
保护好那个家伙
Secure the creature!

295
00:25:29,820 --> 00:25:31,700
-快去  -阿斐
- Now! - Ophir.

296
00:26:00,350 --> 00:26:01,690
格杀勿论
Give no quarter.

297
00:26:03,160 --> 00:26:04,860
能杀一个是一个
Take as many of them with you as you can.

298
00:26:05,330 --> 00:26:07,200
你们是最后的防线
You're our last line of defense.

299
00:26:09,500 --> 00:26:11,700
这是你的神圣使命
This is your sacred duty.

300
00:26:42,400 --> 00:26:43,900
这边
This way.

301
00:26:47,370 --> 00:26:51,240
阿斐  武器  我要为我的生命而战
Ophir, give me a weapon! Let me fight for my life!

302
00:27:49,430 --> 00:27:51,580
不要
No!

303
00:28:54,330 --> 00:28:57,100
基茜亚  我会想办法救你的
Keziah. I'll do what I can.

304
00:28:57,100 --> 00:29:00,570
不  我想和阿斐在一起
No! I wish to be with Ophir.

305
00:29:01,170 --> 00:29:03,540
虽然战团明令禁止
It was forbidden by the Order.

306
00:29:04,170 --> 00:29:06,370
可是死后不受约束
It will not be so anymore.

307
00:29:25,360 --> 00:29:27,840
快  去帮忙
Quickly, go help the others.

308
00:29:47,450 --> 00:29:50,380
-纳贝里士在哪儿  -在等你
- Where's Naberius? - They're expecting you.

309
00:29:50,380 --> 00:29:52,260
什么叫在等我
What do you mean, expecting me?

310
00:29:52,650 --> 00:29:56,200
我们知道夜翼神会竭尽全力
We knew the gargoyles would do everything they could

311
00:29:56,220 --> 00:29:58,870
不让你落入纳贝里士之手
to keep you out of Naberius' hands.

312
00:30:01,060 --> 00:30:03,100
可是激战正酣之时
But in the heat of battle,

313
00:30:03,730 --> 00:30:07,940
他们也便无暇保护他们的至宝
they left unprotected their greatest treasure.

314
00:30:08,900 --> 00:30:12,480
我们的唯一任务  就是调虎离山
All we had to do was lure Gideon and the others away.

315
00:30:12,670 --> 00:30:14,110
它说它带来了
This one has a message for you.

316
00:30:15,440 --> 00:30:17,050
朱利尔的口信
From Zuriel.

317
00:30:21,580 --> 00:30:23,520
告诉我朱利尔把她带到哪里去了
Tell me where Zuriel took her.

318
00:30:23,520 --> 00:30:24,890
与你何干
What do you care?

319
00:30:26,090 --> 00:30:28,120
你要救她吗
You going to rescue her?

320
00:30:31,590 --> 00:30:35,970
把你锁起来的就是她  她看不起你
She locked you up! She despises you.

321
00:30:36,000 --> 00:30:38,630
在她眼里  你什么都不是
You are nothing to her,

322
00:30:38,630 --> 00:30:42,710
不过是人类一个了不起的错误
but another grand human mistake!

323
00:30:48,780 --> 00:30:50,220
她在哪儿
Where is she?

324
00:30:50,540 --> 00:30:52,610
沃尔顿剧院
Walton Theater!

325
00:30:52,610 --> 00:30:56,690
基甸会拿你去那儿换回莱奥诺拉
Gideon is to bring you there in exchange for Leonore.

326
00:31:08,630 --> 00:31:10,740
痛苦会伴你坠入地狱  恶魔
Descend in pain, demon.

327
00:31:48,570 --> 00:31:52,340
你在光明的怀抱里  光明守护你
The light embraces and protects thee.

328
00:31:52,340 --> 00:31:53,950
长官
Sir.

329
00:31:58,280 --> 00:31:59,790
怎么办
What are your orders?

330
00:32:02,680 --> 00:32:04,780
-求您三思  -没时间了
- I beg you to reconsider. - There's no time.

331
00:32:04,790 --> 00:32:06,020
密室安放的都是圣物
Items in the vault are sacred.

332
00:32:06,020 --> 00:32:08,190
你不能碰它们
You cannot remove or replace anything.

333
00:32:08,190 --> 00:32:10,220
一切责任由我承担
Then I shall accept full responsibility.

334
00:32:10,220 --> 00:32:12,760
你无权如此  我们也是
You have not the authority to do this. None of us do.

335
00:32:12,760 --> 00:32:14,590
这是女王明令禁止的
And the Queen has expressly forbidden it.

336
00:32:14,590 --> 00:32:16,200
问题还不在有权无权
Authority is not the problem.

337
00:32:16,200 --> 00:32:17,900
重要的是这太危险
It is dangerous. You must know this.

338
00:32:17,900 --> 00:32:19,730
我当然知道
Of course, I know!

339
00:32:19,730 --> 00:32:23,040
可莱奥诺拉是整个战团的精神领袖
But Leonore is the spiritual leader of the entire Order.

340
00:32:23,040 --> 00:32:26,310
她是我们与大天使间的唯一使者
Our only direct link to the archangels.

341
00:32:26,370 --> 00:32:29,610
失去她  我们只能是
And without her, we're but a dying flock of vigilantes

342
00:32:29,610 --> 00:32:31,580
孤立无援垂死挣扎
with no hope of ever being reinforced.

343
00:32:33,810 --> 00:32:35,020
你们希望如此吗
Is that what you want?

344
00:33:39,380 --> 00:33:41,320
愿上帝宽恕我
May God forgive me.

345
00:34:02,040 --> 00:34:04,240
别过来  基甸
Stay where you are, Gideon!

346
00:34:04,370 --> 00:34:05,740
女王陛下
Your Majesty.

347
00:34:05,810 --> 00:34:08,010
-你不该来的  -交出武器
- You should not have come. - Weapons!

348
00:34:09,210 --> 00:34:13,360
按照你的指示  我没带武器
I am unarmed. As you instructed.

349
00:34:13,650 --> 00:34:15,760
弗兰肯斯坦的那个怪物呢
Where is Frankenstein's creature?

350
00:34:15,850 --> 00:34:17,360
我也不知道
I no longer know.

351
00:34:17,520 --> 00:34:20,930
我回教堂的时候  那家伙已经逃了
When I returned to the cathedral, it had already escaped.

352
00:34:21,250 --> 00:34:22,930
等一下
Wait!

353
00:34:24,420 --> 00:34:25,930
我带了别的东西
I've brought something else.

354
00:34:26,390 --> 00:34:28,600
基甸  不要
Gideon, no!

355
00:34:28,760 --> 00:34:32,740
这是维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的秘密笔记
This is the private scientific journal of Victor Frankenstein.

356
00:34:32,770 --> 00:34:34,670
200年前  我们救那只怪物的当晚
We found it on Frankenstein's body

357
00:34:34,670 --> 00:34:37,540
在弗兰肯斯坦的尸体上找到的
the night we rescued the creature 200 years ago.

358
00:34:38,000 --> 00:34:40,710
里面详细地记叙了
It contains, in detail,

359
00:34:41,880 --> 00:34:44,880
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦是如何构思
how Victor Frankenstein conceived,

360
00:34:44,880 --> 00:34:48,080
如何创造出这个令人恶心的生物
and then constructed his unholy abomination.

361
00:34:49,050 --> 00:34:51,730
我希望能用它换回女王陛下
And I pray that it might save my Queen now.

362
00:34:52,190 --> 00:34:55,450
基甸  我命令你带着笔记离开
Gideon, I command you, take the journal from this place,

363
00:34:55,460 --> 00:34:56,790
让我升天吧
and let me ascend.

364
00:36:12,830 --> 00:36:14,970
这具是今早送来的
This one came in just this morning.

365
00:36:14,970 --> 00:36:17,100
太平间的人卖给我们的
Morgue sold him to us.

366
00:36:17,100 --> 00:36:18,340
肝脏是不能用了
The liver was ruined,

367
00:36:18,340 --> 00:36:20,310
不过其他器官还行
but the other organs are healthy enough.

368
00:36:22,680 --> 00:36:24,750
和其他的放在一起吧
Store it with the rest.

369
00:36:28,280 --> 00:36:29,480
这是什么
What is that?

370
00:36:29,480 --> 00:36:32,450
好像是维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的手稿
It looks like Victor Frankenstein's handwritten account

371
00:36:32,450 --> 00:36:34,500
记录了他是如何赋予了那个怪物生命
of how he brought his creature to life.

372
00:36:35,290 --> 00:36:37,160
这比那怪物更有用
This is better for us.

373
00:36:37,720 --> 00:36:40,730
有了它  我们就能召回所有坠落的恶魔
This is everything we need to bring back our fallen.

374
00:36:41,830 --> 00:36:44,370
先问问人类的意思
We'll let the humans decide that.

375
00:37:59,310 --> 00:38:01,710
你想要弗兰肯斯坦创造的怪物
You asked for Frankenstein's creature.

376
00:38:01,710 --> 00:38:04,750
可我带来了更有用的东西
I bring you something far more edifying.

377
00:38:07,580 --> 00:38:08,750
弗兰肯斯坦
"Frankenstein."

378
00:38:08,750 --> 00:38:10,720
你说过他一定留下记录
You said there must be a record of his work somewhere.

379
00:38:10,720 --> 00:38:13,420
-你从哪儿找到的  -这是真的吗
- Uh... where did you get this? - Is this real?

380
00:38:13,920 --> 00:38:15,530
你说呢
You tell me.

381
00:38:34,670 --> 00:38:37,010
我们失去了16个
We lost 16.

382
00:38:37,110 --> 00:38:39,240
他们都是勇敢的战士
Good warriors, all of them.

383
00:38:39,250 --> 00:38:40,650
我当初就不该把他留下
I should never have held him here.

384
00:38:40,650 --> 00:38:43,420
这都怪那怪物  不是你的错
This was the creature's doing, not yours.

385
00:38:43,420 --> 00:38:44,580
要不是他回来了
If it had not come back...

386
00:38:44,580 --> 00:38:46,590
也许保留那本笔记就是错误
Was I wrong to keep the journal from him?

387
00:38:46,590 --> 00:38:48,490
你做的一切都是为了人类
Everything you do is for the good of humanity.

388
00:38:48,490 --> 00:38:50,400
无可厚非
There is no wrong in that.

389
00:38:50,420 --> 00:38:51,280
不过  既然那只怪物
However, now that the creature

390
00:38:51,290 --> 00:38:53,090
已经知道了笔记的存在
knows of the journal's existence...

391
00:38:53,090 --> 00:38:54,660
你就非要叫他怪物吗
Why must you call him that?

392
00:38:54,660 --> 00:38:57,900
既然"他"已经知道了  你打算怎么办
Now that "He" knows, what are you prepared to do?

393
00:39:00,330 --> 00:39:01,830
找到亚当
Find Adam!

394
00:39:01,840 --> 00:39:03,500
发动所有的夜翼神
Call every gargoyle you can spare.

395
00:39:03,500 --> 00:39:05,100
搜索每个角落
Post them on every rooftop.

396
00:39:05,100 --> 00:39:07,010
找到之后又怎么办
And when we find him?

397
00:39:07,010 --> 00:39:09,170
再把他带回这里
Do we bring him back here again?

398
00:39:09,180 --> 00:39:11,650
牺牲更多人去保护他吗
Sacrifice even more of us to protect him?

399
00:39:12,480 --> 00:39:14,340
不如让我们了结此事
Or do we finally put an end to all of this,

400
00:39:14,340 --> 00:39:15,550
破坏纳贝里士的计划
and deny Naberius his prize,

401
00:39:15,550 --> 00:39:17,020
我们当年就该如此了
as we should have done long ago?

402
00:39:17,020 --> 00:39:18,880
也许不是上帝赐予了亚当生命
God may not have put Adam on this earth,

403
00:39:18,880 --> 00:39:20,190
可神还是允许了他
but he did allow him to live

404
00:39:20,190 --> 00:39:23,230
在这世上顽强地活了200多年
for over 200 years against incredible odds.

405
00:39:23,660 --> 00:39:27,330
神意不是你或我可以违背的
It is not for you or I to deny God's purpose.

406
00:39:27,890 --> 00:39:30,600
等着瞧吧  女王陛下
Well, sooner or later, Your Majesty,

407
00:39:31,130 --> 00:39:32,930
很快你就将别无选择
you will have no choice.

408
00:39:37,800 --> 00:39:40,250
电鳗
Eels.

409
00:39:40,410 --> 00:39:41,680
什么
What was that?

410
00:39:41,910 --> 00:39:44,520
他的电能来自电鳗
Electric eels, that's where he got his power from.

411
00:39:44,880 --> 00:39:46,180
那只是种鱼
You know, it's actually a fish...

412
00:39:46,180 --> 00:39:49,380
每只电鳗释放500伏电压
Six electric eels generating 500 volts each.

413
00:39:49,880 --> 00:39:51,350
6只就是3000伏
That's 3,000 volts.

414
00:39:51,350 --> 00:39:53,690
杀头大象都绰绰有余
That's enough to kill an elephant.

415
00:39:55,860 --> 00:39:57,660
电流要维持多久
How long did he hold the current for?

416
00:39:57,660 --> 00:39:59,930
每5秒钟爆发3次
Three bursts of five seconds each.

417
00:40:00,930 --> 00:40:02,940
那可是15000焦能量
That's 15,000 joules.

418
00:40:03,000 --> 00:40:05,970
我开始好奇那怪物到底活了多久
Makes you wonder how long that thing lasted.

419
00:40:06,770 --> 00:40:09,840
你想  所有这些能量都要通过静脉
Think of it, all that energy coursing through its veins

420
00:40:09,840 --> 00:40:14,540
为它的心  肺  神经系统供能
powering its heart, lungs, nervous system.

421
00:40:14,540 --> 00:40:16,480
如果这它都撑了下来
Well, if it survived that at birth,

422
00:40:17,540 --> 00:40:19,150
那要杀死它又需要怎样的能量呢
what would it take to kill it?

423
00:40:43,940 --> 00:40:45,170
看看他的眼睛
Look at its eyes.

424
00:40:47,110 --> 00:40:48,790
摄人心魄
The way they hold you.

425
00:40:49,880 --> 00:40:52,710
说明它有一定的智力水平
It suggests a certain level of intelligence.

426
00:40:52,710 --> 00:40:56,480
也许只是维克多·弗兰肯斯坦画出来的感觉
Maybe Victor Frankenstein just drew it that way.

427
00:40:56,480 --> 00:40:58,720
重新检查一下我们的细胞繁殖公式
I want to re-examine our cellular reproduction formula.

428
00:40:58,720 --> 00:40:59,960
我觉得我们漏掉了什么
I think we've missed something.

429
00:41:42,260 --> 00:41:44,200
别碰他
Leave him be!

430
00:41:45,260 --> 00:41:49,600
很抱歉保安人员这么小题大做
My apologies for the zealous nature of our security.

431
00:41:49,600 --> 00:41:52,770
不过要是你能走正门
Perhaps if you'd simply knocked on the front door,

432
00:41:52,770 --> 00:41:56,940
局面也不必如此尴尬
this unfortunate awkwardness might have been avoided.

433
00:41:56,940 --> 00:41:58,210
你是谁
Who are you?

434
00:41:58,280 --> 00:41:59,890
查尔斯·威塞克斯
Charles Wessex.

435
00:42:01,450 --> 00:42:04,490
你一定就是弗兰肯斯坦了吧
And you must be Frankenstein.

436
00:42:04,820 --> 00:42:06,660
我是亚当
My name is Adam.

437
00:42:06,690 --> 00:42:09,700
可是父子关系也不容置疑  不是吗
We are all the sons of our fathers, are we not?

438
00:42:09,960 --> 00:42:14,900
否认不过是迷失自我的表现
Denying who we are only means that we are lost.

439
00:42:15,630 --> 00:42:17,770
我是一名时光旅者
I am a journeyman,

440
00:42:18,230 --> 00:42:20,410
发展论的忠实信徒
a partisan of progress.

441
00:42:20,500 --> 00:42:22,500
和你父亲一样  试图解开
Like your father, I too seek

442
00:42:22,500 --> 00:42:25,470
人类生死之谜
to unravel the mortal coils of life.

443
00:42:25,470 --> 00:42:27,970
这位是维德博士
This is Dr. Wade.

444
00:42:27,970 --> 00:42:31,350
享誉世界的电生理学家
She's one of the world's most respected electrophysiologists.

445
00:42:31,710 --> 00:42:32,910
你好
Hello.

446
00:42:34,050 --> 00:42:36,310
一直以来  我都希望
I have been trying to replicate

447
00:42:36,320 --> 00:42:38,890
能够重现维克多·弗兰肯斯坦
Victor Frankenstein's stunning triumph

448
00:42:39,520 --> 00:42:41,130
创造的生命奇迹
for quite some time.

449
00:42:41,150 --> 00:42:44,560
我读到的笔记已经对我们大有帮助
What I've read of the journal has already been extremely helpful.

450
00:42:45,390 --> 00:42:47,540
想清楚  亚当
Be reasonable, Adam.

451
00:42:47,930 --> 00:42:50,730
你的生命本身就是奇迹
You are a living miracle.

452
00:42:50,760 --> 00:42:54,240
你身上隐藏着多少人苦苦探寻的答案
You contain the answers so many seek.

453
00:42:54,700 --> 00:42:56,500
我也有答案要找
I seek my own answers.

454
00:42:56,500 --> 00:42:58,500
当然如此
Of course you do.

455
00:42:58,500 --> 00:43:00,210
和我们一起吧
Stay with us.

456
00:43:01,370 --> 00:43:03,410
帮助我们解读你父亲的创造
Help us understand your father's work,

457
00:43:03,410 --> 00:43:06,990
我们联手一定能找到答案  也许更多
and, together, we can unlock those answers and more.

458
00:43:12,420 --> 00:43:13,790
没错
Yes...

459
00:43:14,620 --> 00:43:17,620
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦赋予了你生命
Victor Frankenstein gave you life,

460
00:43:17,620 --> 00:43:20,800
可他却无法赋予你灵魂
but he could not restore your soul.

461
00:43:21,060 --> 00:43:22,330
不是吗
Could he?

462
00:44:12,580 --> 00:44:15,280
没有找到那怪物  他可能躲在任何地方
There's no sign of the creature. He could be anywhere by now.

463
00:44:15,410 --> 00:44:16,650
他会找一个安全的地方
He will find a safe place

464
00:44:16,650 --> 00:44:18,650
研究笔记  然后回来
where he can study the journal, then it will come back here.

465
00:44:18,650 --> 00:44:19,780
回来
Come back?

466
00:44:19,790 --> 00:44:23,560
这200年我一直在找他
I've been pursuing the creature for the better part of 200 years.

467
00:44:23,590 --> 00:44:25,530
-我相信它一定会回来  -为什么
- It will come back. - For what?

468
00:44:25,990 --> 00:44:27,930
威塞克斯先生
Mr. Wessex.

469
00:44:27,930 --> 00:44:29,230
为了答案
Answers.

470
00:44:29,260 --> 00:44:30,760
有什么能为您效劳的  博士
How can I help you, Doctor?

471
00:44:30,760 --> 00:44:33,670
不如先解释一下究竟怎么回事吧
Well, you can start by please explaining to me what is going on.

472
00:44:33,670 --> 00:44:36,100
有人入侵  单纯的安保问题而已
We had a break-in. It's a simple security matter.

473
00:44:36,100 --> 00:44:37,340
恕我直言  先生
With all due respect, sir,

474
00:44:37,340 --> 00:44:39,270
弗兰肯斯坦创造的那个生物真的活着
but Frankenstein's creature is alive.

475
00:44:39,270 --> 00:44:40,880
您应该回家  好好休息
Why don't you go home and get some rest?

476
00:44:40,880 --> 00:44:41,840
你又是什么人
Look, just who are you?

477
00:44:41,840 --> 00:44:44,210
他是我的人
This gentleman works for me.

478
00:44:44,210 --> 00:44:46,320
算是额外的安全措施吧
A sort of extra layer of security, if you will.

479
00:44:46,610 --> 00:44:48,010
你的安全措施
Well, your extra layer of security

480
00:44:48,010 --> 00:44:50,020
刚刚破灭了最后一丝
just blew any hopes I might have had

481
00:44:50,020 --> 00:44:51,320
我能分析那个生物的希望
of analyzing that creature.

482
00:44:51,520 --> 00:44:53,690
你没听到它的话吗  它在寻求答案
Didn't you hear what it said? It wants answers!

483
00:44:53,690 --> 00:44:55,620
而能给出这答案的人是我
And I am the one who might've been able to provide them!

484
00:44:55,620 --> 00:44:57,220
也只有我
The only one!

485
00:44:57,220 --> 00:45:01,060
也许吧  你看起来很疲惫  博士
You may be right. You look tired, Doctor.

486
00:45:01,060 --> 00:45:02,130
很晚了
It's late.

487
00:45:02,130 --> 00:45:04,060
你该回去休息了
You really ought to get some rest.

488
00:45:04,060 --> 00:45:06,030
休息  威塞克斯先生
Rest? Mr. Wessex...

489
00:45:06,030 --> 00:45:08,670
怪物和笔记都不在了  博士
We've lost both the creature and the journal, Doctor.

490
00:45:08,670 --> 00:45:10,400
-你今晚还能做什么呢  -可是
- What more can you do tonight? - But, Mr...

491
00:45:10,400 --> 00:45:14,280
不管找到哪个我们都会通知你的
I will notify you should we recover the one or the other.

492
00:45:14,310 --> 00:45:15,780
回家吧  博士
Go home, Doctor!

493
00:45:22,580 --> 00:45:25,230
我记录的不是一个疯子的幻想
"I am not recording the visions of a madman.

494
00:45:25,480 --> 00:45:29,250
我的方法和原理都是有科学依据的
"My methods and reasons are scientifically sound.

495
00:45:29,260 --> 00:45:32,260
我发现了生命
"Succeeded discovering the cause...

496
00:45:32,260 --> 00:45:33,860
繁殖的奥妙
"and generation of life.

497
00:45:33,860 --> 00:45:38,060
墓地提供给我实验的原材料
"A graveyard has furnished the few raw materials I required.

498
00:45:38,060 --> 00:45:39,860
今夜  我将用我的设备
"Tonight, I gather my instruments...

499
00:45:39,870 --> 00:45:43,710
打破生死的绝对界限
"shatter the ideal bounds of life and death!"

500
00:45:50,610 --> 00:45:51,950
谢谢
Thank you.

501
00:46:06,690 --> 00:46:09,130
你确定他会为了这个女人回来
How certain are you it will come for her?

502
00:46:09,200 --> 00:46:12,900
他需要有人为他解释笔记
It needs someone to make sense of the journal.

503
00:46:12,900 --> 00:46:14,580
只有她能做到
Only she can do that.

504
00:47:03,580 --> 00:47:05,130
我不会伤害你的
I'm not going to hurt you.

505
00:47:14,930 --> 00:47:16,630
跟我来
Come with me.

506
00:47:20,670 --> 00:47:21,970
你为什么要跟踪我
Why are you following me?

507
00:47:21,970 --> 00:47:24,370
你复活尸体的进展如何了
How close are you to re-animating a human corpse?

508
00:47:24,370 --> 00:47:27,350
-不能告诉你  -这个有帮助吗
- I can't tell you that. - Would this help?

509
00:47:28,510 --> 00:47:31,380
我还没来得及完成我的实验
Oh, I haven't had the chance to finish it yet.

510
00:47:31,680 --> 00:47:33,610
研究我有用吗
What if you examined me?

511
00:47:33,610 --> 00:47:35,280
回研究所吗
Back at the Institute?

512
00:47:35,280 --> 00:47:38,090
不去那  离那很远的地方
Not there. Somewhere away from it.

513
00:47:38,280 --> 00:47:40,820
可我的仪器笔记还有研究都还在研究所里
But all my equipment's there. My notes, my research!

514
00:47:40,820 --> 00:47:42,890
你不知道你在为谁效力
You don't know who it is you're working for.

515
00:47:42,890 --> 00:47:43,960
不是威塞克斯先生吗
Mr. Wessex?

516
00:47:43,960 --> 00:47:45,190
你不了解他
He's not who you think he is.

517
00:47:45,860 --> 00:47:49,900
一场不为人类所知的战争正在进行
There's a war. A war humans don't know about.

518
00:47:49,960 --> 00:47:52,040
数百年来战火不断
It's been going on for centuries.

519
00:47:52,060 --> 00:47:54,330
人类能否幸存取决于战争的结果
It could mean the end of all mankind.

520
00:47:54,330 --> 00:47:56,230
那是谁的战争
Between who?

521
00:47:56,240 --> 00:47:57,940
夜翼神和恶魔
Gargoyles and demons.

522
00:47:58,240 --> 00:48:01,970
你的老板是个名叫纳贝里士的恶魔王子
I think your boss is a demon prince called Naberius.

523
00:48:01,970 --> 00:48:03,350
恶魔王子
A demon prince?

524
00:48:03,640 --> 00:48:07,020
两百多年来他一直在追捕我
Been hunting me for over 200 years.

525
00:48:07,080 --> 00:48:08,280
现在我终于知道原因了
Now, I think I know why.

526
00:48:09,580 --> 00:48:11,390
我们得躲起来
We have to get off the streets.

527
00:48:17,990 --> 00:48:19,230
来吧
Come on.

528
00:48:24,330 --> 00:48:25,610
纳贝里士将大批人类尸体
Naberius is storing human

529
00:48:25,610 --> 00:48:27,670
贮存在威塞克斯研究所的地下
corpses underneath the Wessex Institute.

530
00:48:27,670 --> 00:48:28,900
尸体
Corpses?

531
00:48:29,170 --> 00:48:31,840
不可能  我们离人体实验阶段还远着呢
No, we're still years away from human trials.

532
00:48:31,840 --> 00:48:33,240
我亲眼所见
I've seen the bodies.

533
00:48:33,340 --> 00:48:36,450
其数量足够拼出一支像我这样的怪物大军
There's enough to animate an entire army of monsters like me.

534
00:48:39,880 --> 00:48:43,520
你说你叫什么名字  亚当吗
What did you say that your name was? Adam?

535
00:48:43,520 --> 00:48:46,020
夜翼神的女王给我取的
That's the name the Gargoyle Queen gave to me.

536
00:48:46,020 --> 00:48:48,850
我怀疑你在复活过程中
Look, I understand you probably suffered

537
00:48:48,850 --> 00:48:49,950
很有可能遭受了
severe brain damage during

538
00:48:49,950 --> 00:48:51,720
严重的脑损伤  而且鉴于
the reanimation process given the level...

539
00:48:51,720 --> 00:48:54,800
我说的都是真的  全都是
This is real! All of it!

540
00:48:55,560 --> 00:48:57,400
抱歉  我
I'm sorry. I...

541
00:48:57,700 --> 00:49:00,640
我只是不相信夜翼神和恶魔的存在
I just don't believe in gargoyles and demons.

542
00:49:00,700 --> 00:49:02,440
弗兰肯斯坦
Frankenstein!

543
00:49:05,870 --> 00:49:07,810
天哪
Oh, shit.

544
00:49:08,210 --> 00:49:09,820
快跑
Run.

545
00:49:25,390 --> 00:49:26,660
今晚必须有个了结
This ends tonight.

546
00:50:45,300 --> 00:50:48,670
我看见那些躯壳了
I've seen the bodies.

547
00:50:48,670 --> 00:50:50,620
你们绝对无法控制他们
You'll never be able to control them.

548
00:50:50,640 --> 00:50:54,020
控制不是问题
Control has never been the problem.

549
00:50:54,810 --> 00:50:58,550
地狱囚禁着千百万魔灵
There are millions of demon spirits trapped in hell

550
00:50:58,550 --> 00:51:01,490
只等着一个附体人类的机会
waiting for the chance to possess a human body

551
00:51:01,490 --> 00:51:03,860
杀回人间
and return to our world.

552
00:51:07,160 --> 00:51:09,030
这跟我有什么关系
What's this got to do with me?

553
00:51:09,030 --> 00:51:11,570
为什么要把我牵扯进来
What's in hell that's got to do with me?

554
00:51:11,600 --> 00:51:15,070
你没有灵魂
You have no soul,

555
00:51:16,340 --> 00:51:20,640
而恶魔之灵只能附身没有灵魂的躯壳
and a demon spirit can only possess a body that has no soul.

556
00:51:20,840 --> 00:51:22,570
不  不
No. No.

557
00:51:28,350 --> 00:51:30,590
知道拿到笔记最大的好处吗
You know what the best thing about having the journal is?

558
00:51:31,450 --> 00:51:34,430
那就是不必把你活着带回去了
I no longer need to bring you in alive.

559
00:51:35,720 --> 00:51:37,160
但我需要他活着
I need it alive!

560
00:51:37,260 --> 00:51:39,990
我需要研究它
I need to study it!

561
00:51:40,930 --> 00:51:42,190
把它带回实验室
Bring it back to the lab and...

562
00:51:42,190 --> 00:51:44,810
你完全可以根据笔记研究它的尸体
You can read the journal and study its corpse.

563
00:51:45,360 --> 00:51:48,170
尸体没法体现机体运作的过程
Its corpse won't show me how its organs function,

564
00:51:48,200 --> 00:51:49,670
也无法对实验作出反应
how they respond to tests.

565
00:51:50,870 --> 00:51:54,270
让我把它带回实验室  我可以解剖它
Let me bring it back to the lab where I can open it up,

566
00:51:54,270 --> 00:51:57,420
而且确保它活着完成威塞克斯先生的实验
but keep it alive while I run my tests for Mr. Wessex.

567
00:51:57,710 --> 00:52:00,150
你可以等我做完再下手
You can destroy it when I'm done.

568
00:52:18,460 --> 00:52:19,770
笔记
The journal!

569
00:52:33,480 --> 00:52:35,490
没事了  来吧
It's okay. Come on.

570
00:52:35,580 --> 00:52:37,950
我要把你的外套脱下来  好吗
I'm going to take your coat off now. Ready?

571
00:52:37,950 --> 00:52:39,080
去柜子里找找
Look in the cabinet.

572
00:52:39,080 --> 00:52:40,290
好的
Okay.

573
00:53:05,110 --> 00:53:06,310
坐下吧
Sit down.

574
00:53:11,280 --> 00:53:12,520
请坐下
Sit down, please.

575
00:53:13,620 --> 00:53:15,260
没事的
It's okay.

576
00:53:17,460 --> 00:53:19,100
不会有事的  你坐下就行
Please, it's all right, you can sit down.

577
00:53:43,420 --> 00:53:45,600
我们不能在这待太久
We can't stay here long.

578
00:53:46,090 --> 00:53:47,520
请别乱动
Okay, hold still, please.

579
00:53:47,520 --> 00:53:50,390
恶魔肯定正在满城搜寻我们
Demons will be looking for us everywhere.

580
00:53:52,090 --> 00:53:56,030
我们得去找夜翼神女王莱奥诺拉
We have to get to Leonore, the Gargoyle Queen.

581
00:53:56,730 --> 00:53:58,570
现在只有她才能帮我们
She's the only one who can help us now.

582
00:53:58,660 --> 00:54:02,100
你亲眼看见恶魔了  你也知道真相了
You saw that thing. You saw what it was.

583
00:54:02,100 --> 00:54:03,410
我不知道我看见的是什么
I don't know what I saw.

584
00:54:03,740 --> 00:54:05,880
他们肯定会来找你
They'll come for you.

585
00:54:05,940 --> 00:54:08,740
-他们需要你的帮助  -帮他们做什么
- They need you to help them. - Help them do what?

586
00:54:08,770 --> 00:54:10,980
复活尸体军团  然后占领世界
Animate an army of corpses to take over the world?

587
00:54:11,010 --> 00:54:13,850
-是让恶魔附身到尸体上  -这不可能
- Corpses possessed by demons. - It can't happen. It won't.

588
00:54:13,850 --> 00:54:18,220
他们首先要做的就是彻底消灭夜翼神战团
First thing they'll do is wipe out the Gargoyle Order.

589
00:54:19,050 --> 00:54:21,290
剩下的夜翼神太少了  肯本无法抵抗
There's so few gargoyles left, they won't stand a chance.

590
00:54:22,350 --> 00:54:26,470
胜利之后  纳贝里士就会对人类宣战
Then Naberius will launch a war on humans.

591
00:54:28,390 --> 00:54:31,400
杀掉大部分  奴役剩下的
Kill most, enslave the rest.

592
00:54:32,770 --> 00:54:34,100
人类世界就此崩溃
Your world will end.

593
00:54:41,110 --> 00:54:42,580
那你打算怎么办
And what will you do?

594
00:54:50,080 --> 00:54:51,280
这本来就跟我没什么关系
It has nothing to do with me.

595
00:54:51,320 --> 00:54:52,620
当然有关系
Of course, it does.

596
00:54:52,620 --> 00:54:54,420
你和其他生灵一样也是世界的一部分
You're as much a part of this world as anybody.

597
00:54:54,420 --> 00:54:57,360
不  我不一样
No, I'm different.

598
00:54:57,790 --> 00:54:59,260
区别没你想的那么大
You're not that different.

599
00:54:59,490 --> 00:55:02,300
我是几块尸体拼出来的
I'm a dozen used parts from eight different corpses.

600
00:55:04,400 --> 00:55:05,600
一个怪物
I'm a monster.

601
00:55:09,100 --> 00:55:11,140
只要你不行怪物之事  那你就不是怪物
You're only a monster if you behave like one.

602
00:55:27,250 --> 00:55:29,960
从前还没有人类做过什么需要我感激的事
I've never had to thank a human for anything before.

603
00:55:32,590 --> 00:55:35,030
看来我们还是有点用的
Well, we have our uses, I suppose.

604
00:55:46,100 --> 00:55:47,310
亚当
Look, Adam...

605
00:56:10,130 --> 00:56:11,930
笔记不见了  先生
The journal is not here, sir.

606
00:56:32,020 --> 00:56:33,360
感觉如何
How are you feeling?

607
00:56:34,050 --> 00:56:36,100
这次还不是最惨的
I've been through worse.

608
00:56:48,430 --> 00:56:50,580
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦后来怎么了
What happened to Victor Frankenstein?

609
00:56:51,570 --> 00:56:53,720
据说他妻子去世之后他
They say he vanished after his...

610
00:56:54,910 --> 00:56:56,250
就失踪了
wife died.

611
00:57:06,950 --> 00:57:08,150
我杀了他的妻子
I killed his wife.

612
00:57:11,860 --> 00:57:13,160
他四处追捕我
He hunted me.

613
00:57:16,130 --> 00:57:18,240
我本打算也杀了他
I would've killed him, too.

614
00:57:19,930 --> 00:57:21,940
但他冻死了
But he froze to death.

615
00:57:22,870 --> 00:57:24,340
我恨他
I hated him.

616
00:57:27,410 --> 00:57:29,950
那之后你杀过人吗
Have you killed anyone since?

617
00:57:31,710 --> 00:57:33,320
只杀过恶魔
Only demons.

618
00:57:37,950 --> 00:57:39,690
笔记我读完了
I finished reading it.

619
00:57:41,390 --> 00:57:45,290
看来在你逃走之后他又大幅改进了技术
Seems he refined the process significantly after you.

620
00:57:45,290 --> 00:57:49,960
他的手段和方法仍然十分超前
I mean, his science is still incredibly, wildly out of the box,

621
00:57:49,960 --> 00:57:54,270
但我想我可以再现这一过程
but, um, I think I can reproduce it.

622
00:57:55,400 --> 00:57:57,510
甚至对其进行改进
Perhaps even improve on it.

623
00:57:59,640 --> 00:58:03,010
弗兰肯斯坦曾许诺给你做个伴侣  对吗
Frankenstein promised to make you a companion, didn't he?

624
00:58:04,910 --> 00:58:06,680
他没能履约
A promise he broke.

625
00:58:07,850 --> 00:58:09,820
所以你才来找我吗
Is that why you came to me?

626
00:58:11,750 --> 00:58:14,900
你希望我完成维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的诺言
You want me to fulfill Victor Frankenstein's promise?

627
00:58:24,460 --> 00:58:26,000
-卡尔  -我收到你的留言了
- Carl! - I got your message.

628
00:58:26,000 --> 00:58:27,470
还以为你应该睡了呢
Thought you'd be asleep by now.

629
00:58:27,470 --> 00:58:30,340
卡尔  我要你立即离开威塞克斯研究所
Carl, listen to me. I want you to leave Wessex right now.

630
00:58:30,440 --> 00:58:31,600
离开
Leave?

631
00:58:31,600 --> 00:58:34,300
我们火车站见吧
And I want you to meet me at the train station.

632
00:58:34,310 --> 00:58:36,010
我还有不少数据要分析
I've still got all the data crunching to do.

633
00:58:36,010 --> 00:58:37,410
卡尔  求你了
Carl, please.

634
00:58:37,780 --> 00:58:39,920
请相信我  这和笔记有关
Please just trust me. It's about the journal.

635
00:58:40,950 --> 00:58:42,590
好吧  我20分钟后到
All right, I'll be there in 20.

636
00:58:42,610 --> 00:58:44,380
好  回见
Okay. Bye.

637
00:58:48,120 --> 00:58:50,490
你不该打给他
You shouldn't have done that.

638
00:58:50,820 --> 00:58:54,130
他对复活的流程和我一样熟悉
Well, he knows as much about the re-animation process as I do.

639
00:58:54,130 --> 00:58:56,030
如果你说的是真的  那他也有危险
If what you say is true, then he's in danger as well.

640
00:58:56,030 --> 00:58:57,260
我们用不着他
We don't need him.

641
00:58:59,130 --> 00:59:01,000
这和用得着用不着无关
This isn't about what you need right now.

642
00:59:01,130 --> 00:59:03,840
我和你一起去  好有个照应
I'll go with you, look after you.

643
00:59:03,870 --> 00:59:05,470
你应该去找夜翼神女王
You go talk to the Gargoyle Queen.

644
00:59:05,470 --> 00:59:06,840
一小时后我们在这碰头
I'll meet you back here in an hour.

645
00:59:06,840 --> 00:59:08,010
特拉
Terra!

646
00:59:08,010 --> 00:59:09,840
这样的话你只需要保护自己
That way you can just look after yourself.

647
00:59:10,540 --> 00:59:12,350
这是你的长项
You're good at that.

648
00:59:16,010 --> 00:59:17,690
给你
Here.

649
00:59:33,670 --> 00:59:34,870
卡尔
Carl!

650
00:59:35,170 --> 00:59:36,540
对不起
I'm sorry.

651
00:59:36,840 --> 00:59:39,440
-什么  -是他们逼我的
- What? - They made me do it.

652
00:59:39,440 --> 00:59:41,080
我别无选择  我是被逼的
I had no choice. They made me!

653
00:59:45,540 --> 00:59:46,880
当心身后
Behind you!

654
00:59:51,680 --> 00:59:54,060
你还有工作要做  维德博士
You have work to do, Dr. Wade.

655
01:00:08,030 --> 01:00:09,300
放开他
Release him.

656
01:00:14,110 --> 01:00:15,370
你骗了我
You lied to me.

657
01:00:15,370 --> 01:00:16,610
没错  我说谎了
Yes, I did.

658
01:00:16,640 --> 01:00:19,190
但我肩负保护人类的重大使命
But I had a higher duty to protect the human race.

659
01:00:19,210 --> 01:00:21,120
你知不知道那笔记对我多么重要
Do you understand what that journal is to me?

660
01:00:21,210 --> 01:00:24,550
里面详细记录了我是如何做出来的
It's the chronicle of how I came to be.

661
01:00:24,550 --> 01:00:26,090
我是谁
Who I am.

662
01:00:27,750 --> 01:00:28,990
我是什么
What I am.

663
01:00:29,790 --> 01:00:31,890
你是一个独特又孤独的造物
You are a unique, lonely being

664
01:00:31,890 --> 01:00:34,330
被你的创造者和全人类排斥在外
rejected by both your maker and the rest of humanity.

665
01:00:34,330 --> 01:00:37,130
正因为此  你满怀愤怒
And, as a result, you are filled with rage.

666
01:00:37,400 --> 01:00:39,600
这些并不需要什么笔记来提醒你
You do not need a book to tell you that.

667
01:00:40,630 --> 01:00:41,760
纳贝里士发现了一种
Naberius has found a way

668
01:00:41,760 --> 01:00:43,840
把你们打进地狱的恶魔召回人间的办法
to summon every demon you've ever descended.

669
01:00:43,900 --> 01:00:45,070
什么
What?

670
01:00:45,070 --> 01:00:46,440
附身
Possession,

671
01:00:46,740 --> 01:00:48,940
让他们附在无魂躯壳上
in bodies that have no souls.

672
01:00:48,970 --> 01:00:51,480
只有死者才无灵魂
Only the dead have no souls.

673
01:00:51,480 --> 01:00:55,150
-附于死尸之上于他何益  -没有益处
- What is the use of possessing a corpse? - There is none.

674
01:00:56,980 --> 01:00:59,160
除非能让死尸复活
Unless you could animate that corpse.

675
01:00:59,920 --> 01:01:02,360
纳贝里士为此谋划了几个世纪
Naberius has been planning this for centuries.

676
01:01:02,490 --> 01:01:04,670
维克多·弗兰肯斯坦使之成为可能
Victor Frankenstein just made it possible.

677
01:01:05,090 --> 01:01:07,500
-你怎么知道  -我亲眼见到了躯壳
- How do you know all this? - I've seen the bodies.

678
01:01:08,930 --> 01:01:10,800
数量足有千万之巨
There are tens of thousands of them.

679
01:01:11,030 --> 01:01:12,230
在哪
Where?

680
01:01:12,530 --> 01:01:14,300
我们是你的盟友  亚当
We are your friends, Adam.

681
01:01:14,430 --> 01:01:16,130
我们不会再试图控制你
We will never try to control you again.

682
01:01:16,270 --> 01:01:18,440
但如果你有维克多·弗兰肯斯坦的笔记
But if you have Victor Frankenstein's journal,

683
01:01:18,440 --> 01:01:21,310
想必你完全明白为何要立刻将其毁去
surely you see now that it must be destroyed.

684
01:01:21,310 --> 01:01:23,580
形势已经变了
My circumstances have changed.

685
01:01:26,140 --> 01:01:29,720
我有他人相助  一个人类
I have someone with me now, a human.

686
01:01:30,050 --> 01:01:31,350
一位科学家
A scientist.

687
01:01:31,880 --> 01:01:34,390
我要保护她
I have to protect her.

688
01:01:35,450 --> 01:01:37,290
你想让我们做什么
What would you have us do?

689
01:01:37,290 --> 01:01:38,560
帮我们逃出去
Get us out of here.

690
01:01:39,190 --> 01:01:41,200
然后我就告诉你他们在哪
Then I will tell you where to find him.

691
01:01:50,640 --> 01:01:52,670
找到这位科学家  带她过来
Retrieve your scientist, come back here,

692
01:01:52,670 --> 01:01:55,040
我们会送你们去你想去的地方
then we shall take you where you wish to go.

693
01:01:56,740 --> 01:01:59,010
我在你身上屡次犯下大错  亚当
I've made too many mistakes with you, Adam.

694
01:01:59,010 --> 01:02:00,520
但我不会再犯错了
I'll not make another.

695
01:02:08,550 --> 01:02:12,260
你让感情凌驾于神圣使命之上
You put your emotion before your sacred duty!

696
01:02:12,260 --> 01:02:13,560
跟着他  基甸
Follow him, Gideon.

697
01:02:13,660 --> 01:02:15,740
只要笔记到手
As soon as you have the journal in sight,

698
01:02:17,900 --> 01:02:19,200
你就杀了他
destroy him.

699
01:03:25,460 --> 01:03:27,200
特拉
Terra?

700
01:05:26,020 --> 01:05:28,990
别忘了  我没有灵魂
Remember... I have no soul.

701
01:05:29,250 --> 01:05:31,430
上帝必会降罚于你
God will surely damn you.

702
01:05:31,460 --> 01:05:33,230
他已经惩罚过我了
He already did.

703
01:06:35,750 --> 01:06:37,230
我知道你是谁
I know who you are,

704
01:06:38,420 --> 01:06:40,530
也知道你想让我做什么
and I know what you want me to do.

705
01:06:43,190 --> 01:06:44,630
我不会做的
And I won't do it.

706
01:06:46,630 --> 01:06:48,000
我宁愿死
I'd rather die.

707
01:06:58,110 --> 01:06:59,980
卡尔
Carl!

708
01:07:02,780 --> 01:07:05,150
卡尔
Carl!

709
01:07:11,960 --> 01:07:13,530
想救活他吗
Do you want him back?

710
01:07:14,130 --> 01:07:15,830
救给我看看
Show me how.

711
01:08:27,800 --> 01:08:29,340
太棒了
Excellent.

712
01:08:30,370 --> 01:08:31,810
多谢  维德博士
Thank you, Dr. Wade.

713
01:09:57,790 --> 01:09:59,530
女王陛下
My Queen!

714
01:09:59,860 --> 01:10:01,200
我们找到那怪物了
We found the creature.

715
01:11:32,120 --> 01:11:34,490
先生  它来了
Sir, it's here.

716
01:11:38,290 --> 01:11:41,160
是"他"  不是"它"
"Him", not "It".

717
01:12:16,430 --> 01:12:17,630
是这里
This is the place.

718
01:12:20,630 --> 01:12:22,140
他是故意引我们来的
He led us here.

719
01:12:24,840 --> 01:12:26,640
我来对付他
Leave him to me!

720
01:13:37,840 --> 01:13:39,080
纳贝里士
Naberius!

721
01:13:40,110 --> 01:13:41,550
弗兰肯斯坦
Frankenstein.

722
01:13:42,050 --> 01:13:44,280
真高兴你能回来
How good of you to come back.

723
01:13:44,280 --> 01:13:48,060
我是来摧毁你和这地方的
I've come to destroy you and this place.

724
01:13:48,190 --> 01:13:51,720
夜翼神战团一定会取胜
The Gargoyle Order must survive

725
01:13:51,720 --> 01:13:53,900
人类也将存续
and mankind with it.

726
01:13:54,760 --> 01:13:58,400
你可毁不了我
You cannot destroy me,

727
01:13:58,400 --> 01:14:01,170
这样的地方我多的是
and I have many other places such as this

728
01:14:01,800 --> 01:14:03,810
遍布全球各地
all over the world.

729
01:14:03,900 --> 01:14:08,640
至于什么战团和人类
As for the Order and mankind,

730
01:14:08,640 --> 01:14:14,290
他们必将消亡  即便怪物如你也无法阻止
nothing can stop their demise, let alone a monster like you!

731
01:14:35,070 --> 01:14:36,340
太晚了  维德博士
Too late, Dr. Wade.

732
01:14:36,900 --> 01:14:39,510
你对我们已经没有任何用处了
We already have everything we need from you.

733
01:14:54,620 --> 01:14:57,490
我是个恶魔王子
I am a demon prince!

734
01:14:57,490 --> 01:15:00,730
而你将臣服于我
You will kneel before me!

735
01:15:18,110 --> 01:15:22,310
我知道多年来你一直想要什么  亚当
I know what you want, Adam. What you've always wanted.

736
01:15:22,350 --> 01:15:25,550
我会给你创造成百上千的同类
I will make hundreds like you.

737
01:15:26,780 --> 01:15:28,260
成千上万
Thousands.

738
01:15:28,720 --> 01:15:33,560
数个世纪以来我一直在收集人类尸体
I have been gathering human corpses for centuries,

739
01:15:33,560 --> 01:15:36,790
每一具都可供我从地狱召唤来的
each one a host for the legions of demon spirits

740
01:15:36,790 --> 01:15:39,940
魔灵大军附身
I will now summon from hell!

741
01:15:40,530 --> 01:15:44,680
而你就是第一个  你会成为我们的一员
You will be the first. You will be one of us.

742
01:15:45,540 --> 01:15:49,240
从此不再孤独
And you will no longer be alone.

743
01:16:26,010 --> 01:16:28,920
陛下  一旦他们苏醒就会被魔灵附身
Your Majesty, the moment they awake, they would be possessed!

744
01:16:29,380 --> 01:16:32,120
毁掉躯壳  通通毁掉
Destroy them. Destroy them all!

745
01:17:54,930 --> 01:17:56,430
欢迎  吾儿
Welcome, my son.

746
01:17:56,430 --> 01:18:00,140
你附身的躯壳非常优秀
You have possessed a truly remarkable body.

747
01:18:03,440 --> 01:18:05,480
我才不是你的儿子
I am not your son.

748
01:18:09,610 --> 01:18:12,660
这具身体是我的
And this body is mine.

749
01:18:12,780 --> 01:18:14,930
这不可能
No, it's not possible!

750
01:18:16,050 --> 01:18:17,860
你居然有了灵魂
You have a soul!

751
01:20:44,440 --> 01:20:45,640
基甸
Gideon...

752
01:20:45,940 --> 01:20:47,140
我知道
I know.

753
01:20:47,140 --> 01:20:49,040
那为什么还要救我
Then, why did you save me?

754
01:20:50,140 --> 01:20:52,480
因为你终于找到了崇高的追求
Because you finally found your higher purpose.

755
01:21:05,220 --> 01:21:06,590
笔记在哪
Where's the journal?

756
01:21:07,620 --> 01:21:09,360
我不再需要它了
I don't need it anymore.

757
01:21:25,140 --> 01:21:27,540
生命也许并非我们求得
We do not ask for the lives we are given,

758
01:21:28,980 --> 01:21:31,790
但我们人人都有权捍卫自己的生命
but each of us has the right to defend that life.

759
01:21:33,320 --> 01:21:36,020
我捍卫了我的生命
I have fought to defend mine.

760
01:21:36,420 --> 01:21:39,120
如果将来黑暗力量重返人间
And when the forces of darkness return,

761
01:21:39,520 --> 01:21:41,760
我定会奋力拼杀
you shall know that I am out there

762
01:21:42,590 --> 01:21:45,030
为捍卫你们的生命而战
fighting to defend yours.

763
01:21:46,160 --> 01:21:49,900
我  是驱魔人
I, descender of the demon horde.

764
01:21:50,930 --> 01:21:53,980
我  是我父亲之子
I, my father's son.

765
01:21:56,340 --> 01:21:57,810
我
I...

766
01:21:58,080 --> 01:21:59,780
是弗兰肯斯坦
Frankenstein.

