Peking - China.
The summer
of the year 1900.
The rains are late,
the crops have failed,
a hundred million
Chinese are hungry
and a violent wind
of discontent
disturbs the land.
Within the foreign compound
a thousand foreigners
live and work,
citizens of a dozen
far-off nations.
Priests and missionaries,
bankers and businessmen,
engineers and adventurers,
diplomats,
soldiers and students...
People with families, homes,
jobs.
Many have lived here
a lifetime and feel secure
as they go about
their daily routine.
What is
that terrible noise?
Different nations
saying the same thing,
We want China.
Sha-shao!
Separated from the compound
by only
a wall and a gate,
is the Forbidden City.
Here, in untouchable isolation
lives the Dowager Empress,
last of the Manchus.
Protected by
an army of eunuchs,
she holds court
and confers with her ministers,
mandarins and generals.
Halt the execution.
But Prince Tuan s orders!
Now
you have my orders.
The nightingale will recover.
The Court physician s
arts will work.
Only yesterday
I listened to its song.
The execution
has been stopped.
Who?
Jung-Lu,
Your Majesty,
I come to ask
your displeasure.
My life instead
of the Colonel s.
We cannot spare you.
I gave the order
to fire on the Boxers.
They were burning missions,
killing foreigners.
We have sad news.
The nightingale...
it was your gift.
Do you remember, Jung-Lu?
I have not forgotten.
I live to serve Your Majesty.
How does the attack
on the Boxers serve
Her Highness?
If they are unchecked,
foreign armies will fall
- on China.
- We are tens of millions.
Does the Empress believe that
where the imperial Army has failed,
the rabble will succeed?
- Our Gods are with the Boxers.
- The nightingale is still.
I hear only
the sound of crows.
Your Majesty,
a violent wind
is short-lived.
The Boxers have arisen
like the wind and rain,
and like the wind
and the rain, will die.
May the Boxers be guided
by the will of the gods.
About the Colonel, Your Majesty.
His end
will be a sign,
and a warning
to the foreigners.
His death
is of no consequence.
But his life has set
my Prince against my General
and this disturbs
the morning s tranquility.
Let him die
for this offense.
You are concerned, Jung-Lu?
If the Boxers fail,
I will give the foreigners
Prince Tuan s head.
Eyes front, soldier.
All right,
Marines, eyes front!
We re almost in Peking,
the capital city of China.
This is an ancient,
highly cultured civilization,
so don’t think
you re any better than them
because they
can t speak English.
A few Chinese words
go a long way.
Repeat after me.
The word for yes is shih.
Shih.
- The word for no is poo shih.
- Poo shih.
it s the same here
as anywhere else in the world,
everything has a price.
Pay your money and
don’t expect any free samples.
Yes, sir.
Right turn!
Column... Halt!
We going to stop that, Major?
Stay right there!
- Murphy!
- Yes, sir?
Ni hao.
Tell the Boxer chief
I want to do business with him.
I want to buy
the old man.
But he's not American.
Twenty dollars.
Hold it!
Tell him the old man
must be alive.
Nothing if he s dead.
Forty dollars.
All right.
He s dead.
But he say
you pay
for spoiling the ceremony.
Nothing doing.
Twenty dollars.
Tell him
I'll still do business.
I'll buy
the dead Boxer.
Forty dollars.
Twenty dollars.
- Did you fire that shot?
- Yes, sir.
Nice shooting, Sergeant.
Thank you, Major.
That'll cost you twenty bucks
out of your pay.
Fall in!
Alright...
- Take them to the barracks.
- Yes, sir.
- Murphy!
- Sir?
Madame.
Tell her I’m waiting.
I have sent her
a note, Excellency.
You re the owner.
Tell her.
Here s your key, Count.
Excellency, please.
As Russian Minister here
I order you to get her down.
As you wish, Excellency.
But remember she is still
a guest. I cannot order her.
Excellency, I think
you need a cold drink.
- And so do I.
- Champagne, sir?
How are you?
it's been a long time.
Natasha!
Baroness Ivanoff!
Yes, Sergei?
You keep me waiting
and then ignore me.
You are a little
nervous, Sergei.
I suggest something cool
for all of us.
Excuse me.
Natasha...
Thank you.
I won t talk
about the necklace.
But you are.
- As Russian Minister in Peking...
- Please, Sergei,
speak as
my brother-in-law.
Natasha,
I've told Bergmann
your visa s canceled.
So you cannot stay
in this hotel.
Or in Peking
or even in China.
- By law you don’t exist.
- That s frightening.
Where will you go?
To your Chinese friends?
How you hate me, don’t you?
No, you re wrong.
I don’t hate you.
Go!
You fool.
Is it my fault,
if you lose everything
and end up naked
in the street...?
Not completely naked.
There s still the necklace.
Today...
- She has to go today.
- Yes, sir.
I'll see to it.
Good evening.
I want a room
with a bath this time.
- Have you reserved, sir?
- You're late, Lewis.
Hello.
When did you arrive?
- Today.
- Why so late?
We walked
the last 10 miles.
Don’t the trains work now?
Gentlemen, the railroad
is no more.
- Major Lewis!
- Bergmann.
- Is there a room for me?
- They re all taken.
But if you'll wait
- a short while...
- Fine.
Thanks, Chiang.
Here you are.
Any time you need me.
Half my life s here.
Take care of it.
And more of your life’s here.
Oh, yes.
Let me use the bin.
Wont you open it?
Open it and
you must read it.
Then you must answer.
Lewis!
- Ah, Carlo!
- My dear chap!
- Captain.
- You re late.
What kept you?
I lost 2 men.
Had to bury them.
- Come on, let's get a drink.
- Alright.
Try and get a room
here too, Andy.
I want to look up the kid.
Ah yes, your little girl.
- How old is she now?
-11.
No, she must be 12.
It s a pity. No mother
and practically no father.
What can I do?
She s in a French mission
for Chinese orphans.
You re better than most.
You do try to see her.
But leaving her in a mission
is no way to raise her.
But what do I do?
Take her to Illinois?
How would she make out there?
They'd treat her
like a freak.
She s better off
among her own kind.
- You really think so?
- Sure.
May I have your key?
I need it for
the American officer.
Thank you.
Besides,
you have to live
your own life.
I've just had an invitation.
Please sit down, Major.
Ask him and
we'll drink together.
He d tell us his troubles.
What shall I tell you?
That you're happy I’m here.
You re very direct.
I’m a marine.
I’m short on time.
How much is there for me?
All you want.
Have you found
this approach successful?
Not really, no.
I don’t know another.
Keep drinking, Major.
The uniform
will hold you.
- Clever women make me nervous.
- No, please...
Please don’t go.
What can I offer you?
My life?
My room.
They gave it to you.
Is that too much to ask?
My life isn't worth much,
but hotel rooms here
are at a premium.
Do you always offer
your life to strangers?
To a soldier, strangers
are the best friends.
I’m not in uniform, Major.
Things are fine
as they are.
Major Lewis.
A British orderly
to see you.
The Minister wishes
to see you, sir.
He told me to tell you
he s been authorized
to act for your Minister.
Fine. Tell him
I'll be right along.
Yes, sir.
Here s you key.
Thanks.
What about your things?
- Put them back.
- But there s only one room.
Let the Baroness
figure it out. She s clever.
Don’t laugh yet, Major.
It s a very small room.
I've been
in tight places before.
So have I, Major.
- Daddy!
- Teresa!
Daddy!
- Hello, Britten.
- Good day, sir.
Wake up, sentries!
Take a tip
from an old soldier.
Whenever you see a Major
of the American Marines,
you will present arms.
And don't forget it!
If this be I,
as I suppose it be,
my little dog
will know me.
Come in.
I’m, sorry,
are you busy?
Of course I am.
I always am.
Busier than usual?
Or just busy?
Both.
Well, what s
the pressing female problem?
Just this,
Am I to pack or not to pack?
Do we go to England?
Do we leave
this year or not?
I don’t know.
You don’t know...
Pack. If we don’t go,
all you need do is unpack.
If men had
to do the packing,
the world
would be different.
- If I had my way...
- What?
We d have packed long since
and now be miles away.
We?
A comforting thought.
Thank you, darling.
Will it all
go up in flames?
- Not if I can help it.
- What?
I'll put it
in a nutshell.
If I encourage the Great Powers
to be tough with China,
China will become just
another battlefield for them
to fight over.
It s wiser to accept
temporary humiliation
at the hands
of the Boxers
in the hope that
by damping down the fire,
the kettle
won t boil over.
And then?
I shall probably receive
the Government s displeasure,
and we'll be retired
on an inadequate pension.
Remember what Napoleon said?
I never forget it.
Let China sleep.
' When she wakes,
the world will tremble.
He said a lot, didn't he?
Come in.
- Major Lewis, sir.
- Ask him to wait.
Darling, I have to put on
my official face.
You haven’t forgotten
our soirée?
Twenty-four bottles of champagne
are already on ice.
- Anything else the Sahib requires?
- The first waltz.
I'll consider it.
Philip!
Major Lewis, Sir Arthur.
Stand up, sit down,
or walk around the room.
I'll walk around.
You please yourself.
I have an unpleasant
task to fulfill.
First, congratulations on
your initiative this morning.
We were a little late.
Unfortunate that
a Chinese was killed.
- A Boxer?
- A Chinese citizen, Major.
You re not
in the Wild West now.
You can t shoot
Chinese like red Indians.
No, sir.
Secondly,
I warn you that such
irresponsible behaviour,
could easily
involve us all
in a great conflagration.
I understand.
And lastly, since
your Minister is suffering
from a diplomatic illness,
you are required
here no longer.
No longer
required by whom?
This is a message
from your own Legation.
I d be delighted
if you stayed.
Yes, sir.
You know all hell s
going to break loose?
If it does, it will not be
because we have provoked it.
So we'll all
just walk soft and
hope for the best.
If we walked on our knees,
we can t stop it.
I've just marched
from Tientsin.
Boxers are everywhere.
Killing white men,
missionaries,
and all Chinese Christians.
The Imperial Army s
doing nothing about it.
Boxers have been
around for years.
You re unnecessarily alarmed.
Well, the next time
I see them killing an English
priest, I'll try not to be.
I've been a soldier myself.
I understand how you feel.
But my job s to see
the larger picture.
I wouldn't know about that.
I just patrol the rice paddies
in the back country.
I know this much...
If the Boxers come,
we'll need more soldiers
in these compounds.
Well, now we’ve both
had our say.
I'll go quietly.
Oh, by the way,
it s our Queen s birthday.
Tonight we re entertaining.
Why not come?
Thank you.
I won t leave Ming.
I'll pack him in my case.
Don’t be silly.
He d suffocate.
- What s that?
- He d suffocate.
- It s only for five weeks.
- Come on.
May we speak
to you, father?
It s very important.
There are no negotiations
at the moment. What is it?
Mother says we can't
take Ming to England.
- I wont leave my dog.
- He s my dog.
- Who feeds him?
- Who taught him to sit up?
Tell you what.
We'll cut him exactly in two.
You each get a half.
- Father. Don’t play King Solomon.
- Well, I tried.
Atten...
shun!
Shoulder...
arms!
Present...
Slope...
arms!
His Excellency,
the Minister of Austria-Hungary
and the Baroness Von Riedel.
Welcome, Prince Tuan,
to Her Majesty s Legation.
I am deeply honoured.
His Imperial Highness,
Prince Tuan.
I bring greetings
from our Empress.
You are
most welcome, Highness.
Greeting and felicitations
to your great queen.
May the lions
of China and Britain
live in peace forever.
Our Queen is touched
by the words
of your illustrious Empress.
Your Imperial Highness,
Your Excellencies,
ladies and gentlemen,
the first dance
will be the Military Two-Step.
Marvellous, fabulous.
They should be
around my neck.
Of course, Sophie,
you look naked without them.
- Shall we join the line.
- No.
Not yet.
I've waited
for this a long time,
and I’m enjoying it.
Natasha, you blind us
with your glitter.
Would you recognize me
without them?
I understand
you're going to Tientsin.
That's right, Excellency.
There’s a Russian woman
who wishes to leave Peking.
Anyone we know, Sergei?
She d do well
to meet you.
It may be her only chance
to reach Tientsin.
It might be...
If you disregard me the
Russian government will remember.
- Sir Arthur.
- Evening, Major.
Lady Robertson.
I wanted
to thank you personally
for trying
to help Father Bemish.
You know the Baroness?
Yes, of course.
It s been a long time.
I know my husband
has thanked you.
Yes, I've expressed
my gratitude.
This is Baroness Ivanoff.
- And Major Lewis.
- Your Highness.
You must be the American
who had the encounter
with the Boxers this morning.
It was the priest
who had the hard time.
My government
is most distressed.
But do not conclude
that all Boxers are bandits.
Most of them
are harmless vagabonds.
Market place entertainers,
much like the gypsies
in your country.
In fact, Sir Arthur,
I have brought such a troupe
to entertain your guests
tonight.
Boxers here?
With your permission.
Of course, Your Highness.
He wants you
to take this sword
and try to strike him.
Try it.
It s part of the performance.
If I kill a Boxer,
does that, er...
create a diplomatic incident?
There is no danger.
You've made your point.
Not quite.
Bravo!
I guess he wasn't
a true believer.
It seems, Sir Arthur, that
your troops are invulnerable.
Forgive me,
but the Major
doesn’t seem
to play the game
according to Chinese rules.
I apologize, Sir Arthur.
I don’t think he came here
tonight to play games.
Good night.
Unfortunately, Sir Arthur,
I must return
to my duties at the palace.
No need to escort me.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next dance will be a waltz.
- Aword, Sir Arthur.
- This is an insult to the British
and a challenge
to all Powers!
Areport
will reach the Kaiser.
Her Majesty's Government
is not alarmed by this
Boxer invasion of its Embassy.
I shall complain
to the Chinese ministry.
What will you do, Sir Arthur?
I intend to have
a glass of champagne.
You know,
I admire Sir Arthur.
He makes me think
that God must be an Englishman.
We go and we go
and we don't get anywhere.
Why not head back to the hotel?
- Are you tired, Major?
- Tired? No.
Ready to turn in? Maybe.
Ever been
inside this temple?
Wed get a better drink
at the hotel.
Very interesting.
Can we go now?
But we haven’t
had our dance yet.
Shall we?
What'll you do
in Tientsin?
I'll be entirely
in your hands.
You are now but you keep
slipping through my fingers.
I think I’ll get you to take me
to San Francisco with you.
Why to San Francisco?
It s where
they found all the gold.
Just a minute.
What s that trinket worth?
A lot of money.
We won t leave today. They've
killed the German Minister.
But Matt, we must leave...
I have to leave.
You have to wait.
Your sword, Sir Arthur.
You are well, Sir Arthur?
If you are, Your Majesty.
- We are pleased to receive you.
- It s an honour,
Your Majesty.
We have been informed
of the German Minister s death.
The Boxers
will be punished.
But the people s anger
cannot be quieted so easily.
The Germans
have seized Kiaochow,
the Russians Port Arthur.
The French have obtained
concessions in Yunnan,
Kwangsi and Kwangtung.
In all, thirteen of the
eighteen provinces of China
are under
foreign control.
Warships occupy our harbors,
foreign armies
fill our forts,
foreign merchants
administer our banks,
foreign gods disturb
the spirits of our ancestors.
Is it surprising
our people are aroused?
Please allow me to observe
that Boxer violence cannot
redress China s grievances.
China is a prostrate cow!
The Powers are
butchering her for her meat.
If China is a cow, she is
indeed a marvellous animal
that gives
both meat and milk,
but at the same time
grows stronger.
She learns
Western arts of peace.
But China s greatest virtue
is her patience.
If she exercises that now,
she will achieve everything.
And if not?
If not,
if violence
and impatience prevail,
the blood of millions
will be shed
and the agony be prolonged.
Go to the window, Sir Arthur.
I’ve arranged something
for you to see.
Please inform
your government
that Chinese justice
is swift and thorough.
Those men murdered the
German Minister this morning.
Where lies the guilt?
With he who wields the sword
or who gives the command?
You know
who gave the command?
With your permission,
I d like to present
an eyewitness.
By all means,
Sir Arthur.
Major Lewis, Your Majesty.
Evidently, Major, you possess
secret information
about the Boxer leadership.
It s not much
of a secret.
Please go on, Major Lewis.
I saw the Boxer
commander this morning.
The one who had
the Minister killed.
You would know him?
It was Prince Tuan.
You believe this story?
I do, Your Majesty.
And you ask us to take
action against Prince Tuan?
I’ve come here
with the truth
now known by the German
government and the other Powers.
We reject your truth.
And your protest.
We are pleased
to inform you that Prince Tuan
is our closest adviser.
He now heads
the Foreign Office.
For our part, Great Britain
wants nothing more
than continued
friendship with China.
Because of the drought,
the hunger and the unrest
among my people,
of the merciless demands
of the foreign powers,
the situation in Peking cannot
be expected to become tranquil.
Therefore we
earnestly advise you
that all foreign residents,
including diplomatic personnel,
should leave Peking
within twenty-four hours.
Is Your Majesty informing me
that she is severing
all diplomatic relations?
Not at all.
Her Majesty
was clear enough.
She is offering informal
advice for your safety
and protection.
- I am in favour of that.
- Major.
She can't control the Boxers.
We d better get out.
Prince Tuan,
you will see
that these gentlemen
are escorted safely
to their Legations.
We d do better
on our own.
- Do we walk?
- Yes, very slowly.
Keep walking.
Squad!
Double time.
- Thought you d need some help.
- Thank you.
Count the votes.
We're awaiting
the American Minister.
Oh, Mr. Maxwell.
- Hello.
Sorry to have
got you up,
but we need your vote,
on staying in Peking or not.
The United States have no
territorial concessions in China.
Nor are we interested.
I d better abstain, Sir Arthur.
I understand, Mr. Maxwell.
I just wanted you to be here.
Congratulations, gentlemen.
It's unanimous.
Nine votes
in favour of evacuation.
Great Britain
has decided to stay.
Alone if necessary.
That s not possible.
We d look ridiculous
if we left
the British alone in Peking.
Perhaps Britain
has its reasons
for being the only
foreign power in Peking.
Our friend is right.
They may have
secret reports.
I’ve made it
completely clear.
Admiral Sydney
is on his way
with several thousand men.
He’ll be here
in 9 or 10 days.
Meanwhile, I refuse
to worry about
the Boxers giving
a victory to Prince Tuan.
Then the Germans stay too.
Sir Arthur,
we Spaniards
fulfill our obligations.
There s no word for
flight in our dictionary.
We feel obliged to protect
the civilians who depend on us.
I recognize
that obligation, Guzmán,
and I believe
that if we stand united
the Chinese
won't dare to attack
the representatives
of 11 great Powers.
If we stand firm,
there'll be peace in China
and in the whole world.
Spain is with you.
If the other Powers stay,
so will Austria.
Congratulations, Sir Arthur.
The British win
another bloodless victory.
I take it You’ve
unanimously decided to stay?
I shall report that
the first vote was9 to 1
and that in a friendly spirit
it was then decided
to make
the decision unanimous.
Well, then I suggest
we call in the military.
This way, gentlemen.
Colonel Shiba
will give the report.
As to the military aspects,
we have agreed that
with fewer than 400 men,
to defend
a 2-mile perimeter,
the position is untenable.
We recommend
immediate evacuation.
For political reasons the
Ministers say we must remain.
So you must defend
the area until Admiral Sydney s
forces arrive.
Sir, what if the relief
column doesn’t make it?
It s over 70 miles
through hostile territory.
We’ll consider
that situation when it arises.
We have 5 defense sectors.
The wall defended
by the Germans and Americans,
the west end,
the British Legation,
the Fu, held by
the Americans and Japanese,
and the east end, held
by the Italians and French.
- Boxers?
- Yes.
- Where the hell are they?
- All around us.
Their purpose is
to make us nervous.
Once the shooting starts You’ll
see them outside that wall.
Who's nervous?
No!
You cant have them!
But Sarah, we agreed.
We need the books
for barricades.
Not the Set of
the Napoleonic Wars.
Mother sent them
for your birthday.
I must confess
that French history bores me.
English history? Bah!
- Go away. The shop is closed.
- It s Baroness Ivanoff.
I thought all Peking's
doors were closed to me,
that I d lost face
in the Chinese streets.
Our Empress has
those same fears, Baroness.
The Boxers.
It is hoped
her wisdom will prevail.
I got your message, old one.
Your friend thinks
you should leave Peking.
- Which friend, old one?
- General Jung-Lu.
It was not possible before.
We would have been accused
of meddling in
Russian affairs.
And now?
Now...
it makes no difference.
The Boxers will attack.
If you disappear
in the confusion who d be left
to point a finger?
At 5 p. m. the fighting
will have begun.
You’ll meet a man at the corner
of the French Legation.
He’ll be wearing
a green peasant jacket.
You will be there?
- Go up on the ramp and take a look.
- Yes, sir.
- I don’t like this.
- Don’t worry.
Tell those men
to get their backs into it.
Whoa there.
- Where are you going?
- I’m getting out of Peking.
Those Boxers
out there are angry.
- Not with me.
- We have 200 rounds each.
- That s 20 per man per day.
- Enough for warming up.
They d better start out warm.
Yes, sir.
I’ll tell them.
Get out
before I get mad!
Mad Americans inside, mad Boxers
outside, mad Russians there...
I’ll risk going out.
I split the men in 2
platoons. 4 hours on, 4 hours off.
The sergeant will take
the first watch.
Right.
I wanted to go to Tientsin
but you prefer to stay.
I wear a uniform.
They pay me for that.
Go on then.
And get out of my way.
Have a nice war, soldier,
a real nice war.
Where do these go?
Where do you think?
Get up on that wall!
Fire!
Let s go!
Forward!
- Cease firing.
We did it!
We beat them!
What if they come back?
We’ve used
over half our ammunition.
Are you good
with a slingshot?
A friend of yours?
Soldier.
- Can you open the door?
- You cant go through, ma'am.
That was bad luck.
- I’ll be all right.
- I’ll be right back.
- What do you make of her?
- This is quite a weapon.
What would you call it?
Across between
an alligator and an ostrich.
We call her Betsy
after the Empress.
It s an old German barrel
with Russian shells
of approximately
the same caliber.
The carriage is Italian,
the wheels French,
and that boy's
fool enough to fire it.
Would it be safer
in front or in back?
The point is where is
Betsy going to be fired?
-Major...
- Please, gentlemen.
- Captain Marshall...
- What's up?
The Chinese
are on top of the wall.
- Now we know where Betsy goes.
- You! Over here!
Come on, bring it along.
Run!
Cone on, Andy, run!
Sergeant, get in.
Take cover.
Damn it!
What happened?
We tried but they re too many.
They keep coming.
Major.
- How many did we lose?
- Turner and Spencer.
5 wounded.
The Germans got it even worse.
Why don’t they
rush us right now?
We wouldn’t stand a chance.
Maybe they think
We’ve got millions of men.
Come morning
they'll think different.
They’ll roll down
those ramps like Niagara Falls.
We must get them
off this wall...
We can t.
Or They’ll shoot
into the Legation area.
Like fish in a barrel.
We might just as well
open the gates and let them in.
Take the French priest
to the Legation.
Right.
They wont start
up here till morning.
Just hope they don’t.
- No sign of activity?
- No, sir.
They're all asleep.
Well, we'd better not be.
- Better wake them all up.
- Yes, sir.
Wake up.
Good morning.
Here they come!
Keep rolling!
Andy, get down.
Major, what
are we doing here?
- Why didn’t we get out?
- I don’t know.
I really don’t know.
Handley told me
you re-took the wall.
I suppose you heard...
He died too.
The Minister
can tell us why.
And Marshall, too.
He has all the answers.
That s all, sergeant.
Get on back.
He s a good soldier.
When he knows
why he’s fighting.
When it s
something you can see...
a wall, a hill,
a river, it s easier.
But how can you explain
it s for a principle?
You cant.
Not here in China.
It s too far from home.
I know.
I wont stay.
No!
I won t stay!
Don’t let...
Don’t let them take my leg.
Tell them...
Tell them not to...
Please!
- Tell them!
- There, there.
I don’t want
to live like half a man.
He s only fainted.
You can go now.
Can you save his leg?
May I stay with him?
Your dress is
a breeding-ground for germs.
What re you waiting for?
Take it off
and put on a uniform.
Thank you, doctor.
Who'll tell her?
The captain s little girl.
It s pretty late now.
Tell her in the morning.
But she might hear
about it from somebody else.
I guess not.
- Let s get a drink first.
- No, later.
Coming?
- I’m going back to the wall.
- Wait.
All right.
Where'll I find her?
With the orphans in the Fu.
How do I tell her?
Like she was
your own, I guess.
Like someone
telling your own kid.
- Do you know which one she is?
- No.
So many new children
came in today.
Haven’t you met her?
Just once.
I cant remember
what she s like.
I didn’t pay much attention.
Major Lewis.
We re looking for
the Marshall girl.
Ah, of course.
Yes, Teresa... I heard.
I guess she must
be sleeping, eh?
Please tell her
in the morning.
It s important
you tell her, Major.
She knows you were
her father s friend.
I'll wake her.
Here she is.
A friend of your father's
to see you.
Teresa...
You...
- Do you remember me?
- Yes, Major.
I have something to tell you.
Why don’t the two of you
stay here and talk?
You know
there s been some fighting?
Well,
I have something to tell you.
Is it about my father?
Yes.
Is he... dead?
Did you know?
Well...
you knew
he was a soldier.
It could happen at any time.
You’ll be taken care of.
You won't have to worry.
Well,
You’ll be
all right now, huh?
Wont I be going home then?
Home?
To America.
He said he d take me home.
He did?
When?
Every time.
And just today again.
Well...
I don't think
you d like it.
Everything's
very strange.
Things are all different.
The people,
and the food,
the houses, the schools.
If you want, we can talk
some more in a few days,
when things quiet down.
I promise.
All right.
Bye.
Think she understood?
When a mother dies,
a child feels deserted.
When a father goes away,
a child feels abandoned.
She s had more than her fair
share. She understands too well.
What else
could I have told her?
A child understands
only one language...
love.
Well, she isn’t mine.
They say that
every man is the father
of every child.
I suppose
it's only true
if you really feel it.
The British Admiral
and his forces
are trapped between
Langfang and Anping.
The Boxers do not climb
a tree to look for a fish.
They have done
their work well.
The railway is destroyed.
He can neither
proceed nor retreat.
You see, the Boxers are not
as useless as you believed.
It does not
require courage or skill
to rip up
a few rails.
The Boxers
flee the foreigners.
If Sydney cannot
use the railway,
he will now
march on Peking.
I expect him
within the week.
It is true.
The Boxers cannot
stop such a force.
Only General Jung-Lu's
Imperial troops can do that.
They have no part
in this uprising.
The troops will do
as Her Majesty commands.
Who can make
muddy water clear?
Your Majesty,
first they said the Boxers
would destroy
the foreigners in two days.
Next that no foreign army
would even approach the city.
If we commit the
Imperial Army against Sydney,
we shall be declaring
waron all the Powers.
Our armies,
for all their courage,
could not
win such a war.
The Boxers
have created an opportunity
for a great
Chinese victory.
If our troops
destroy their forces,
it will prove that China
is no longer helpless,
and be
the beginning of freedom.
Each speaks with
the voice of a patriot.
Prince Tuan counsels
a reckless adventure,
General Jung-Lu counsels
prudence and patience.
Prudence and patience for what?
China's condition
can be no worse.
Even if we start
a war and lose it,
what more can
the powers take?
General Jung-Lu,
you will command our troops
and turn back
the foreign armies.
Stop it, Tommy.
- You’ll wake the baby.
- You can t talk. You re dead.
Don’t play
at that end.
Oh, Tommy!
Tommy!
Mummy! Mummy!
He’ll die
without going home.
Funny how he used
to talk about home,
as if he remembered
how it was.
As if he’d
actually been there.
Arthur.
He used to ask me about it.
He mustn't die. Poor Tommy.
Yes, and poor us too.
Arthur.
I’ve the strangest feeling.
What is it?
Do you think if a child dies
without going home,
that his soul
doesn’t rest?
I think
it goes into limbo.
An enormous,
empty Chinese limbo,
wandering there,
lost and crying.
- He’s fine.
- Why doesn’t he wake up?
The doctor says
he s in a coma.
It may last several days.
He may not
come round at all...
He may never
come round.
Why? Why?
How did he sin?
Against whom?
What s he doing
in this foreign place?
Whose ambition
is he serving?
Must a child die
to serve the ends of ambition?
Who d gain
from his death?
Who'd be
the happier for it?
How many children must die,
how many people suffer,
before there is an end?
A child s life
is too high a price to pay.
I cant stand it!
- Sarah, try to understand
- Understand what? Tell me!
- Tell me!
- I feel the pain too.
Have you ever
been to England?
Yes.
Manchester?
No.
Is it a beautiful city?
I wouldn’t
call it beautiful.
But,
you know how it is,
coming from a far place.
Go to sleep now.
Dream of Manchester.
It would be like a visit home.
Litnoff is
the Tsarina s second cousin.
You cannot treat him
like a common soldier.
The bullet
wasn’t afraid
of wounding a Count.
Germs wont care
if he s her first cousin.
He’ll be treated
like any other man here.
Good day, Baron.
I understand
you are here
early and late.
A true angel of mercy.
- The men won t be...
- Quiet!
...nursed by anyone else.
I've always
had a way with men.
Even with
the German doctor.
He can t do without me.
And the Major?
The American?
What do you want?
I d like to be present
when he finds out
what you are.
You’ll be present.
You’ll tell him. You're
just waiting for the moment.
Where is it?
Right here.
Open the door.
Hello, Sir Arthur.
A message from Admiral Sydney.
Welcome, Reverend Michaelson.
Heavens.
Where is it?
I hope I haven t lost it.
- Where did you see the admiral?
- Here it is.
We’ll have to decode it.
Come with me.
With a column
of 2,200 men
we came
by rail to Anping,
where we were driven back
by a large contingent
of Chinese Imperial forces.
Our troops were decimated
and we lost a huge amount
of equipment.
'It is impossible
to march on Peking,
so we must
fall back to Tientsin,'
along the River Peigei.
- 'Signed, Harold Sydney'.
- Is there nothing more?
- What shall we do now?
- What shall we do?
You've eaten nothing.
- Have something now.
- Thank you, Sarah.
Need more light?
No, thank you.
You asked me
why we were here.
Why we hadn’t left.
I’m sorry.
I shouldn’t have.
Sometimes it s
good to wonder why.
These last few hours
it s all I’ve done.
What about?
First,
Who am I?'
Second,
What have I achieved
in 20 years of diplomacy?'
Third,
Am I a good diplomat,
or a failure,
only fit for
a minor post in Peking?
Fourth,
Have I honestly tried
to avoid war with China,'
or have I only tried
to make a name for myself?
Fifth,
Am I a fool
in search of adventure,
or a sensible man'
who s taken a risk?
What kind
of father am I
to put my family s
lives in danger?
Am I acting like
some god playing
with the fate or others?
I've been with you
since you started your career.
I know what
You’ve been through
and I know you well.
Only an honourable man
says such things.
- Excellency.
- I was just leaving, Major.
We were talking
about the good times.
Don’t go.
My brother-in-law is eager
to tell you something.
This is a family matter.
Don’t discuss it
- before strangers.
- Don’t play games.
Get it over with now.
We were talking about
my dead brother, her husband.
I'm not interested.
How do you suppose he was?
Like me?
Fat, past middle age?
Something like that.
The youngest Colonel
in our army.
With a brilliant future.
The Tsar himself
had taken notice...
Do you know
why he died?
No.
Go on.
I cant...
It suddenly seems...
He was drunk
and had an accident.
Let s forget it.
They said
it was my fault.
His family tried
to take away all I had.
Don’t you believe me?
I guess a man
gets what he deserves.
What can I offer?
A soldier s pay?
Yes.
A soldier's pay
buys a soldiers woman.
An urgent message
from Her Imperial Highness.
'Therefore,
in view of the aggression
of the armed forces'
of Great Britain,
Germany, Russia, France,
the United States,
Japan, Italy and Austria
' under the command
of Admiral Sydney,
the Imperial
Chinese Government demands
the immediate
and unconditional surrender
of the armed forces
of these nations
' and of all their weapons.
We will
await your reply.
I believe, Sir Arthur,
that you are
the architect of our dilemma.
What do you propose?
I think you should all
know the military facts.
We have had
almost 100 casualties,
that is about 25%
of our forces.
Over half
our ammunition is gone,
food is low, medical
supplies are non-existent,
and by a reasonable estimate
it will take 4 or 5 weeks
to assemble forces on the coast
to fight through to Peking.
What is your answer?
We are all aware
of our own weakness.
I’ve been thinking
about the Chinese.
Prince Tuan persuaded
the Empress to commit her troops
in the hope
of an easy victory.
And he allowed Michaelson
through with Sydney's letter
hoping we d collapse.
The ultimatum
means he s promised
our immediate surrender.
Now,
if instead of collapsing
we show unexpected strength,
and not only hold out
but attack,
we may destroy
Tuan s influence
with the Empress
and force her to face reality.
This is a man of faith.
He thinks if we blow
our trumpets, the walls
of Peking will collapse.
How many trumpets do we have,
Major?
I don’t know, Baron.
But Sir Arthur has
a good idea about the Empress...
About the Empress, understand
there must be
no attempt on her life.
I wouldn’t even
know where to start.
I don’t want her killed.
You don't want!
It would mean chaos.
Wed be fighting here
for the next 20 years.
Do you have a better idea?
I give you my word,
it would only enlarge the war.
You re the diplomat.
But let us
fight the battles.
Come on, Colonel.
- What do you think?
- Well...
I’m thinking that
if you re thinking
what I think you re thinking,
then...
I’m afraid
I must agree
with Sir Arthur.
They re using
the big guns.
The Empress
has committed her troops.
Get everybody
into the compound.
Here, take her.
Arthur,
Tommy s all right!
He just woke up
and spoke to me.
He s going to live!
- He s going to live!
- Live?
You wanted to avoid
a war and We’ve got one.
You wanted
to wait for Sydney.
Sydney isn’t coming.
You say we should attack.
Attack whom?
The Imperial Army?
And with what?
With 115 rusty guns?
I’ve heard
Tuan is preparing
a victory celebration tonight
in the Imperial Courtyard.
I suppose
we're all invited?
Rather than surrender, we must
make Tuan lose face.
We could
blow up the palace.
The Chinese have an arsenal
near the Imperial City.
- We could...
- I’ve heard of it.
- Blow it up during their party.
- It's behind their lines.
Then We’ll go
under their lines.
- How?
- Look at your map.
We could get to it
via the sewer
and blow it up when
Tuan s telling the Empress
we've been defeated.
- It's through here.
- Getting back is another matter.
We...
You don’t need genius
to crawl up a sewer.
We can t get away.
We’ll be blown sky high.
I’ve got to cut it.
It s too short.
If we light it
we won t get clear.
Get those
two ends joined.
I suppose you
have come to report
the destruction
of the Legations,
for the tenth time
since the last moon.
I have come to ask
Your Majesty s permission
to impeach
General Jung-Lu
as a friend
to the barbarians.
It s true he turned back
the foreign admiral,
but he has guns the Boxers
need yet refuses to lend them,
despite your commands.
Be silent.
General Jung-Lu.
Despite the empty
promises of the Boxers,
the foreign devils
grow stronger.
Even the Forbidden City
is no longer safe.
Underestimating the enemy
is a great calamity.
You will speak
to the foreigners, Jung-Lu.
Tell them peace
is a great blessing
and that no calamity is greater
than lightly engaging in war.
- Have they called off the war?
- Throw a line.
Here, what have we got?
A message for each
of the Ministers from Jung-Lu.
They want a truce.
We spoiled
the Empress s party.
She s just as likely
to decide to finish us off.
What does it say?
'We are disturbed by the
arrival of troops at Tientsin'.
Tientsin?
Unless they are withdrawn,
I must consider it
an act of war and will
commit the Imperial Forces. '
Allied troops in Tientsin.
- But they must think we re dead.
- Only 70 miles away.
Yes.
If we could
get word to them...
You mean if I
could get word to them.
Oh, no.
Old soldiers never volunteer.
Natalie.
I’m going away.
- When?
- Right now.
I’m waiting,
Baroness.
- Where are you going?
- To get help.
The patient is waiting!
This is not
a reception hall.
Will you come back?
Sure, if I can.
Natasha!
Listen...
What does he want?
Do you think
people can change?
That s something I can t
study under a microscope.
- You look wonderful. You shaved.
- You noticed.
Get me some
adhesive please.
I’m going now.
You said that.
Yes, I know but...
So long.
Wait a minute.
We never did
get a chance to talk?
Look, I have
to go somewhere but...
I’m coming back.
Like my father.
We'll talk then.
All right?
Come on.
Where s that other
bottle of ether?
- You say that every day.
- There was one.
We used it over a week ago.
- And the morphine?
- It s all gone. You know it.
Well,
We’ll have to operate
on the Italian regardless.
He may faint
and feel nothing.
lodine.
Here.
This is empty!
I’m sorry.
Don’t stand there.
Get me another bottle.
This was the last bottle.
No alcohol,
no iodine, amateur nurses...
We re back
in the Dark Ages.
No ether
for anesthetics,
no morphine for pain.
We are in
the land of opium
and there are no opiates.
Look out!
Rogers, are you all right?
Major, I’m hurt.
I'm hurt bad.
I’ll get you back.
Death s about and yet
your door is open.
Open or closed it cannot
protect either of us.
Old man...
Life and death,
are they important?
Not to the gods.
There are many men dying.
In pain.
They need drugs.
I do not deal in opiates.
There are others who do.
The Chinese outside
can only help you now.
Even in war, old man,
a valuable gift
can work miracles.
I want the drugs today.
And a wagon full
of fruit for the children.
Come on, Charlie. Rest here.
Let s see
what s in here.
All right, open it up!
How did you do it?
To your positions.
The truce is over!
It s all right.
We made it.
Get him to hospital.
I didn’t make it.
Major, I heard
you were back.
Off you go.
Major,
wake up! Wake up!
The railroad...
tracks are much closer.
Yes.
- How close are they?
- Almost to the wall.
All right.
Get me a shirt.
- Did you hear about the Baroness?
- No.
She was shot.
- What?
- She s in the hospital.
Major, we d better hurry.
Yes... Yes.
Don’t...
Don’t take it
so hard, doctor.
You must
let me try again.
Soon it will be too late.
You’ve done
all you can do.
I must find
the focus of the infection.
You wont find it
with a knife, doctor.
Don’t you want to live?
I...
I have lived.
Don’t think of anything
except living.
Give yourself
a chance.
A chance?
A chance for what?
A chance to do
it all over again?
No, thank you, doctor.
If you die the light
will be gone from this place.
No.
You're...
the one who makes
all the light here.
Forgive me
when I say that
working with you
I’ve learned
to care for You very much.
I’m glad
you said that, Hans.
A woman likes to hear it.
Most men haven’t
the courage to say it.
They re closer
now than when I left.
If it was for a gun,
they wouldn’t come so close.
Yes.
Get Father de Bearn.
Yes, sir.
What is it, Major?
Ever seen
anything like that?
I certainly have not.
You can t stop
that with rifles.
But we have to stop it.
Get me those urns
from the tower,
coal oil and
some black powder
and empty
champagne bottles too.
Right now, put it
down here, not there.
Pick up those bags.
Where are those bottles
and the powder? Come on, hurry!
That s it.
With a little prayer
and a lot of luck...
- Bad luck.
- You weren’t praying hard enough.
Give me that.
- Here you are.
- Thank you.
- Come on.
- We'll pray harder, Father.
Yes.
It must be terrible
to be a soldier.
Yes...
Sometimes it is.
I was looking for you.
The Baroness is dead.
Nothing to say?
She didn’t mean
much to you.
Shut up!
- Sorry.
- Let me alone! Let me alone!
I just heard.
I’m sorry.
Thank you.
Well, we bought
ourselves another day.
Still, it wasn’t
a bad fight.
What time is it?
5.37 a. m.
August 14th, 1900.
How many days
did we hold out?
Fifty-five.
Those guns!
They re not Chinese!
Strange!
They re ours!
It s the relief forces!
They re here!
They re ours!
Water can support a ship.
And water can upset it.
The dynasty is finished.
Listen.
They re playing
different tunes.
Well, for 55 days
we played the same tune.
Fifty-five days you
held us together.
You might
have started something
that people
will remember some day.
- We re ready.
- I’ll be right there.
Will you stay in China?
Oh, I go where
they send me.
How about you?
I’ll be going
home to England.
Retired to private life,
I suppose.
In the country with
a dog and a few books.
An Englishman s dream, really.
What s home for you?
I don’t know.
I may have
to make one.
Good luck, Matt.
Thanks.
Right shoulder... arms!
Here, take my hand.
Forward ho!