Winter Wonderland
冬季仙境
Mairead - Violinist
Sleigh bells ring, are you listening
Meav - Vocalist
In the lane, snow is glistening
Lisa - Vocalist
A beautiful sight, we're happy tonight
Susan - Vocalist
Walking in a winter wonderland
Celtic Woman
Gone away is the bluebird
Here to stay is a new bird
He sings a love song, as we go along
Walking in a winter wonderland
In the meadow we can build a snowman
And pretend that he is Parson Brown
He'll say: Are you married? We'll say: No man,
But you can do the job when you're in town
Later on, we'll conspire as we dream by the fire
To face unafraid the plans that we've made
Walking in a winter wonderland
In the meadow we can build a snowman
And pretend that he's a circus clown
We'll have lots of fun with mister snowman,
Until the other kids knock him down
Sleigh bells ring, are you listening
In the lane, snow is glistening
A beautiful sight, we're happy tonight
Walking in a winter wonderland
What Child Is This
孰为此儿
What child is this,
who laid to rest on Mary’s lap is sleeping
Whom angels greet with anthems sweet
While shepherds watch are keeping
Raise, raise the song on high
His mother sings her lullaby
Joy, joy for Christ is born
The Babe, the Son of Mary
This, this is Christ the King
Whom shepherds guard and angels sing
Haste, haste to bring Him praise
The babe, the son of Mary
So bring Him incense, gold, and myrrh
Come, peasant, king, to own Him!
The King of Kings salvation brings
Let loving hearts enthrone Him!
This, this is Christ the King
Whom shepherds guard and angels sing
Haste, haste to bring Him praise
The babe, the son of Mary
This, this is Christ the King
Whom shepherds guard and angels sing
Haste, haste to bring Him praise
The babe, the son of Mary
This, this is Christ the King
Whom shepherds guard and angels sing
Haste, haste to bring Him praise
The babe, the son of Mary
Thank you so much, thank you
I can't tell you how obviously delighted
we are to be back here in the Helix
This is where all started for Celtic Woman
So it's like our spiritual home
Delighted you could be here with us
So many of you that travelled,
and for the home crowd as well
Very nice to see you here tonight
And we are having a ball
so please feel free to join in
You definitely know the next song,
even my four year old daughter knows it
and she's been singing it in the car
with me when I have been practising
And it is
"We wish you a merry Christmas"
We Wish You a Merry Christmas
祝你圣诞快乐
Good tidings we bring
to you and your kin
Good tidings for Christmas
and a Happy New Year
We wish you a Merry Christmas
Oh so bring us a pudding
bring us a pudding
and a cup of good cheer
We won't go until we get some
won't go until we get some
so bring some out here
We wish you a Merry Christmas
and a Happy New Year
Merry Christmas
Good tidings we bring
to you and your kin
Good tidings for Christmas
and a Happy New Year
We wish you a Merry Christmas
Good tidings we bring
to you and your kin
We wish you a Merry Christmas
and a Happy New Year
I'll Be Home For Christmas
圣诞回乡
I am dreaming tonight
of a place I love
Even more than I usually do
And although I know
it's a long road back
I promise you
I'll be home for Christmas
You can count on me
Please have snow and mistletoe
And presents by the tree
Christmas Eve will find me
Where the love light gleams
I'll be home for Christmas
If only in my dreams
You can count on me
Please have snow and mistletoe
and presents by the tree
Christmas Eve will find me
Where the love light gleams
I'll be home for Christmas
If only in my dreams,
if only in my dreams
Hark The Herald Angel Sing
听啊! 天使高声唱
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the newborn King!"
Peace on earth and mercy mild
God and sinners reconciled
Joyful, all ye nations rise
Join the triumph of the skies
With the angelic host proclaim:
"Christ is born in Bethlehem"
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the newborn King!"
Christ by highest heaven adored
Christ the everlasting Lord!
Late in time behold Him come
Offspring of a Virgin's womb
Veiled in flesh the Godhead see
Hail the incarnate Deity
Pleased as man with man to dwell
Jesus, our Emmanuel
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the newborn King!"
Hail the heaven-born Prince of Peace!
Hail the Son of Righteousness!
Light and life to all He brings
Risen with healing in His wings
Mild He lays His glory by
Born that man no more may die
Born to raise the sons of earth
Born to give them second birth
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the newborn King!"
Joyful, all ye nations rise
Join the triumph of the skies
With the angelic host proclaim:
"Christ is born in Bethlehem"
Hark! The herald angels sing
"Glory to the newborn King!"
Santa Claus Is Comin' To Town
圣诞老人要来了
You better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout
I'm telling you why
Santa Claus is coming
Santa Claus is coming to town
You better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout,
I'm telling you why
Santa Claus is coming to town
He sees you when you're sleeping
He knows when you're awake
He knows if you've been bad or good
So be good for goodness sake!
You better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout,
I'm telling you why
Santa Claus is coming
Santa Claus is coming to town
Little toy dolls that cuddle and coo
Elephants, boats and Kiddie cars too
Santa Claus is coming to town
He sees you when you're sleeping
He knows when you're awake
He knows if you've been bad or good
So be good for goodness sake!
You better watch out
You better not cry
You better not pout,
I'm telling you why
Santa Claus is coming
Santa Claus is coming to town
He's making a list
and checking it twice
He's gonna find out who's naughty or nice
Santa Claus is coming
Santa Claus is coming to town
You better not pout,
I'm telling you why
Santa Claus is coming
Santa Claus is coming to town
to town
We Three Kings
东方三王歌
We three kings of Orient are
Bearing gifts we traverse afar
Field and fountain, moor and mountain
following yonder star
Born a king on Bethlehem's plain
Gold I bring to crown Him again
King forever, ceasing never
Over us all to reign
O star of wonder, star of night
Star with royal beauty bright
Westward leading, still proceeding
Guide us to thy perfect Light
Star of wonder, star of night
Star with royal beauty bright
Westward leading, still proceeding
Guide us to thy perfect Light
Glorious now behold Him arise
King and God and Sacrifice
Alleluia, alleluia!
Earth to heaven replies
Star of wonder, star of night
Star with royal beauty bright
Westward leading, still proceeding
Guide us to thy perfect Light
Carol of the Bells [Violin]
圣诞钟声 [小提琴]
O Tannenbaum
圣诞树
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
Du grnst nicht nur zur Sommerzeit
You're green not only in the summertime
Nein, auch im Winter, wenn es schneit
No, also in winter when it snows
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
*Italian :((( *
O Christmas Tree, O Christmas Tree
How lovely are your branches
They are green when summer days are bright
They are green when winter snow is white
O Christmas Tree, O Christmas Tree
How lovely are your branches
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
Du grnst nicht nur zur Sommerzeit
You're green not only in the summertime
Nein, auch im Winter, wenn es schneit
No, also in winter when it snows
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
O Tannenbaum, o Tannenbaum
O Christmas tree, o Christmas tree
Wie treu sind deine Blatter
How loyal are your leaves
Silent Night
平安夜
Silent night, Holy night
All is calm, all is bright
Round yon virgin , mother and child
Holy infant so tender and mild
Sleep in heavenly peace
Silent night, Holy night
Shepherds quake at the sight
Glories stream from heaven afar
Heavenly hosts sing Alleluia!
Christ, the Saviour is born
Silent night, Holy night
Son of God, love's pure light
Radiant beams from Thy holy face
With the dawn of redeeming grace
Jesus, Lord, at Thy birth
It's Beginning To Look A Lot Like Christmas
圣诞将至
It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas
Everywhere you go
Take a look in the Five and Ten
Glistening once again
With candy canes and silver lanes aglow
It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas
Toys in every store
But the prettiest sight to see
Is the holly that will be on your own front door
A pair of hopalong boots and a pistol that shoots
Is the wish of Barney and Ben
Dolls that will talk and will go for a walk
Is the hope of Janice and Jen
And Mom and Dad can hardly wait
for school to start again
It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas
Soon the bells will start
And the thing that will make them ring
Is the Carol that you sing right within your heart
It's beginning to look a lot like Christmas
Everywhere you go
But the prettiest sight to see
Is the holly that will be
on your own front door
So it's Christmas once more
The Light of Christmas Morn
圣诞节之光
The winds of chill December sound
The farewell of the year
And evening shadows gather round
And cloud the soul with fear
But rest you well good Christian men
Nor be of heart forlorn
December's darkness brings again
The light of Christmas morn
The welcome snow each Christmastide
Falls shining from the skies
On village paths and uplands wide
All holy white, it lies
It crowns with pearl, the oaks and pines
And glitters on the thorn
But purer still the light that shines
On gladsome Christmas morn
The shepherds poor, how blest were they
The angel song to hear
In manger cradle, as he lay
To greet the Saviour dear
The Lord of heaven's eternal height
For us a babe was born
And He, the very light of light
Shone forth that Christmas morn
The chapel lights above the snow
Do warm the coldest chill
And manger scene, by candle glow
Inclines us to goodwill
Ablaze in wonder and in awe
As every heart adores
But brighter still, the light that falls
On gladsome Christmas morn
December's darkness brings again
The light of Christmas morn
It Came Upon A Midnight Clear
星夜颂赞
It came upon a midnight clear
That glorious song of old
From angels bending near the earth
To touch their harps of gold
Still through the cloven skies they come
With peaceful wings unfurled
And still the heavenly music floats
O'er all the weary world
Peace on the earth
Good will to men
From heaven's all gracious King
The world in solemn stillness lay
To hear the angels sing
It came upon a midnight clear
That glorious song of old
From angels bending near the earth
To touch their harps of gold
[hear the angels sing]
It came that glorious song of old
From angels bending near the earth
To touch their harps of gold
Peace on the earth
Good will to men
From heaven's all gracious King
The world in solemn stillness lay
To hear the angels sing
Peace on the earth
Good will to men
Ladies and gentlemen, the Discovery Gospel Choir!
Good evening everybody
Are you having fun?
Good
We are obviously thrilled that
you are all here with us to celebrate Christmas scent
What a night spin and thank you all
so much for such a beautiful warm welcome
And it is so lovely to see so many beautiful kids
eagerly awaiting Santa Claus here with us tonight
Thank you all for being here with us it's fantastic
I want to take you all across the sea to Scottland
This is one of the very oldest traditional songs
That's sung around this time of the year
And this song, it's by saying
Farewell to one year
And welcoming in the new
This is,
Auld Lang Syne
友谊地久天长
Should auld acquaintance be forgot
and never brought to mind?
for auld lang syne?
For auld lang syne, my jo
For auld lang syne
We'll take a cup of kindness yet
for auld lang syne
We two have run about the braes
and pu'd the gowans fine
And we've wandered many a weary stop
since auld lang syne
For auld lang syne, my jo
For auld lang syne
We'll take a cup of kindness yet
for auld lang syne
We two have paddled in the burn
from morning sun till dine
But seas between us broad have roared
since auld lang syne
For auld lang syne, my jo
For auld lang syne
We'll take a cup of kindness yet
for auld lang syne
Ladies and gentlemen, thank you so much
You have been such a fantastic audience
Good night, and merry Christmas!
Joy To The World
普世欢腾
Joy to the world! The Lord is come
Let earth receive her King!
Let every heart prepare Him room
And heaven and nature sing
And heaven, and heaven and nature sing!
Joy to the world! the Savior reigns
Let men their songs employ
While fields and floods,
rocks, hills and plains
Repeat the sounding joy,
repeat the sounding joy
Repeat, repeat the sounding joy!
He rules the world,
with truth and grace
And makes the nations prove
The glories of His righteousness
And wonders of His love
And wonders and wonders of His love
Joy to the world! The Lord is come
Let earth receive her King!
Let every heart prepare Him room
And heaven and nature sing
And heaven, and heaven and nature sing!
Joy to the world! The Lord is come
Let earth receive her King!
Let every heart prepare Him room
And heaven and nature sing
And heaven, and heaven and nature sing!