Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
-Morning.
-Good morning.
MARQUEZ TAlLORlNG
Wait!
Thank you.
-Evening.
-Good evening.
Do you need help?
Thank you.
My name is Alexandra.
Carlos. l live downstairs.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
What's your problem?
Goodbye.
Good evening.
-Hello.
-Good morning.
-This place is very pretty.
-Thank you.
There are hardly any tailors left
in my country.
What is this?
Wool.
lt feels different.
lt's pure wool.
But if you're used to pret-a-porter,
you don't recognize it.
What's pret-a-porter?
Suits made in a factory.
You say it like that's a bad thing.
lt isn't?
They're cheaper, right?
And don't last as long.
A handmade suit
lasts a lifetime.
What's this called?
A pincushion.
Listen.
l brought some advertising,
for your customers.
lt's for massages.
lf you want to help me...
Shiatsu?
Thai?
They cost 60 euros.
But since the best advertising
is word of mouth,
you're invited to try one anytime.
Massages aren't my thing.
Lots of people say that,
but they love them after.
Excuse me.
Hello?
Well?
Will you help me?
Leave me a couple,
l'll see what l can do.
The truth is,
l don't know anyone here
and l need to make some money.
Of course.
l was serious
about that invitation.
Since we're neighbors,
whenever you like.
l'll think about it.
-Goodbye.
Good morning.
-Good morning, don Gabriel.
-Were you leaving?
l was going to run an errand,
but come in.
How are you?
Please, after you.
-How's the family?
-Fine, thank you.
May l take your coat?
ALEXANDRA'S MASSAGES
What's this?
A neighbor of mine.
She just left it.
Are you going to try it?
Not the sort of thing
you try with a neighbor.
You're right.
By the way, thanks for recommending
me to the brotherhood.
There's no need to thank me.
You're the best.
You can go in.
Yes?
How are you?
Same as always.
-Have you got everything?
-l think so.
Who is it?
lt's me.
l need your help.
Please...
l just had a fight in my apartment
and l want to call the police.
l need a witness.
You only have to say what you saw.
-l didn't see anything.
-You didn't hear anything either?
What was l supposed to hear?
Please, help me.
l'm sorry,
l don't want any trouble.
lt'll only take a minute.
We'll call the police and...
Where's your phone?
You didn't hear me?
l'm sorry.
l need to drink something.
Can you give me a glass of water?
A glass of water and you leave.
Make it cold, please.
Or if you had a beer...
Close the fridge.
You only have meat.
Why do you only have meat?
Close the fridge.
Thanks.
You drank it, now please go.
You think l haven't realized?
You're one of those guys
who only likes to watch.
Leave.
l don't want any trouble.
Everybody wants trouble.
But fine. lf you can't help me,
l'll go.
Wait!
l can go with you
to the police station.
lt's better to go in person
than to call.
What took you so long?
l was freezing.
That's the one.
Can you do it?
l think so.
You can come as often as you like,
measure it, take photos...
But it can't leave here.
Don Gabriel told me.
lt's a piece of great value.
Obviously it could get ruined
if we take it outside.
Seventy-four.
Eighty.
Why do they want you to do it?
Because l know how.
lt isn't right.
-Why?
-Because it's sacred.
lt's only a cloak, Aurora.
Your father wouldn't have done it.
Trust me. Tell them to find
another tailor.
My father would have been proud.
You're wrong.
Twenty-two.
You might be right after all.
l'll have to find another job.
And a nice woman.
So l won't have to come
and play bingo with you.
You'll never find a woman.
Seventy-eight.
What do you know?
Forty.
Hello, good morning.
Good morning.
l'm sorry to bother you with this,
but l haven't heard from my sister
since yesterday.
She's your upstairs neighbor.
Her name is Alexandra and...
l was wondering if you've seen her
or spoken with her.
-Me?
-Yes.
Why me?
We had an argument two nights ago.
We had a fight in her apartment,
you may have heard us.
Alexandra walked out
and l haven't heard from her since.
What's that got to do with me?
Nothing. lt's just...
l'm asking all the neighbors
in case anyone saw her.
l don't know anything, l'm sorry.
l'm sure she'll turn up.
She's probably with a friend.
No, Alexandra doesn't know
anyone here.
-Sorry l can't help.
-Thank you.
Sorry to bother you.
Excuse me, one second.
Can you come here?
-Yes?
-Come in.
l have a friend who works
at the police station.
Afriend?
lf your sister doesn't turn up,
l can talk to him.
-Could you call him?
-Of course.
Now?
Hi, Antonio. lt's me, Carlos,
from the tailor's.
l'm here with a friend
whose sister is missing.
Please call us back
when you hear this message
and tell us if you can help us
or what we should do.
Thanks.
-He must be on duty.
-Thank you.
-l don't want to put you out.
-You're not.
-Would you like a cup of tea?
-No, l'd better go.
lt'll do you good.
lt was ready when you knocked,
l was making breakfast.
How would you like it,
with sugar, saccharine?
With nothing.
Thank you.
Where are you from?
Romania.
lt's a pretty language.
Sometimes l heard
your sister talking...
but she often sounded angry
on the phone.
l think she was probably
talking to me.
Alexandra's kind of special.
She has a different lifestyle.
-Where did you learn Spanish?
-ln Zaragoza.
We got a job in a spa there.
You lived there?
How long have you been in Spain?
About a year and a half.
Are you sure she has no friends
in Granada?
l don't know.
As soon as he calls me back,
l'll let you know.
Thanks.
Don't mention it.
-Good evening.
-Evening.
-Afternoon, Dori.
-Hi, Carlos.
-Hi.
All set.
-How much?
-80 euros.
-Here.
-Thanks.
-Good afternoon. Goodbye.
-Goodbye.
l thought something might have
happened to her.
Want me to go with you?
Please.
-lf you need anything else...
-Thanks.
-Good morning.
-Hi.
Did you talk to your friend?
He's out of town,
l talked to his wife.
-He won't be back for 3 weeks.
-Oh.
But he'll call me
when he gets back.
l can't wait that long.
l'm sorry.
Would you like to come in?
-l don't want to bother you again.
-lt's no bother, really.
l was making breakfast.
Have you eaten?
You're not hungry?
Can l ask you something?
You said you and your sister
argued the other day.
Why?
When...
Alexandra left Zaragoza,
she took some money
that wasn't hers.
We had saved it
so that our parents
could buy an apartment...
And we were supposed to send them
3 thousand euros.
But...
Alex argued with them,
saying it was her money,
that she had earned it and...
she took the money and left.
l saw a man ring her doorbell
the other day.
What did he look like?
Strong, a little taller than me...
and young, but some gray hair.
That's Bogdan.
What?
That's his name.
His name is Bogdan.
He's her friend, boyfriend?
Boyfriend.
She might be with him,
if she doesn't want to see you.
How do you know
she doesn't want to see me?
Because of the money.
Maybe she's avoiding you,
waiting for you to leave.
Yeah...
-lt's possible.
-Why don't you go back to Zaragoza?
l have your number,
l'll call you when she turns up.
Because l can't.
l need to find her and...
l need the money.
l'll have to go to the police.
What will you tell them?
The truth, that...
she left the apartment
and disappeared.
Want me to go with you?
l don't have much work
at the tailor's this morning.
-You would do that for me?
-Of course.
Thank you.
l shouldn't have come.
What did they say?
That since we argued
and she left by her own choice,
they're going to wait a few days
before doing anything.
What'll happen if your parents
don't get the money?
They'll lose the apartment.
l'll give it to you.
What?
The 3 thousand euros.
l can give it to you. l'm serious.
l have no idea when
l'll be able to pay you back.
You don't have to.
You're just going to give me
3 thousand euros?
To help your parents,
so you can go back to Zaragoza.
You would really do that?
Tomorrow.
Tell me the truth.
-What do you want?
-Nothing.
Everybody wants something.
To help you.
What do you gain by helping me?
Why do l have to gain something?
Otherwise you wouldn't do it.
You think that's how people work?
That's how the world works.
Not me.
Please, let me talk.
The next customer l see come in here
l'll call the police, period.
-What's the problem?
-Hi, Carlos.
Nothing, l was explaining
to the young lady that she should do
her thing somewhere else, not here.
You're making a mistake.
Excuse me?
You've got the wrong person.
That's her sister, she's visiting.
l was only saying
that we won't stand for...
You already said that.
l'm sorry.
lt's not your fault.
-Would you like to come in?
-No, thanks. l'm in a hurry.
l brought you the money.
Carlos...
l don't want you to feel obligated.
l don't feel obligated.
-Goodbye.
-Bye.
This thread doesn't exist anymore.
We can fold it.
We'll see if we can find needles.
Hi.
My parents got the money.
And... l want to invite you
to dinner to thank you.
lt's my sister's.
Thank you, but l don't think
that's necessary.
Why?
Because you don't owe me
anything.
What if l want to thank you?
l'd rather not, thank you.
Why are you saying this?
You do me a huge favor and
won't even let me buy you dinner?
l don't feel like going
to a restaurant, that's all.
Then we can do something else.
Please, don't insist.
Why did you give me the money,
Carlos?
l already told you,
to help you.
So you can go back to Zaragoza.
Alexandra is behind all this,
isn't she?
She wants to get rid of me
and she's using you.
Do you know where she is?
Have you spoken to her?
Nina, that's nonsense.
There's something
l don't understand.
What's that?
My sister is capable
of just about anything, but...
l don't know,
this time it's different.
l can feel it here.
l bet she's with her boyfriend
waiting for you to leave,
laughing at all this.
You could be right.
But l don't want to keep
talking about her.
Have you got any brothers
or sisters?
No.
And your parents?
They died.
And you have no other family?
No.
And a girlfriend?
A girlfriend?
Yeah.
Never had one.
Never?
l've seen women,
but never a real girlfriend.
Why not?
l like living alone.
You like being alone.
l'm used to it.
How does somebody
get used to being alone?
l read a lot,
l listen to the radio...
l really like my job.
But... what about at night?
When you get in bed...
you don't think about what it would
be like to have someone with you?
Nina, not wanting to learn to be alone
is pure fear.
That's not true.
Carlos... do you like girls?
l like girls.
Nina, l'm not trying to sleep
with you. lf you think that's why...
No, l don't think that.
Everything you're doing for me
is very important.
And l don't want you
to get the wrong idea.
lt's not only about the money.
l want to do something for you
as well.
Would you let me?
Of course.
Here's a towel,
in case you're cold,
to cover yourself with.
And...
take off your clothes
and lie down.
l'll be back in a minute.
What's wrong?
Carlos?
Hi.
l wanted to see you.
Come in.
What's wrong?
l went to the police station.
And...
they found a dead girl
the same age as my sister.
And...
they want me to identify her.
Would you mind coming with me?
You'll see only her face.
lf you'd like to see something else,
a tattoo or birthmark, tell me.
Take your time. The body was
in the water for more than 48 hours.
Tell me when you're ready.
Whenever you want.
That's not my sister.
lt's not Alexandra.
Okay, thank you.
Thanks.
See you tomorrow.
Carlos...
The other night in the apartment...
l'm sorry l left like that.
What happened?
l don't know.
ls there something wrong with me?
No.
You say you've never had
a serious girlfriend...
but l don't think that's true.
You don't?
l'm sure of it.
And whoever it was,
she really hurt you.
See you tomorrow.
''Take this and eat it
for it is my body
given for you.''
ln the same way,
after supper he took the cup,
and giving thanks once again,
he passed it to his disciples
and said:
''Take this and drink it
for it is my blood,
the new testament
to be spilt for you
and for all men
in forgiveness of all sin.
Do this in remembrance of me.''
l'm leaving town for a few days.
Why are you telling me?
Why do you think?
So you know.
Other times you disappear
-without telling me.
-l'm telling you now.
ls something wrong?
No.
Are you sure?
Why did you say the other day
l could never be with a woman?
Because it's true.
People change.
People are what they are.
l'm glad you're not my mother.
Nina?
What happened?
Are you okay?
lt was Bogdan.
He found out l sent my parents
the 3 thousand euros.
He says l killed my sister
to keep the money.
He tried to make me confess.
He went into a frenzy
when he saw l was living here now.
And he wants to go to the police.
But l didn't do anything.
l swear to you
l didn't do anything.
How are you?
Did you sleep here?
On the sofa.
Thanks for staying.
Nina, l was thinking...
Bogdan might come back.
You should stay at my place
until things calm down.
You'll be safer.
Here.
The number at the tailor's
in case you want to call me.
You can sleep in the bedroom,
l'll take the sofa.
l left you some towels on the bed
to shower.
l turned on the hot water.
Don't open the door for anyone.
You promise?
Yes.
Hi.
l made dinner.
l wanted to cook for you.
l bought some food,
you didn't have any.
l made pasta.
You don't like it?
lt's great.
You don't like it.
l can tell.
No, really, it's not that.
Then what is it?
l'm tired.
Do you like Alexandra?
What are you talking about?
You had one of her flyers
in your studio.
Advertising massages.
Then l saw it disappeared.
l suppose you took it down.
Your sister put them
all over the neighborhood.
Why did you keep it?
l forgot to throw it away.
What does that matter now?
lf it doesn't matter,
why did you take it down?
Because you didn't want me
to see it?
l didn't think it would do you
any good.
l couldn't take it happening again.
My sister's always taken
everything from me.
She won't take anything from you.
-l'd rather you told me the truth.
-That is the truth.
Your sister won't take anything
from you.
Nina, l have a cabin
in the mountains.
lt's a place l go sometimes.
There isn't much to do there.
Go for walks, sleep...
But l disconnect
and forget about my problems.
Would you like to go?
lf you want.
We can leave early tomorrow morning.
lt's a nice place
to see the sunrise.
Echo!
Thanks.
lt's like a dream.
Carlos?
What are you doing over there?
Nothing.
Come here with me.
Thanks.
l killed Alexandra.
l killed your sister.
l killed her.
Last night l tried to kill you.
You could never do that.
Your sister's not the first woman.
l've done it before.
You've done what?
Kill.
l kill them...
and l eat them.
Why are you telling me this now?
Because it's the truth.
Nina, we have to go.
We should get in the car
and drive back to Granada.
The police are looking for you.
lf you don't turn up,
they'll think you're guilty.
lf all this is true...
why didn't you kill me
last night?
l couldn't.
You couldn't?
Why don't you kill me now?
lt would be easy.
We're in the middle
of the mountain,
l can't run away.
Nobody will find out
and it will all be over with.
-Please stop.
-l don't want to.
Everything you're saying,
all this nonsense
about dead women
and my sister...
lt's all a lie.
Why don't you tell me the truth?
l desired your sister.
From the moment l saw her.
With all my heart.
That's why l killed her.
Like the other women.
With you l couldn't.
l can't.
Nina...
Nina, my love!
CANNlBAL
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player