(exhales)
(people chattering and laughing)
(lively music playing)
(clamouring)
A beer.
(man) Barman. One more, one more.
- Now?
- Now, upstairs.
Forestier!
- Charles Forestier!
- Yes.
Georges Duroy.
The 6th Hussars. Algeria, '85.
Yes, Georges Duroy.
Yes.
You look terrible.
Let me buy you a drink.
When did you last have a proper meal?
Excuse me.
(crowd cheering)
Champagne!
(dancer yipping)
So, what have you been doing
all these years?
I only just got out.
- (glass shatters)
- (chuckling)
I'm hoping for better luck in Paris.
You couldn't have come at a better time.
Paris is filthy with money.
Rotten with it.
If you can't succeed here
you might as well lie down and die.
Yes!
Even the whores are getting rich.
And me, ex-soldier,
living on the Boulevard Haussmann,
Political Editor of La Vie Francaise.
We're going to be the newspaper
that brings down the government.
I'm working as a clerk
at the railway office.
I don't have your connections, Charles.
I have to make money somehow.
And we can't go on
a looting spree any more.
We're not in the desert.
Why don't you come
to dinner tomorrow night?
Come and meet my wife.
(Georges) Well, the thing is, uh,
I don't have any evening clothes.
Well, here.
Buy some, hire some.
Come at 7:30, yes?
- Er, yes.
- Good.
Georges Duroy!
- (grunting)
- (panting)
(sighs)
What name shall I give?
Georges Duroy.
(butler) Monsieur Georges Duroy.
I am Madeleine Forestier.
(chuckling softly)
You're married to Charles?
Of course.
Charles has told me all about you.
- Madame Francois de Marelle.
- Madeleine!
(Madeleine) Clotilde.
You look lovely.
I'm Clotilde.
You can call me Clotilde.
(butler) Madame Pierre Rousset.
(Rousset) He's frail.
The gout's gone to his kidneys.
He'll become a member of
the Academy for the rest of his life.
And so everyone will be satisfied.
- (all chuckle)
- You're awful.
It's this knife, Duroy.
What?
He's not used to eating like this.
I believe you've only just returned
from your posting in North Africa.
You were in Algeria?
Yes.
Charles and I were first there
together, five... Five years ago?
(Charles) Five years.
He was a little thinner then.
(all chuckle)
Where were you garrisoned?
I was garrisoned at the frontier.
The very edge of the Sahara.
I once heard a very foolish story
about the desert.
It may well be a myth,
but I find it rather romantic.
I was told that the sands sing? Hmm?
Oh, it's true.
It's an effect of the wind on the dunes.
It makes a kind of music.
Oh. And what does it sound like?
It sounds very sad and mournful.
At least, it does to a lonely soldier.
You? But how could you be lonely?
And there, where the women are divine.
The women are ravishing,
and yet I was still homesick.
Hmm.
Sandstorms and mangy dogs,
- that's what I remember.
- (all laugh)
You could run something
extraordinary about this.
Mmm? I think it would be timely.
Timely? Why?
- Don't you read the newspapers?
- No.
The government
are trying to take Morocco.
Yes. For the good of
the Moroccan people, of course.
- But surely nobody wants a war.
- That won't stop them.
No. But we will.
(Madeleine) Think of it.
An eyewitness view.
A handsome young soldier
on the frontier.
Homesick and alone.
His adventures,
his insights.
The Diary of a Cavalry Officer.
Hmm?
What do you think, dearest?
- What fish are we having?
- Oh!
Oh, yes. Let's change the subject.
I can't bear politics.
Men talking about men
fighting with men about men.
It bores me stupid.
What does interest you?
Well...
I like enjoying myself.
What do you enjoy?
Well, I don't know.
Everything.
(Rousset) All right, you.
Diary of a Cavalry Officer.
I want the first article in the morning.
You realise he's never written a word?
I'll help him get started.
(whinnying)
We'll write it as a letter to a friend.
"Dear...
"Henri.
"I'm sorry I haven't
written for so long.
"It is almost a month
"since I first set foot
in this glorious land.
"I do not know that the heat will
agree with you, dear friend,
"but I know you would share
my enthusiasm for the people. "
(striking match)
"if only I could convey to you
the true wonder of the souk.
"The scent of cinnamon and saffron,
heavy on the warm air.
"She was wearing a simple dress
and a shawl against the sun,
"the colour of pomegranate blossom.
"She needed no other ornament.
"The simple perfection of her face,
the beauty of her smile,
"I cannot describe.
"All I know is that with one look,
"and one look alone,
"I was hers. "
I like being a journalist.
I hope you don't think I'm going to
write all your articles for you.
No.
I would never presume. I...
I meant something quite different.
I know what you meant.
Let's be clear.
I have no interest
in being your mistress.
There's nothing more boring to me
than an infatuated youth.
I know perfectly well that
love for you is an appetite.
It makes idiots of you all.
Look at me, please.
I will never be your mistress.
Do you understand?
- Yes.
- Good. (chuckles)
Then we can be friends.
Real friends.
And I can give you some advice.
The most important people in Paris
are not the men.
are their wives.
Call on Madame Rousset.
She likes you.
Madame Rousset likes me?
(chuckles) Not like that.
Never like that.
No.
Her husband values her opinion
above all others.
One good word from her
is worth ten years of grovelling to him.
But you may very much enjoy
a visit to my friend, Clotilde.
She is such wonderful company
and her husband is very often away.
If there is ever any way
I can repay your kindness.
(door opening)
May I present Georges Duroy.
We're helping him get on his feet.
This is the Comte de Vaudrec.
The Comte is our
best and closest friend.
Get out of my way!
Duroy!
(Charles) Monsieur Rousset,
you remember Georges Duroy?
Diary of a Cavalry Officer.
Your article was a success.
Write me another.
Put him on the payroll, Forestier.
If you think so.
(Charles) You'll get
five francs for this article.
Five for the next.
Then 200 a month.
Plus ten centimes a line
for any articles you manage to place.
Here.
Give this to the Chief Cashier.
What's the matter?
Can't believe your luck?
Hello, I'm Laurine, you're Georges.
Please sit down.
Maman will be down shortly.
What's your favourite game?
Tag.
Oh, well.
You...
- are 'it'.
- (screams excitedly)
(Laurine laughing)
Who's 'it'?
You are. (screaming)
I'm going to get you.
Going to get you.
(whispering) Going to get you. Tag!
- (Laurine) Get Georges.
- Tag.
(Laurine squealing)
Off ground.
- Who's chasing who?
- You're chasing us.
It is time for Laurine
to take her lunch.
I want to stay with Georges.
Well, perhaps you'll permit me
to call on you again.
Come soon, Bel am!
Kiss.
"Bel ami. " She never hugs anyone.
I'm so glad you called.
When can I see you again?
I'll come to you.
Tomorrow.
Come today.
Well, I hope you haven't gone to
too much trouble.
(both laugh)
- Would you like a drink?
- Yes. Yes, I would.
- I'm a bit nervous.
- So am I.
(train rumbling)
(laughs)
(bed creaks)
Do you think it will
take both of us? (laughs)
(bed creaks)
(coughs)
(neighbours arguing)
Oh.
I'd like to do this again.
I'd like to do this now.
I mustn't come to your room, though.
Anyone might see.
I can't risk a divorce.
I would lose Laurine.
And I don't want to
embarrass my husband.
He's a good man.
Mm.
A love nest is what we need.
A little place we could go
to be alone from time to time.
I would pay for it.
My money,
to spend on me,
on something I want.
(both laughing)
(Clotilde laughing)
(bell tolling)
What are you reading?
It's a letter from my father.
Every week he puts on his best suit
and goes to the priest
and the priest writes a letter for him.
And every week it's the same thing.
Your mother sends her blessings.
The pigs have diarrhoea.
- When are you getting married?
- Ooh!
(both laugh)
- My father's a peasant.
- Mmm.
He's never left his village.
And he's asking me for money.
I'd like to see where you grew up.
I'd like to see you there.
Promise me something.
- Don't bring your other women here.
- Ha!
I don't have other women.
All men have other women.
Not me.
Honestly?
Don't lie to me.
Honestly and truly.
(lively music playing)
(laughing)
Champagne!
Hello.
I was talking to your friend here.
Georges?
I think you've mistaken me
for somebody else.
So, I see.
Not so friendly after all, are we?
Now that you're not looking for
a cheap fuck.
(women exclaiming in surprise)
Clo!
Don't you dare touch me!
It was before I knew you.
Clotilde!
(door closes)
(woman) All you had to do
was say hello to me.
Who are you to speak to me?
Who am I?
Beggar.
- Rival?
- Yes.
No.
You still owe me 40.
I need to eat, too.
Why don't you try earning it?
Diary Of A Cavalry Officer.
Whatever happened to that?
Perhaps you can get my wife to write it.
Perhaps you think you can
draw your salary
and she will do your job for you.
Now, I...
I brought you into my home,
I fed you, I clothed you,
and how do you repay me?
By learning to play cup and ball.
I mean, my...
(coughing)
If you'll shut up, I'll write it now.
You will, will you?
(coughs)
- There you are, Forestier.
- (coughs)
Did you really write this?
Yes.
You write like an errand boy.
(all laughing)
Rousset shall see this.
Forestier.
(laughing)
Forestier!
Pompous idiot.
He can talk.
Couldn't even write his own name
without his wife to spell it for him.
You know what they say about her.
What?
You know. Vaudrec. (chuckling)
You shut your mouth.
You don't know her.
Monsieur Rousset regrets to inform you
that your services are
no longer required.
Pack up and get out.
You're on your own, Duroy.
There's no women to help you here.
(Georges) Madame Rousset.
I hope you'll forgive me for intruding.
Monsieur Duroy.
I wanted to make a gift to you
of these pears
I received from my parents' orchard
in Normandy today.
Oh. How very kind.
Would you care to join us?
(ladies chuckling)
I would. Thank you.
Will you eat a pear, Madame Rousset?
(ladies chuckling)
Well, Um.
Yes, I think I might.
(ladies chuckling)
(Rival) Head of Gossip.
Head of Gossip?
(Charles coughing)
(Rousset) Ah, Duroy.
You remember my wife.
Monsieur Duroy.
Now, do you remember
Madame de Marelle?
(Georges) Of course.
Well, Bel ami.
Don't you have a smile
for your old friend?
Let's go into dinner, ladies.
We have pages and pages
of gossip for you.
Madame Forestier.
Bel ami. Ha!
I thought you'd forgotten me.
Impossible.
- (piano playing softly)
- (singing Ave Maria)
(coughs)
(continues coughing)
I missed you so much.
Why didn't you come to me?
I thought you didn't want me anymore.
I always want you.
I must go.
My husband
will be wondering where I am.
My other husband.
Your rich husband.
The father of my daughter.
Will you lace me up?
Don't forget to tie a double bow.
- Like your husband does it?
- Mmm.
(sighs) Poor Charles.
He won't live to see another spring.
Madeleine has taken him to the sea,
but it won't help.
Poor thing.
She won't be a widow for long.
(gulls crying)
(carriage approaching)
Thank you for coming.
You're the only one.
How is he?
I brought him to Cannes
to make him better.
But I'll bury him here.
They're my favourite. Thank you.
(Charles chuckles)
You've come to see me die.
No. I've just come to escape the city.
Because I'm going to live.
Yes.
I am.
I'm going to live.
Help me.
I want to go for a drive!
You're not strong enough.
Help
(coughs)
(coughing)
(Charles coughing)
(Charles groaning faintly)
I want you to listen
to what I have to say
and try to understand.
Don't be angry.
I only want you to know that
with one word you can make me happy.
You can make me your friend,
your brother,
or you can make me your husband.
My heart and my body are yours.
You have to understand,
I am not like other women.
Marriage to me is partnership,
a contract between equals.
I will not accept authority, jealousy,
or questioning my conduct.
I insist on being free.
(softly) Of course.
You must give it more thought.
It is an important decision for us both.
Clo.
Just tell me.
Tell me quickly.
I'm getting married.
Oh.
Of course you must.
Who is she?
Madeleine Forestier.
Oh.
(chuckling) Well,
you've chosen exactly
the woman you need.
Yes.
And you love her?
Clo.
(tearfully) No, no. I'll be fine.
(door opens)
(door shuts)
(Madeleine) "The government insists
that it has abandoned
"its designs on Morocco. "
No, no, better.
"The government insists it has listened
to the will of its people
"and abandoned its designs on Morocco. "
(Georges) Shh.
Look, Georges, the papers.
(sighs)
This is so boring.
This endless to and fro.
- They say this, we say that.
- Yes, you're right.
It's as stale as old bread.
Wasn't there a deputy?
Who was it? I know it's here somewhere.
He bet his moustache
the government was lying.
Sarrazin.
We should give Sarrazin's moustache
a column of its own.
Georges,
it's brilliant.
That is brilliant.
Rousset will love it.
I've been thinking.
The Political Editor of
a leading newspaper
should have a more memorable name.
Something...
a bit grand.
Where were your parents from?
My parents are from Canteleu.
You remember?
We didn't have our honeymoon there.
(Madeleine laughs)
Georges...
Duroy de Canteleu.
No. It's not quite right.
Duroy de Cantel.
Madeleine, I'm from Canteleu.
I prefer that.
No, no, no. Listen.
Georges Duroy de Cantel.
Say it again.
Madame Duroy de Cantel.
Sarrazin's moustache.
This is exactly what we need.
Originality of thought. Print!
Sit.
They're for my wife.
(man laughing)
Georges.
Oh!
Thank you.
You know how love them.
One can never have too many.
The Comte was just leaving.
Not for my sake, I hope.
No, no. I have business to attend to.
Thank you, Paul. Thank you.
And give my regards to your wife.
I wish her better health.
(Paul) You are too kind,
Monsieur le comte.
That'll be all.
What did he want?
(Madeleine) It's Tuesday.
He always comes on Tuesday.
And when are your politicians arriving?
Ah!
In half an hour.
Half an hour!
Yes.
In half an hour.
- Now, I've invited Laroche.
- Uh-huh.
You must pay special attention to him.
He's going to be foreign minister
one day, I promise.
(Georges grunts)
Georges.
(people chattering)
(Rousset) We are going to bring
this government down with one word.
I want the word on the front page
of every newspaper.
I want it on every wall
and every shop window.
I want every man,
woman, and child, to know
that this government is lying.
Forestier can dig something up.
What's that?
What?
You just called me Forestier.
Oh, force of habit.
Don't be offended.
It's an easy mistake to make.
How do you mean?
And we should look into
troop movements.
Logistics.
(Rousset) Yes.
Laroche, you can help us here.
I know a couple of officers
who are sympathetic to our cause.
You can talk to, uh...
Laroche will tell you what to write.
Look at these exports to Algiers.
Why have we gone from shipping
hundreds of tons of grain here to...
Look, look.
Thousands of tons here.
Why?
(clears throat)
I don't know, to feed an army. Hmm?
To feed an army.
This is it.
Who is supplying the grain?
Georges, that's the question.
Georges, I need to work.
Mmm. My brilliant wife.
All right.
(Madeleine grunting)
(chuckling) Mado.
(Madeleine grunting rhythmically)
Mado, slow down. Slow down.
(Madeleine panting)
Mado!
(Georges straining)
(Georges grunts)
Look.
They're going to invade.
(both sighing)
La Vie Francaise has found proof.
Oh, of course, it's Tuesday.
The Comte de Vaudrec
must be arriving soon.
Incontrovertible proof
of the government's true intentions
toward Morocco.
We've never talked about that, have we?
The Comte de Vaudrec.
The man
who arrives unannounced,
who knows all the servants
better than I do...
Buried deep amongst
the dreary columns
of our trade figures.
What is he to you, huh?
Where no one would think to look.
What is he to you?
Do you want to be the man
who brought down the government?
Or do you want to be a fool?
- (lively music plating)
- Ah!
(people clapping)
We're just waiting for Laroche.
- You know my daughter, Suzanne?
- Oh!
So pretty.
And another for Bel ami.
- (laughs)
- It's what Maman calls you.
I have from time to time.
I hope you don't mind.
Call him whatever you like.
Ah!
Our foreign minister.
Go on.
Thank you, thank you, my good friends.
My excellent,
hard-working friends.
But I'm afraid I have bad news for you.
Our work has only just begun!
(guests laughing)
We have a great task ahead of us.
- Our achievements in government...
- Would you excuse me'?
...must dwarf our achievements
in opposition.
There will be battles.
There will be conflicts.
But they will be fought
not on the sands of Morocco,
but on the floor of the chamber.
(man) Hear, hear.
(Laroche) My first act
as foreign minister
is to recall General Boutin
from Algiers.
There will be no minister of war
in this government.
- (guests cheering)
- Hear this, my friends.
People of France...
I don't have to ask how you are.
I've been very pleased for you.
How's Laurine?
She still hasn't forgiven you.
She calls you Monsieur Forestier now.
She's too young to understand.
And you'?
You made a good marriage.
We all have to do it.
And I miss you.
Our love nest feels cold without you.
You kept it on.
I'm an optimist.
(Laroche) Once and for all!
Morocco is safe.
(guests cheering)
(lively music playing)
- What a formidable partnership.
- Very kind. Thank you.
(man) Well done.
(guests chattering)
Thank you.
Come. Play a hand.
Sit.
Let my boy deal.
I warn you, I'm on a winning streak.
(sighs)
I'm more powerful than a king.
Not as rich.
(chuckling)
Not yet, anyway
In a mere morning,
I emptied the Chamber of Deputies,
and filled it again
with men of my choosing,
with nothing more than words on a page.
They're not your words, though.
Are they?
How's married life?
How do you get along with Vaudrec?
He visits quite often.
I dare say it's only fair.
After all, he does own the apartment.
Duroy?
Yes, he set them up in the apartment
after he married Madeleine to Forestier.
He married Madeleine to Forestier?
Well, he introduced them
and then he paid the dowry,
so I suppose
that is how you would put it.
Vaudrec is a father to her.
Hmm.
Perhaps.
Why don't you go and enjoy the party?
I'm sure the ladies will want a dance.
Bel ami.
(thunder rumbling)
(thunder)
(Georges exhales)
What brings you here?
You were caught in the rain?
No, I didn't come here by chance.
I don't mean to frighten you.
I expect nothing. I ask for nothing.
I don't even know what I'm doing.
I'm sorry if I've offended you.
No.
No, you’re not offended me.
But we must talk of it no longer.
Shall I leave'?
Shall I stay? I...
(gasps)
Is there any hope for me?
You are trying to seduce me in a church.
I've never had a lover before.
Look at me.
Does your husband
tell you you're beautiful?
(gasps)
Virginie. Virginie.
Georges.
Whose arms are these?
They're mine.
- And whose lips?
- Virginie.
Whose lips?
They're my lips.
- Now, come on.
- Hmm.
Get dressed.
When will I see you again?
Please leave.
My beautiful Georges.
My darling boy, please tell me when.
- Tomorrow.
- Tomorrow!
Yes, tomorrow.
Well... (giggles)
- (door opens)
- (Clotilde) Georges?
Georges?
(Georges) Hmm.
Madeleine will be wondering
where you are.
Madeleine?
Where's my wife?
She's with the Comte de Vaudrec.
What?
He died this morning.
I have asked you here today,
Madame Duroy de Cantel,
to hear the will
of the Comte de Vaudrec.
The Comte has named you, madame,
as the sole inheritor of his estate,
the value of which stands at
one million, eighty thousand
and fifteen francs.
And 29 centimes.
There is one complication.
Uh, the nature of the legacy.
The nature of the legacy?
Uh...
If you'll forgive me, sir,
it is unusual for an estate to be left
solely to a married woman.
It would normally be left
to the husband.
And why is that?
To avoid any suggestion of, forgive me,
impropriety in the relationship.
(sighs) What was he to you, hmm?
What was he thinking,
the stupid old bastard?
He should have left it all to me.
It would have been much better for you.
He must have known
what people would make of it.
He must have realised
how it would compromise you.
Unless it was done in innocence.
A fatherly gesture.
He was like a father to you, wasn't he?
A guardian.
(sighs)
I can't accept it.
I must protect my reputation.
I don't want a million francs.
(sighs)
(Georges) Come on, let's not be hasty.
I'm sure we can reach some kind of...
(chuckles)
But the will is there for all to see.
I can only redeem it by rejecting it.
(Georges sighs)
But if I, your husband,
chose to accept it,
then who is to question me, hmm?
Mmm?
Indeed,
to refuse is to admit the shame.
Whereas,
to accept is to deny it.
(Georges sighs)
Good.
Perhaps your old man
wasn't so stupid after all.
(tearfully) Don't speak of him.
What was he to you?
Tell me.
Tell me. I deserve an answer.
(sobbing)
He is the man I have lost.
The man I am grieving.
You want it to be something small,
something squalid and contemptible.
He was my friend.
My father.
And my lover.
(Madeleine sobbing)
You loved him.
Ah!
(wailing)
(Madeleine sobbing)
(sobbing) How will I live?
How will I live?
You haven't been to see me for a while.
For a whole week
I've waited for a word from you.
Georges, my beautiful boy.
Don't call me that.
- (horse neighing)
- (man) Make way there! Make way!
Make way!
They're not for you.
You're meeting someone else.
Take me with you. I need to talk to you.
- Just for an hour.
- Remember where you are!
Remember where you are.
You shouldn't have seduced me.
You should have left me where I was,
a happy and faithful wife.
Please, let me come with you.
Please, just for an hour.
I've got something
so important to tell you.
Something to your advantage.
It's about my husband.
Please.
If you're going to cry you should leave.
Please, Georges.
Oh, my darling Georges.
My beautiful boy.
I have been so clever.
So discreet.
I've asked all the right questions.
I've listened carefully.
- (gasps)
- Oh, come on!
What?
Our new government
is going to take Morocco.
(laughs)
Virginie, the new government
came to power,
I brought them to power,
on the promise that they would not.
That's the whole point.
Don't you see?
No one's expecting it.
My husband and Laroche have been
hatching this plan for a long time.
The first troops sail tonight.
Tonight.
But they would have included me.
They don't trust you.
They think you're too impulsive.
Too greedy, they say.
Not used to having money.
They think that you'll give them away.
(scoffs) They think I'm too greedy.
They don't know you as I do.
Over the past few weeks
they've bought the entire Moroccan loan.
They've bought every copper mine
in Morocco. Every last one.
They stand to make 70 million apiece.
Seventy million.
He's spending it already.
He's going to buy
the Palais Saint-Honor.
Seventy million
and I've shamed myself for a pittance.
Aren't you proud of me?
Don't you love me?
Haven't I done well
finding this out, my darling?
I've bought shares for you, too.
And they'll make you at least 70,000.
- (whimpers)
- I don't want your pennies!
They're not worth the price
I paid for them!
(gasps and whimpers)
You disgust me!
But I love you.
I don't want your love.
I've never loved you.
Your smell, it turns my stomach.
Because you smell of him.
Your filthy husband!
I used to laugh, every time I'd had you,
to think I'd sent you back to him
with my sweat on your skin.
When all the while, it was me!
I was the one getting fucked!
Me!
- Get out of my house.
- Just listen to them, Georges.
Get out! Get out of my house!
(Madeleine) Listen to them, Georges.
Just listen to what they have to say.
lam going to ruin you.
Don't be a child.
Consider your best interests.
There's still money to be made.
You think I've robbed you.
You're not my responsibility.
The opportunity was there for anyone
who had eyes to see it.
You!
You were an embarrassment to Charles.
A failed soldier, barely literate.
He said you'd never amount to much.
Seems he was right.
Pity you didn't marry more wisely.
You'll be missed.
You knew.
Don't be absurd, Georges.
How could I know?
I'm a woman.
I'm not invited to the card game. Hmm?
Who was it today, hmm?
Clotilde?
Or Virginie?
Or both?
And yesterday?
You stupid, stupid man.
You complete and perfect man.
(Madeleine laughs scornfully)
I poured my talent into you.
My intelligence.
My vision into you.
I had no conception of the depths
of your emptiness.
Nothing.
There is nothing there.
Nothing but rage.
Like a dumb animal.
That's what you are. An animal.
I thought I could teach you.
But what I should have done
was train you.
(door slams)
(grunting)
(crowd cheering)
Aah! Ah!
(laughs)
(grunting)
Get out of it!
(conversing indistinctly)
(instrumental music playing)
Excuse me.
I always liked your audacity.
I don't need to hide my face.
I'm not the criminal.
- You're not gonna throw me out.
- No.
Stay. Drink my champagne.
Dance with my wife.
Yours, I see, is already spoken for.
(Clotilde) Georges. Georges?
(sighs)
I've been such a fool.
Why do you come back to me?
I don't know.
Perhaps because you never expect me to.
I am sorry I hurt you.
It is worth saying.
(Clotilde) I've never seen
such a host of buck-toothed cretins.
Everyone a noble bankrupt.
All here for Suzanne
and her thirty million francs.
(gasps)
Open this door or we will force it!
- (Madeleine) Who is it?
- Police.
Madame Madeleine Duroy de Cantel?
Wife of
Monsieur Georges Duroy de Cantel?
Yes.
(gasps)
Madame Duroy de Cantel,
I have found you here in a place
that is not your home
with Monsieur Francois Laroche.
Do you admit
that this man is your lover?
I admit it.
Madame, I have no choice
but to charge you with adultery.
Is there anything that you wish to say?
- No.
- (Georges) Let's leave her in peace.
We have no further business here.
What should I do'? Should I go?
No, stay.
Finish, if you like.
Well, you'll hear from my lawyer
in a few days.
Goodbye, Georges.
Goodbye.
(laughs) I couldn't get away.
They were shouting and screaming,
on and on. (laughs)
Maman wouldn't stop crying and wailing,
she was like a madwoman.
I wish I could see their faces
when they find me gone.
Papa will turn blue!
Oh! (laughs)
(driver) Whoa!
We'll need two rooms.
Good night, Suzanne.
But...
I need a good-night kiss.
You should get some sleep.
But...
Get some sleep.
Papa.
Maman.
- He will not marry her.
- I should have seen it coming.
He will not marry her!
I will not suffer it!
(Rousset) He will marry her.
He must marry her.
And you will accept it, Virginie.
This is as much your doing
as it is mine.
My doing!
Your infatuation for him
infected my daughter!
He will marry her
and I will be glad of it.
What more can a father wish for
than to see his daughter
with a man he can respect?
She's only a child.
- Do you love her?
- No.
She's of no interest to me.
Poor little Suzanne.
Suzanne's her father.
Just in perfect miniature.
- You've ruined her.
- I haven't. I'm going to marry her.
Did you sleep with her?
No.
You didn't sleep with her?
I didn't touch her. I didn't need to.
It was enough for people to think I had.
I don't know you at all.
You do.
Oh, do I? (scoffs)
You planned it.
You ruined Laroche.
You humiliated Madeleine.
You humiliated her.
All so you could take Suzanne.
Suzanne chose me
because I was the only one
- she wasn't allowed to have.
- And me?
Did you ever think
how this would hurt me?
It has nothing to do with you.
(tearfully) Then why am I in pain?
I don't know.
You didn't even tell me yourself.
I had to hear it from my husband.
You think I'll forgive you anything.
I will not be stopped, Clotilde.
I will marry her.
You're just one of them, after all.
Just another selfish, brutal man.
Just another thief.
It's not enough to be loved, is it?
No, you must be a king.
No.
It's not enough to be loved.
Even by you.
I loved you when you had nothing.
I don't understand
why you must be so proud.
I don't understand.
That's because you've never been poor.
Trying to scrape out some
miserable scrap of an existence.
I can't live like that.
Like my father.
Working to the bone,
and then down on his knees every week,
praying to God that
the next life will be better.
Well, there is no next life.
The flesh, it rots in the earth.
It rots.
I have seen a man die.
And I am going to live.
It's so clear to me.
I thought you would understand.
(dialogue silent)
- (echoing chatter)
- (bells pealing)
(people applauding)