They say
that a split second before you die
your whole life passes before your eyes.
If the moron who said that had a bullet inches from his face
I wonder what he'd say.
That's me when I was two.
It's the only thinp I've pot of my mother.
This photo.
She said she pave birth to me in the street.
Now I see I've been trapped in these streets all my life
and if nothinp chanpes
I'll never pet out of here.
NE0N FLESH
But let's start at the beginning.
Anyone born on the streets knows the world is split in two.
Those who buy and those who sell.
Those who supply the flesh
and those who fuck it.
You're on one side or the other.
Want a gold chain?
0K, I'll keep it.
Ricky, we have to talk.
I'm sick.
Fuck it, Princess, it's too early.
I'm suffering from anxiety.
I saw the psychiatrist.
He says I'm psychosomatic.
Princess has a screw loose.
She thinks the king is her father.
That's why she wears a blue wip,
the same color as her blood.
If she's in a pood mood, you can ask about her real name.
My name?
Juan Carlos.
Like my father.
Ricky, you know that really I'm an actress and a singer,
and artists in this country either serve tables or suck dicks.
The other day I was sucking a guy off.
It turns out he's a director
and he's making a movie.
What's it called?
"Maid to Suck". Is that cinema?
Well, it's cinema, more like "home cinema",
but, yeah, it's cinema.
Real cinema.
It's not what I imagined when I left the village,
but one has to compromise.
Stop, stop.
Do you know Glamour Muff?
She doesn't know Glamour Muff.
When I discovered her in "Gang Bangs of New York".
Chichi was like you,
a star in the making.
We had to make the chop.
Wait, wait.
Have I got this right?
They offered you the lead in a porn movie
if you cut off your dick.
That makes it sound a bit gross,
but he says it's anti-aesthetic.
What can I say?
I don't know.
You're intelligent and sensitive.
Since I had my nipples pierced I'm not sensitive anywhere.
I think: "Cut it off."
"You don't use it anyway."
But it's what makes transvestites a bit special,
it pays the rent.
But if I cut off my dick
I could be a movie star.
The world of movies, 0scars, red carpets...
I can't decide.
How do you get into these messes?
I don't know.
Go on inside.
Jesus Christ.
Edu, may I have a mint tea, please?
Hey, Angelito.
Ricky! Come over here.
Have a coffee with me.
Here.
What's up? Can't I have a coffee with a pal?
Scrag worked for Angelito.
They say she's hooked on smack but pives preat head.
Maybe because all her teeth fell out.
Angelito pimps Scrag and some other girls
but the one who really does the dirty work is Rocco, his dog.
He knows he can only be arrested if he's caupht threatening a whore
so he manages not to even touch them.
Go on, get her.
Scrag and me... We've got a lot of feeling.
I just do that, and she goes and works the street.
I got a present for you. Kid...
This is for you.
What the hell is it?
A suit.
Your mother's being released soon.
You'll look good in it.
What's up?
Don't you like it?
It's not that. It's just I'm a bit scared.
I don't know if I can face her.
Don't be such a wimp, Ricky.
You're going to go and pick your mother up,
dressed to the nines.
Shit, there's blood stain on this.
Just a few drops.
Hey, you try beating the shit out of a guy and taking his suit off.
Just try it!
I want to show you something back at my place.
We all know what your asshole looks like.
- Come on.- Edu, my tea. You are as slow as Molasses.
You got all this selling pills and hash?
I've been saving for five years.
You've got balls.
Who's to say the Kid and I won't slit your throat
and take the box?
A question.
To answer it, you need to know more about the Kid.
Two years apo, Scrap fell in love with a puy.
He promised he'd take her off the street.
Angelito and the Kid went looking for him
and, of course, ended up finding him.
Tell me where she is or I'll fry your balls.
I don't know.
Kid, will you tell that fucking dog to shut up!
Shit!
People say that the Kid always takes thinps literally
and that he once killed someone.
They also say he didn't have a pun that day,
he just threw the dog out the window.
Will you tell that fucking dog to shut up!
Motherfucker!
I don't know.
And Angelito is a liar.
But I know the guy talked, Scrag went back on the street,
and the next week Angelito appeared with a new dop.
Who's to say the Kid and I won't slit your throat and take the box?
Fuck off, you bastard.
Just fuck off.
You're a pal. What's this all about?
It's for my mother.
Building to rent
The Hiroshima.
I'm opening it for her.
The Hero-what?
Look.
When I was little
she always said she'd quit the street.
She said: "Ricky, you and I are going to open a club."
"A great club."
She wanted to call it the Hiroshima.
But she went to jail and everything got fucked.
No, I'm sorry, Ricky.
She dumped you and then she went to jail.
You don't owe her shit.
And, anyway,
why do you want to open a whorehouse?
Angelito,
maybe his mother likes the idea.
Yeah, sure.
My mother's dream is for me to open a whorehouse for her.
What a fucking lovely gesture.
So you won't come in on it?
Then help me with the girls.
I know where this is going.
You said you knew people who bring girls from Eastern Europe.
No, I said I'd a cousin whose friend...
I know what you said.
Listen to me.
I need three girls, four at the most. That's it.
If you want something that's a fucking money-maker, look.
Watch-calculators.
It's the new business.
They're in fashion again.
Don't touch that!
If you won't help me, OK, but this is for the Hiroshima.
No, don't you touch me, OK?
Look, the club business is run by people who are real bastards.
You hear me?
The street is shit, but it's ours.
- So it's over. - No, it's not.
I've had enough.
I'm doing this for my mother.
You want her to end up on the streets again, like us?
Where are you, Angelito?
We're both on the fucking street.
Angelito...
Maybe we could get him some girls,
couldn't we?
Shut up, you haven't got a fucking clue.
And you, Ricky,
don't ever say I traffic with Rumanian pussies,
or African ones,
or with whatever.
Kid, you are breaking my balls with the goddamned ball.
Come on, let's go.
See you, Ricky.
I don't like animals
and Angelito always dumps the dog on me.
It's mine, it's mine!
And people are really depraved.
Today a guy offered me 100 to do it with the dog.
The dog pulls in more clients than I do.
Kick it to me!
Look, it's your father.
How's my crazy boy?
Move, move, move.
- What's up, Angelito? - Nothing, it's all OK.
- On the ground. - Take it easy.
Come on, hands up.
Attack, Rocco, attack!
For fuck's sake, Rocco!
The cop, not the whores!
What about the two missing policemen?
You've lost two?
You guys can't be let out on your own.
Good for you, Kid!
Stop!
I've got him.
To all units in the vicinity of the port area,
a suspect is beinp pursued.
- Sweety. - Hi, dad.
- We've caught you again. - I wanted to see you, I miss you.
I miss you too,
but I've been really busy.
- With all this work... - Manuel!
- Hang on. - OK.
Can we talk?
Know why I run away from boarding school?
No one touches me like you.
No, I can't touch myself here, I'd be embarrassed.
Don't say that, please. You're making me feel wicked.
Are you talking to yourself?
No, dad.
Stop that nonsense.
- Shit! - I didn't even see it.
We have to take it to a hospital.
We're not taking it anywhere.
Fuck you, we won't let him die.
What's your name?
Rocco...
Look at what those bastards did to my face.
Fuck them anyway.
They can stick those two cops up their ass.
Angelito...
What a beauty! Where did you get those wheels?
Don't tell me you found Rocco.
What the fuck is this?
What?
Where did you find her?
Stop!
Stop, police!
Stop moving!
Who the hell are you?
Stop!
What the hell is this?
This...
It's your fucking Easter egg.
A pussy with no papers.
You wanted into the business. Now you're up to your neck in it.
- Fucking great. - What?
Am I the only one here who's got any brains?
They'll find out about your club.
Who will? The police?
Fuck them.
Yeah, and Charlie's Angels can come suck my cock.
I'm worried about Chino.
Chino?
Jesus Christ.
You don't even know who he is?
No.
Look, he's into everything illegal
and gets a cut from everyone.
I'll tell you a story about him
so you can learn.
Once
a narco who worked for him was arrested.
Chino knew he could testify apainst him in a trial,
and he put so much money on the guy's head
that the cops who were supposed to protect him, killed him.
So far, so good.
But the Colombian's mother wanted the puy who killed him
and Chino didn't want to lose the coke business,
so he took the first cop he saw,
cut off his hands,
cut out his tonpue,
and handed him over to the Colombian family.
If he finds out you're setting up on your own
your life will be shit.
It already is, he can't make it much worse.
Sell her to me.
3,000, right now.
Jesus, Ricky, you are so fucking hardheaded!
You want to set up all on your own,
just for your fucking mother.
And they're going to catch you.
And I'll feel like shit because I couldn't help you.
I won't sell her to you,
Ricky,
I'll rent her.
Hell, we'll get the shit kicked out of us
but you won't be the only one to make a packet.
Let's see the place.
It's a fucking dump, Ricky.
If you want to set up a real club,
we do it seriously, right?
First lesson:
No second-hand whores.
The Hiroshima is goinp to be a classy joint.
I've got a deal that you'll like.
I can offer you three knock-out women.
You can have Desi for 2,000.
Her tits are still firm, they're new.
Leti for 1,500.
Scrag is even cheaper.
No, not Scrag.
Not Scrag, no way.
How does she suck your dick?
She leaves your cock as good as new.
- Scrag for 200. - Forget it!
100.
3 for 2, like in the supermarket.
Don't go, dickhead!
Son of a bitch!
Have you seen my dog?
I can't sell Scrag, I can't even give her away.
That's OK, what about the others?
I've been thinking about it.
Scrag is bit of a nuisance.
It might be best if she had an accident.
- What? - What's up?
She isn't going to have an accident.
Are you saying I don't have the balls?
- Are you saying that? - No.
You're saying I haven't got the balls!
Listen, Angelito...
I haven't got the balls?
I'm not saying that. I'm saying you're talking about Scrag.
How long are you with her?
Maybe too long.
I'm hanging up, she's here.
What a great looking car!
Where are you taking me?
To the country. I've got a surprise for you.
That's what I said.
Angelito wouldn't sell me.
We've been through too much shit for him to get rid of me.
Pick up, Angelito.
Careful, love, don't hurt yourself.
Don't open your eyes.
And don't turn round.
You'll love this surprise.
Look, I've got two options.
I do it privately, and pay a fortune,
or I get it done on the State.
But there's a horribly long waiting list.
I never knew this country's full of fags.
Princess,
take her inside.
Angel, I thought
you were going to take me off the street,
that you and I...
Come on.
Forget him.
You're worth a lot.
But, you know,
you look like a Junkie-cow-girl.
Make more of yourself.
You had me scared, you old bastard.
If you'd hurt her...
What is this?
Stop that fag stuff.
We're buddies, but no fag stuff.
- Give me a hug. - No.
- Give me a hug, Angelito. - No.
- A man's hug. - All right.
Don't be angry.
All ripht, second lesson.
You've pot money, now find the pirls.
Where?
You're about to see.
Angelito,
it's first class stuff tonight.
For the clubs, real money.
Come on Monday.
You can get the leftovers.
Are you bringing your mother and your sister?
Look, look.
Great tits, a wonderful ass. We'll take her.
How much?
- Wait. - What's up?
Look at her arms.
- Shit, a junkie. - Yeah.
Fuck her.
0n the left, see that woman?
That's Frida.
She's the queen of porn.
She has a girl fucked in front of a camera,
from in front, from behind,
with dogs, with Arabs, with anything that's got a dick.
We'll continue with number six, Irina. Slovakia.
Natural blonde. 20,000.
Shit!
It's Loco. You have to be real careful with him.
Who's Loco?
It's obvious, isn't it?
He works for Chino.
If he finds out we're looking for material, Chino will find out,
so be careful, OK?
If you want any of them grab them now.
Go on, move.
Give me the bag.
Stand here and don't move.
Let's go, Ricky.
Gentlemen,
we're in a hurry, the car's double parked.
Come on.
Hey, are you following me?
Spying on me?
Who's this?
Rocco?
Look!
You big lump!
You're better!
Angelito...
What is it?
You see how she looks at me?
The black woman?
It's like we're connected, like...
there are "fill-ins".
Like you and Scrag.
"Fill-ins"?
I think she looks more like she's shitting in her panties.
Didn't you want to get into the business?
Well, you're in!
Say a few words.
What do I say?
I don't know, your mother's a whore.
You've known the business all your life, right?
Go on, break the ice, champ.
You know why you're here.
This isn't easy.
Not for anyone.
Nor for you, not for us.
I won't lie to you.
This is tough.
It's shit.
Ricky...
You're scaring the fuck out of them.
I'm trying to help them.
No, you can't help them.
They'll eat you alive.
Watch me.
All right, this is the Hiroshima Club.
From today on, you are not going to leave here, ever.
Silence, a bit of respect
or I'm gonna have to kick your ass.
She don't understand
your language.
It's very clear, look.
We've paid a shitload of money
for each one of you.
And now you are in debt to us.
And there's just one way to pay it.
- Niet what? - Not do nothing of that.
What will do is we go.
- Are you the smartass? - What are you doing?
- I'm going kick your fucking ass. - You are bastard!
Hang on, calm down.
What's your name?
Irina.
OK.
You want to go?
Then go.
What'll you do out there?
Get a job?
You got papers?
You got money?
You got nothing out there.
You got nobody.
You want to get caught and sent home?
Here, we are
offering you a job.
- Decent. - Right.
When you pay off your debt we'll give you your papers
and you can leave.
You decide.
What's wrong with you?
If we can't go out on the street
how can we buy our things?
Here,
toy money.
You'll get paid in this.
The only currency in Hiroshima.
If you want to buy anything,
food, clothes, cigarettes, I'll sell it to you.
When you leave, we'll swap this for real money.
No dealing in euros. You get that?
Euros?
She has no fucking idea.
Look, yes, euros, euros.
All legal.
Is that all clear?
Welcome to the Hiroshima.
Couldn't you have got a smaller sign?
And it's pink!
That's my mother's favorite color.
Yeah, but it looks a bit fudge packer.
OK, before we start fucking, let's look at the theory.
The Kid's brought a porn movie
so you can see all the stuff about postures and things.
Let's shape up.
Excuse me.
The gun's rubbing against the tip of my dick
it's giving me eczema.
My mother gets out tomorrow.
I want her to be knocked out when she sees it.
Then we'll take it down.
I'll tell you what I've got.
I call it "the fuck pack".
It's got one condom, wet wipes,
sheets in sky blue, they don't stain so easily.
I've got them in pale pink too.
You want to see a photo of my dog?
Me and Rocco.
That's me.
Look.
Like it?
Want to touch it?
No?
Can I?
It kicked me.
Now?
- Will I do it now? - Yeah, do it!
She's running away!
Kid, go fetch! Fecht!
I told you. This is because we're too nice.
I got her.
Angelito! Screw you!
Come in!
What a place!
Its fairground lights, its pinball machine...
It fell off a truck, but it's perfect.
Kid! That's good, I want to see all the balloons blown up.
Girls, smile, Ricky's mother is coming.
Let me see some teeth.
You! Don't get sick, I know you. You're putting it on.
Pleather armchairs, see?
And, most important,
a fireman's pole, so the girls can rub their muffs.
Scrag isn't too good at it.
She's practicing.
But don't worry. As long as she can move her pussy
we're all right.
And smile, it's not every day your mom gets out of jail.
Mom...
Hey!
Who do you think you are?
Mom, it's me.
Ricky.
Your son.
- My what? - Your son, Ricky.
What did you say?
My son!
What do you want, kid?
Look, it's 5,000 for the whole works.
3,500 for a blow job.
Mom, are you all right?
Do you feel 0K?
Jesus, kid, you're really going on!
You want me to be your mother?
Pay me, and you can call me what you want.
- We have to go. - Don't touch me.
I called a taxi, it's there.
Mom!
The minimum fare from here is 50 euros.
That's no problem.
You don't take pesetas now, do you?
I've got no dough.
I'll tell you what.
Take me out of here and I'll suck your dick. I'm a whore.
Well, not now. I'm being "rehabed" into society.
But I'll give you a blowjob, no obligation.
Shit for brains!
Hey, I'd rather go with you than rot to death here.
But give me 50 up front and don't call me mom,
or I'll thump you.
0K?
Shit!
Wow, classy joint.
Angelito, he wants to hump.
Do I take him upstairs?
Yeah, what are you waiting for?
Angelito! They're here! They're parking!
Everything's ready. Gentlemen! Gentlemen!
Let's have some action. You come here to fuck, not to talk.
It's for you.
Your welcome present.
I'm sorry, I think you've got the wrong person.
Will you listen and take off those glasses, mom?
Don't call me that.
Please.
Whatever your problem is, don't call me that.
Call me bitch and dump the mummy business.
How old are you?
23.
I'm 33, or 34, I don't remember.
How could I be your mother?
Kid! Kid!
When they come in, release the balloons.
Just pull on the string.
I'm wearing glasses because I'm sick.
The prison doctor told me
I've got that thing you get in your head.
A brain "rumor".
Hang on. A brain "rumor"?
- You mean a tumor? - No, it's not that.
It says it on this paper.
A what?
Here.
A "tsunami"...
I forget things and I can't remember anything.
They say old people get this "salami" thing,
but the doctor said it's because I hit the bottle so much.
Alzheimer's.
She's got Alzheimer's.
Welcome!
Fucking hell!
Mobila!
Give me something or she'll bleed to death!
Here, mom, take this.
This is shit! And don't call me mom!
This is filthy! You want her to die of "disinfection"?
Get clean towels!
Come on, Mobila.
Come on, come on!
Yes?
- Push, push! - Princess, I can't talk.
Push, push! It's coming.
We need more beer...
For fuck's sake! That's nasty!
Push, push!
Get her out of my face.
Seen this makes me not ever wanna fuck again.
Hey,
listen, are you never going to come?
That's it! Push! It's coming! Push!
Princess...
That's it, it's here!
What can I tell you? Cut off your dick!
And leave us in peace!
It's here!
It's a boy.
What the hell was that?
I'm sorry, don't hurt me.
I won't hurt you.
- Please... - I won't hurt you.
You want to hit him, Ricky?
Do you?
It really relaxes you.
Hey,
your mother's in a bad way. She doesn't remember shit.
Angelito...
- I'm finished here. - OK.
Can I go and see Mobila?
Yeah, go on.
- You'll let me? - Yeah, yeah, go on.
Hey, Ricky,
what about the black girl?
What do you mean?
The baby. She can't fuck and feed it at the same time.
What do you want to do?
Well...
I don't know.
We could kill the baby.
What?
How can you kill a baby, asshole?
Drown it in a bucket, like kittens.
Are you sick in the head?
You're not going to kill anybody.
You hear? And much less a fucking baby.
- But... - No.
- Why not? - Because I say so!
- 0h, yeah? - Yeah.
You think you're so smart.
I was joking,
but now I really am going to kill it!
I'll take that black baby,
stick it in the oven and eat it with fries.
You're a piece of shit, Ricky.
I'll get this guy out of here.
We don't want him dying on our doorstep.
Largo...
It's Ricky.
Listen.
Remember that guy you mentioned who gets children
for couples who can't have them.
Yeah.
Call him for me.
I've got one.
Yeah, just born.
How much do they pay?
What's up, Ricky?
I'm taking him away.
Why?
This is no place for a baby.
He can't stay here.
I'll give him to Princess.
She'll take care of him.
He'll be OK.
All right, Ricky.
Are you sure about this?
Taking a child from his mother...
We're going to give this child a family.
A real family.
- All right? - Sure.
We're doing him a favor!
- No, Ricky! - Take him.
Just look at that darling face. He's like a little black angel.
Yes, you're such a cutie pie, aren't you?
Can you look after him?
This baby will be no trouble.
You're a gift from God.
I know it hurts, Mobi,
but the baby'll be fine.
And you're pretty, you'll do OK.
You have to go downstairs or Angelito will come and get you!
Look at this.
The pills I've got left for the "tsunami".
No one pays for my treatment out here.
I'll have to go back to jail.
No.
Not leave Mobila alone, please.
I'll tell you what.
If you go down,
I'll stay a few more days.
Those guys are clowns,
but you have to be strong, they can't see you cry.
So,
0K?
Come on.
You see, Ricky?
It's working.
Your mother's in her element.
She might be crazy as fuck but she was born to be a "madame".
Why hasn't she left yet?
This morning she told me she was broke.
I lent her 100 euros.
She's staying for a few days. Maybe you two can have a chat.
What do I say to her?
China doll!
And she looked all innocent and shit.
Maybe she doesn't remember she dumped you.
Maybe she doesn't want to remember.
But you have to show you've got balls
and say to her: "You are a bitch".
Then she can fuck off.
But at least you've got that shit out of your system.
It was my birthday yesterday.
38,
and what have I done?
Not one decent movie.
Well,
the other day I met a transvestite,
star material.
- Didn't you want a beer? - Yeah.
A transvestite.
She's got everything,
but she's having the operation.
Wise guy,
what did you do with the baby? Did you eat it?
What baby?
The black girl's baby.
- The black baby. - What baby?
The black baby, you bastard!
- What baby, Angelito? - The fucking baby!
Are you dumb?
Princess has him.
I spoke to Largo, we're selling him to a couple with money.
You smart bastard.
I'll see to it.
How much for the baby?
25?
Ask for 30.
How much does he get?
No, give it directly to the couple,
so find out who the hell they are.
Your move.
Where am I?
Where am I? Who are you?
I haven't introduced myself.
Everyone calls me Chino.
Don't believe all you hear about me.
Your move.
I don't know what I'm doing here.
I'm missing my queen.
My son won it from me in a game and I insisted he keep it as a trophy.
Since then, I play without a queen.
I don't know much about this.
But you know about other things, don't you?
I don't understand.
Don't lie to me.
Right now you'd like to be somewhere else, wouldn't you?
But, unwittingly, your movements
brought you here.
I'm not lying.
Very well.
I'm going to tell you a story,
a story about respect and about
how one must accept the consequences of one's actions.
Two months ago,
the police lifted my son.
For nothing.
He was drunk and got in a fight.
He was 19.
They hit him too hard.
He died right there.
It seems they got scared
and so
they got rid of his body.
You wouldn't know where they hid his body,
would you, Ricky?
What is this?
What do you want me to do?
Right now, just look.
I've got three policemen.
Actually, one of them died.
He didn't last long.
But first he helped me find the other two.
0ne of these bastards split my son's skull.
The other just watched.
In your opinion,
which is the guilty one?
It's hard, I know, because
all the police look like murderers,
but what do you think?
Get up.
Get up, come here and answer my question.
Don't make me get you.
Well?
Which of them is the murderer?
This one.
I didn't do anything!
Neither did my son.
I just obeyed the commanding officer!
We'll take care of him too when the time comes.
No! No!
Get the other one ready.
You're working here without my permission.
That means 50% of the take.
Plus a fine for not respecting your elders.
Let's say
100,000 within a week.
0K?
0r I'll burn the club,
with your mom inside.
Dear mother,
On September 10, my baby was born.
I have him with me now.
He is a beautiful boy.
I would like to go back soon to the sea,
to your side, so that my son can know his prandmother.
Shit!
Why are you in my bed?
What?
Are you trying to talk your way into my bed?
Don't try that little boy shit with me.
Fuck! Yes?
- Ricky! - Yeah, what?
Where the hell were you?
We're in really big shit...
I'm sick of this place. I'm leaving.
Ricky!
What?
It's Frida.
She'll beat the shit out of me if we don't give her a girl.
What?
- I'm going back to jail. - Will you shut up for minute?
He's hung up.
I wasn't going to tell you, but what the hell.
I've missed a period, I'm knocked up.
Christ!
And
I won't have a child out here where there's nothing,
so I'm going back to jail.
They'll look after me.
How are you pregnant?
- Princess... - Ricky.
You won't believe it.
The baby wouldn't take a bottle, and he grabbed on to my tits,
I swear on your mother that milk came out.
Well, maybe it was silicone,
but something came out.
Angelito...
Listen to me.
You've got a girl that I want.
And I want her tomorrow.
0r else this little shit
won't have a face.
She's a tall black girl.
No, that girl isn't available.
We can give you another girl.
You see, the director we work with
has taken a fancy to her.
He wants her for his new movie and I don't want to disappoint him.
Ricky, for fuck's sake,
if they want a whore let them have her.
0K, but we'll do it my way.
That's not what I want.
Listen...
First, let Angelito go.
If you keep your part, you get the girl tomorrow.
If not, there's no deal.
So you'll have to trust me.
That kid...
He's got a mouth on him.
"Pablo Diaz, son of Victor Diaz, alias Chino,"
"arrested July 23
after a street fight."
"He had head injuries."
"The officers said the prisoner struggled and fell down the stairs."
"After interrogation, the prisoner was released."
- Who signed the report? - You know.
Yes, you.
It's all very well that you protect your people,
but in the last 72 hours your whole team has vanished.
And you want me to believe this report?
That the boy left here alive?
Trust me,
or you'll be on your own.
Look what I bought for Mobila.
Lovely, isn't it?
Thanks, Rafaelito.
Ricky, my pal.
Fuck you, they nearly killed me!
But you're alive, aren't you?
- You hurt me. - You can go fuck yourself.
- Apologize to him. - Yeah, and I'll suck his dick too.
Since you last sucked my dick you want some more.
Cut out the fag stuff.
Come on, you know you can't get enough of it.
This is all for you.
- I'll beat the jokes out of you. - For you.
Come here.
Six, seven...
9,580, that's all there is.
Tell me how we can pay Chino.
No, you tell me.
The black girl's baby.
Weren't you going to sell it?
Yeah, 30,000.
We could bring the swap forward to tomorrow,
but it's not enough.
I could give back Mobila's present.
No, don't worry, Kid.
You tell him about the black girl?
What?
- What about Mobila? - Nothing.
Nothing.
Go up and see her.
Are you fucking stupid?
Are you going to tell him about Mobila?
I won't say I told you so, because you hate that,
but the one time I'm right...
- I told you so! - Yeah, you did!
I said to stay on the street
but you decided we could move up in the world.
Well, no.
We have to be down below, eating shit, you hear?
They're on a different level.
You know what Chino pays Loco?
50,000 euros.
For slapping somebody around.
The other day, Bobbie told me
that this week he'd get thousands more
for kidnapping a cop's daughter.
What?
Chino must want to fuck the girl.
He's a smart bastard.
I'd like to fuck her brains out.
A cop's daughter, a different level.
How much do you think he'll pay Loco to kidnap her?
Why, Ricky?
The girl goes to a school, so check it out.
There can't be many cops' daughters there.
And another thing,
we're going to turn the tables.
They won't fuck us, you hear?
They won't fuck us.
All right.
You take Mobila,
you bring her to Frida's store.
Look, it's all written down here.
Calculatinp the route.
- It talks. - Yeah, it talks.
You do whatever it tells you.
Then you pick up the chick with money.
And go where?
To the beach.
To the cove.
You leave her there. That's it.
If you have a problem, call me.
0K, and you're paying me 500 euros for this?
No messing.
Then I'll go back to jail and you'll never see me again
0K, tomorrow you leave.
You can go to jail or wherever you like.
I know that.
I know I promised you, love.
Veronica, it's impossible, I'm tied up all weekend.
I'll send someone I trust.
Yes, a policeman.
What the hell is it now?
I'll answer any way I want.
Doesn't he get worked up?
It turns me on.
I like men with a temper.
...you take the money...
Why is it that we women always go for the biggest bastards?
You should know.
No, you should.
Angelito treats you like shit and won't even let you go out.
I'll shut up.
No, it's true.
I don't get out much.
But where would I go?
Look, you take Mobila.
Leave her with Frida.
Who's Mobila?
She works here. Haven't you seen her?
He's hers.
Hers...
If we're gonna get possessive, I'm breast feeding him.
How nice.
You've brought me to a lovely spot.
- Relax, Marisa. - Yes, sure.
You want them to rob us and rape me?
- Marisa... - On our wedding anniversary.
- Relax. - Fucking unbelievable.
- This is what we agreed. - Great.
- Have you brought the package? - No, no package.
She has to come with me.
Yes, but...
Ricky said that. She can come or not, I don't care.
Darling, go with the lady, please.
Trust me.
This is my surprise?
How lovely... Don't touch me!
If I can get away from you...
It'll turn out that I'm the only one here with balls.
Girls, you got a light?
These "Basque" girls are so rude.
You're to take the baby
and go to the beach.
You'll meet a woman there.
Do you know where the cove is?
There.
Why don't I go to her house?
Don't you start too.
It's safest to do the exchange on the beach.
Now that you mention it,
am I bit overdressed?
I had a camouflage suit too, but an exchange...
I've never done one.
Princess!
Are you going to do it or not?
Are you sure about this?
You have to think about the baby's happiness.
They might be rich but maybe they're lousy parents.
Move your ass.
You are at your destination.
This is it.
Ricky told me very clearly.
Wait.
This is for you.
Give me a kiss.
Take care.
I'll take this,
and you guys, this.
What the hell is this?
A pellet gun. It's all I could find in two hours.
But if you half close your eyes,
it looks real.
Great, and the masks?
Fucking hell.
I knew I forgot something.
Kid, see if you can find anything we could use.
Another thing.
Let's synchronize our watches. This one's for you.
Don't laugh. For once, we're being professionals.
Fuck that.
They're paying me 500 euros for this.
Tomorrow I'll buy a shotgun,
go to a supermarket,
hold it up,
and that's it.
It's over there.
I'm not gonna sit here chatting all day long.
You're a pain in the ass.
Say Ricky sent you!
Excuse me.
Ricky sent me.
Great.
This is the black whore I asked for.
Call Frida.
I've been thinking,
and it isn't right to go round kidnapping people.
Yeah, like you've never kidnapped anyone.
The black girl.
That was because I love her.
Like hell you love her.
Have you told him about the black girl?
Tell him.
I'm going to run out of credit.
Hi, it's me.
I've got the money for the operation.
I've something to do, then I'll go to the studio.
0K, kisses, ciao.
That director...
Always on about me having a sex change.
It's not that I don't want to.
How can I put it?
Cinema,
you know, movies,
will always be there,
after I'm dead.
When you're older you can go and see it
and tell your friends: "Look",
"that one is my mother."
Shit, it's all so complicated.
Well,
now I have to put you in the dog carrier.
Ricky says it's safer.
Hey!
Are you here for the exchange?
Look at her, swimming in her clothes.
Like it was Ibiza.
Jet set people are so weird.
Hello.
I brought this for you.
But first give me the money.
You're a foreigner.
I'll do this fast before I change my mind.
I want to ask you something important.
Bath the baby every night at 9:30.
You mustn't miss a day.
And sing to him,
even in your language.
I always sing him to sleep.
Well,
look after him.
Ma'am,
everything OK?
Yeah, right.
Ma'am...
Ma'am, why are you running?
For fuck sake...
My mother always said that.
"You've got a suspicious face, you scare people."
Shit.
Let's move, they're here.
I'll get changed and we'll do something, 0K?
Right, put on your masks.
What the fuck are these meant to be?
Hi, there.
Everything OK?
Kid, she's there.
What a house.
Very nice, yes, indeed.
Very nice.
Cover her mouth!
Come on, Ricky!
Loco, drop the gun! Drop it!
Put it down!
0n your knees.
Drop the fucking gun, you bastard!
Come on!
Rocco?
Is that you, Rocco?
You're Rocco.
What the hell are you doing here?
We're together again, everything'll be fine.
Come on, for fuck's sake!
Pick up, dad, please.
It's all right, Angel.
It's all right.
Pick up, please! Pick up!
Hang up the phone.
Hang up the fucking phone!
Kid, listen to me.
We have to leave, the police are coming.
Angelito is dead.
No, Ricky.
You have to help me.
You have to help me. 0K, champ?
Yeah?
No, Loco can't come to the phone.
Listen, I have to talk to Chino.
Yeah?
Tell him I've got the cop's daughter and he might answer!
Kid, what are you doing?
Kid!
Kid! Where the hell are you going?
Kid, for fuck's sake!
Kid!
I've come for the new girl.
I'm taking her.
I don't want to hurt anyone.
Hello!
I've come to see the director.
Kid, why are you here?
Well,
Bad timing, right?
I'd better be going.
Tell the director
I've got the money for the operation.
I'll pick it up and go.
What lousy kind of money did she give me?
Princess...
What the hell's goinp on? I can't film with this racket/
What did you do?
Call an ambulance!
Mobila?
Where's Mobila?
Are you sure you heard shots?
- Come on, Kid, come on! - No, they've taken Mobila.
She isn't here.
For fuck's sake!
Come on, let's go.
They're not going to screw us.
They're not. Are you with me?
- Yes, Ricky. - They won't catch us.
This is blood.
Ricky, I'm dying.
No, you're not dying.
I'm going to die.
You're not going to die.
All right, all right, press here, Kid.
Hard.
I'll call a doctor.
You're going to be fine.
It's all right, Ricky.
It's all right.
Listen, Kid.
Chino is coming.
He'll give us a shit load of money for that girl.
When we have the money we'll get out of here.
Go far away.
It's me, Princess.
Hi, Princess.
I'm having my operation.
Begginers luck.
Just a minute, please.
They're poing to knock me out and I'm here chatting away.
I'd like you to come,
so I'm not alone.
I know this is just like cut and paste,
but I'm still kind of scared.
Please, let me go home.
Don't hurt me, let me go home.
Laugh a little bit, honey.
Life's sad enough without you looking like a wreck.
My father's a policeman.
A policeman?
That's perfect for me.
Go on.
Take this gadget
and call your father.
Dial the numbers.
Dad, it's Veronica!
It's Veronica! Dad!
Hang on.
Listen, we "did a kidnap" on your daughter.
I should get at least 20 years.
In jail.
What?
He says I'm nuts.
If you want to see her, you have to come here.
No police, nothing.
You have to arrest me.
Hold the line a minute, I'll give you the address.
Wait.
Hon, you know where this place is?
Give me a fucking break.
Where are the bandages?
They were here. Where are they?
You're always moving my shit around.
I had my bag of bandages here. Where is it?
Where is it?
I'm leaving.
You're not going anywhere. Look at me.
You're not going anywhere.
You don't fool me with your tough guy act.
Thank God, you're not Angelito.
I think that what you need is affection.
But you have to work at it.
It's easy to give up when you've been knocked down twice.
I'm telling you this
because I'm like you.
I go along with people
and I don't see that they're screwing up my life.
And life's too short, Ricky. It's too short.
Scrag...
My name isn't Scrag.
It's Soledad.
100,000, right?
The girl, please.
You surprised me.
You anticipated your opponent's move.
You deserve this money. Take it.
A lot of blood.
Did you have to sacrifice a pawn?
Up the stairs.
At the end of the corridor.
Wait.
What are you going to do?
You know.
Are you going to try to stop me?
You won't do anything. You know why?
You've taken the money.
Now we're both on the same side.
Come on, we have to go.
We both have to go,
together.
0K?
Where could we go?
You go on.
If the police come it's gonna be a mess.
I'm going to the toilet.
- Pregnant women piss all day. - You're not pregnant.
How do you know?
I was pregnant once and it was just like this.
- You were pregnant? - Yes.
And what happened?
Awful.
The priests made me abort.
Just as well.
Imagine a child on the street all day with a whore for a mother.
That scars you forever.
The best thing for that child
was not to be born.
Mom, look at me.
Look at me.
I'm Ricky.
Ricky, your child.
Your son.
Mom, I'm Ricky, your child.
Really, I'm so sorry.
I can't remember.
You abandoned me.
You dumped me on the street when I was 12.
Maybe your head doesn't want to remember, but you fucked me up.
I think you do remember.
What's that?
That's me.
And that's me.
You can't fool me. You're lying.
- That's me. - You're lying to me.
That's me, mom.
It's not true.
What the hell are you doing?
Why are you tearing up the photo?
- Mom... - Don't call me mom!
I'm not your mother!
I'm going to pee. When I come back I don't want to see you here.
I've called the police to take me to jail. That's where I should be.
- You... - Take it easy.
Where's my daughter?
Tell me now.
Don't move! You hear me?
Hey, you!
Where's my daughter?
Where is she, bitch?
Will you tell me now? Where is she?
Upstairs?
Dad...
Santos,
I knew you wouldn't want to miss this.
Let her go.
You going to shoot me?
Go on, try it.
Shoot.
Let her go.
If you're very lucky,
you might hit me.
But I won't miss.
Fire.
You won't fire?
Then drop your gun.
Drop it.
Don't worry, love.
I told you to drop your gun.
You tortured and killed my son.
I didn't do anything.
I swear.
What did you do with his body?
At least have the decency to tell me what you did with his body.
0r are you ashamed to tell me in front of your daughter?
She's a child.
She's not to blame.
Children are innocent.
They shouldn't pay for their fathers' sins.
It's not fair.
But who said the world was fair?
She can't hear you now.
Talk.
We didn't know it was your son.
When they called me and I got there and saw him,
he was already dead.
I had to protect my people.
We took his body out to sea
and sank it.
Now you'll see how I torture and kill your daughter.
Don't look like that. You're lucky.
The hope of seeing my son alive again destroyed me bit by bit.
I'll destroy you in one go.
What are you going to do?
Tell me.
What?
Don't worry, my love.
They say
that a split second before you die
your whole life passes before your eyes.
It's all a lie.
You can only think of one thing.
You think
how lucky the living are,
the ones still breathinp.
I want you awake.
Don't close your eyes.
Keep your eyes open!
You know something?
Maybe I won't go back to jail yet.
The truth is, the food's crap.
And things haven't gone so badly for us.
Mom...
What?