GOING PLACES
C'mere, sweetie!
Open up! Hurry!
I dream of you at night, Ursula.
I've been dreaming of you for months.
My name's not Ursula!
- What is it?
- Suzanne.
- How old are you?
- Dunno.
- Got kids?
- No.
- Why not?
- Dunno.
Oh, Ursula.
My Ursula.
15 francs.
Stupid bitch.
Bitches are cautious these days.
Screw-up after screw-up!
I'm sick of it!
Got a better idea?
Gimme money
and I'll come up with something.
THE HAIR COMPANY
Don't move...
What is it?
I have an idea.
What?
Look around. It's clear as day.
The engine's still warm.
Not again.
Isn't this great?
Feel that hydraulic suspension
under your ass?
Hydro pneumatics, man.
Don't be a scaredy-cat.
Did you shit your pants?
Don't worry.
We'll take the car back
and put it back exactly where it was.
The guy won't have time to report it.
Well?
Feel like a couple of idiots now?
Check out these two tough guys.
She's not bad, huh?
Only in your dreams.
I bet you'd love a feel...
In the meantime, hands up.
Bad timing, boys.
I just got my gun license.
Third time this year
someone steals my DS.
I've had my fill.
We didn't steal it.
We borrowed it.
We brought it back in one piece.
Exactly where we took it.
Save it for the cops.
- Go call them.
- That'd be stupid!
Don't get the cops involved.
We didn't hurt anyone.
We just went out for a spin,
to kill some time.
It's like you picked us up
hitchhiking on the side of the road.
Except you weren't there.
That's the only difference.
Let's not make a big deal of it.
We just used up some gas.
Not even a scratch.
You need to adjust the idle.
I've got a screwdriver.
I could do it right now.
Go on.
Don't listen to them.
Before you start crying
over their touching story.
- Please, miss...
- Hands up, I said!
- Want me to call the cops?
- Yeah.
-I'll call them.
-Wait!
I gotta tell you something first.
My pal and I got in trouble recently.
We got a suspended sentence.
- Next time it's jail.
- And we don't want that!
- We don't feel like it.
- You're pathetic.
I'll drive you there myself.
Give 'em haircuts first.
We're in France all right.
Watch out!
- Jean-Claude.
- What?
I'm bleeding bad.
- He needs a doctor.
- Mind your business!
What's all the racket?
Hide the DS and get us another car.
- Got any dough?
- I got something better.
Not leaving me with this guy,
are you?
What's wrong?
Don't I turn your crank?
What does endocrinology mean?
How should I know?
Hurry, it hurts bad.
Otorhinolaryngology?
We don't have a dictionary,
so screw their specialty!
I'm gushing blood here!
My pal here got shot.
Treat him or I'll smash your face
in front of your family.
A superficial wound in the left testicle.
Three stitches.
The bullet went in through his thigh,
avoiding the arteries.
- He lucked out.
- We always do.
We're lucky devils.
We got the Midas touch.
I'm glad to hear it.
For a minute there,
I was worried.
Our lucky streak continues...
Hand over your dough.
Sorry, I don't have any.
I never made it to the bank.
No kidding?
I'm even out of checks.
Or maybe you're taking me for a fool.
Search the place, then.
No...
I'd rather say hi to your two brats,
see if they've been tucked in.
Sometimes they have nightmares
and throw the covers off...
They might get sore throats.
Wait.
Bruno, give them something.
Here, it's the best I can do.
Wallet, Bruno...
You lowlife.
Goddamn lowlife.
That broad is a real dead fuck!
She doesn't bite or scratch,
just spreads her legs!
Just counts the flies till you finish!
What're you whining about?
You got off, didn't you?
Like screwing a piece of meat!
Beat it.
My pal needs to rest.
That tramp.
Doesn't even wear panties.
Come...
I'd like to go now.
Why no panties?
Will you answer my goddamn question?
Here.
- Wanna see what your boyfriend did?
- Don't tire yourself out!
What if I can't fuck anymore?
Ever!
- That bitch has to see!
- The doc said you're fine!
I'm not the one who shot you!
I could care less about his stolen DS!
- Who was that guy?
- My boss.
- Does he do you?
- I'm not happy about it...
That why you don't wear panties?
It turns him on
when I walk around like that.
Even at that time of the month?
Hey, don't be gross.
Let's see your papers.
- What do you do?
- Shampoo girl.
What do you shampoo?
- Dicks?
- Bald heads?
I need to get some sleep.
The salon opens at 9.
Shut your face!
Shut your face.
Hearing voices or something?
Guess what we'll do to her pimp.
Guess.
Jean-Claude...
- Listen closely.
- I'm listening.
Listen closely.
The guy seemed nuts about his car.
So we'll return it.
We'll leave it by the side of the road.
- Follow me?
- Yeah...
Now for the good part.
The cops find the car,
the pimp picks it up at the station.
The car's intact.
He drives away with it.
He's really happy, whistling away.
But what the jerk doesn't know
is that we tampered with it.
We sawed off the front wheel.
It's hanging by a thread.
Get it?
It'll come off at any turn!
So one fine day,
the guy's driving down the highway...
90 mph, hanging loose,
puffin' on a cig...
A Marlboro man.
Then, bam!
The wheel breaks off!
Brilliant, huh? Brilliant!
In a turn! Plenty of trees!
You're right.
That asshole's got it coming.
Now come sit.
Don't wear yourself out.
Since we'll probably never see you again,
we want a little favor from you.
Now I'll be late for work...
What is it?
We wanna touch your ass hairs.
It brings good luck.
OK, but make it snappy.
I don't wanna get in trouble at work.
I didn't know
it was supposed to bring good luck.
Of course.
Touching something dirty
always brings good luck.
- It's like walking in shit.
- Bastards.
Sure you're in the right place?
My mistake.
- Nice ears.
- Oh, yeah?
- They stick out just right.
- Careful, or I might box yours.
- A haircut every Saturday?
- No, I work Saturdays.
Shoplifters galore.
I arrest hooligans like you by the dozen.
That's good.
If everyone worked as hard,
there'd be less waste.
Bet you're great at dice.
Who told you that?
I know your type.
I come across tons of guys like you.
So clingy.
Came here for a good thrashing?
No, a coat.
American-style.
A birthday present for my brother.
It's back there...
on the right.
- The right?
- After the TV sets.
I'll frisk you at the exit.
Look...
Just got your first paycheck?
God, no.
I met a high-society woman.
She's nuts about me.
Ursula gives me anything
my heart desires.
Good for you.
That badge is useless.
People can smell that Brylcreem
from 500 feet away.
You're lucky.
I'm in a good mood today.
So am I. Life is beautiful.
I could almost hug you.
Watch your nose.
I might be inclined to smack it.
Say...
Do you grope the salesgirls?
Watch out or I'll give you a swift kick.
Jerk.
- We've got nothing in common.
- That's for sure.
- Yet I'm kinda fond of you.
- Likewise...
I feel like...
being closer to you.
If I weren't in a hurry,
I'd invite you to dinner.
You goddamn bastard!
Isn't this nice?
You see?
When people leave us alone,
the simple things make us happy.
It's hopeless!
They're like flies around shit!
It's like the world would come
crashing down if we died!
Slow down, will ya?
- My balls hurt.
- Pedal standing up!
I win the Pernod trophy!
Jerk!
Shit!
This is how people get caught.
That's mean.
He's still thirsty.
Don't go.
We just want Baby Jesus
to quench his thirst.
Take this
and give him something to drink.
- I don't want that.
- Please.
Come on, don't make such a fuss.
Your tits are hot.
I'm meeting up with my husband.
He's doing his military service.
In Angelras.
Is that right?
Isn't it cozier like this?
Isn't this nice?
What do you want?
Nothing.
Is it a crime
to contemplate my cash?
Is your husband on leave?
Yes.
When did you last see him?
Two months ago.
Rock 'n' roll.
Where will you go?
Dunno...
To a hotel.
Here.
For you.
What for?
I want you
to spend that leave
in the city's fanciest hotel.
In the most expensive suite,
with a private bathroom.
To scrub your stinky husband clean.
So you can get off on a spacious bed
and have champagne
brought up on a silver tray,
which you'll drink in the sack.
Interested?
- Yes...
- "Yes"?
But you'll have to earn this money.
How?
Breast-feed my pal here.
He loves milk,
plus he never knew his mom.
Whaddaya say, old man?
Yeah...
Go for it, then.
Don't you like it?
I'm not getting hard.
Angelras!
I have to get off!
That soldier's gonna get his rocks off.
We warmed her up for him.
What about me?
Why can't I get a boner?
That asshole pimp!
I hope he wipes out at a turn.
- Think he got his car back?
- No, it's way too soon.
- Cops are so fuckin' slow!
- There's no fire!
There is!
I can't wait to see him
in the accidents section.
- Got friends in the area?
- No.
- Why'd we come here, then?
- Gimme time.
I'm not a computer.
Just quit worrying.
Platform 4, train No. 1411.
Destination: Bridolle.
The train is about to leave.
Are you nuts?
What does "off-season" mean to you?
The million-dollar question.
A first-class town if ever I saw one.
Quaint, huh?
The cheapskates didn't even
leave any sugar behind.
But they did leave some
soundproof double-ply toilet paper.
How touching.
Granddad, Grandma,
Jacqueline...
Poor Jacqueline.
All alone with those old geezers.
That's where little Jackie sleeps.
Look what the sweetie pie left us.
Isn't that cute?
How old would you guess?
Dunno.
13...
14 at most.
Let's see...
She's much older, Pierrot.
Much older.
She's at least 16.
Have a whiff.
You're right.
Holy cow.
She's at least...
Jacqueline's a real lady.
It's like she just took them off,
like she's in the next room.
Jacqueline!
Jean-Claude...
Jean-Claude!
I can't get it up.
So? Neither can I.
What would we need to get it up for?
I usually get a morning hard-on.
It's too dirty, that's why.
You got so much shit on that thing,
you'd need a bulldozer to get it off.
Come on in.
This feels fantastic.
I can't.
My wound'll bleed!
Your feet won't bleed.
Clean them up a bit,
purify the air...
Don't worry.
It'll come back.
No reason why it shouldn't.
It's just psychosomatic.
It's because you can't get your mind off it.
Feels good, huh?
Takes a weight off, right?
See how handsome you are?
You almost turn me on...
- Take your hand off.
- What hand?
Take your hand off, fag.
- No need to be ashamed...
- It's not about shame.
I just don't feel like it.
How would you know?
If you've never tried...
Really think you can turn me on?
I want a woman. Get it?
Something attractive,
not repulsive.
Someone just came in.
I'll show you, old fag!
I feel humiliated!
Come on,
it's only natural between friends.
And I hate this town!
Lousy stinkin' town!
Lousy stinkin' France!
I get screwed everywhere I go!
Shut up or you're eating sand.
Jean-Claude...
- Why can't I get it up?
- I told you it'd come back!
Fuckin' pain!
What I need is a broad.
A hot one.
A broad who loves me.
There must be some goddamn tail somewhere!
Obviously!
But how to get it
without attracting attention?
We can't become priests
just to avoid the pigs.
And we're running low on funds.
- How much have we got?
- 100 francs.
Holy shit!
What?
I've got it.
- "Got" what?
- Everything!
Listen here...
We want some tail.
I found some tail.
We're out of dough.
I found some dough.
Come on.
Hey, what're you doing?
That's my bike...
Guys!
Hi.
Door!
If you wanna screw, go ahead.
None of your lip.
We didn't come for that.
We'll screw if we feel like it.
- Whaddaya want, then?
- News of your boyfriend.
- Which one?
- Your pimp!
He's not my pimp.
He can screw himself!
And screw you too, dirty fags!
Say that again.
What'd you say?
Nothing.
They're small,
but it hurts anyway, huh?
- You're a whore, right?
- Yes!
Repeat it!
- You're a hooker, right?
- Yes, a dirty hooker.
- Who sucks hairdressers.
- "Who sucks hairdressers."
- Who doesn't wear panties.
- "Who doesn't wear panties."
You slut.
- Your pimp got his car back?
- Yes.
- Is he happy?
- About what?
- Getting his nice car back.
- I could care less.
Answer me!
He sold it.
- He sold his DS?
- Yes.
- To who?
- To some car salesman.
Filthy bastard.
When I think of the poor people
who'll buy that scrap heap.
Do I take off the rest or what?
Here you were whining
about your rod for two weeks.
Take it easy.
I'm getting seasick.
Calm down.
Don't get so excited.
Take your time.
Negotiate.
Wow. Great performance.
3.5 minutes.
That's what I call a sprinter.
You got there so fast,
she never left the starting gate.
- I'll go again!
- After me, if you don't mind.
Watch and learn, old man.
Admire the professionalism...
It's all about finesse.
Nice and easy does it.
We have the whole night ahead of us.
First you rev her up,
to get the juices flowing!
Then back into first...
You gotta make her want it.
Right, sweetie?
Then back into high gear!
- Am I hurting you?
- No...
- Sure?
- Yeah, yeah.
- 'Cause they usually suffocate.
- No, I'm fine.
You realize you're in the hands of a stud?
- You OK?
- Yeah, I'm fine.
Why are you always like that...?
Like what?
Dunno...
You just lie there.
She could care less
for your smooth talk.
She prefers me.
Then be my guest, old man.
She's all yours.
Make her come
and I'll buy you a bottle.
Look at that...
What a cold fish.
Can't you make an effort,
show a bit more enthusiasm?
How, with you yelling in our ears?
Quit bugging us.
I'll go pee.
At least I'll feel something.
Only yogurt in here.
If you're bored, just say so.
No, not at all...
Well, that's not working.
Flip over.
- Her eyes closed?
- No.
- Biting her lips?
- Sweating under the arms?
- No.
Shit, I give up!
Why bother wearing my rod out?
She's a hole with pubes around it.
An unfeeling aperture.
A patient on an operating table!
I bet she could stay like that for hours.
You can flip over.
The fuck is over.
Have you no modesty?
Please. She could care less.
Sorry we're not more romantic,
Marie-Ange...
- Don't you ever get off?
- Dunno...
I don't mind.
- What do other girls do?
- They enjoy themselves!
They moan,
thank you with their eyes...
Their eyes roll back
till you see the whites.
Just teach me.
- Wanna try?
- No way.
She's all yours.
Fine...
C'mere, boy.
You like that, huh?
- Kiss me.
- Not now.
Where's the till?
Everything in its own time.
First the cash.
There's only change.
Could be a booby trap.
- Try with your knife.
- Obviously.
- There an alarm on here?
- There an alarm?
Hey, is there an alarm on it?
Well, anybody in there?
Fuck you.
That clear? Fuck you!
I'll give you an alarm right now!
- You lost your mind?
- I wanted you to kiss me!
I'm not some goddamn revolving cunt!
Stop it!
Stop or I'll shoot you!
Bastard...
Bastard!
You can't abandon me here.
You can't leave me here, guys!
Wanna play another one?
Listen, chicks, it's 11.
We can't spend all night
clowning around with balls.
Since we'll end up in bed anyway,
let's not waste any more time.
How presumptuous!
- You think all girls are that easy?
- Of course they are!
Obviously.
We just bought a new car,
great seats...
As good as sofas.
- Can you believe it?
- You got a screw loose?
To tell you the truth,
we could care less.
Sex or no sex,
it's no skin off our noses.
'Cause we've had enough
of dead weight like you!
Know what I mean by "dead weight"?
Girls who just lie there!
I'm not ruining anything, old man.
The place is full of girls like them.
Look around.
They've been ogling us for over an hour.
Don't think you're so special.
Come on, Ginette, we're going.
You do that, and good riddance.
Know what you are? Hicks!
Now that's a good one.
You didn't even remove the price tags.
What about your drinks?
- So we're stuck with the check.
- You're an idiot!
- We were gonna screw 'em.
- Screw what?
More dead meat? No, thanks.
We can't spend our lives doing dead meat.
But you don't care.
You'd fuck anything.
But I wanna hear her whimper.
You know, that sound
that comes from deep down,
like a creature that you strangle,
that goes...
Excuse me, miss.
At night,
do you sometimes go...?
You're nuts!
And you wanna bother with that?
It's not worth it, Pierrot.
We're better than that.
Life is too short.
No more shampoo girls.
Know what you need?
You need to spend the night
with a real woman.
- A tiger!
- I'm all for it!
Not the type that goes...
A fighter.
You don't know which end is up.
You think it's over,
but she swoops in again!
A woman who wants it bad.
A woman who hasn't had it
in a long time...
- An old bag, you mean.
- I never said an old bag.
A nun, then.
They must be hungry for it too.
- Count me out.
- Hold on.
I'm on the verge of something.
- What, a new idea?
- It's simple, old man.
If I'm not mistaken,
it's my best yet.
My masterpiece.
Go on, tell me.
A woman like you've never dreamed of...
- Someone you know?
- No.
But we'll soon meet her.
- How much do we owe you?
- We're going right now?
No choice, it's 700 km away.
Where are we going?
What's this brilliant idea?
A reservoir...
A private hunting ground.
300 women. That ring a bell?
All dying for it.
You barely touch 'em
and they explode!
Stick your finger in and it burns.
"300 women"?
You gone bonkers?
We can't do an old lady.
She's so plain.
I find her beautiful.
What do you want?
Nothing.
Just to help you.
- Why?
- No reason.
We saw you being released.
I don't want your help.
She's a loon.
Who wouldn't be?
Who are you?
Nobody. Just two friends.
Can't you leave me alone?
Especially today.
Can't you see you're bothering her?
Shut up and get the car.
Unbelievable.
Un-fucking-believable!
Wait!
Don't be scared.
There's no reason to be.
Put this on before you catch a cold.
Where are you going?
Do you even know?
No.
Got any money?
50 francs.
Got anyone to call?
No.
We'll take care of you.
I'm sick of being taken care of.
Come on.
My friend'll be back with a car.
Heated, with nice seats.
And you need a change of clothes.
- Got any in that suitcase?
- No.
There you go.
No money, no clothes,
no place to go...
You're in a fix.
- What do you suggest?
- Everything.
My friend and I are at your disposal.
We've got a car and plenty of cash.
I don't trust you.
Need help?
Hey, beat it!
- Leave us alone!
- Why are you so rude?
I said, "Beat it!"
Why's he pushing us?
Here.
Now do you trust me?
OK, first things first.
What would you most like to do?
Nothing special.
We can't drive around all day.
- Let me off, if you like.
- No, that's not what I meant.
I simply wanted to know...
Can't you leave her alone?
You insisted she get in,
so you make the plans.
Yeah, you're right.
First we need to get you
some warm clothes.
- You must be cold.
- A bit.
- And my feet are sore.
- That's it, we'll go shopping.
We should really split.
I don't like the woman.
She gives me the creeps.
I don't trust her.
If you ask me, she's trouble.
Split if you want.
You can keep the car.
No.
Thanks.
Easy.
- Why?
- Take it easy.
You have to take your time.
You're right.
All done.
You OK?
Yeah.
Thank you.
For what?
For everything, the meal...
I don't get it, but thank you.
You're beautiful.
No...
Not exactly fetching.
How old are you?
25.
- And you?
- 23.
How old do you think I am?
The tide's up.
What do you do?
You, for example.
Do you work?
He's a mechanic.
We work in a garage together.
- Is business good?
- Not bad.
Would you consider
sleeping with an old broad?
Yes,
but I don't see any around here.
- You?
- No.
'Bye, ma'am.
- Thank you so much.
- No, thank you.
No, I insist.
Lunching here was wonderful.
I just spent 10 years in prison,
in a cold and damp cell.
I haven't had a period in ages.
At first I was just late.
They sent me to the infirmary.
They gave me aspirin.
Then I was later and later:
two, three weeks, a month...
I gradually stopped thinking about it,
until they stopped altogether.
Why tell me all this?
Just so you understand how lucky you are
to have regular periods,
even if it makes you crabby.
That stuff's not important:
mood swings, jumpiness, cramps...
That's nothing.
The worst part
is not having periods anymore.
Good-bye, ma'am.
Easy, easy...
Easy.
- I got my period, by the way.
- Shut the fuck up!
It's all over...
It'll be all right.
Shit.
Son or daughter?
It's signed "Jacques."
They're all from Jacques.
- How old is he?
- He's just a kid.
Jacques Pirolle?
Yes, that's me.
Your mom sent us.
Where is she?
- Wasn't she released?
- Yes, but she's abroad.
- Where?
- Portugal.
She could've written.
Not a word in three months.
What's she doing in Portugal?
She left with a friend of ours,
a great guy, an agronomist.
- What's his name?
- Loiseleux.
Don't worry, he's very reliable.
He spent two years in Cuba
as a technical advisor.
Now he's on a job in Sierra Leone.
If he's so great,
why doesn't he work in France?
'Cause he's got a record.
- What'd he get?
- One year inside, two on parole.
OK... What kind of car you got?
- American.
- Let's go.
And what do you do?
Nothing. We've been waiting
three months for you.
Her name's Marie-Ange.
She's our girl.
Now she's yours too.
She's consenting.
She's no goddess,
but there are worse lays.
Only one little hitch:
She never comes.
So if she's quiet and still,
that's just the way she is.
We've been trying for weeks...
A total washout.
Hi...
- Care for some coffee?
- Sure.
- Not hungry?
- I am.
- Want some jam?
- Dunno.
I think the newbie
wants a tour of the place.
You should show him around.
We share everything here.
Go ahead.
It's our pleasure.
Doggie-style is her forte.
I highly recommend it.
The first cigarette of the day
is always the best.
Yeah...
Gets your mouth into shape.
- Did you hear that?
- What?
Listen...
Pierrot!
Jean-Claude!
I did it!
It happened!
- What happened?
- I came!
You're a goddamn pain!
That'll cool you off!
I came!
- What the hell did he do to you?
- Nothing special.
- The usual?
- I swear.
Impossible.
He must have some trick.
- No...
- We know all the tricks.
- Actually, I did everything.
- How's that?
- You usually just lie there.
- Exactly, he was doing the same.
- Stage fright?
- I'll say.
He was shaking all over.
He was looking at my body,
but he was scared to touch me.
I had to undress him myself.
Then all of a sudden,
he came in my hands...
- He apologized...
- That's not what made you come.
Let me finish!
So I held him against me
and said,
"Crying'll make you feel good."
So he started crying,
but while awkwardly making love to me.
And just as suddenly,
he came a second time.
After about a minute.
- How complicated.
- I'm not finished!
It all started after our third try.
I asked if I was his first woman.
He said yes
and started making love to me again.
Slowly, while kissing me.
- And then...
- We get the picture.
But then...!
I swear...!
Shall I serve you?
If it's not too much trouble.
Any meat left in there?
Seems you have a gun?
- Who told you that?
- The girl.
Great going.
Not bad.
Yeah...
But nothing to write home about.
Interested in our gun?
Yes, actually.
Why?
'Cause it's a work tool.
Plan on getting back to work?
Someone has to.
We're flat broke.
How does an old couple's nest egg sound?
Depends.
I got a tip from a cellmate.
Easy and risk-free.
They're retired and defenseless.
We'll take stock of the risks ourselves.
I don't mind going alone,
but I need a gun to persuade them.
Do we lend it to him?
I don't give a shit.
It's your decision.
Here. Good luck.
Thanks.
I told you they'd chicken out.
Let's go.
Pirolle!
Now that's what I call a surprise.
I'm with friends.
I'll be right out.
Hey, what's going on here?
Pirolle!
Jean-Claude, Pierrot...
Hello, boys.
Good timing, I have champagne.
Well, come in.
Jacques...
Is this some kind of joke?
Better get your cash and fast!
- What cash?
- Forget the cash.
Come on, Jacques... Pirolle.
I've never done anything to hurt you.
Get the chaplain, if you want.
Tell him there was another suicide attempt,
that the victim needs comforting.
Don't do anything rash.
- Floor it!
- Where's Jacques?
I said, "Floor it!"
Why'd he do it?
Who knows?
Ex-cons probably all have a screw loose.
Want us to hold it for you?
Where are we going now?
No idea.
If we don't know where we're going,
we could stop somewhere.
We'll get there eventually.
- Stop to do what?
- Have sex.
This isn't the time, sweetie.
Only thing that counts
is getting away from that dead man.
Please fuck me.
I have to know...
Don't be mean.
You know about her problem...
OK, fine, but I'm not stopping.
Do it in the backseat.
Come on!
Want me to have an accident?
Yes!
I feel it!
It's coming!
I'm gonna come!
It's gonna be big!
Careful, it oversteers.
What's going on?
"What's going on?"
They stole our goddamn car!
MURDERERS OF A MODEL WARDEN
Get out.
What's going on?
This is where we part ways.
- What'd I do?
- Nothing. That's just it.
But we're accomplices to murder.
We've become a burden
for a nice girl like you.
You have to leave us...
Just when I'm starting
to enjoy myself? No way.
Shit!
You're nuts.
The thought of you
rotting in jail makes me sick.
You're too pretty, too fragile.
You need love and affection.
We won't go to jail.
You hear me?
We won't go to jail. I'm sure.
Where's my car?
I'd left it right here,
with the motor running...
Goddamn piece of junk!
What a fuckin' lemon!
Lousy stinkin' proletariat!
We're nice guys!
But you're mean!
Asshole!
Why aren't these bastards stopping?
We'll have to steal another one.
I feel like a Resistance fighter,
minus the fur-lined jacket and the beret.
What the hell is he doing?
Comrades!
My car fascinate you that much?
We find it irresistible.
The nerve!
Do something, Henri!
Don't mind us!
Join us, while you're at it!
We wouldn't want to impose.
What do you want, then?
A car, silly as that sounds.
You've already got one,
so leave us alone!
OK, fine.
Honestly!
Don't do anything stupid, boys...
I believe they will.
- Think this is funny?
- Rather.
Jacqueline!
We'll just finish our trip
with another car.
Jacqueline!
- Is her name really Jacqueline?
- Got a problem with that?
- Jacqueline...
- What's that supposed to mean?
- The bikinis...
- "Bikinis"?
- The scent...
- What scent?
The scent, ma'am, the scent.
They're out of their minds!
And who's she?
- Hi.
We just wanna trade.
Our jalopy for your limousine.
An old model, lots of fun.
And it's still a Citroën,
like driving your DS's ancestor.
It's a great deal!
He just doesn't get it.
I forbid you to touch my DS!
Watch it!
- This hurts a lot.
- Especially upside your head!
Who cares about your DS?
A car's a car.
It's beautiful out, Dad.
We're on vacation.
Tonight we're going to the seaside.
I just got kicked out of school.
Isn't life wonderful?
Creep!
Loser!
Little shit!
Stinkin' engineer!
Know what your only daughter says?
I'm not going anywhere with you!
No more volleyball, tennis and shrimp!
I've had it!
Please take me with you.
We'll take their DS.
I can't be with them anymore!
If I don't get away from 'em,
I'll just die!
I swear I won't cramp your style!
We can't do that.
It's a shame, but we really can't.
It'd be criminal to take you with us.
You can't abandon me here!
I've burned all my bridges!
Please take me.
OK, we'll drop you off somewhere.
- There are 200,000 francs in Mom's purse.
- Great.
- How old are you?
- 16.
- Ever had sex?
- No...
You're kidding?
No...
Poor dear!
Do you realize?
We can't let her go like that.
Thanks for everything!
And now?
Where'll we go now?
Dunno, quit bugging us.
I'd still like to know
where we're going.
Simple curiosity.
He said he didn't know
and to quit bugging him.
Quit worrying.
Everything'll work out.
They can't put a hole in our ass.
We already got one.
We can't just drive aimlessly,
till we run out of gas.
Why not?
Aren't you happy?
Isn't this nice?
Yes.
Peacefully.
In the cool of the evening.
Hanging loose.
(subtitle from http://shooter.cn by SPlayer™)
We can fuck anytime we want to.