Jeun Jee-hyun
Cha Tae-hyun
MY SASSY GIRL
Exactly two years ago today,
she and l buried
a time capsule here.
We promised to meet here
two years Later,
but she hasn't come yet.
I知 going to wait.
Here we go.
Please don't move.
One, two...
Wait a minute.
Hello? Oh, auntie.
Sorry, I知 on my way.
I知 really sorry. Yes, I知 coming.
I知 having my photo taken.
Bye.
Are you ready?
Here we go.
One, two...
My parents wanted a daughter,
so they raised me like one.
So l thought l was a girl
until l was seven.
l had to go to the women's
public bath, too.
The older l got,
l thought my penis would
get smaller and disappear.
But it was the opposite.
First Half
He hasn't changed at all.
No, I知 a real man now.
Hey, asshole.
Think clerical work in the
army makes you a man?
You irritate me!
Give me a break, asshole.
My job was tougher than you could imagine.
Hey!! l worked near the DMZ.
Who are you kidding?
Hold it. Anyway, welcome back home.
She's just my type.
When I see my type,
I can't help it.
l need to hit on her.
Who's interrupting me?
Hello? Who is this?
Your mother, you bastard.
Oh, mom...
Why aren't you at your aunt's house?
I知 leaving soon.
Keep quiet! It痴 my mom!
Talk over there!
Make sure you pay a visit.
It痴 been over a year since you saw her.
That long?
You know she feels lonely after
losing her son last year.
She says you resemble him.
She'll be so glad to see you.
Still there?
We don't look alike.
Plus, l hate when she rubs
my face and kisses me.
Uncle does, too.
She'll introduce you to a girl. Hey!
l know the type she likes.
Tell her no thanks.
l want to meet a girl like the ones
in romantic comic books.
But on that day...
She's my type, but l don't like her.
Why?
Drunk girls disgust me.
Hey, get up!
Offer your seat to the elder!
Ugh!
Go!
Hey.
Don't wear pink.
Honey!
She call him honey!
I知 not...
What are you doing!
You handle this!
I知 not...
Think I知 stupid?
Come here!
Are you laughing?
Why didn't you look after her?
Hurry and do something!
What are you doing?
I知 sorry.
Let me help with cleaning expenses.
Forget it. Just take care of her.
Nothing's there when you need it.
Where did all those motels go?
l hate being with a drunk girl.
Carrying her on my back is worse.
Wow, your honeys wasted.
No, it's not my fault.
Of course, it is. l know everything.
You see, we're engaged.
Western or Korean style?
Give me any room.
Room 405.
None on the first floor?
Fourth floor!
You forgot to check in.
It痴 40,000 won, kid.
What? 40,000 won?
Why? Find another place then.
Count it.
Hello?
This phone's owner?
She's sleeping beside me.
What? Here?
The Uk-su motel near Bupyung station.
Better wash and leave fast.
Aha~!
Hands in the air!
What are you doing?
Aaggh~~~~~~!
All of you.
Eat one a piece, okay?
Yes, boss.
What are you looking at?
Look away.
Gyeon-woo! You're out!
Did you go to Bupyung?
Yes, l did.
Come here!
Where did you sleep?
Your aunt said you didn't come!
And you're telling me a lie!
What happen to your sweater?
I知 such a poor guy.
All this cause of a drunk girl.
l wanna die.
You asked if l went to Bupyung!
l did, but not to see auntie!
What?
Bastard! Wait till he comes back.
Know me now, right?
I知 a typical student.
An engineering major.
Study?
I知 smart, but l never study.
My parents can prove that.
You're smart like me,
but studying is your problem.
Since you inherited
your brain from me,
you'll get good grades
if you study harder, idiot.
Up four points in three years.
Call this a report card?
Since you inherited
your brain from your mom,
you'll get good grades
if you study harder.
lf you raise kids,
never tell them they're smart.
They'll never study.
My goals?
Haven't thought about it yet.
You know now?
You got it.
I知 a hopeless student.
Hello?
Who are you, asshole?
What? Who's calling?
Why were you naked
in a motel with me?
What?
Come out!
To Bupyung station now!
Uh...
How could she do this?
l went to jail and got beaten
with a vacuum for her.
Excuse me.
Is it you?
Yes?
Follow me.
Get over here.
What do you wanna eat?
Cherry jubilee...
Mango Tango or Shooting Stars...
Jamonka Almonds good, too.
I値l just have a Love Me.
Hey, wanna die?
Drink coffee.
Two coffees.
You pay for it.
Girl:Tell me.
What happened last night?
Well, it's...
You were drunk, so...
Don't stumble, and speak clearly!
You see.
You were drunk and staggering
at the subway station.
l saved you from the train.
l thought maybe this girl was a snake.
Pretending to be drunk
and vomiting
to use the guy
in a state of confusion.
So l called you honey?
That's right.
l kind of remember that.
You showered to wash
off vomit and sweat,
and the police came?
Gyeon-woo:That's right.
Would you believe that, too?
To a girl like this, you need to
show her who's the boss.
So l did that, right?
Yes, you did.
Sorry, it's late.
Yeah...
When she's not drunk,
she's just my type.
You look prettier and livelier
than yesterday.
Are you mocking me?
No, I知 not.
Then are you hitting on me?
l don't wanna date you.
We're not destined
for each other.
Throw the trash away.
Damn it.
l think she's a heavy drinker.
You order.
Kimchi soup and Soju, please.
Eat Golbangee.
Then you should order.
Stop pouting!
Golbangee, please.
Let's go somewhere fun later.
Teenage girl 1 :l know what that means.
A motel? Are you rich?
-Of course.
How much will you give us?
We'll see, so don't worry.
You kids are prostituting, huh?
Why'd you order Golbangee?
Eat something else!
Teenage girl 1 :What's it to you?
Mind your own business.
We're just having a drink with
some friends. What's wrong?
You take friends to a motel?
How old are you kids?
Teenage girl 1 :Old enough to drink.
Mind your own business.
Think I知 doing this
'cause you're drinking?
Show me your lD.
You, too.
Teenage girl 1 :What's with you?
Show it, now.
Teenage girl 1 :This sucks.
She's a vicious chick.
No matter how pretty she is,
I知 too embarrassed to be with her.
Who are you to butt
in other people's business?
Don't you have a daughter?
l don't. Bear me one.
Who the hell do you think
you are?
How dare you?
Come on, let's fight!
Come on! I値l show you.
Don't live like that!
Catch the girls.
Have a drink and calm down.
Shit!
Ah~!
Huk~!
Seeing a girl cry
makes me sad for some reason.
She's more attractive
the closer l look at her.
Did you blow
your nose on this?
No.
Huk~ huk~ huk~~~!
Please stop crying.
Also...
The handkerchief is mine.
To be honest,
l broke up with
my boyfriend yesterday.
Excuse me.
Wake up.
Come on, wake up.
Your fiances wasted again?
What now?
Sign you in like before, right?
Yes.
But mister, have any medicine
for alcohol?
No, you buy it.
l saw her lips.
Her white neck.
And...
l saw her breast, too.
While watching her
sleep like a baby,
it may be forward,
but this occurred to me.
l want to heal her sorrow.
Give me some water.
Hey.
Why am l here?
You see.
I知 sorry,
but l saw your lD,
and you're twenty-four.
lf you talk down on me again...
So what are you gonna do?
Just that...
Nothing.
Give me the towel.
Yes. You see, I知 a year older.
Then talk like friends.
Yeah?
Toothbrush.
Toothpaste?
In the bathroom.
Our relationship
is so peculiar.
We met only three days ago,
and slept twice in a motel.
That's how our
relationship began.
Lee Hyung-chul.
Here.
Jeun Mi-young.
Kang Man-gyu.
Yep.
Gyeon-woo.
Is he absent?
No, no!
I知 here!
Then answer right away.
Phew! Gonna be sucks!
Lee Jeung-min.
Here.
Gu Seol-soo.
Yes, I知 here.
Professor. How about a break?
You're right. Let's take a break.
Let's go.
Go where?
Class isn't over yet.
Don't be a coward.
He called roll, right?
Let's go.
l can't. l can't miss this class.
Kill me instead.
All right.
Who is she? She's pretty.
Pretty? Doesn't matter.
A girl needs to act pretty.
But she's still pretty.
Nice body, too.
Who's Gyeon-woo?
It's me, sir.
l won't mark you absent
so you can leave.
Pardon me?
l said leave.
Why?
Wasn't that girl
your girlfriend?
So go see her.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, Gyeon-woo.
lf you can, raise it with her.
It worked.
What did you tell him?
That I知 getting an abortion,
and you're the father.
What?
No, no!
Professor, it's not true!
She wanted
to be a scriptwriter,
so she kept writing stories.
She called them synopsis.
To get me into the mood, she took me
to the park to read them.
Reading her synopsis
was stressful.
lf l miss anything, I知 dead.
Wanna die?
Finish reading it.
l will.
Mister! How could
you throw the butt here?
Pick it up!
And why did you
wear that colour?
Man on the street:
Then what about you?
Don't wear the same
colour as mine!
The heroine is
tough, like the 'Terminator'.
The year is 2137.
Villains kidnap her lover
and travels to the present.
l don't know why.
To save her lover,
she travels in a time machine
to the present.
Aaggggggghh~!
Bang! Bang!
Uuh~ ack!
Fizz~ Bang!
Click!
Bang!
Uuuaaaaahh~~~
Bang! bang! bang!
They have to kiss in the end.
This isn't a melodrama.
It痴 an action movie.
You don't know movies.
Koreans like melodramas.
Why?
Know what novel touched us
when we were teenagers?
Shower by Hwang Sun-won.
It shaped our people's
sensibility in their teens.
Koreans like sad movies
all because of 'Shower'.
Shower? What's sad about it?
It痴 sad when she asked
to be buried in the clothes
reminiscent of her love.
l couldn't sleep for one week.
The ending sucks.
Gotta change it.
How?
It痴 sad. Her family couldn't afford
to pay for her medicine.
Their family line
is broken up now.
But you know, she must have
been an extraordinary girl.
Why?
This was her last request.
When l die, please bury me
with my loving friend.
What?
To bury him alive, even.
Oh, my gosh.
What's the matter?
What's wrong?
No way!
This is wrong!
Please. Don't!
Bury him!
They bury him alive.
Isn't it sad?
l must be hurt still.
l think I値l never get over him.
How deep could it be?
l don't know.
Gyeon-woo, go in the water.
l wanna know how deep it is.
Come on.
Uuaaaah~!
Help me!
Wow, it's deep.
l can't swim!
Yes, it's deep...
My mind was getting blurry.
At that moment...
Heard you
got a girlfriend.
Introduce me.
Really?
I知 serious.
Is she pretty?
Have you kissed her?
Girlfriend?
Gonna introduce me or not?
She really pretty?
What are you looking at?
See that girl over there?
She's my girlfriend from today.
Got it?
Hey...
Excuse me...
Hey, baby.
Are you free?
Hey?
What?
Baby?
Hey! Come here.
Hmm!
How could
a coincidence like this happen?
Reportedly say there is
an accident of runaway soldier...
Hello?
You call a wrong number
or the dial is not in service.
Please, call again.
You call a wrong number
or the dial is not in service.
Please, call again.
Let's drink.
Drink till we die.
Since I知 drunk,
l decided to take revenge on her.
lf I知 out cold
at Bupyung station,
then she'll have to carry
me on her back.
This stop is Bupyung station...
Hey, kid.
Wake up. Wake up.
Where am l?
I知 at Inchon station.
Be here in 30 minutes.
Wake up.
Get up, idiot.
Go away, buttbrain.
Talking back?
Get up, bastard!
What the...
How're you?
Hi!
How are you?
Oh, how is it going?
What?
Go away, buttbrain?
You got a bad mouth.
I値l set you
straight the gangster's way.
On your head.
Get up.
Sit down. Get up. Sit down.
Roll right. Roll left.
Do it right.
Keep going!
What's going on there?
Stop fooling around.
Hey!
You low-life thieves.
What officer?
Keep quiet.
Low-life thieves?
Damn it.
Hey. Want some of this?
No thanks.
Try it. It痴 delicious.
No.
Hey, boy.
Pay attention to your elders.
Eat it, buttbrain.
l told you no.
How many times did l tell you?
Am l your toy? Leave me
alone you petty thieves!
Stop toying with me, you jerks!
It痴 humiliating!
Oh, shit!
Good morning.
Keep quiet!
Thank you. Thank you.
You bastard!
Do that again,
and you're dead.
What? Are you free, baby?
Your English is good, too.
Better behave!
Wanna die?
Taste good?
It痴 so delicious.
lf l sleep out, mom beats me with
whatever's in her hand.
lf she's sweeping,
it's a broom stick
lf she's cleaning,
it's a vacuum.
When I知 lucky,
it's a cucumber or eggplant.
So l have to come
at the right time.
You're not looking
at dirty pictures, right?
Of course not, dad.
You don't trust me?
No, l do.
Time for bed.
Go to sleep.
Good night, dad.
Hi, Gyeon-woo.
My birthday's in two days.
You're dead if you forget.
Got it?
Since l like you so much,
better make me smile like this.
Got it?
l got it.
Phew~~
Her birthday.
lf l prepare nothing,
she may murder me.
l have a good idea.
Before going to the service,
l worked in a theme park.
So this is my plan.
At midnight, I値l be alone
with her in the park.
It'll be completely dark
all around us.
One by one, the lights
to the merry-go-round flick on.
l raise my arms up there,
and her birthday song starts.
Then all the lights turn on
and it moves.
There's fireworks, too.
Isn稚 it fantastic?
She'll be thrilled.
l gave 200,000 won
to my friends working there.
Jump over here?
Yeah. We have to.
l always wanted to
come here at night.
It痴 my birthday, not yours.
Please, let's just try.
I値l go up first
and help you.
Eh? There's a step here.
Take my hand.
Oh, shit!
Shit!
Gyeon-woo.
Hey!
Answer me.
I知 leaving. I知 leaving.
Answer me!
You're dead.
Wait till l catch you.
Why didn't you answer?
Wanna die?
Come with me!
Hurry and get in.
Shut up!
Go in fast. Move it.
Sit here.
lf you're loud, I値l kill you.
Got it?
Yes.
Answer quietly!
Is that a real gun?
Wanna see?
Forget it.
How are you two related?
We're just friends.
Why are you here?
We just wanted to
come here at night.
Tell me the truth, idiot.
Nothing special.
Bullshit.
What makes you
trust a guy like him?
l trusted myself.
l had a girlfriend, too.
She visited me
every week for one year.
l was so happy.
But that bitch fell in love
with the guard house sergeant.
l found out the fact
after he was discharged.
Damn it.
While I知 in the service,
even my dog...
ran away with some mutt, too.
My Yorkshire terrier.
Bitch.
Fuck. l came out to
kill both bitches. Fuck.
l have the worst luck
in this world.
Damn it.
Know what special day
is it today?
Huh, damn it?
This sucks!
Uuuuuuuhhh~ ack!
Hey, what are the odds to meet
a runaway soldier in a park?
Don't know.
Heard your head blows up
if you shoot in the mouth.
Yeah, the hole in your head
is this big.
That's serious.
A teeny bullet does that?
Yeah, the bullet tears the...
Hey! What are you two doing?
Stop joking around.
Damn it. Damn it!
Even you bastards ignore me.
That's why don't be foolish.
Why am l foolish?
Even if you do this,
she won't come back.
l know. l know, too.
But if l die,
she'll be heartbroken.
She'll never be the same.
You're wrong.
The pain goes away
sooner than you think.
You went through
something like this?
Yeah. It happens that way.
Damn it. lf I知 caught,
I値l go to the can.
I値l always think of her there.
What does 'can' mean?
It means prison.
Don't interrupt.
Sorry.
Anyway, you're responsible
for your actions now.
Excuse me, sir.
How about letting her go?
lf l say no?
Then...
... let me go,
instead.
Come to think of it,
your eyebrows remind
me of that sergeant.
You act like him, too.
You can go.
And you...
We die together.
Got it?
Pardon?
Hey, lady.
Forget about this bastard,
and look for a nice guy. Got it?
Go!
Let's go together.
All three of us.
Will you leave if l kill him?
Gyeon-woo.
Don't worry too much.
This soldier isn't a bad guy.
You'll come out safely.
You're leaving me alone?
There's no other way.
l was afraid to die alone,
but I知 glad we're in it together.
Oh, right.
Over there,
there's an exit near
the merry-go-round.
Nobody knows about it.
l used to work here.
Really?
You're not tricking me, right?
I知 a man, too.
Why would l?
Walk in front of me.
See? l told you so.
This way!
Shit!
What's going on?
It痴 Gyeon-woo.
Screw you!
Don't come closer!
I値l kill him!
I値l really kill him!
Tell that bitch to come!
So she can see me die!
I値l give you an hour!
lf not, I値l kill him,
and myself, too!
Got it?
Hurry up!
Sniper 2!
The hostage is in danger,
but we can still fire.
Don't! Wait!
Don't shoot!
Hey, soldier! l mean sir!
Your girlfriend changed
her mind, right?
Did you really love her?
Ask yourself.
l think you didn't.
lf you really love her,
you should let her go.
lf not, then it's not love.
What's wrong with someone
you don't love getting married?
Stop this,
and go back to
base as a real man.
A person like you
should learn more about love.
lf we want to learn,
then we should keep living.
Damn it.
She's the nicest girl I致e met.
Hey! Don't let her go.
Got it?
lf you do, I値l take her.
Can l go?
Go. Screw it.
Shit! Don't know.
Pop! Pop!
Thank you.
Today's my birthday.
I値l live on until
l learn what love is.
What?
We're just friends?
No, l said that to save you.
Let me go, instead?
Wanted to save yourself, huh?
He wouldn't
have let you go.
Stop lying!
Stop lying! Stop lying!
Have a nice life alone.
l screwed up her
birthday, but l feel good anyway.
'Cause I知 proud
to be with her,
and things turned
out as planned.
l hope you believe in me.
You can't?
Wait...
Second Half
l remember.
She always came
with him until last year.
Was it last spring or winter?
One day, she came alone
with flowers to ask a favour.
To not let anyone
sit in his seat that day.
What's up?
Oh, hi.
You're early.
l was in the neighbourhood.
Miss me?
Of course!
She always tried
hard to look cheery.
l like her that way.
What would you like?
Coke, please.
Wanna die? Drink coffee.
Two coffees, please.
He he he~
l know her.
She pretends to be happy,
but she's full of sorrow inside.
What are you doing?
What are you smiling at?
No. It痴 nothing.
Looks fun, huh?
Another one?
Why? Don't wanna read it?
She may
get disappointed,
but l should be
honest for her sake.
Looks fun. I値l read it.
Ha ha ha~
This time it's
a martial arts film.
The heroine is a bounty hunter.
The villain wears rain
slippers even on clear days.
The worst of his kind.
What happened?
His name's Gyeon-woo?
Gyeon-woo?
The story's
setting is a mess.
Japan invades during
King Sejong's reign,
and the king's father
is the tyrant Yeonsan.
In the end, the heroine
fights the villain in a field.
Heavy rain pours
down on a sunny day.
He he he~
Yaaaah~
Yup~!
The heroine becomes a king.
King Jung-jo.
She's from the future, of course.
It痴 fun, huh?
Why is the heroine
always from the future?
Science is advanced then,
so they invent a time machine.
And people go to
the past to travel.
People from the future
could be here now.
l think UFOs
are time machines.
Someday, I値l meet
someone from the future.
l have to.
lf you do,
ask him to take you.
What?
lf it's possible...
Give this to Shin Cine.
Tell them to cast
Han Suk-gyu and Shim Eun-ha.
Jeon Do-yun is okay, too.
Excuse me,
we talked on the phone, right?
Well... this is
'The Warrior's Sad Love Story'...
On the way, we
play fun games, too.
Left foot over the line, l win.
With the right foot, you win.
What's the prize?
Let's see...
How about a kiss?
A kiss?
Wanna die?
You choose.
Hitting each other.
Again?
You can hit me, too.
Okay.
Someone's coming.
Ha ha ha~~~~~!
l think this is unfair.
I知 a girl, so I値l
slap the cheek.
No. Then I値l change it, too.
But I知 a girl.
Men and women are equal.
Okay, then.
You slap, and l slap, too.
Go easy on me,
and I値l kill you.
Better slap me on the cheek.
lf you don't, I値l kill you!
All right.
You slap, and I値l use my finger.
Right, that's fair.
Saw that?
See that guy step over
with his left foot?
l had my eyes closed.
Plus he came the opposite way.
l thought it was this way.
Shut up. Here they come.
Left foot. Left foot.
It値l be the right foot.
Left! Left!
Switch to the right.
You have to hit me?
Come here. Stay still.
Ugh! Uh uh uh~!
When I知 with her,
l never know how
the day will turn out.
What?
What are you looking at?
l quit!
Is your face a racket?
Why does the ball
always hit my face?
It痴 strange.
Ugh~!
l never want to lose a game.
So l play until l win.
Aaaaaaaaah~!
Ugh!
Wait long?
Just a teeny bit.
My mom bought me these heels,
but they're killing my feet.
Want a massage?
No, it's okay.
Instead, let's exchange shoes.
Don't wanna?
How can a guy wear heels?
It値l fit.
But, l can't...
Yeah? l see.
Come on. I値l buy you some sneakers.
Forget it.
Then wear mine,
and I値l carry yours.
You don't understand women.
Okay! Let's exchange.
Really?
Wanna know a secret?
What is it?
l don't wear panties on exam day.
But l had one today.
Catch me, honey!
Hey. lf you don't, I値l kill you.
Phew~
Catch me, honey~!
Stop right there!
Stop!
Out!
It was just a second, but l
felt something in her eyes.
That's my house.
Wait. I値l bring you an umbrella.
I知 okay. I知 already
wet so I値l just leave.
Are you my daughter's boyfriend?
Yes, sir.
How much do you know
about my daughter?
Not much...
Next time, don't hang out till late.
You don't understand me.
Why'd you stand him up?
What's wrong with him?
Why do you stand guys up?
And what happened to your heels?
What's wrong with you?
l told you not to meet Gyeon-woo.
He's dumb and has no future.
It痴 none of your business.
Why is he stupid?
You're stupid so you don't know.
What has gotten in to you?
Let me live my own life!
Afterwards,
l didn't hear
from her for a long time.
Hello?
Gyeon-woo, it's me.
Long time no see.
Her voice sounds cheerful
as if nothing happened to her.
Our 100th day celebration
is soon.
It痴 100 days already?
When do you think
a girl's the prettiest?
When a sexy woman is naked.
Where are you now?
Stay right there.
No, I知 just kidding.
The prettiest is when she's
playing the piano.
What's your favorite song?
That George Winston song.
Pachelbel Canon?
Yeah, that song.
You're not gonna ask me?
When is the guy the prettiest?
Just give me a rose.
Still have your high school uniform?
Yeah. Why?
Bring it on our 100th day,
and give me a rose
during my class.
Do it yourself, okay?
What? What did you say?
How can l during class?
Hey! Just hung up on me!
Damn it!
l don't wanna get beaten by her,
or get humiliated
at a women's college.
I知 cleverer than l look.
These girls sure
love Chinese food.
Hey, you! Where you headed?
Come here!
I知 delivering Chinese food.
l ordered it. Bring it here.
Really?
Bring a lot of radish?
Oh, l forgot something!
Give me the food first!
That's the wrong way!
There's another customer.
Hey!
But that wasn't enough for her.
We relived our old
high school days.
After we visited that club, a school
uniform party was held every month.
But she got wasted again.
Oh, wild teens!
Here's a condom.
Let's prevent AIDS.
Taxi!
She's having a happy dream.
Compared to when l looked at her
in the motel the first time,
She looks so different.
Could her pain be cured now?
Maybe it means that she doesn't
need me anymore.
Excuse me. Can you drive slowly?
Here.
Have any plans after graduation?
Actually, I致e never
thought about it yet.
Can l see what's in your pocket?
Sir? Right.
What is this for?
Oh, right. l learned that
it prevents AIDS.
But l haven't used it yet.
Actually, on the way here.
Forget it.
'Chicks Hen'?
What does this mean?
Oh, right.
It痴 a chicken soup restaurant.
'We'll satisfy all your wishes?'
l think it's to
satisfy our tastes.
How do feel about our daughter?
Oh, right. We're just friends now.
Please don't worry.
lf we get closer,
I値l let you know, sir.
Don't see her any more.
After that day, she never calls me.
It was sudden,
but that's how we broke up.
We're broken up.
Now, I知 free.
It痴 me. Come to the cafe
by seven o'clock.
Why?
What? l have a blind date today.
Come in 45 minutes.
l have a blind date, too.
Are you on your way?
I知 on a date with a girl.
Hurry up.
l have to go to the bathroom.
'Gotta go to the bathroom.'
Eh?
Nice to meet you.
I知 Cha Seok-won.
Same here.
Have a seat.
Were you really with a girl?
No, l was with a guy.
Can l take your order?
Coffee, please.
You can drink coke.
I値l drink coffee.
Gyeon-woo. You're very lucky.
l heard a lot about you.
That you're close friend.
Friend...
l need to go
to the bathroom.
Where's Gyeon-woo?
He left already.
He told me ten rules to follow.
l have a good memory.
I値l recite them.
First, don't ask her to be feminine.
And don't...
Second, don't let her drink
over three glasses.
She'll beat someone.
At a cafe, drink coffee
instead of coke or juice.
lf she hits you,
act like it hurts.
lf it hurts, act like it doesn't.
On your 100th day together,
give her a rose
during her class.
She'll like it a lot.
Make sure you learn
fencing and squash.
Also, be prepared to
go to prison sometimes.
lf she says she'll kill you,
don't take it lightly.
You'll feel better.
lf her feet hurts,
exchange shoes with her.
Finally, she likes to write.
Encourage her.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please pay attention to here...
Gyeon-woo.
Step backward on the yellow line...
Gyeon-woo!
... after passenger's
getting off, take in order...
Gyeon-woo!
...please use the next train.
What's his name?
Gyeon-woo. I値l do it myself.
Gyeon-woo. Where are you?
l looked all over for you.
Gyeon-woo.
Come to the escalator. Okay?
You're dead if you don't.
Hurry up.
Who told you to hug me?
Dummy. You're supposed to dodge.
Sometimes l feel like l know her
and sometimes l don't.
We're definitely standing
at the crossroad now.
What's going on between us?
Can this relationship
last forever?
Who is it?
It痴 me, Dad.
She told me to write a letter
and bring it.
To write it on paper.
To express my feelings,
l tried hard to find
the right words.
When l first met her,
l wanted to cure her grief,
but now l can't give her up.
l wish we can get serious.
I知 writing about
these feelings.
She's probably
writing about me now.
This is how we're
preparing to split up.
Gyeon-woo.
See that mountain top?
Yeah.
Could someone
hear me from there?
Yes, probably so.
Or probably not.
Then go over there.
I値l shout here.
lf you hear, answer me.
You want me to go over there?
Yeah.
Gyeon-woo?
Can you hear me?
Gyeon-woo! I知 sorry.
l really can't help it.
Gyeon-woo. I知 sorry.
I知 sorry... l can't help it.
l thought l was different,
but I知 just a helpless girl.
Gyeon-woo! I知 sorry.
Did you bring your letter?
Yeah.
What's that?
A time capsule.
We put our letters
in it and bury it here.
And two years later,
let's meet here again.
We'll read the letters that day,
and maybe we can
find an answer then.
This was her way of saying good-bye,
and l kept repeating in my mind
that two years isn't long.
Let's open this exactly
two years later, at two, Okay?
We can meet two years later.
When we meet then, we'll be
different from what we are now.
We may become closer,
or stay forever apart.
We can only choose one.
Gyeon-woo. You go first.
Let's separate here.
See you two years later!
Okay, in two years!
Two years!
Bye!
Gyeon-woo!
That's how we broke up.
Overtime
l couldn't endure the loneliness
after we broke up.
Thinking of those memories,
l started to write about
our stories on the Internet.
Then l made up my mind.
lf l meet her again,
I値l show her a different myself.
Got to make use of my time.
For her and my future's sake.
Why does the ball l hit keep
hitting my face?
l wrote our stories on the
Internet everyday,
and l kept myself
busy for two years.
Excuse me. l wrote 'My Sassy Girl'.
Shin Cine saw my writing,
and offered to make
a movie out of it.
l made her dream
come true instead.
l wanted to tell her
right away,
but l can only wait
till that day.
She didn't come.
It痴 our only day to meet.
No one knows
when she will come.
How did he get in here?
It痴 a mystery.
Gyeon-woo! How are you?
l was so happy
while being with you.
I知 not sure if you knew,
but the person l loved passed away.
The day when l first met you
was the day he died
a year ago.
Actually, l tried to
look for him in you.
l know it was wrong.
I知 sorry.
l also met him on
the subway like you.
l was really sick at that time.
He did everything l wanted.
Like you did to me.
Under this tree, we planned
our future together.
But he suddenly passed away.
While l was dating you,
l met his mother often.
She wanted to introduce
a nice man to me,
but l couldn't.
The day l first met you,
l came under this tree,
and l prayed to him.
To let me free.
When l met you,
this occurred to me.
That maybe...
he introduced you to me.
But the more l met you,
he seemed to grow
jealous of you in me.
The more l liked you,
l felt guilty inside.
While the two of us are apart,
l want to forget him alone.
After that day, l went often to
this place.
lf I知 not with you
after two years,
it means l still lack of courage.
How much will we change
after two years?
l feel like you live
in the future,
and l stay in the past.
l want to meet you soon,
so l can read your letter.
Why are you staring at me, sir?
Because you're so pretty.
l thought an angel came down.
Do you come here often?
Sometimes. This tree has a secret.
l have a secret here, too.
Really?
Three years ago, l buried a letter
here with my boyfriend.
What's your secret?
So what happened?
We promised to read
the letters a year ago.
But l couldn't come.
l guess you're a year late.
But two years didn't seem that long.
l haven't made any decision yet.
l just wasted my time
on stupid thoughts.
Like what?
lf we were destined to meet,
l thought we'd meet
by chance somewhere.
Know what fate is?
Building a bridge of chance
for someone you love.
To be honest,
l read you guys letters.
l said this tree
had a secret, right?
Yes.
Look closely. Does this tree
look the same as before?
Well, it looks like it
changed a bit. But I知 not sure.
People are dead or alive.
There's a dead tree
and a living tree, too.
This tree was struck dead
by lightning last year.
It was split into two.
But this young man felt sorry for it.
During this spring,
he planted another tree
that looked the same.
When he planted the tree,
he asked me if it look the same.
He said that someone
would be sad if it died,
so no one should know.
Gyeon-woo...
You call a wrong number
or the dial is not in service.
Please, call again.
Hi.
It痴 been a while.
You've gotten prettier.
You still look young.
How have you been?
You were in England?
Yes. For one and a half years.
So l can forget him.
l see. Feel better?
Yes. A lot better.
Is it true now?
My son might be sad.
He won't.
He'll like it this way.
Good,
that's what l really hoped.
Auntie! l was getting
my photo taken.
You naughty boy.
Know how long it's been?
Sorry l didn't tell you before.
This is Gyeon-woo.
Doesn't he resemble him?
When you had a hard time,
l tried to introduce you
to him for several years,
but he kept getting out of it.
Heard you came to Bupyung often,
but you never visited me?
Go out with him.
l thought he'd make
things easy for you.
Oh, yeah. Gyeon-woo,
you're going to England, right?
She's already been there,
so she can give you some tips.
l don't have to go now.
Why? You two know each other?
You may not believe it, but l think l
met a man from the future.
From your future.
This is how l met her again.
Think it's too coincidental?
It痴 building a bridge
of chance for your love.
Synced By J11