Hello!
John Cameron !
Chingachgook!
How are you?
The Master of Life is good, John.
Another year passed.
How is it with you?
Getting along. Yes, l am.
Nathaniel.
Hello, John.
Cleared another quarter, l see.
Yes, l did.
Alexandra.
Welcome.
Jack, how are you?
Hello, Nathaniel.
How've you been?
Good. Thank you.
Where you boys been trapping?
West of the Cuyahoga.
Why is Uncas with you?
He should have settled with a woman,
started a family by now.
Hey! Hey!
Hey, Uncas, look!
Mohawk field we saw was five mile long
on the river.
Chief Joseph Brandt's field.
You take much fur?
That we did.
Lots.
The Horicon's
near trapped-out now.
Where are you
trading your skins?
Castleton?
No.
Schuylerville.
Schuylerville,with the Dutch,
for silver.
French and English want to pay with
wampum and brandy.
So what is it, Jack?
What brings you here?
French and lndian army are heading south
out of Fort Carillon to war against the British.
l'm helping to raise New York's militia to
fill the Crown's levy.
And the people here are gonna
join in that fight?
We'll see in the morning.
Where're you boys heading?
We'll trap over the fall.
Winter in Can-tuck-ee.
Find a Delaware-speaking
woman for Uncas.
She will say,
"You are the one!"
Bear him many children.
BOY: Then you can
have a boy like me.
Never.
You're too strong.
Turn me old too fast.
That's what he's
doing to his mama.
MAN: John Cameron,
thank you for
your hospitality.
Mohawk traded furs
with les francais.
We got no quarrel with les francais.
Now les francais
bring Huron, Ottawa,
Abenaki onto Mohawk land.
Now Mohawk will
fight les francais
and Huron.
l speak for
the Twin Rivers Mohawk
of the Six Nations.
His Majesty, King George ll,
is very grateful
for your support.
How far up the valley?
Up to Fort William Henry.
That's two nights
and a bit from here.
Should be enough
to remind you all that
France is our enemy.
France is your enemy.
What did you say?
While we're at your fort,
what if the French
attack our homes?
What then, Lieutenant?
For your homes,
for King, for country!
That's why you men
ought to join this fight!
You do what you want
with your own scalp.
Do not be telling us
what we ought
to do with ours.
You call yourself a patriot?
A loyal subject to the Crown?
l do not call myself
subject to much at all.
l agree with some of what
Nathaniel and John say,
but l believe England's
still our sovereign.
l'll go.
We will go to
fight the French.
My brother and l will volunteer up.
l'll fight with you, Jack.
l'm staying on my farm.
Any man who goes,
his family's welcome
to fort up with us
till he comes back.
Boys, my sense of it is
we have enough here
to fill the county levy,
and it's a fight
we ought to make.
But first
we got to get terms
from General Webb.
Where are you
meeting him?
We'll go to Albany.
Attention !
We speak for the men,
not command them.
lf they're not allowed
leave to defend
their farms and families
if the French
attack the settlements,
then no colonial militia is going to
Fort William Henry.
They will report or be pressed
into service.
Any of the boys worth having
can disappear into the forest.
They will be found.
And where does that leave you then?
Those men will be
found, arrested. . .
l cannot imagine His Majesty,
in his benevolence,
would ever object to his loyal
American subjects
defending their hearth and home,
their women and children
Does that mean they
will be granted leave
to defend their homes if the settlements
are attacked?
Of course.
You got yourself a colonial militia, General.
lt is what we wanted.
Major Duncan Heyward reporting, sir,
en route to Fort William Henry
and bearing dispatches. Safe journey,
l trust?
Yes, and l didn't experience anything
so surprising from Bristol to Albany
as that that l witnessed here today.
And what was that?
The Crown negotiating
the terms of service.
l know.
One has to reason with these colonials
to get them to do anything.
Tiring, isn't it?
But that's the lay of the land.
l thought British policy is
"Make the world England," sir.
l see you're to serve
with the 35th Regiment of Foot
at Fort William Henry
under Colonel Munro.
l'll be marching
the 60th to Fort Edward.
Explain to the Major,
he has little to fear
from this General Marquis de Montcalm
in the first place,
and therefore scant need
of a colonial militia in the second,
because the French
haven't the nature for war.
Their Latinate voluptuousness
combines with their Gallic laziness.
And the result is,
they'd rather eat and make love with
their faces than fight.
Might l inquire if
General Webb has heard
from Colonel Munro's
daughters?
l was to rendezvous with them
in Albany and escort them
to the fort, sir.
You there,
what does Munro
call you?
The Scotsman has sent you
one of his Mohawk allies
to guide you.
Magua.
The Scotsman's daughters
are at the Poltroon's house.
A company of the 60th
will accompany you,
and Magua will
show you the way.
Dawn. At the encampment,
6:00 a.m. sharp.
See to it you're there.
l'll take him
for you, sir.
Cora.
Duncan !
How long have
you been in Albany?
For days and days.
And yourself?
Just arrived.
By God,
it's good to see you.
l don't know
what to say, Duncan.
l truly wish they did,
but my feelings don't. . .
Don't go beyond friendship.
Don't you see?
Respect and friendship.
lsn't that a reasonable basis
for a man and a woman
to be married?
And all else may grow in time?
Some say that's the way of it.
Some?
Cousin Eugenie,
my father. . .
Well, then, Cora.
ln my heart l know,
once we're joined,
we'll be the most
marvelous couple
in London.
l'm certain of that.
So why not let
those whom you trust,
your father,
help settle
what's best for you?
ln view of your indecision,
you should rely
on their judgment.
And mine.
Will you
consider that?
Please consider that.
Yes.
Yes, l will.
ALlCE: Duncan !
By God, you've grown up.
We leave in the morning?
Yes, miss.
l shan't sleep tonight.
What an adventure. Have you seen
the red men?
A few.
l absolutely cannot wait to return
to Portman Square,
having been to the wilderness.
lt's so exciting, Duncan.
Alice?
ALlCE: Can we rest soon?
DUNCAN: Absolutely.
You, there.
Scout, we must stop soon.
Women are tired.
Not here. Two leagues.
Better water. We stop there.
No, stop in the glade just ahead.
When the ladies are rested,
we will proceed. Do you understand?
Excuse me. What did you say?
Magua said,
understand English very well.
DUNCAN: Hold tight!
Come on !
Right! To the right!
Prepare your firearms!
As three ranks!
Make ready!
First and second rank,
present!
Fire!
No, Duncan.
ln case your aim's any better
than your judgment.
Your wounded
should try walking
on back to Albany.
They'll never make a passage north.
Stop it! Stop it!
We need them to get out!
DUNCAN: Why's he
loosing the horses?
Why don't you ask him?
Too easy to track.
They'll be heard for miles.
We were headed to
Fort William Henry.
We'll take you as far as the fort.
We're walking out of here fast.
Unless all of you'd rather
wait for the next Huron
war party to come by.
Scout, l'd like to
thank you for your help.
How much further is it?
Night and a bit.
Appears we're well away from them.
Maybe. Maybe they ain't alone.
That Huron captain back there. . .
The guide? He's a Mohawk.
No Mohawk. He's Huron.
What reason did he have
to murder the girl?
What?
The dark-haired one.
Miss Cora Munro? Murder her?
He never set eyes
on her before today.
She's only been here a week.
Blood vengeance?
A reproach or insult?
Of course not!
How is it
you were so nearby?
Came across the war party.
Tracked them.
Then you're assigned
to Fort William Henry?
No.
Fort Edward then?
Heading west to Can-tuck-ee.
There is a war on.
How is it you are heading west?
Well, we kind of face to the north,
and real sudden-like, turn left.
l thought all our colonial scouts
were in the militia.
The militia is fighting
the French in the north !
l ain't your scout. And we sure ain't
in no damn militia.
Ottawa, two francais.
What did you say?
Mirrors,
tools,
the clothes.
Everything
was inside.
They didn't
take anything.
And moving fast.
And a war party.
Let us look after them.
Leave them.
Whoever they are, though they're strangers,
they're at least entitled
to a Christian burial.
They can't be left behind.
Let us go, miss.
l will not!l've seen the face
of war before, sir,but l've not seen
war made upon women and children.
And almost as cruel
is your indifference.
Miss Munro,
they're not strangers.
And they stay as they lay.
Why didn't you bury those people?
Anyone looking for our trail
would see it as a sign we passed that way.
You knew them well?
You were acting for our benefit,
and l apologize.
l misunderstood you.
Well, that's to be expected.
My father warned me about. . .
Your father?
Chingachgook.
He warned me about people like you.
Oh, he did?
He said, "Do not try to understand them."
Yes. And, "Do not try to make
them understand you.
"That is because they are a breed apart
and make no sense."
Why did they turn back?
Burial ground.
"Breed apart. We make no sense?"
ln your particular case, miss,
l'd make allowance.
Thank you so much.
Where is your real family?
They buried my ma and pa
and my sisters.
Chingachgook found me
with two French trappers,
raised me up as his own.
l'm sorry.
l do not remember.
l wasn't but one or two.
How did you learn English?
My father sent Uncas and l
to Reverend Wheelock's school when l was 10.
Why were those people living
in this defenseless place?
After seven years
indentured service
in Virginia,they headed out here
'cause the frontier's
the only land available
to poor people.
Out here,
they're beholden to none.
Not living by another's leave.
The name was Cameron.
John and Alexandra Cameron.
My father's people
say that at the birth of the sun,
and of his brother,
the moon,their mother died.
So the sun gave
to the earth her body,
from which was
to spring all life.
And he drew forth
from her breast
the stars.
The stars, he threw into the night sky
to remind him of her soul.
So there's the Camerons' monument.
My folks' too,l guess.
You are right, Mr. Poe.
We do not understand
what is happening here.
And it's not as l imagined
it would be,
thinking of it in Boston and London.
Sorry to disappoint you.
No, on the contrary.
lt is more deeply stirring
to my blood
than any imagining
could possibly have been.
NATHANlEL:
Top of the next ridge.
The fort's downhill of it.
The men of the regiment will fetch
water from the lake,
build fires, and provide every
comfort and desire.
l cannot wait to see Papa.
Fire!
Prepare! Point! Fire!
Open up.
l'm Major Duncan Heyward.
Captain Jeffrey Beams.
Didn't expect you
to make it through.
Let's go to Munro.
Hello, boys!
Nathaniel !
l need to talk
to you, Jack.
MAN: Uncas!
Thought you and Nathaniel
weren't joining up.
We didn't.
Papa! Papa!
Alice! Cora!
Why are you here?
And where the hell
are my reinforcements?
Get Mr. Phelps.
Told you to stay away.
Why did you disobey me, girls?
When? How? l. . .
My letter.
There was none.
What?
There was no letter.
l sent three couriers
to Webb.
DUNCAN: One called
Magua arrived.
He delivered
no such message.
Does Webb not even know
we are besieged?
Sir, Webb has no idea.
And he certainly
does not know
to send reinforcements.
What happened to you?
On the George Road.
Attacked.
We're fine.
Are you all right?
Yes.
What will happen
here, Papa?
We'll be all right, girl.
This Magua led us into it.
Eighteen killed.
These men came to our aid.
They guided us here.
Thank you.
Do you need anything?
Help ourselves
to a few horns
from your powder stores.
Some food.
lndebted to you.
PHELPS: Miss Cora,
how are you?
Hello, Mr. Phelps.
Mrs. McCann
will get some dry
clothes for you.
CORA: Thank you.
Go with your sister, Alice.
lt'll be all right, girl.
lt'll be all right.
Might l inquire
after the situation, sir,
given that l've seen
the French engineering
from the ridge above?
The situation is,
his guns are bigger than
mine and he has more of them.
We keep our heads down
while his troops dig
30 yards of trench a day.
When those trenches are 200 yards
from the fort and within range,
he'll bring in his 15-inch mortars,
lob explosive rounds
over our walls and pound us to dust.
They look to be
300 yards out.
lf they're digging 30 yards a day,
you have three days.
Damn. Damn.
This man here can make a run
straight through to Webb.
Three days is not enough time
to get to Albany and back
with reinforcements.
Webb's not in Albany.
He marched the 60th to Fort Edward two days ago.
Webb is at Edward?
Yes, sir.
That's only
12 miles away.
He could have
reinforcements here
the day after tomorrow.
You, sir, pick your man.
Major Heyward will provide a diversion.
l'll draft out a dispatch.
Captain Beams
will seek you out
and give it to you later.
Something else.
Cameron's cabin.
Frontier cabin.
Came upon it yesterday.
lt was burnt out,everyone murdered.
lt was Ottawa,
allied to the French.
Aye.
So?
lt was a war party.
That means they're gonna be
attacking up and down
the frontier.
Thank you, sir.
People here,
Mohawks, settlers,
have family out there.
That'll be all, sir!
Things were done.Nobody was spared.
Those considerationsare subordinate to
the interests of the Crown.
A terrible feature of war
here in the Americas,
Major Heyward.
Best keep your eye fixed on our duty,
to defeat France.
That hangs on a courier to Webb.
For my children are the children
of the true faith.
My friendship and esteem is boundless.
Tomorrow, l will sing the war song with you
at the great council fire.
Magua, how are things
with your English friends?
We're at one.Join us.Hear what Le Subtil
has to tell us.
The English war chief,
Webb, goes to Fort Edward
with 60th Regiment.
He does not know that my father's army
attacks Fort William Henry.
Magua was successful?
The other two couriers
died in the forest.
By now, Munro would know his dispatch
did not get through.He'll send another.
Grey Hair will try.
Four or five,including two women,
entered the fort.
The Grey Hair's children
were under Magua's knife.
They escaped.
They will be under it again.
Why do you hate
the Grey Hair, Magua?
When the Grey Hair is dead,
Magua will eat his heart.
Before he dies,
Magua will put his children
under the knife,
so the Grey Hair will know his seed
is wiped out forever.
My engineers are advancing the trench
through the night.
You may have your opportunity soon.
GUARD: Miss Cora.Gentleman looking for you.
Miss Munro. Hello.
May l?
lt will seep, and then
it's going to draw.
Thank you, miss.
About done holding hands
with Miss Munro?
We got some work to do.
What are you looking at, sir?
l'm looking at you, miss.
Munro refused to
believe what happened.
He does not even
want to hear it.
Well, he's gonna have to.
Get together by
the west bastion.
lan, Sharitarish,Ongewasgone and William.
Tight weave?
Silk.Another 40 yards.
MUNRO: And how am l
to know it wasn't a raid
by common thieves?
NATHANlEL: The cabin
was attacked by a war party
fighting with the French.
They're sweeping south down the frontier
attacking farms
and Mohawk villages.
All the men are stuck here.
l need proof more convincing than
this man's opinion,
before l weaken the fort's defenses
by releasing the militia.
Chingachgook's of the same opinion
about the raid.
Taken together,that's gospel.
Your fort will stand
or fall depending
on Webb's reinforcements,
not the presence of the colonials.
l judge military matters here,
not you.
Your judgment is not more important
than their right,
under agreement with Webb
to defend their farms and families.
Major Heyward was there.
He was at John Cameron's.
He saw what it was.
What exactly did you see, Major?
l saw nothing that would lead me
to the conclusion it was other than a raid
by savages bent on thievery.
You're a liar!
Major!
Montcalm is a soldier
and a gentleman,not a butcher.
Easy for you to suppose.
lt's their women and children alone
on the farms, not yours!
You forget yourself, sir!
We're not forgetting Webb's promise.
British promises are honored,
and the militia
will not be released,
because l need more definite proof
than this man's word !
Nathaniel's word's been good
on this frontier
a long time before you got here.
This meeting is over!
The militia stays.
Does the rule of English law
no longer govern?
Has it been replaced
by absolutism?
lf English law
cannot be trusted,
maybe these people
would do better
making their own peace
with the French.
That is sedition !
That is the truth !
l'll have you beaten
from this fort.
Someday l think you and l are gonna have
a serious disagreement.
Anyone fomenting on
advocating the leaving
of Fort William Henry
will be hung for sedition.
Anyone actually caught leaving will be
shot for desertion.
My decision is final !
Get out.
Cora?
l wanted to talk to you.
Talk with Duncan, Cora.
l must manage.l cannot be
an invalid schoolgirl.
Alice.
l'll see if Mr. Phelps
needs anything.
l'm sorry.
l didn't mean to. . .
Cora, when we come together
back in England
and are married and away from this place,
what had to be done and said here
will matter not at all.
l'm certain of that.
Duncan, l promised you an answer.
You've complimented me
with your persistence
and patience.
But the decision l have come to
is that l'd rather make
the gravest of mistakes
than to surrender my own judgment.
Please take this
as my final answer.
lt must be no.
l see.
lAN: Yeah, Nathaniel,
but you weren't ever for being here.
That's right.l saw it that way then
and l see it that way now.
lan, if l had kin
in the settlements,
hell be damn sure
l'd be long gone.
What do we do about
being under Crown law?
l believe if they
set aside their law
as and when they wish,
their law no longer
has rightful authority
over us.
All they have over us
then is tyranny.
And l will not live
under that yoke.
So l will stay here no longer.
Anyone caught
leaving the fort
could be shot,
so each man make
your own decision.
Those who are going,
be back in an hour.
Out the northern sally port.
Strike for the east side
of the swamp
till you clear the French picket line.
Head north over the ridge,
then come about southeast.
Fork left in Little Meadow
and you're free of
the outpost and skirmishes.
Should've gotten
out of this long ago.
Got no families, Captain.
Figured we'd stay
and give a hand.
l'll cover you from
the top of the bastion.
You're not coming with us?
l got a reason to stay.
That reason wear a striped skirt and
work in the surgery?
lt does.
No offense, but it's
a better-looking reason
than you, Jack Winthrop.
Push hard,
'cause you got to clear
the French outpost by dawn.
Good luck, Jack.
Ongewasgone,are you staying?
Yes.
There's too many French.
And so few of us to fight.
Not too many to die.But we've given our word
to our English fathers.
You, sir! As you were!
Stand off.
Take him.
As you were.
He saved us.We're alive only
because of him.
The man encouraged the colonials to desert,
in this very room,
and in my presence.
Sir.
He is guilty of sedition.
He must be tried
and hanged like any other criminal,
regardless of what
he did for my children.
But he knew the consequences
and he stayed.
Are those the actions
of a criminal?
Duncan, do something.
He knew the penalty for his actions.
He ought to pay
without sending you
to beg.
You know he wouldn't send me.
You falsely spoke of what you saw.
What happened at the farm
was as Nathaniel said.
But not with enough certainty
to outweigh British interests
in this fort.
And who empowered these colonials
to pass judgment on England's policies
in her own possessions,and to come and go
without so much as a "By your leave"?
They do not live
their lives by your leave!
They hack it out of the wilderness
with their own two hands,
bearing their children
along the way.
You are defending him because you've become
infatuated with him !
Duncan, you are a man
with a few
admirable qualities.
But taken as a whole,
l was wrong to have thought
so highly of you.
Cora!
Cora, l would do anything
l could to keep you from being hurt.
But this man is guilty
of sedition
and subject to military justice
and beyond pardon.
Justice?
lf that's justice,
then the sooner French guns
blow the English army out of America,
the better it will be
for the people here.
You do not know
what you're saying !
Yes, l do.
l know exactly
what l'm saying !
And if it is sedition,
then l am guilty
of sedition too.
They're going to hang you.
Why didn't you leave
when you had the chance?
Because what l'm interested in
is right here.
What can l do?
Webb's reinforcements
will arrive or not.
lf they do not arrive,
the fort will fall to the French.
lf that happens,
stay close to your father.
Stay close to him.
The French officers will try
to protect the officers among the English.
No. l will find you.
Do not.
Promise me.
The whole world's
on fire.
What is it?
Remember what l told you.
Stay close
to your father and the officers.
Colonel Munro,l have known you as
a gallant antagonist.
l am happy to make your acquaintance
as a friend.
And l yours,monsieur Le Marquis.
Please accept my compliments
for the strong and skillful defense
of your fortress.
Under the command of a lesser man,
it would have fallen long ago,
given the superior
numbers and materials.
Chance has allowed me
to array against you.
Monsieur Le Marquis,
l am a soldier,
not a diplomat.
You called this parley
for a better reason
than an exchange of compliments.
You have already done
everything which is necessary
for the honor of your prince.
But now l beg you to listen to the
admonishments of humanity.
l beg you to consider my terms
for your surrender.
Perhaps the general's
glass can reach
as far as the Hudson
and seize the size
and eminence of
the army of Webb?
My scouts
intercepted this dispatch
intended for you.
Capitaine de Bougainville.
"To Colonel Munro.
Sir, l regret to inform you
"that l have no men available
to send to your rescue.
"lt is quite impossible.
"l advise you to seek terms
for surrender.
"l remain. Jerome Webb
at Fort Edward."
This is the signature of Webb.
And l know
the temper
of our men.
Rather than spend the war
in a French prison
hulk in Hudson Bay,
they'd fight
to the end.
You've had your answer,
monsieur Le Marquis.
Sir, l beg you not to sign
the death warrant of so many
until you have listened
to what l have to say.
Go on.
None of your men
will see the inside
of a prison barge.
They are free,
so long as
they return to England
and fight no more
on this continent,
and the civilian militia
return to their farms.
Their arms?
They may leave
the fortress fully armed.
My colors?
Carry them to England
with pride.
Allow me to consult with my officers.
l have lived to see something
which l never expected.
A British officer
afraid to support another.
Webb can burn in hell.
And we'll go back
and dig our graves
behind those ramparts.
Death and honor are thought
to be the same,
but today l have learned that
sometimes they are not.
Sir. . .
Monsieur Le Marquis,
l am deeply touched
by such unusual
and unexpected
generosity.
My fort is yours
under the condition
that l be given till dawn
to bury my dead,
to prepare my men and women
for the long journey ahead
and to hand my wounded
over to your surgeons.
Granted, monsieur.
ls the hatchet buried
between the English
and my French father?
Yes.
Not a warrior has a scalp
and the white men
become friends.
My master
owns these lands,
and l have been
ordered to drive off
the English squatters.
They have
consented to go,
so now l call them
enemies no longer.
Magua took the hatchet
to color with blood.
lt's still bright.
Only when it's red,
then it will be buried.
So many suns have set
since Magua struck the war post.
And where is that sun?
Magua is the son of his people
and he has come
to lead many of them.
But Magua has power
with his Huron people
and others here,
l know well.
Magua's village
and lodges were burnt.
Magua's children
were killed by the English.
l was taken as slave
by the Mohawk
who fought for the Grey Hair.
Magua's wife
believed he was dead
and became
the wife of another.
The Grey Hair
was the father
of all that.
ln time,
Magua became
blood brother to the Mohawk
to become free.
But always in his heart,
he is Huron.
And his heart will be whole again
on the day
the Grey Hair and
all his seed are dead.
Does the chief of the Canadas
believe the English will keep the terms?
l fear having let them go,
which l must,
l will only fight the same men again
when l drive towards Albany.
But l cannot break
the term of the surrender
and sully
the lilies of France.
Monsieur,
the fort is yours.
MAN: Left three ranks,
make ready!
Aim, set.
Fire!
Present, fire!
Full company!
Grey Hair,
before you die,
know that l will put under the knife
your children,
so l will wipe your seed
from the Earth forever.
Leave her alone!
When you fall into
British hands again,
l'll have you hanged !
Faster!
Head to the river!
DUNCAN: Where are we going?
Nowhere.
l don't understand.
This is as far as we go.
lf we're lucky,
they'll figure we beached
our canoes and headed cross land.
lf we're very lucky,
they'll figure we went over the falls.
Our only hope is
that they pass us by.
lf they do?
Take the south rim
down the mountain.
lt's 12 miles cross country
to Fort Edward.
And if they don't?
You'll just have to forego
the pleasure of hanging me.
Powder?
Gone.
Mine's soaking wet!
CORA: Our father. . .
Did you see my father?
From a distance.
Say nothing to Alice.
Get back!
(GASPS)
Yes! Go ahead !
What the bloody hell
plan is this?
l want you to go!
lf we go, there's a chance
there won't be a fight.
There's no powder.lf we don't go in that,
there's no chance.
None! You understand?
Coward !
You've done everything you can do.
Save yourself!
lf the worst happens. . .
You stay alive!
lf they don't kill you,
they'll take you north
up to the Huron lands.
Submit, do you hear?
You're strong.
You survive!
You stay alive,
no matter what occurs!
l will find you,
no matter
how long it takes,
no matter how far!
l will find you.
l don't speak Huron.
Do you speak French, Major?
Yes.
Translate for meinto French
every word as l say it.
l come to you unarmed
and in peace
to unstuff your ears, Sachem.
Let the children of
the dead Colonel Munro
go free.
Take fire out of
the English anger
over the murder of
their helpless ones.
Sachem, the French fathers
made peace.Magua broke it.
lt is false that the French
will be friends
still to the Huron.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(DUNCAN TRANSLATlNG
TO ENGLlSH)
Would Magua use the ways
of les francais and the Yengeese?
Would you?
Yes!
Would the Huron make his Algonquin brothers
foolish with brandy
and steal his lands to sell them for gold
to the white man?
Would Huron have greed for more land
than a man can use?
Would Huron fool Seneca
into taking
all the furs of all the animals
of the forest
for beads
and strong whiskey?
Those are the ways of the Yengeese
and the francais traders
and their masters in Europe infected
with the sickness of greed.
Magua's heart is twisted.
He would make himself
into what twisted him.
l am Nathaniel
of the Yengeese.
Hawkeye, adopted son
of Chingachgook of the Mohican people.
Let the children of the dead Munro
and the Yengeese officer
go free.
This belt,which is a record
of the days
of my father's people,
speaks for my truth.
(SPEAKlNG FRENCH)
(SPEAKlNG HURON)
Tell him l'll trade him.
Me for her! Say it.
Stop it!
l am La Longue Carabine!
My death is a great honor
to the Huron ! Take me!
Did you tell him?
Yes.
Stop!
l said to take me.
Take me!
My compliments, sir.
Take her and get out!
Duncan. . . What are
they doing to Duncan?
Where's Alice?
Alice!
Uncas!
Great Spirit and maker of all life,
a warrior goes to
you swift and straight
as an arrow shot into the sun.
Welcome him,and let him take his place
at the council fire of my people.
He is Uncas,
my son.
Tell him to be patient
and ask death for speed,
for they are all there but one,
l, Chingachgook,the last of the Mohicans.