Subtitles : GDING
You look like shit, man.
l'm a l right.
Keep telling yourself tht.
That right there?
That s the best homework ss gnment
the cty ever came up with.
Yeah. Me and the kid start this weekend.
That s, of course unless Amanda botches
everyth ng up, like she always does
l could have Monica give her a call.
They aways got a ong pretty wel .
You know, Eddie, l apprecite it,
but it's best if you stay out of it.
Yo, D'Mc, whts up?
Yeah, l'm interested. Wht do you got?
Haitins. Boy e Heights.
Yeah, l know the place.
3- B got it.
Ya yo chang ng hands.
You really wnn mess with
this low-level sh t?
Yeah, et's go.
-Are we good?
-Al signs po nt to it.
Which one of you gentlemen
is gonna s gn forthis?
Nice suit.
l heard there was a problem with the toilet?
All right, fellas.
We got less than one hour Lets go.
Move.
-Police, freeze!
- Shit!
-Get h m!
-On the f oor, God dmn it!
Stop!
Don't move!
-You got him?
-He got away.
- What?
-He got away!
Sh t!
Not a word, Welles. Not a goddamn word!
Son of a b tch!
Now.
What the ..
Chief. We got a problem with the elevtors.
-Get down!
-And sty down!
Now that l have your attention,
get on the floor, right now!
-Take t easy tke it esy.
-Everyone!
-You too, come on!
- Get down!
Everything's reading ''Ma function.''
-The hell s this?
-l don't know.
Were not here to hurt you!
You stay ca m, you go home fordinner,
you understand me?
Don't ook at me.
Nobody move! And get down on the floor!
Shut up!
We got a naughty one here.
Jesus! FedCl, the bank.
All rght, that's it bad girl.
Now we get to go make a phone call.
Forty- five!
-News 14 hotIine.
-Tell them there's a robbery in progress.
l'm from the FedCl Bank, downtown LA.
There's a robbery in progress.
-Are they still in the bank?
-Theyre still...
Are they...
Come on man, et's get out of here.
Let's go!
Jump!
Get down!
Hey, guys, a bank robbery.
We're headed downtown.
Let's go now!
-l got the back!
-l'm on it!
They left the bank us ng the stairs!
All exits are covered.
Look, on the roof, a guard Land it!
-We're not cleared for th s.
-We're first on the scene. Lnd us, now.
Let's go!
Get the camera out.
Are you okay?
- No
-Get on the ground!
Get on the ground!
Get out of the chopper now!
Take  seat next to yourfrends!
Wht a bunch of dummies! Good boy.
Nothing but glorified paparazzi!
Get us out of here!
There goes Channel 14 going the wrong way.
That's why they're in last place.
Come on Rivers, you're a free mn.
You're out of here.
Any vacant floors?
Yeah, 26 is under construction.
You got securty camers on that floor?
Not in the construction area.
Have forensics go over it.
You'l p ck up prints
from half the damn city.
Do it anywy.
-You got it.
-Okay.
Went down pretty fast We got  mixed crew.
Apparenty, one of the guys
had some type of an accent.
-How much did they take?
-North of two million.
Some of the bills might be marked.
Who knows, maybe we'll get lucky.
So, they used C-4 to knock out the elevtors.
Residue's being sent to the lab now.
Thanks. Automatic weapons,
precis on tim ng.
Shape charges.
Degree of difficulty is off the chrts.
They were hot shit, no doubt bout tht.
lt'll make t that much sweeter
when we take them down
Yeah.
Wht is t you want?
You Sergei?
Mikhil, from in the joint, sent me.
Oky.
Y'all having fun, huh?
Not so fast my mn.
Show me lD.
USA USA USA!
Th nk about it.
Cool down.
We... We have vodka
and take care of bus ness, huh?
That's what l thought youd say.
Weve got some serious stacks now.
And l mean t's love, bby.
-Yeh we did all right.
-Al right my ass.
Our biggest heist yet,
and you, you don t seem too jzed.
No l m good.
l'm good.
L sten, Dd cal ed ast night.
He wants us to come see him.
No. Hell, no, Jake.
l've been to see Dad n jail.
lve been to juvie
l'm not go ng back. Not foryou not for Dd,
-not for anybody. Ever.
-Okay, okay
He's got less than five.
So, when he gets out,
maybe we bu ld him a house.
-Cool?
-Cool.
Gordon says you find anything marked,
burn it.
Sounds tight.
You just gonna leave your k d bro up there
with al that paper?
lf he runs out with it, shoot him.
l wll too.
Rememberthe song?
A' ght.
l don't know what to tell you.
Were so... We're so busy Look at this.
And if we get tht empty space next door,
think about how amazing its gonna be.
-What's this?
-Open it.
Oh my God.
lt's beautiful.
l think you're beautiful, too.
lf you'll hve me,
l wanna spend the rest of my life with you.
Cocky ssholes.
Tapes re redy.
All right, et's see what we got.
There's 20 e evators forthe lobby.
Twelve forthe lowerfloors,
eight forthe uppers.
You can cross overat 22.
So, overthe course of the day,
how many people on and off?
-Ten thousnd, give ortake.
-Shit.
Wel , et's see who got off
on the construction f oor.
lt couldnt hve been more
than a handful of people.
Well, it doesn't work that way.
These tapes are time- coded not floor-coded.
All these people getting on nd off
nd we have no idea
what floorwe're watching?
Yeah. l mean, that's how t works.
Come on.
Th s is some system you got here, Chief.
Most of the bui dings in the city
are set up this way.
-Whoever set it up is an idiot.
-Hey, l don't need this!
All right, l'm down here trying to help.
Hey. Look, mn
he doesn t mean nothing by it all right?
-Thanks for com ng by, okay?
-Screw you.
Meds not work ng
orwe just need to get you laid?
-What's the prob em?
- Look at this.
lt's a camera.
They knew the elevatorwas empty.
They knew the bu lding.
They knew the whole system.
Yeah, must be a hundred hours here.
We don't know
what the hell were looking for.
Not to piss on Grand Caymn,
but I th nk l cn get you an addit onal
75 bas s points
in the Dutch Anti es l say why not?
Yeah, but the wy the markets
keep jumping around, man
notherfour, six weeks,
who knows what the ratesll be?
And hve you seen
the latest Bloomberg report?
-Sh t s blek out there.
-''Bloomberg reports''? Are you kidd ng me?
Come on, college guys.
Let's not over- th nk t.
Yeah, come on.
Dutch Anti es wanna pay us more money.
-That's a no- bra ner.
-l ike the Dutch Antlles,
as ong as the banks don't pack up
and take my money overn ght.
Of course 10% to the usual charities?
- Absolutely.
-Coo by me.
l chartered a jet.
lt's tak ng off Van Nuys Airport tonight.
Anybody wants to come,
l got your prvate park ng passes right here.
lt'll be sweet.
Mn, life's ook ng pretty good
from rght here.
l'll let you know lter.
Nice house. Cool view.
Great scotch.
You know, jacking tht news chopper
had 'A.J.'' written all over t.
How'd you get in my house?
Please.
They let you out eary orwhat?
Good behavior About a year early.
But l guess you guys kind of lost track, huh?
No contact. That's what we greed upon.
So, whats up?
l think l m gonna have another scotch.
It's good shit, John.
You gonna drnk with me, right?
Sure you re.
You see, l cme to you John,
because you the one with tht
higher consciousness and shit.
- All right l'm listening.
-We , you asked whats up.
l m ss my homies. Thts wht's up.
That, and some unfinished business.
Your money from '04 is safe
and accruing interest.
Gordon's got the bnk account numbers.
What about L li? Who's got her numbers?
Shes with Jake now.
Wel , good forthem.
l got a deal we need to discuss.
-Ajob.
-You re kidding me right?
You're coming t me with a job rght now?
Th nk l'd come at you on some bullshit?
Once in  lifetime, John. You know me.
l do my homework.
All rght, so what do you
want me to say here?
You a n't got to say shit.
Just remember l ws the one left b eeding
on that fire escape in '04
And they tried everything they could
to fl p me.
l ain't budge 'cause we had  del.
I kept my end
l kept this too You owe me, bro.
Al of you.
What were you boosting Camaros
back in R verside
when me and Gordon decided to let you in?
So, don t be so qu ck to write me off.
Al rght, l ll talk to the boys
and l' l get back at you tomorrow.
You do that. Love the plce.
Alarm system sucks though.
There she is.
Hello. Hows my baby G doing?
l'm good, l m fine.
-You look good.
- l feel good.
-Yeh? Yeh?
-Yeah.
They tell me maybe
you f n sh the program next week.
lt's been  tough eight weeks.
Don't worry l'm gonna do it this time.
That's wht my m nd
and my body's telling me.
l'm with you. l'm with you.
You know that, right?
- Yeh?
-l'm not gonna need these anymore.
By the time l leve here,
l m gonna be clener
than the day l was born.
You know l'm grateful, don't you?
Stop it. You dont need to say that to me,
ll right?
-D d you get my letter?
-Yeah sure did.
l've been non-stop tripp ng overthis,
l tel you.
-Car bbean huh?
-Look at the water.
C ear and blue
Cool and warm at the same time.
l've just got to get back there.
Soon as you're out of here,
l'm gonna take you there myself.
-l prom se.
-Al right.
l love you.
Turn that off.
l know, so l walk into my house.
Hes standing there,
hes drinking my whiskey.
l was gonn shoot him
in the back of h s head.
Shouldve shot him.
The guy's been out 24 hours,
already wants to do a job.
-He's crazy.
-Or he's got huge balls.
Yeah, Ghost doesn't play
when it comes to money.
He's too smart forthat.
-The bastrd s not that smrt.
- That's for sure.
He's clever, not smart.
You guys, we alwys wait
at least a year between jobs.
- There's a reason fortht.
-Gordon, you guys go way back, right?
Th nk he's be ng stright up?
Ghost couldve ratted us out
a long time ago,
but he didn't. Kept his word.
Whts to stop him from do ng exactly that
once we g ve him h s cut from '04?
-See, that's the problem.
- Yeah.
-That's a big problem there.
-Someth ng ain't right.
-l don't trust him.
- Relax.
- He's trouble.
-l th nk he's onto something though.
-He says it's b g.
-Do l look like l care what he says?
Wel , whatever you decide to do,
l'm down with you.
- All right.
-l'm going to the loft.
Privte prty!
-Where you going?
-None of your damn bus ness!
-Gentlemen.
-lt's L lli.
-Baby, who ordered the Dom?
- That's forJohnny- boy.
lt's the girl in the green t the bar.
She's cute.
- Don't et her pay for it.
-No, no, she's gonna pay, man.
Th s is how t's done. Let me show you.
S ow down, lvy League
Th s ain't the frt house, mn.
Well, that's some funny shit, mn.
That's some funny shit.
l'll come bck up lter.
- Ghost.
-lt's been a long time girl.
-When did you get out?
- Why? You m ss me?
Ghost. You need to bck up.
Easy Jke. Esy.
l w sh you guys the best. Relly.
lts the past.
l'm here to discuss the future.
lf l my.
To d you tomorrow, Ghost.
l'm not here to bust any balls. Just business.
Aight?
A.J. Any new tts?
-Yeah man, couple.
-Me, too.
- G.
-Ghost.
How's my mn?
l'm doing good, mte.
Lot of tension in the room, huh?
Wht do you want Ghost?
Goddamn.
lt's like that?
lt's like that.
Well, l'll be brief.
Let's say we go ltalian Job on that ass.
Why don t we take this upstairs Ghost?
Fa r enough.
Sme pln s before, gentlemen.
25 to 30 mil.
All the cash we cn carry.
Got to move fast though.
When you sy ''fast,'' how fst?
Next Tuesday.
What?
Ghost, you want us to take down
n rmored truck in five days?
l mean, t's not even worth talking about
un ess you got the route,
and they change the route all the time.
-That's what screwed us lst time.
-Yeah man, you got the route?
l got it. Exct one from next Tuesday.
Any more questions?
-Howd you get it?
- ln the joint.
l got in good with this Russin.
Had the pleasure of keeping them guys
from Compton off h s ass.
ln exchange, he had h s comrades
on the outs de
put the rm down on the disptcher.
So the dispatcher do anything
to screw the job up
they're wiping out h s who e family
back at the Ukraine.
Down to the sheepdog.
Why should we trust the Russins?
They love their sheepdogs.
Al oullshit aside,
l'm in for a quarter mil with the Russians
out my cut when the job's done.
lt's not your concern,
so don't trust the Russians. Trust greed.
-Why shou d we trust you?
-We , shit, A.J.
l'm fresh out. l in t in no hurry to go bck.
Besides, why would l screw over my guys?
Especally when
you're hold ng all my money, right?
Okay. What about the setup?
l mean, there's knowing the route,
and then there's the logistics, you know.
F ve days Jake's right.
That's a rea , real short fuse.
That's where you come in.
But l trust that when you and Jake
put your heads together you'll figure it out.
Eitherway, l need to know tonight.
You ain't got the heart to pu l it off, ight.
Well sett e up on the money you owe me,
l'm sayonara.
Appreciate yourtime, gentlemen.
Thanks forthe cigar.
-Hey, G, et me check out that route.
- Yeah.
This is not the way we do things, gentlemen.
lt's too fast, it's too rushed
lts  lot of money,
but this whole th ng feels forced.
Five days? Five?
Yeah, man, but, you know,
we can get the setup right.
Bet big, win big.
lt's the only wy to ply.
We're takers, gents.
That's what we do for a iving.
We take.
lt's a lot of money, Jake.
-And that's what we're here for.
- You sure about this?
lf it checks out.
lf it checks out, l'm in.
- Yeah, wht's up?
-Thought you'd wanna know,
your Haitin buddy?
His lwyer just filed on you
for excessive force
All right. The guy was 6'5' he was resisting.
What ws l supposed to do?
Yeah, well, you mustve hurt his feelings.
The bank. Hey, isten, what about the C-4
they used to blow the elevators?
Well, from the taggants, forensics trced it
to a mining company out of Nevada
sto en about About two months go.
All right. And what about the mrked bills?
Bank finaly sent over a list.
Max is gonna fax out a memo right now.
L sten, man,
it's been a couple of weeks now.
You hear anything from Amanda?
L sten l apprecate it,
but l don't need any help.
We can work it out on ourown. But thanks.
All right. l'll tlk to you lter.
All right, so, for th s route
Ghost is talking about.
The on y place we stnd  chance
is right there.
-What's there?
-It's an o d subway carturnaround.
lt's lrge enough,
and it runs para lel to the street.
lt's kind of perfect.
l mean, we can get access on Hope Street,
but l say we ho d them up
at Olive and Fourth.
Al right.
And we need to get down there
first and get some intel on,
you know street patterns traffic density,
that sort of thing, but it ooks good.
Once we determine the blast radius
and street density,
l cn tell you how much C-4
you're gonna need to score
What about the exits?
Work in progress G.
You know, we got to get down there first,
check it out
-Give me some exits.
- You got it.
-lt's good work.
- Cool
-Al right gng.
- Good to go
Easy money, baby. Sme as before.
All the cash is in the front truck.
Second truck's totlly empty. Just n escort.
Two men up front, two men in the back.
Pump act on 12- gauge
and .40 ca iber Glocks.
Maybe 9mm.
They may have upgrded
their communication by now,
but the same stndard bulletproof windows.
They ain't gonna know what hit them.
Here we go. Must've tken up the trcks.
That's it.
Yeah, he's still working it.
Got brand- new wheels to show for it, too.
All rght, let's go.
All right, wait for my go-hed.
-Good morning, Frnco. N ce whee s!
- What do you guys want?
-Get up aga nst the car.
-Turn around.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, l'm clean, mn.
Hands off. All rght?
Why don't you move your car?
Wht do you know about some
C- 4 boosted out of Nevada?
Nevada? l don't know nothing bout tht.
Come on, f it's guns orexp osives,
you heard someth ng about it
You know, you get busted gin,
you're facing 10 years minimum.
- You know that, rght?
-I know this is a pub c place.
l ain't done noth ng.
So, why don't you move your car?
-Do me  fvor.
- Hey, Hatch.
- Look at this!
-What you got?
-What's that?
-Come on, Frnco.
- lts  damn shame
-Looks like you caught a nail.
-Yeh you got  flt.
- Twice.
- Come on.
-You got  spare in the trunk, right?
-Come on, l' l help you. Come on.
- You wnna check my trunk,
why don't you go get yourse ves a warrant?
Hey, Dispatch, we got a d sabled vehice
on 9th and the 1 10.
How long would it take to get here?
Yeah, right around the corner.
You got one in the re.
That's great. lt's my lucky day.
l'll see you in a minute
You guys must th nk l'm stupid
orsomething, right?
-Bring it n
-Man, what the hel is this?
Come on This hs got to be i egal!
-No.
-Entrapment or some shit!
Th s looks like a disab ed vehicle to me.
Hey, don't worry bout it.
We'll do a ful inventory
includ ng everything in the trunk.
Yeah we wouldn't wnt you
accusing the LAPD of stea ing anything.
-Hey, come on, al rght? Hey!
-Give us something, Franco.
-Give us something
-This here is bu shit! Come on, man!
Come on, Franco, what do you wnn do?
You know, you two guys,
you're a couple of...
-Al right, hook it up!
-What are you doing?
-Come on! Be n ce its  new cr!
Okay, okay, okay, ll right!
l got something foryou guys all right?
-Come here.
-What do you got?
There's... They got these guys,
they're trying to go upsca e.
-They're p anning something big.
- What?
They're definite y p anning
someth ng rea big
- Like what?
-l don't know like what.
But l know they're gonna use  C-4
on the job.
Whts up?
'Sup.
You alone?
L ke l said on the phone.
He's clean.
-No one.
-You Paulie?
L ke the sign sys.
So, you're the one who wnts some C-4?
L ke l said on the phone.
l know, the street's gone dry.
Someone bought up a big p le of it.
That what brings you to me?
-Smart mn.
-Yeah.
So, let me see yourcategory one permit.
Perm t? Thought th s was
supposed to be s mple.
lt is. You got a permit.
My ctegory one.
Yeah, t s simple.
See, we take your money,
nd you don't get sh t.
Get over here!
Hey, who! Hey. Come on.
Move, l put three ho es in your head
ike a bowl ng ba l big boy
Shouldve kept it simple, huh?
-Thought you might need some backup.
- Backup?
Looked like you getting your ss kicked.
Mn, l to d you guys to wa t in the car.
-You hd it undercontrol, huh?
- Yeah, l did actually.
-Where's the C-4?
-lt's n the shed.
-Speak English! Wheres the C-4?
- lt's in the shed!
-Back n the shed!
-ln the shed?
-lt's n the shed?
-Back n the shed.
lt's in the shed.
Nice job squeezing Frnco.
Looking at 10 years,
funny how he gave up that address.
Th nk t's the FedCl guys?
Only so many people know
how to use C- 4, Chief.
- Duncn!
-Lieutenant Carver?
- Moving and grooving Jck!
-l wanna speak to Detective We es!
l can't do this right now.
Were executing  search warrnt.
Police work. Rememberwhat that is?
lnternal Affa rs w l have to wait.
Hey, you ca l me, Welles. Get back to me!
You don't wnt me to
have to come fnd you!
The he is wrong with you,
com ng down here now?
l wanna show you something.
Police, on the ground now!
Go!
Welles, l got nothing.
Hatch hes coming up on Spring!
Sh t!
Wel es!
-You ll right?
- Yeah.
Ourtwo dead guys,
Ethan nd Constantine Symnski.
Brothers. Suspected Russ an mob,
but they're no good forthe FedCal job.
- Why's tht?
-INS said they were being sworn in
as U.S. citzens at the t me of the robbery.
-Coup e patriots, huh?
- Yeah.
They burned a bunch of stuff
before we got here.
Th s is all that was left.
Looks ike a map of LA.
Yeah. Mybe.
Look at th s stuff
C-4 automat c weapons, b asting caps.
They were definitely onto something big.
Stples Center Persh ng Square,
Union Station.
The he were they up to?
-Were good to go
-Jakes all connected. You ready?
All rght, Jesse, were up.
Show it to us.
Nice.
All right, te l Jke to stop showing off.
All right, mn, turn it off.
-Good job.
But the point is, l mean,
can we do it in three days?
Not only can we do it
but we're gonna play it safe.
All right, were gonn drill at
bout an inch an hour,
16 holes n 64 hours.
Split the work, keep the schedule.
So, tht leaves us one lst day for prep?
Exacty. Enough time forJke and l to wire.
lt's good.
All right, l'm gonna ca l Rhway
and see f we can get down there tonight.
Whos there?
G!
Naom . Wht re you doing here?
You're supposed to be at the...
l know, l know, l...
-Catch up with you later, man.
-Al right man.
Wow look t this place.
What is this? Naomi?
Look, l am realy cean now. l feel gret.
Naomi, wht are you tlking bout?
Look, anotherweek in that place
wouldn't have made any difference.
-We spoke about this, d dn't we?
-Come on
l was doing relly well.
l asked if l cou d leve erly,
and they said yes.
lf you don't believe me cll them.
Look, they told us that when you get out,
you got to have a plan.
Yeah? Without  pln, you re ded.
So l started th nking about you and me,
our plan, and go ng home.
And that's gonna happen.
You had one more week, that's all,
one more week.
lt's a busy time for me, Naomi.
-You dont remember it, do you?
-No, l don't.
Look at how cute you were.
Mum was so beautifu .
l was truly happy bck then.
l'm not gonna be right untl l get back there,
so l can start again.
And we cn. ln just three dys.
l'm working l need to put you in a hotel.
What? Why can't l stay here?
You can. lts just a bad tme for me.
Al right?
Yeah.
Well, l can tell you it's not a street mp.
lt's some k nd of a public works project.
But wthout a reference number,
there's no way l can work it out.
All right. Thnks.
You got it.
Rivers, Delonte.
Put your body in it.
Right here Edd e. Up with it.
Yes! Tht's what l m talking bout.
Hey, Eddie
Take it easy on Uncle Jack all right?
Time out. l d d some work last night.
Wanted to ta k to you.
Hey, f you're gonna puke, do t on the grass.
Come on, Dd, let us fnish.
Yeah, why don't you take my plce?
l'm good. Go ahead, keep play ng, Eddie.
-Edd e looks like he's doing  lot better.
- Yeah, hes doing great, man
l mean, t's been bout  month
since h s last dialys s.
Down for  couple days,
then he bounces back. l mean...
-So, anyway, whts up?
-All right.
You remember the jewe ry job
in Koreatown, few years back?
They used wires
and went from one building to the other?
Guard got oose
He ended up shooting one of them?
Yeah. The guard ended up being
like a big hero.
The perp got shot on a fire escpe, right?
Name's Delonte Rivers, a k.a. Ghost.
He just finished serving five at Chino.
And somehow, h s prison lD ended up
at the Russians.
l saw it in the Polaroids.
So, you think this guy's good
for the FedCal heist?
l don't know. He ws released the same day
the bank was hit.
There's got to be some type of
connect on there, rght?
Yeah, Mx. Whts up?
-Morning Jck.
- Hey Mon ca
Whoa, whoa, s ow down.
- Mrketing rep
-You got to be kidding me.
Look, Max, you cn just tel Carver
he cn cal me Monday.
l don't work weekends, okay?
lnternal Affairs.
Well, can l make you some breakfst, Jack?
No, that's all right. l got to pick Sunday up.
Were gonn go look t some lndmarks.
-l' see you Monday.
-See you, Jack.
So, what do we got?
Whts the ass gnment fortoday?
Afterwe go to the Wlk of Fme,
l'm supposed to wrte about us going there.
Honey, the Wlk of Fame's not a andmark,
t's a tourist trap
l got a better andmark
Let's go overto La Brea Tar Pits,
and then afterwards
we can go to the museum,
we can look at the fossils.
And then afterthat, we can go to
the Farmers Market and get some burgers.
Good idea
Burgers and shakes at the Farmer s Market.
Yeah, what do you got for me?
Sweetheart, we're gonna have
to make a stop somewhere first.
When l got your messge from last night,
l pulled Rvers' file
saw he was due this afternoon.
Cons like him
they're good for a visit or two.
But fouryers of lockdown,
l wouldn't bet on him.
Theres your boy now
Want me to hold him? Ratt e his cage?
No. No, keep it routine.
-You got n ddress on this guy?
- Some dump in Long Beach
Probably good for a week if tht.
Al rght thnks.
Ltt e Tokyo Lets go.
Now are we going to the museum?
Just a sec honey We will.
-Anyth ng else?
-Give me a coup e of these, too.
Here, on the right.
-Thanks, mn.
- You got it.
-What's up?
-You're late.
-Howd the prole meeting go?
-We good.
You know they try and turn pissing in a cup
into a seven- game seres
We stra ght though.
-Can l help you?
- Relish.
-Jesse
-What's up?
What's happen ng? Where the guys?
l'm take-out. They're witing on me.
Sounds good.
- So, did you get t?
-Come on, mn lt's me.
Wht re you looking t, Daddy?
Just a second, honey.
Sme thing the rescue workers use.
Easy as shit. Works just like  cn opener.
-Speak to the disptcher?
-Yeah
Yeh, yeh yeh
l spoke to him this morn ng. We good.
-Come on, man
-Hey, the route's a lock G.
Ta k to you lter.
Hey, man, find you something else
to worry about, G
l got you, homes.
What?
Hold on to your set, honey.
What are you do ng idiot?
You see a pen baby? No?
There, you see that blue sedn back there?
Two cars back?
- Yeah.
-He's shark ng us.
Mke  right.
You have a pen, baby? Anything?
All right, make nother right.
-He's staying with us.
- Yeah.
Let's pull over.
- Who re they?
-They're just some guys.
-ls it a cop?
-Wth a kid?
Whts so importnt tht you'd drag my ass
all the way down here?
-l found him, Htch.
- Who?
Him, FedCal Gordon Cozier.
l mean, ook at that.
Sme height sme build, same everything.
Wait, ho d on. Wht re you tlking bout?
-Where's al th s com ng from?
- l followed that guy Rivers,
from h s prole meeting.
-And he gets out of a cab downtown.
- Wth Sunday?
What, are you gunn ng for
Fatherof the Year now?
And from my car,
l see him go to this hot-dog stand.
And Cozier's there.
Now, he's got his back to me.
But l swear l see Rivers
pass someth ng to him
A second ater, this guy on  motorcycle,
he ooks at Coz er.
And then right before he takes off, bam,
the sme gesture
the assho e used in the bank.
And then l followed Cozier
and got h s license plate number.
Yeah, it's very offical Wht is that, crayon?
Look, man l'm telling you, it's him.
Except you can't see his fce.
The guy's got a clean sheet.
Come on, man, you fol ow an ex.con
who's no good forthe bnk job to,
what a hot-dog stand?
-Then he meets somebody...
-Listen to me.
Mybe he meets somebody there,
maybe he doesn't
- Mybe he psses someth ng...
-Look Hatch, l'm te ling you l was there.
...nd buys  hot-dog
with ketchup and relish,
-nd then, some guy on  motorcycle sys...
-Call me crazy.
''So long,'' and rdes off.
Come on, man, give a brother a break.
Are you kidding me?
Can we st l go
to the Frmer's Mrket Daddy?
Baby, l m sorry. Geez.
l cn t believe t's this lte.
We can go eat somewhere else.
Just gonna take a few minutes here.
Whereveryou want.
Shit.
Your dddy loves you very much,
you know that, right?
-Don't ever forget that, okay?
- Okay.
Take care of the rea stuff Jack.
Hey, how about some pizza, huh?
l just wnn go home.
Let's go.
Well, whend it hppen?
No, no, no. lt's all right.
lf she comes back, do me  fvor,
you just keep her there, al rght, Jimmy,
and you ca l me.
She doesn't leave the hotel.
Do you understand me?
Al right.
Naomi?
l left Jimmy some money at the hotel.
He didn't put it in the safe.
- She took it?
-She's gone and so is the money. Shit!
-What you do ng, mate?
-l'm pulling over.
-Why?
-Cause you got to find her.
l'll tke yourtme n the tunnel tonight.
- Thnks
-You got it.
Damn it.
-How's t hanging?
-Funny guy.
All right, come on down.
Well go hot tomorrow morning.
Th s is gonna be lovely.
Hey G.
We good?
All s gns point to it.
-Any word from Naomi?
- No
Th s time, l think shes gone.
Shell turn up fine.
What mkes you so sure?
lf l hd any fmily left, thts where ld be.
You know, if nything goes wrong
tomorrow, we can't let him wa k away.
He could sti l hang us for 04.
l'll bring the nsurance.
There he is. How's t going Ghost?
l can't call it, gentlemen.
-Yeah
-What's happening?
-G. Cool
-Yeh, mn.
Feels good to be back n action agin.
lts like old times, huh?
So, where we meeting at after the drop?
Scotts giv ng me the informtion.
I'l et you know tomorrow.
''Come s p from the cup of destruction.''
- Gengh s Khan.
-Yeh. One of my heroes.
Saw what he wanted,
reached out and took it.
L ke us, tomorrow.
Just like us.
-To tomorrow.
To tomorrow.
Yeah?
Slow down, s ow down What?
Where are you?
All right. Wait, no, no, l'm coming.
l'm coming.
Where do l find Processing?
Through the far door. Follow the yellow line.
Where's Vice?
Take the stairs to the basement.
We got your fax last week
about the bank bills,
so when we na ed this scum
with a bunch of fresh hundreds,
thought we'd call you.
Th s low- lfe? You gotta be kidding me.
He ws husting some stolen shit
with his girlfriend when we stopped him.
None of the bills were marked but we f gure
they gotta be from some job.
Did you question h m?
No. He didn t go esy.
He's high as hell, too.
We decided to et him chill.
All right. Let me tlk to this guy.
All right, l don t hve time for this bu lshit.
Where did you get the bills?
l got him!
l'm not gonna ask you again.
Where did you get the b lls?
-lt was a oan, man, t was a loan!
- A loan. Bullshit!
l want a name. G ve me a name.
- Nomi.
-Naomi what?
-Naomi what? She got a last name?
-l don't know man l just met her.
You bust her too?
Yeah, her names Naomi Cozier.
Coz er? Did you hearthat Htch?
Yeah.
l aint going back to no hotel
to s t on my own.
Right you ain't going bck to the hotel,
you ain't go ng
to the freak ng Caribbean either.
You're going back to the rehab
to start your program again
-He l no, l ain't!
- Yes, you are
l'm tired of them nurses and doctors
mak ng you stand up
and chat your bus ness in front of strngers.
Every time you do the sme thing!
Every time Two days out of rehab!
Just two days
and you're in the pol ce station already.
Wheres the money l gve you?
ls it in your ve ns?
You know your prob em is
you're too nto my shit.
Let me see your arm Your shit.
You're not nto your own shit!
Why don't you get a fe?
You don't care about me.
You wouldn't even et me stay
at your apartment.
- Thts right.
-You're ashamed of me. And l raised you!
You ra sed me?
My crackhead sister raised me?
-Can't even ra se yourself.
- You ungratefu bastrd!
- Shut up
-But you a n't worth shit, mn.
-I should've let Welfare take you!
- You're right, you re right
Wonder.
Naomi!
No Naomi! Naomi!
Gordon Cozier.
Signed for her 20 minutes go.
-Second time in two dys.
- Yeah, l hearyou.
Even if we tie those bil s to a certain job,
it doesn't prove Cozier did anything.
Question him now, he awyers up,
sp ts town. We can blow th s case.
lf we can put him in the elevators
on the day of the heist,
we'll hve plenty to talk to him bout.
lt's time. Let's go, Casnov.
l'll see you tonight.
You be careful.
- l love you.
-Love you too.
Come on, lover boy! Let's go, mate!
Got a job to do, bby. Come on.
Let's go, et's go!
You wnt  coffee? Donut? Anything?
Naw. l'm okay.
Hey, Jack. Crverwants to see you.
Not now Mx.
Were getting close on th s FedCal job.
lt's not a request Detective Welles.
Orders Jack.
Al right.
Th s is chicken sh t, Chief.
The Ha tan the Russians.
l make judgment ca ls every day.
-The union sys l get an attorney...
- Before you go on about th s
-you need to...
-...just ike the assholes
-l gotta deal with out there.
-Jack, stop
Look, if you stll want to see  lawyer
in five minutes, you can have one.
Sit down.
Get down! Get on the ground!
Get on the ground! Spread your legs.!
-Keep your head down.
-The day you busted the Haitian,
Narcotics had surveillnce set up
in the bui ding across the street.
-Shut up! Stay down!
-l said they'd give you money.!
-What? What money?
-Money, right there!
Stay there, don't move! All right.
All right, get out of here. Go.
Turn it off. All right, turn it off.
l wanted you to know
who you were working with.
Felt l owed you that much.
lnternal Affairs s brnging chrges.
Papers are being drawn up today.
You wnn drop Hatcher? l understnd.
No no. No. No.
How'd it go?
You know same old, same old.
Shouldnt hve roughed up that drug dealer,
you know?
-That's the beef? Tht's it?
-Yeah
Wrning, short and sweet.
Check it out. That's our guy We got him.
Time to turn up the het on Mr. Cozier.
Let's go pay him  vis t.
All right, we're hot. Ready to rock, mn.
All right. Kill the traff c light.
Let's go.
Officeron duty.
All right, Officer.
Package is due n five minutes.
Crow's nest. Put an eye on him.
Copy tht.
You're drving.
Come on, let's go!
Come on, man. What's wrong with you?
Whyd you do it, Eddie?
Whyd you take the money?
Wht re you... What are you tlking about?
They got it on tpe.
Whyd you do it?
Shit, mn.
Monica's aid off We got a mortgge.
lnsurance doesn't pay shit.
All these medica b lls.
You gotta help me, Jack.
lt was right there
lt was rght there, and l took it.
Why didn't you come to me?
l'm Eddie's godfther.
Come on. You're ke my brother.
The kind of money I'm tlking bout,
you couldn't save it in a lfetime.
Look, youve had my bck
forthe ast six years
l'm gonna do whtever it tkes to help you,
okay?
Yeah.
Package is lte.
Mustve gotten hung up. They'll be here.
Goddamn! Get off my ass.
Th s is not good. Th s is not good.
Let me know G. l'm redy.
Come on, boys have some fith.
l nevertrusted this guy.
Th s is bad, we gotta do something.
Th s is LA, mn Nothing runs on time.
Damn a that We got a sh tload of C-4,
and we're ve down here. Come on.
Just be cool ll right?
Where the hell s it Ghost?
Talk to me. Where s it?
They're coming, God damn it.
They'll be here.
Sy the word G. l'l send it.
Y'aIl need to relax. l toId you they coming.
Damn!
G, we gotta mke a move. Come on, mn.
Al rght!
Where you t, John?
l know you up there, son of a bitch.
WelI? ls there anything?
Nada. lf he bolts, this may be
our last shot right now.
-G.
-Everybody, stay sharp.
They'lI be here, G.
They just running a little behind.
We gott do something. Come on.
Come on, bitch. Where are you?
Take him out.
They're here! They're here God damn it!
l told you they were com ng
All right, ho d up, hold up!
Buckle up, boys.!
They're turning down the ramp now.
Train's about to eave the station.
A'lght, G. Here they come.
Merging onto 4th.
God damn t. You kidd ng me?
What's the holdup?
Come on, guys, l m holding traffic.
Just give me the word
All right, boys we've still got cars
nside the cones here.
All right, keep me posted.
Come on.
Come on, already Yo, whts up?
- Let's go
-You gonna move this orwhat?
Cones look clear to me Holla at me.
Go on ahead and wave them through,
Officer.
Fina ly!
Where you going?
Showtime, boys!
-Al right, it's on.
-Al right, here we go.
- lt's on
-lt's in your hands now.!
Let's get paid, man.!
Fifty yards!
Twenty-five yards! Ten yards!
-Look out! Bike!
-Hit it!
Holy shit! Goddamn bicyc st!
Sh t!
-Jesus Christ!
-You ll right?
Damn t, too soon!
I stlIl see the trucks!
We missed! Where is it?
-Truck stopped short.
-What's going on?
-Shit!
-God damn it, Jake, you went too erly.
Shut up, Ghost, shut up!
The street blew up We're in trouble.
We gotta get out of here!
Sty in tht truck! We'll get you out of th s!
-Get out and move that traffic, let's go!
-G, now what?
-What we doing?
-Crow's nest! Where are you, crow's nest?
-Talk to me, talk to me!
-Jake, its a bust, mn.
-We gotta get out of here!
-What are we doing, G?
-l can't see sh t
-Follow procedure! Stay in that truck!
-Okay, lets cearth s!
-G, call it off!
-No, no hold on!
-What are y'a l doing?
G!
Abort! Abort!
All he l broke oose up here, man!
G!
Lets go, let's go
We gotta abort th s, we gotta abort th s!
- Abort, abort
-Ho d on, ho d on l see something up here!
We got a mn on the move.
No, Officer, we're abortng this now!
Not yet, God damn t, we got action!
You don't see what l see, G!
Just keep them busy!
What's this crazy son of a b tch doing?
Hey!
Shit! He just jacked a gurd!
Open this door!
We got a vehicular, people!
He in the truck!
Crazy son of a bitch is go ng for it!
He hit the car!
Keep it clear down below boys!
-Shit man, here he come!
-Here he comes, here he comes!
He's ramming the truck.!
-Here it come!
-Get out of the way!
That's wht I'm tlking bout! Damn!
-Get the jaws, get the jws!
- Keep them back
Shit! Litt e bastard!
Soldier boy done ost his damn mind!
Shit! What's he doing?
Our man got a problem here.
Hit the gurd!
lncoming!
Hell, yeh.
Take his shit!
l've got you man. Come on Got you.
We got it.
AIl units, 21 1 on an armored vehicle,
4th and OIive.
Repeat, armored vehicle robbery
ln progress, 4th and Olive.
4th nd Olive. That's them.
Turn the cararound.
l'm taking you home, Eddie.
Come on turn the carround.
lt's a couple blocks away.
- No, man.
-God damn it, man, I'm stil a cop!
Turn the car around!
Al right.
Let's hustle boys come on!
Yeah!
- Come on!
-Come on, Jake!
Go go go go!
Yeah, let's go, et's go, et's go, let's go!
Move t, move it!
Look at this.
Took  shit oad of explos ves to do this.
- C- 4.
-Yeah.
-Wht do you got?
-We got two down in the hole.
Guard got  look t one of them.
Caucsian mle, adult, n his 30s.
l got a sketch rtist coming here now
to work with our witness.
Jesus Christ.
They're ong gone
Sewertunne s in every direction.
Sewertunnels?
Rememberthat public works map
we found at the Russ an safe house?
The burnt fragment? The sewers, explosives.
High- powered weapons.
So the job went down
without ourtwo ded guys?
Yeah, wel , you remember the mp?
There was a subway map at the Russians.
Yeah, you th nk the sewers
connect to the subway station?
Could be, let's check it out.
-What was the closest stat on circled?
- Pershing Square.
Pardon me.
That's h m, Hatch! The guy with the gry hat!
From the hot- dog stand
- Shit!
-Freeze!
-We have a runner!
-Stop!
Asshole!
Get out the way, get out the wy!
Look out! Look out!
-Are you crazy?
-Shit!
You al rght? Hey! Where you going, pl?
We're in pursuit!
Headed toward Pershing Square.
He's headed through the prk!
Move. Move. Move.
Get off my car Hey!
He just left Grand!
He's headed towards the librry!
Yeah, man.
Sh t!
Police! Freeze!
Move!
Move, move, move, move! Get out the wy!
Police! Watch out!
-Wh ch way did he go?
- Back there.
-Can we exit this way?
- No
-Get out of the wy!
-Coverthose doors!
-Move move move!
- He went that way.
-He went that wy.
- Down the hall
Hey!
Move it!
Hey, hey!
Get out of my wy! Get out of my wy!
Everybody out!
Come on, Jesse.
Hatch?
Hatch!
Sh t!
Hold on buddy Just hold on. Jesus.
-The son of a bitch was fst.
- This is un t 14.
l got an officerdown
Sixth floor Monroe bu lding.
l need immediate assistance.
Freeze!
He's outs de!
Come on, come on
Just keep breathing buddy.
Keep breathing Come on, stay with me.
l need that crash un t fast! Now!
Come on, buddy. Hng in there.
We ost him!
L ne of duty, Jack Line of duty.
Yeah, come on. Come on.
You just keep brething.
You gotta make it, man Come on.
Look at me look t me.
My fm ly, man. Monic.
You take care of Eddie.
l'm gonna take care of yourfamily.
Don t worry about that.
They're gonn be taken cre of.
You just keep breathing.
- Come on.
-Tell Monica l love her.
-l will.
-Tell her l ove her.
Come on, buddy. Hng in there.
lt's me.
I know who t s l watch news.
You think l'm stupid, you punk bitch?
Hey, cool it brother
l sense a litt e too much hostility.
l was just trying to make everybody...
l give you dispatcher, and you do job
with somebody else
Two of my men dead. l k ll you!
You do not wanna k ll me. lf l'm dead
how am l gonna get you ha f the money?
You do wnt the money, don't you?
You Iistening now? Thought so.
Hey we meeting at the Roosevelt Hote .
l'm gonna convince them to give you half.
I'Il call you Iaterwith the room number.
Were ll rel sorry, Jack.
l just spoke wth his wfe.
Wht about the surve llnce tpe?
His family?
Forget the tpe.
He was kil ed in the line of duty.
He' l get  cops burial and fu benefits.
Good. Thanks.
You were mking hedway
with FedCal Bank. Was it them?
l don't know.
Guy started running, we chased him.
Eddie got shot. l got nothing.
You oky, Jack?
Yeah. l m fine.
-Jake? You herd from Jesse?
- No not yet
$19.3 million, so far.
Easily the biggest l ck yet, gentlemen.
Witnesses report...
l can feel it, man Somethings not right.
This is my faut, man.
l shouldve never brought him in.
-Hey, Ghost?
- Yes sir?
Yeah.
That's the account crd forthe 04 job.
That's $250,000 for the Russins.
That puts us even now, Ghost.
Sy what Rahway?
You heard me That puts us even.
Yeah, a'ight. My plan your commnd.
l knew l could trust y'all.
Who s it?
lt's him. Where you been? l been ca ling you!
-Po ice chsed me.
- Police? Where?
You brought them here?
Jesse, you brought them here?
No. l shot one of them.
-Wht?
-What?
-Ho d on! You shot a cop?
- l hd to, man
-Where the money?
-l stashed it
-You left the money? Dmn!
-Goddamn!
Stashed it? Hold, ho d on Everyone
hold on. What happened, Jesse? Ta k to me.
At the subwy sttion, there ws two cops.
And they just started chsing me.
And they chsed you
out the crowd because of what?
How, how the hell am I supposed to know?
-Why?
-Ghost. Hold on.
- Hold on! Hold on!
-No, man, let h m tel me why!
-So, what happened? You shot becuse?
-l don't know!
-l had to. He had me...
-Why'd you shoot h m?
'Cause you stupid.
l had no cho ce
He had me. He had me cold, mn.
But he neverfired t me
lt was... lt was kind of like...
L ke what?
L ke he wanted me to shoot him.
Stupid ass!
Shit! l'l beat the shit out of you.
- G! G! Wait!
-Let him go! Let him go!
Get off me! Yo cool it.
Get your hands off me!
-Back off! Back off!
-You understand what you just did?
- lt wasn't my fault!
-You don t shoot cops!
l'll del with it! Let him go!
You dea with t then Jake!
That's a death sentence young blood,
and l ain t going with you
Nice one, Jesse.
Still taking passengers tonight?
Van Nuys Airport, 8:30.
Look, with everything that happened
today, noth ng personal,
l'll tke cre of yourfinances
and then l'm out.
-Okay.
-Fir enough.
I'm standing about a block away
from the Monroe offlce buiIding
in downtown Los Angeles
where an LAPD detective
was shot and kiIIed about an hour ago.
Right on time.
Witnesses describe...
So, Jesse, how'd it fee
losing that money, shooting tht cop?
-Ghost. Esy.
- What?
Now, we can't confirm,
at this hour, but the suspect...
Ghost we a n't gotta act
like we friends nymore, do we?
Hey, business is bus ness Money is money.
l neversaid we were friends.
-Now, me and Lilli, however.
-Come here! You wanna...
Hey Tke it esy! Hey, Jake Jke Jke!
Hey, come on, take t easy!
He's not worth it all right?
All right, let's get the fellas
and get out of here.
l'm here. Wh ch room?
11 16. A'ight.
Hey, WelIes, where you at? You got a 20?
Come on, man, l know you're out there.
Pick up
We're worried about you. Where you...
All rght, fells, were good.
We're out ofhere.
So, heres the dea .
Anyone wants to fly with...
- Where's Ghost?
-ln the bathroom.
Get Ghost for me.
Ton ght, Scott, 8:30, Van Nuys Airport,
al rght?
Plne's ready. Bring your passports,
your bags, and your guns.
Ghost? Hey!
lf you need nything,
make sure you give us a call.
Whts he doing, taking a shower?
What's go ng on in here?
-What ws that?
-Shower's on
Hey, he's gone!
-I to d you l told you!
- What?
-I don't know about this.
-Damn!
-What are you tlking about?
- Where'd he go?
-l knew this ws a bad dea!
-Damn it!
Let's get out of here, let's get out.
Oh, sh t!
Take out the automat c!
Jesse!
Hey, Jake, you okay?
Get up man, get up! Come on buddy!
Come on, man, come on!
-Out the back!
-Jesse, Jake, let's go!
Come on, let's go!
Go l'm coming.
Go!
Come on come on!
Wheres A.J? Wheres A.J? Wheres...
Down, get down!
-Sh t Who re these guys?
-Sounds ike Russians
Jake! Check the halway.
Let's put these beds up, let's go!
We got a shotgun in the hllwy!
Sty low sty low!
Shit! l'm out of mmo! l'm out l'm out!
Wheres Jake?
We gotta go, fel as. We gott go.
Ghost set us up against the Russins.
Son of a bitch, he must've sold them
on the sme pln.
That's why they gve him the dispatcher
nd that big hurry-up
was just to get us to do the job first.
-Yeah, and we bought it.
-Yeh, all of t.
Shit, the heat's gonna be com ng down now.
l know. See you at the irport.
L lli? L lli?
Hold on baby. Oh God bby get up Baby.
Oh my God, baby, wke up. Oh just...
Goddmn, the money's gone!
Jesse help me! Help me!
Ghost. Ghost, l'm gonna ki you. Oh God.
Jake, we got compny.
Jake, we gott go. We have to go.
Oh God. Ghost.
Los Angeles Police Department.
Exit the bullding sIowly.
You have 20 seconds to come out.
Look, Jake. l ws wrong about Ghost.
l'm sorry, mn.
lt's not yourfult.
Jesse, you a n't gotta be down with me
on this one.
You got your own life to think about, mn.
l already told you l'm nevergoing back.
And th s is my life.
My cr's out bck. Where's yours?
ln front.
Let's take yours.
Thought you'd sy tht.
You ready, bro?
Just me nd you, big brother. Lets go.
-Naomi.
-G!
-What are you doing? Come here.
What are you doing? Are you all right?
-They won t let me in your building.
-We've gotta go.
Come on, let's get in the car. All right.
-Just wnna go home.
- All right.
There you are.
- Talk to me
-l'm almost to the airport.
Yeah, me, too.
Hey, l'm tripp ng
Hear me out right quick, all right?
Yeah, whts up?
Ghost has had the jump on us
from the get- go, rght?
So, why wou d he take us ll out
and then only sett e forthe cash
from the 04 job?
-He wouldn t.
- Un ess
-Man, he plans on tking ll the money.
-Shit, Scott. Scott has all the money
Exacty. l'm on my way l m right behind you.
l know this s a little last- minute.
Have him meet me at the bank.
Come on, Scott, pick up. Scott pick up.
Yeah, l'm coming n tonight.
You have to mke yourself vilab e
at 9:00 a.m tomorrow, all right?
Cn you do tht?
You've reached Scott. I'm away from my cell.
Oh God. No, Scott pick up. Damn it.
Al right.
Okay. Let's get out of here.
lts been a long day.
Can you pour me a Scotch?
Yeah, where re you going? You just
had to have it all, didn't you, Ghost?
-l'm just taking whts mine!
- Oh, yeah?
l should ve shot you on the street today.
Naw, you should've shot me f ve years ago
on that fire escape.
You got caught, Ghost! You got caught!
You knew the gme
when you was p ay ng it!
You left me back there to die l ke l was shit!
You ain't sh t, Ghost!
l helped you put this crew together!
So what? Now you wanna take it apart?
Drop the weapon Drop it! Po ce!
Put them down!
-Put them down!
-Stay out of this
-Better listen to him, cop
-lt's between me and him.
lf you interfere l m gonna kill you, too.
-Lst time, drop them!
- Shit.
Wht you expect me to do, G? Huh?
You took my money. Took my b tch from me.
Just put me out the crew, huh?
Wht you thought I ws gonna do?
Let that shit go?
You got caught!
Yeah. A'ight l see now.
lt's ll bus ness for you.
Well, th s shit just got real personl.
-Shou d've waited for me G.
- The shit went too fast.
Hold hold it, hold t, hold it.
Don't move Don't you move!
You're that cop with the ttle girl.
You shou d've stayed out of this.
-Lets get that money nd get out of here.
- Yeah.
Emergency dispatch.
Yeah.
You got n officer down
Van Nuys Airport, hangar 12.
l've been shot and l need help.
Units en route.
l want help.
G? Are we going home now?
Yeah, baby. We're going home.
Are we good, brother?
All s gns point to it.