1
00:00:34,703 --> 00:00:39,877
苏格兰忆昔
（卡利多尼亚：苏格兰古名）

2
00:01:17,589 --> 00:01:20,357
I don't know if you can see

3
00:01:21,126 --> 00:01:24,093
The changes that have come over me

4
00:01:24,756 --> 00:01:27,868
In these last few days I've been afraid

5
00:01:28,292 --> 00:01:31,139
That I might drift away

6
00:01:33,684 --> 00:01:37,116
I've been telling old stories, singing songs

7
00:01:37,629 --> 00:01:41,389
That make me think about
where I've come from

8
00:01:41,684 --> 00:01:44,796
That's the reason why I seem

9
00:01:45,075 --> 00:01:48,436
So far away today

10
00:01:50,660 --> 00:01:53,580
Let me tell you that I love you

11
00:01:54,525 --> 00:01:57,499
That I think about you all the time

12
00:01:58,532 --> 00:02:01,435
Caledonia, you're calling me

13
00:02:01,732 --> 00:02:05,188
Now I'm going home

14
00:02:06,099 --> 00:02:08,396
But if I should become a stranger

15
00:02:09,475 --> 00:02:12,484
Know that it would make
me more than sad

16
00:02:13,436 --> 00:02:18,187
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

17
00:02:31,964 --> 00:02:34,940
Now I have moved
and I've kept on moving

18
00:02:35,659 --> 00:02:38,931
Proved the points that I needed proving

19
00:02:39,453 --> 00:02:42,219
Lost the friends that I needed losing

20
00:02:42,771 --> 00:02:46,420
Found others on the way

21
00:02:48,355 --> 00:02:51,347
I have kissed the fellas
and left them crying

22
00:02:52,164 --> 00:02:55,075
Stolen dreams, yes, there's no denying

23
00:02:55,692 --> 00:02:58,723
I have traveled hard,
sometimes with conscience flying

24
00:02:59,540 --> 00:03:02,355
Somewhere with the wind

25
00:03:05,122 --> 00:03:07,353
Let me tell you that I love you

26
00:03:08,554 --> 00:03:11,291
That I think about you all the time

27
00:03:12,498 --> 00:03:15,043
Caledonia, you're calling me

28
00:03:15,580 --> 00:03:18,123
Now I'm going home

29
00:03:19,762 --> 00:03:22,211
But if I should become a stranger

30
00:03:23,242 --> 00:03:26,363
Know that it would make
me more than sad

31
00:03:27,138 --> 00:03:31,931
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

32
00:03:45,611 --> 00:03:48,842
Now I'm sitting here before the fire

33
00:03:49,426 --> 00:03:52,490
The empty room, the forest choir

34
00:03:53,074 --> 00:03:56,123
The flames have cooled,
don't get any higher

35
00:03:56,570 --> 00:04:00,473
They've withered, now they've gone

36
00:04:01,938 --> 00:04:04,947
But I'm steady thinking,
my way is clear

37
00:04:05,594 --> 00:04:08,666
And I know what I will do tomorrow

38
00:04:09,074 --> 00:04:12,186
When hands have shaken,
the kisses float

39
00:04:12,619 --> 00:04:16,154
Then I will disappear

40
00:04:18,161 --> 00:04:20,545
Let me tell you that I love you

41
00:04:21,491 --> 00:04:24,226
That I think about you all the time

42
00:04:25,226 --> 00:04:28,049
Caledonia, you're calling me

43
00:04:28,370 --> 00:04:31,530
Now I'm going home

44
00:04:32,410 --> 00:04:34,858
But if I should become a stranger

45
00:04:35,737 --> 00:04:38,562
Know that it would make
me more than sad

46
00:04:39,425 --> 00:04:43,618
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

47
00:04:53,997 --> 00:04:59,196
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

48
00:05:11,957 --> 00:05:18,229
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

49
00:05:19,253 --> 00:05:28,132
Caledonia's been everything I've ever had

50
00:05:43,000 --> 00:05:47,000
Bridge Over Troubled Water
（恶水大桥）

51
00:05:53,089 --> 00:05:57,074
When you're weary

52
00:06:00,417 --> 00:06:05,154
Feeling small

53
00:06:08,881 --> 00:06:15,824
When tears are in your eyes

54
00:06:17,009 --> 00:06:21,716
I will dry them all

55
00:06:25,136 --> 00:06:29,553
I'm on your side

56
00:06:30,480 --> 00:06:35,265
When times get rough

57
00:06:36,240 --> 00:06:41,695
And friends just can't be found

58
00:06:42,711 --> 00:06:50,281
Like a bridge over troubled water

59
00:06:51,530 --> 00:06:54,672
I will lay me down

60
00:06:55,472 --> 00:07:03,937
Like a bridge over troubled water

61
00:07:06,568 --> 00:07:14,672
I will lay me down

62
00:07:17,639 --> 00:07:19,512
When you're down and out

63
00:07:22,304 --> 00:07:25,336
When you're on the street

64
00:07:26,368 --> 00:07:32,472
When evening falls so hard

65
00:07:33,040 --> 00:07:35,528
I will comfort you

66
00:07:37,039 --> 00:07:41,056
I'll take your part

67
00:07:42,049 --> 00:07:45,408
When darkness comes

68
00:07:47,625 --> 00:07:52,944
And pain is all around

69
00:07:53,479 --> 00:08:00,696
Like a bridge over troubled water

70
00:08:01,993 --> 00:08:05,239
I will lay me down

71
00:08:05,728 --> 00:08:13,216
Like a bridge over troubled water

72
00:08:15,832 --> 00:08:25,039
I will lay me down

73
00:08:33,049 --> 00:08:35,815
Sail on Silver Girl

74
00:08:38,028 --> 00:08:40,332
Sail on by

75
00:08:41,845 --> 00:08:47,636
Your time has come to shine

76
00:08:47,989 --> 00:08:50,908
All your dreams are on their way

77
00:08:51,838 --> 00:08:54,790
See how they shine

78
00:08:57,488 --> 00:09:00,631
If you need a friend

79
00:09:02,125 --> 00:09:06,933
I'm sailing right behind

80
00:09:07,844 --> 00:09:14,196
Like a bridge over troubled water

81
00:09:15,111 --> 00:09:17,421
I will ease your mind

82
00:09:18,317 --> 00:09:26,532
Like a bridge over troubled water

83
00:09:36,597 --> 00:09:48,668
I will ease your mind

84
00:09:53,093 --> 00:09:58,189
I will ease your mind

85
00:10:50,623 --> 00:10:55,808
Ave Maria
圣母颂

86
00:11:10,861 --> 00:11:21,303
Ave Maria
Hail Maria

87
00:11:23,565 --> 00:11:30,277
Gratia plena
Full of grace

88
00:11:30,926 --> 00:11:39,256
Maria, gratia plena
Maria, full of grace

89
00:11:40,206 --> 00:11:46,269
Maria, gratia plena
Maria, full of grace

90
00:11:48,336 --> 00:11:55,750
Ave, ave dominus
Hail, Hail Lord

91
00:11:56,150 --> 00:11:59,517
Dominus tecum
The Lord is with thee

92
00:12:01,230 --> 00:12:08,663
Benedicta tu in mulieribus
Blessed art thou among women

93
00:12:10,455 --> 00:12:17,174
Et benedictus
And blessed is

94
00:12:18,374 --> 00:12:26,349
Et benedictus fructus ventris
And blessed is the fruit of thy womb

95
00:12:26,997 --> 00:12:35,238
Ventris tui, Jesus
Of thy womb, Jesus

96
00:12:37,414 --> 00:12:48,974
Ave Maria
Hail Maria

97
00:13:00,782 --> 00:13:05,317
Mater dei
Mother of God

98
00:13:08,453 --> 00:13:17,174
Ora pro nobis pecatoribus
pray for us sinners

99
00:13:17,869 --> 00:13:24,852
Ora, ora pro nobis
Pray, pray for us

100
00:13:25,716 --> 00:13:37,390
Ora ora pro nobis pecatoribus
pray for us sinners

101
00:13:38,933 --> 00:13:47,772
Nunc et in hora mortis
now and at the hour of death

102
00:13:48,509 --> 00:13:54,781
In hora mortis nostrae
at the hour of our death

103
00:13:56,524 --> 00:14:04,414
In hora mortis, mortis nostrae
at the hour of death, our death

104
00:14:09,780 --> 00:14:16,908
In hora mortis nostrae
at the hour of our death

105
00:14:21,493 --> 00:14:37,492
Ave Maria
Hail Maria

