Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Yes, sir. I will do that.
Urgent. Urgent.
Where's Lin? Lin Braddock?
She left.
You know where she went?
I don't know.
Lin...
is your man really
take you to America?
Yes, of course.
What about all this?
I can't take everything.
What about this?
Yes. Take it.
Take anything you want.
Stay back! Stay back!
I can't let you in!
Please disperse.
We can't help you all.
We have no room!
Captain, has a Lin Braddock
come through the gate?
If you work for the Embassy,
have your papers ready!
Not yet, Colonel.
You're a friend of Lin?
I'm her husband.
She went to her home.
When?
One hour, maybe two.
She had to get her papers.
Please disperse!
The dress is so beautiful.
Thank you.
Good-bye, Min. Take care.
Bye.
Hold it.
We found her upstairs.
You know her?
Guess what I've got.
All right. Hit it.
Roger.
I said
get the hell off of there!
I'm Lin Braddock!
Look at the list!
I work for the Embassy!
Lin Braddock!
Captain!
What is it?
She says she's on the list.
What name?
Lin Braddock!
I'm a translator
for the embassy!
Give me your papers.
I lost them!
They stole it!
Please! Look at the list!
I need your papers!
I told you! Somebody stole them!
Oh, God! You have to believe me!
Well, there's nothing
I can do about that.
Please! Lin!
Look at the list!
This morning there was
a Colonel Braddock.
Is Colonel Braddock
your husband?
Yes! Yes!
For crying out loud!
These people are crazy!
Get them down!
Shoot them! Get it together!
Grab the seal.
Step aside! Move!
Come on, Junior.
Get these folks out!
Get off me!
Get out of the way!
Move! Stand aside!
Let's go!
Please!
Wait! Please!
Commander, please.
I give you
a thousand dollar.
Please. I love America.
Come on.
Hey.
Let me go up.
Let me go!
OK. Take off.
Son of a bitch!
Don't worry.
We got you, Colonel!
That bastard was probably V.C.
All right.
There you go, Colonel.
Move them out. Move!
No medals, no ribbons
No welcome parade
It's a lonely road home
And a heavy price to pay
Now I say a prayer
For those that remain
And I wonder
Will they ever
find freedom again?
- Hi, Cindy.
- Hey.
I should run for president.
What'd you say?
I didn't think he needed to.
Oh, really?
Mr. Braddock?
That's right.
Colonel James Braddock?
What can I do for you?
Could I have a few
moments of your time?
- Sit down.
- Thank you.
Please, uh...
could we please talk
more privately?
Yeah. Sure.
Thank you.
Would you like
something to drink?
No, no. Thank you.
I am Reverend Polanski...
from the Amerasian Children's
Mission in Vietnam.
Occasionally,
I come to this country...
to raise funds for the mission.
I was hoping I could
find you before I went back.
Find me? Why?
About a year ago,
a young Amerasian child...
came to the mission
begging for help.
He told me that
his mother was sick.
I went to see if there
was anything I could do...
and found out she worked
for the U.S. Embassy...
during the war.
She has been severely punished
by the Vietnamese government.
Having the half-American
son has made things...
even worse for her.
I'm sorry to hear that, but...
what's that
got to do with me?
The woman's married name
is Mrs. James Braddock.
What did you say?
I'm talking about
your wife, Mr. Braddock.
Lin Tan Cang.
You're mistaken.
No. There is no mistake.
My wife died during
the fall of Saigon.
Your wife is alive.
I know her quite well.
Your son's name is Van.
He's now 12 years old.
My wife and I didn't have a son.
Why is it so hard
for you to believe me?
Because I saw my wife's body
burned to a crisp, that's why.
You may have seen a body...
but it wasn't your wife.
Lin Tan Cang is alive!
Believe whatever
you want, Reverend.
I know better.
Your few moments are up.
Oh, they had this great
place in Georgetown.
Really nice.
Yeah, of course.
I saw it last week.
Even if you did believe me...
I doubt if there
is anything you could do.
I've already gone
to the State Department...
and they will do nothing...
but I had to let you know.
Good-bye, Mr. Braddock.
God be with you.
Braddock?
C.I.A.
Please come with us.
Wait outside.
It's been a long time,
Colonel Braddock.
How have you been?
You know how I've
been, Littlejohn.
Now, what do you want?
You just met with
a Reverend Polanski.
So?
Did he tell you
some kind of...
crazy story about
your wife being alive?
Is it a crazy story?
Of course it is.
Big mistake, Littlejohn.
I didn't believe it until now.
What are you going to do
about getting them out?
Nothing.
If I don't get them out...
they're going to die.
People die every day.
Braddock!
I'm warning you.
Don't step on any toes.
I don't step on toes,
Littlejohn.
I step on necks.
Welcome to Bangkok.
We hope you enjoyed
your flight...
and will fly
with Thai Airlines again.
Take me downtown.
40 bob, please.
Now, look here, mate.
I said I need more room.
Now beat it!
Whoo! You take me home.
You want to try knocking me off?
How the hell are you, Braddock?
Did you get everything?
Yes, I got everything...
but it sure as hell wasn't easy.
That's why
I appreciate you, Mik.
That's what friends
are for, Braddock...
which reminds me.
Got my money?
Let's go.
No, no, no!
No need to hurry.
The plane won't be loaded
for several hours yet.
We got a long drive out of town.
Oh, shit. Here comes trouble.
Go get the car
and pull out front.
Ah, OK.
Hey.
You're not going
anywhere, Miklachek.
Take him to the car.
Jeez. Hey, where's
the rules about...
Hey, watch my beer,
man! Hey, listen.
I warned you, Braddock,
not to fuck with us.
Don't try to stop me,
Littlejohn.
You're stopped.
Come on.
Oh! Oh, my God!
Freeze, asshole,
or you're dead!
Excuse me, girls.
Braddock!
Cut him off!
Braddock.
Stop right there.
Braddock! Wait!
Son of a bitch.
You actually made it.
- Shit!
- Uh-oh.
Braddock!
He's getting away!
Hurry! Get in your cars!
Go after him! Hit it!
Oh, no!
Way to go, man!
Jesus, Braddock.
Couldn't you lighten up
just a teeny bit?
I mean, I got to live here.
You've got a one-way
ticket out.
Jesus, Braddock.
Watch it!
Whoa!
Oh, shit, Braddock.
We'll have the whole
damn police force after us.
How far is it
to the plane?
Uh, it's quite a ways
out of Bangkok.
No. It will be daylight
before we get there.
Hey, the boss is coming!
Don't hang around!
Why didn't you have
her going, man?
Let's go!
Come, come, come!
Are you sure this thing
will get off the ground?
Oh, relax, mother.
Sit back. Enjoy the ride.
It'll be just like Coney Island.
OK, Braddock...
are you gonna tell me
where we're going now?
As if I didn't know.
Along the coast.
Ganh Rai Bay.
We're gonna have to
skim the waves...
when we get there to
stay underneath their radar.
Hey, Braddock, you've
done some flying.
Why don't you take
the controls, eh?
Give me a rest.
Let's see if you can fly
as well as you can drive, eh?
It's been a long time.
Oh, you can do it.
I tell you...
it's a lot calmer up here...
than it is in your automobile.
You know, when we get
to the drop zone...
I'm gonna pull her
up into a climb...
and you'll have
about five seconds...
to make the drop before
I put her into a dive.
I'll need ten seconds.
Well, if you're a good boy,
I'll give you ten seconds.
Vietnam.
I never thought
I'd be coming back.
I guess we never really
can leave, can we?
Aw, come on.
Get your ass back there.
I'll take it.
OK, Braddock.
You got thirty seconds.
Good luck, mother.
See you in hell,
you crazy bastard.
Come on!
Let us each give thanks
in our own way.
- Amen.
Thank you, Father,
wise and good...
for home and friends
and daily food.
Bless, dear Lord,
the food we take...
and keep us all...
Oh, my God.
And keep us all home and safe.
Amen.
Please start without me.
I'll be right back.
Braddock.
How on earth did you get here?
Where's my wife?
She doesn't live very far.
Can you tell me
how to get there?
I'll take you there.
Here. Wear this.
There's a curfew.
We must be very careful.
I tried to tell you
how bad it was.
You'd better go, Reverend.
And thanks.
Good luck. God bless you.
I didn't know.
I thought you were...
It's not important.
I prayed you would
come for us...
and you are here.
That is all that matters
to Van and I.
This is your son, Jim.
Hello, Van.
I speak English, Braddock.
For years, he dreamed about you.
Sometimes, in very
difficult moments...
I would find him
talking to you...
as if you were there...
and somehow you would
make things right for him...
but one day,
he stopped believing.
I tried to keep you
alive in his heart.
I tried.
I guess I know
how you feel, Van...
thinking that I deserted
you and your mother...
but... I want you
to know that...
Van, please.
If I had known that you
and your mother were alive...
there's nothing in the world...
that would have stopped me
from coming for you before now.
You've suffered so much.
I know I have changed, Jim.
I'm sorry I'm no longer
pretty for you.
You'll always be
beautiful to me.
We have to go now.
We are ready.
Let me check the street first.
Van, hurry.
Come on.
Hurry, hurry.
The boat's right down there.
It might be a tight squeeze...
but I think you're going
to enjoy the ride, Van.
If you say so, Braddock.
Please be patient.
We've only had each other
for twelve years...
and now...
it is very difficult for him.
He will need some time.
We have all the time
in the world.
I love you very much,
Jim Braddock.
I think I should talk
to our son for a moment.
I'll go get the boat ready.
Van.
Everything will be all right.
You don't care about me now.
You only care about HIM.
That is not true.
It was our love that
brought you into this world.
Your father loves you as I do.
If you will only
give him a chance.
Please try, Van.
I'm very scared.
I know you are...
but once we get to America...
everything will be better.
I promise.
Your father promises.
Lin, we have to
get out of here.
Hurry!
Foolish.
You're in Nam.
Very foolish to come back.
I am General Quoc.
How do you do, Madam Braddock?
And yoi.
And this must be your son Van.
Very good-looking boy.
When I received the report...
that a strange-looking boat
had outrun my gunboats...
and heading towards
Ho Chi Minh city...
I took the privilege...
of assuming it was you,
Colonel Braddock...
since Reverend Polanski
had just returned...
from your country...
but now...
Braddock...
you must pay for the crimes
that you have committed...
against my beloved country.
They have nothing
to do with this.
You are absolutely right.
No!
Ma!
You will find your first test...
quite challenging.
Usually, we use people
who are...
a little bit taller.
I have tested
many before, Braddock...
and no one has lasted
even an hour.
Maybe you can be the first, eh?
I'll do whatever you want.
Just let the boy go.
You will do what I want anyways.
Well done.
Well done, Colonel Braddock.
You are every bit as tough
as your reputation.
I like that.
You have not disappointed
me, Braddock.
No!
This has gone on long enough.
Van!
I'm in here!
Come on! Come on!
Can you make it?
Yeah.
Go to the mission.
What's wrong?
What are you doing?
Where is Braddock?
I don't know where
Braddock is, General.
You lie, priest. You lie!
We know you helped Braddock!
I? You must be mistaken.
You lie!
Perhaps a change
of environment...
will help you
to think more clearly!
Take him!
Please, no.
I can't leave my children.
They need me!
Of course!
I would not want
to separate you...
from your half-breed
American bastard children!
Take them all!
Priest, your new home
will be Olaha prison!
Don't! Don't!
Don't!
No! No!
Stop!
Kids! In the truck!
Van!
Where's the Reverend?
I know! I get him, Braddock!
Come on, Reverend.
Thank God, Braddock!
Protect yourself!
Reverend, get the kids
out of here!
Out! Hurry! Hurry!
We must get away
from the truck!
Hurry up, Braddock! Here!
Get down, Reverend!
It's OK.
Ninety kilometers to the border.
You don't expect
these children...
to walk ninety kilometers!
I don't expect
a damn thing, Reverend.
But walk or crawl,
we're gonna make it.
Come on, kids.
Come on, Reverend.
Braddock...
the children are dead tired.
We must stop to rest.
Please, Braddock.
They are not very strong.
Wait here.
Reverend. Reverend!
Bring the kids.
Hurry.
Come. Come, children.
Quiet. Be quiet.
Come, children. Hurry. Hurry.
Come, children.
Be careful. Be careful.
Don't hurt yourselves.
Come.
Go. Go.
Come on, kids. Hurry!
Hurry! Hurry! Hurry up!
Thomas!
Hurry!
Sit down and hold on.
Damn it.
Braddock, get back, you bastard!
Come on!
Hold on!
Braddock! I will kill you...
and I will burn
those filthy children!
Hold on.
Oh, my God.
Get back there
with the kids, Reverend.
It's gonna get rough.
It's going to get rough.
Mayday. Mayday.
This is
Colonel James Braddock...
calling American Military
Assistance Command.
Come in.
Mayday. Mayday.
Here. Take a seat.
This is Colonel Braddock.
I'm in a crippled C-47.
I have a planeload
of Amerasian children.
Losing fuel.
I'm approximately eighty miles
east of the Thai border.
If anyone can hear me,
please transfer this message...
to the American Military
Assistance Command.
Is everyone OK back there?
Are you OK?
Yeah. I fine.
How you?
I'm fine, too.
Reverend! We're going down!
Children! Get down!
Hold on! Hold on!
We're gonna die!
Just hold on!
Van.
Come on, Van.
Help the kids.
Everybody down.
Reverend.
My God.
Braddock, there's the border.
As soon as I take
the guards out...
you get the kids
over the bridge...
as fast as you can.
Did you hear what I said?
On my way over here...
I was wondering
what you would be like.
I want you to know...
you're everything
I wanted in a son...
and I'm very proud of you.
I love you.
All right, men. Let's go.
What the hell is happening, Dan?
Braddock and the children.
We intercepted a radio message.
They crashed
somewhere near here.
Oh, shit.
Van!
Don't go!
Can't leave him, Dan.
I got to help him.
Leave it alone, General.
He's on his own.
No one crosses the border.
Get a medic in, man.
All right!
Daddy!
Don't go!
Christ.
I got you, Braddock!
I got you!
Daddy!
No, no. No, Van.
Get back! Get back!
No. No. Please!
You're finished, Braddock!
I've won!
They will not dare to cross.
What's he doing?
Hold your position.
He makes one wrong move,
we'll climb up his ass.
You got it.
The Americans are bluffing.
They will not dare do any more.
Fire! Fire!
Dad!
There he is!
Oh, Braddock.
Thank God you are alive.
Come on, children.
Thank you.
Bless you.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org